<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <title>To require the Secretary of Commerce to study the coverage gaps of the Next Generation Weather Radar of the National Weather Service and to develop a plan for improving radar coverage and hazardous weather detection and forecasting.</title>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>To require the Secretary of Commerce to study the coverage gaps of the Next Generation Weather Radar of the National Weather Service and to develop a plan for improving radar coverage and hazardous weather detection and forecasting.</title>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
        <chamberCode />
        <chamberName />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
    </policyArea>
    <amendments />
    <billNumber>1427</billNumber>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <calendarNumbers />
    <createDate>2017-03-09T05:25:13Z</createDate>
    <updateDate>2018-03-30T14:04:10Z</updateDate>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2017-04-25</actionDate>
      <links />
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <laws />
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <fullName>Rep. Pittenger, Robert [R-NC-9]</fullName>
        <bioguideId>P000606</bioguideId>
        <lastName>Pittenger</lastName>
        <byRequestType />
        <firstName>Robert</firstName>
        <district>9</district>
        <state>NC</state>
        <middleName />
        <party>R</party>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId />
          <lisID>2141</lisID>
          <bioguideId>P000606</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. PITTENGER:H.R. 1427.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Article I, Section 8, Clause 3. To regulate Commerce withforeign Nations, and among the several States, and with theIndian Tribes;Article I, Section 8, Clause 18. The Congress shall havePower to make all laws which shall be necessary and properfor carrying into Execution the foregoing Powers, and allother Powers vested by the Constitution in the Government ofthe United States or in any Department or Officer thereof.[Page H1949]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <cosponsors />
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <notes />
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2017-04-07T15:39:30Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
          <updateDate>2017-03-08T05:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <actionDate>2017-03-08</actionDate>
          <text><![CDATA[<p> This bill directs the Department of Commerce to complete a study on gaps in the coverage of the Next Generation Weather Radar of the National Weather Service (NEXRAD). </p> <p> Commerce shall identify areas in the United States with limited or no NEXRAD coverage below 6,000 feet above ground level of the surrounding terrain.</p> <p>For those areas identified, Commerce shall also:</p> <ul> <li>identify the key weather effects for which prediction would improve with improved radar detection;</li> <li>identify additional sources of observations for high impact weather available and operational for such areas, including Terminal Doppler Weather Radar, air surveillance radars of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), and cooperative network observers; and </li> <li>assess the feasibility and advisability of efforts to integrate and upgrade federal radar capabilities in such areas that are not owned or controlled by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, including radar capabilities of the FAA and the Department of Defense. </li> </ul> <p>In addition, under such study Commerce shall:</p> <ul> <li>assess the feasibility and advisability of incorporating state-operated and other nonfederal radars into the operations of the National Weather Service (NWS); and </li> <li>identify options to improve radar coverage in all of the areas identified as having limited or no NEXRAD coverage. </li> </ul> <p>After completing the study, Commerce shall submit a plan for improving radar coverage in the identified areas by integrating and upgrading additional observation solutions to improve hazardous weather detection and forecasting.</p> <p>Commerce shall seek third-party reviews on scientific methodology related to, and the feasibility and advisability of, implementing the plan to improve radar coverage, including the extent to which warning and forecast services of the NWS would be improved by additional NEXRAD coverage. </p>]]></text>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2017-03-08</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <congress>115</congress>
        <number>572</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestTitle>A bill to require the Secretary of Commerce to study the coverage gaps of the Next Generation Weather Radar of the National Weather Service and to develop a plan for improving radar coverage and hazardous weather detection and forecasting, and for other purposes.</latestTitle>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <systemCode>hssy00</systemCode>
          <subcommittees>
            <item>
              <name>Environment Subcommittee</name>
              <systemCode>hssy18</systemCode>
              <activities>
                <item>
                  <date>2017-04-25T14:34:23Z</date>
                  <name>Referred to</name>
                </item>
              </activities>
            </item>
          </subcommittees>
          <name>Science, Space, and Technology Committee</name>
          <type>Standing</type>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <date>2017-03-08T15:01:25Z</date>
              <name>Referred to</name>
            </item>
          </activities>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <cboCostEstimates />
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
        </policyArea>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Atmospheric science and weather</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <committeeReports />
    <title>To require the Secretary of Commerce to study the coverage gaps of the Next Generation Weather Radar of the National Weather Service and to develop a plan for improving radar coverage and hazardous weather detection and forecasting.</title>
    <recordedVotes />
    <actions>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>4</houseOfRepresentatives>
      </actionByCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-04-25</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hssy18</systemCode>
          <name>Environment Subcommittee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2017-03-08</actionDate>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hssy00</systemCode>
          <name>Science, Space, and Technology Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2017-03-08</actionDate>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <committee />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <actionDate>2017-03-08</actionDate>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <committee />
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
      </actionTypeCounts>
    </actions>
    <introducedDate>2017-03-08</introducedDate>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

