<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<billStatus>
  <bill>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <latestAction>
          <actionTime>10:28:32</actionTime>
          <actionDate>2017-07-28</actionDate>
          <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <congress>115</congress>
        <number>481</number>
        <type>HRES</type>
        <latestTitle>Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3180) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2018 for intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the United States Government, the Community Management Account, and the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System, and for other purposes; waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules; and providing for proceedings during the period from July 31, 2017, through September 4, 2017.</latestTitle>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
            <type>Procedurally-related</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2017-09-07</actionDate>
          <text>By Senator Burr from Select Committee on Intelligence filed written report. Report No. 115-151. Additional and Minority views filed.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <congress>115</congress>
        <number>1761</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestTitle>Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018</latestTitle>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
            <type>Related bill</type>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>H. Rept. 115-251</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <recordedVotes>
      <recordedVote>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <date>2017-07-28T16:46:13Z</date>
        <fullActionName>Passage of a Measure</fullActionName>
        <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
        <url>http://clerk.house.gov/evs/2017/roll437.xml</url>
        <rollNumber>437</rollNumber>
        <congress>115</congress>
      </recordedVote>
      <recordedVote>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <date>2017-07-24T22:55:30Z</date>
        <fullActionName>Final Passage Under Suspension of the Rules Results</fullActionName>
        <sessionNumber>1</sessionNumber>
        <url>http://clerk.house.gov/evs/2017/roll407.xml</url>
        <rollNumber>407</rollNumber>
        <congress>115</congress>
      </recordedVote>
    </recordedVotes>
    <subjects>
      <billSubjects>
        <legislativeSubjects>
          <item>
            <name>Asia</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Caribbean area</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Central Intelligence Agency (CIA)</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>China</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Coast guard</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Computer security and identity theft</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Computers and information technology</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional elections</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Congressional oversight</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Cuba</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Defense spending</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Defense</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Energy</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Homeland Security</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of Justice</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of State</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Department of the Treasury</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Director of National Intelligence</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA)</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Elections, voting, political campaign regulation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Employment discrimination and employee rights</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Europe</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Federal officials</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Foreign and international banking</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Foreign language and bilingual programs</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government buildings, facilities, and property</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government information and archives</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Higher education</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Iran</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Latin America</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Middle East</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>North Korea</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Public-private cooperation</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Research and development</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Russia</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Sanctions</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Terrorism</name>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>U.S. and foreign investments</name>
          </item>
        </legislativeSubjects>
        <policyArea>
          <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
        </policyArea>
      </billSubjects>
    </subjects>
    <introducedDate>2017-07-11</introducedDate>
    <summaries>
      <billSummaries>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018<br /><br /></strong>This bill authorizes FY2018 appropriations for intelligence community programs and activities, including personnel limits. It does not provide budget authority, which is provided in subsequent appropriations legislation.</p> <p>The bill eliminates or transfers several intelligence entities from Defense Intelligence Agency to other intelligence networks.</p> <p>The bill requires a public report from the Office of the Director of National Intelligence about foreign cyberthreats to elections for federal offices.</p> <p>Contracts awarded in the intelligence community must not limit a contractor's interaction with congressional intelligence committees. </p> <p>The bill also sets forth reporting requirements regarding various intelligence matters, including security clearance processes, investigations of&nbsp;leaked classified information,&nbsp;cybersecurity issues, and Russian influence campaigns directed at foreign elections and&nbsp;Russian financing of terrorism.</p> <p>This bill expresses the sense of Congress that per the National&nbsp;Security Act of 1947&nbsp;the intelligence community is required to notify the congressional intelligence&nbsp;committees within seven days of an individual in the executive branch disclosing classified intelligence to North Korea, Iran, China, Russia or Cuba using methods other than established intelligence channels. </p>]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
          <actionDate>2017-07-11</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2017-07-11T04:00:00Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2017-08-03T15:26:19Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <versionCode>00</versionCode>
          <name>Introduced in House</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p><b>Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018</b> </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto">TITLE I-- INTELLIGENCE ACTIVITIES </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto">(Sec. 101) This bill authorizes FY2018 appropriations for the conduct of intelligence and intelligence-related activities in the: </p> <ul> <li>Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI); </li> <li>Central Intelligence Agency (CIA);</li> <li>Department of Defense (DOD);Defense Intelligence Agency (DIA);</li> <li>National Security Agency (NSA);</li> <li>Departments of the Army, Navy, and Air Force;</li> <li>Coast Guard;</li> <li>Departments of State, the Treasury, Energy (DOE), Justice (DOJ), and Homeland Security (DHS);</li> <li>Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI);</li> <li>Drug Enforcement Administration;</li> <li>National Reconnaissance Office (NRO); and</li> <li>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA). </li> </ul> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 102) The amounts authorized and the authorized personnel ceilings are those in the classified Schedule of Authorizations, which shall be made available to the congressional appropriations committees and the President.<br /><br />(Sec. 103) The ODNI, if it provides prior notice to Congress, may authorize employment of civilian personnel over the number authorized for FY2018 if necessary for the performance of important intelligence functions.<br /><br />The ODNI must establish guidelines to govern the treatment under such authorized personnel levels of employment or assignment in: (1) a student or trainee program; (2) a reserve corps or as a reemployed annuitant; or (3) details, joint duty, or long-term, full-time training. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 104) The bill authorizes FY2018 appropriations for the ODNI's Intelligence Community Management Account. Additional funds identified in the classified schedule for advanced research and development shall remain available until September 30, 2019. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">TITLE II--CENTRAL INTELLIGENCE AGENCY RETIREMENT AND DISABILITY SYSTEM </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 201) This title authorizes FY2018 appropriations for the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability Fund. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 202) The bill&nbsp;amends&nbsp;several annuity provisions in&nbsp;the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">TITLE III--GENERAL INTELLIGENCE COMMUNITY MATTERS </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 301) Appropriations authorized by this bill shall not be deemed to constitute authority to conduct any intelligence activity not otherwise authorized by the Constitution or U.S. laws. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 302) Appropriations authorized by this bill for salary, pay, retirement, and other benefits for federal employees may be increased as necessary for increases in such compensation or benefits authorized by law. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 303) The bill amends the National Security Act of 1947 to give Congress oversight of contractors in the intelligence community. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 304) The term "audit" is changed to "review" with regards to assessments of the effectiveness of enhanced personnel security programs, which relate to&nbsp;implementing security clearances of employees in the intelligence community.&nbsp; </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">TITLE IV--MATTERS RELATING TO ELEMENTS OF THE INTELLIGENCE COMMUNITY </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">Subtitle A--Office of the Director of National Intelligence </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 401) The Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 is&nbsp;expanded to allow armed CIA personnel in the United States to protect current and former personnel of the ODNI and their immediate families. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 402) The Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 is amended by: (1) substituting the ODNI for the President in relation to information sharing about terrorism among the private sector and&nbsp;federal, state, local, and tribal entities; and (2) giving the ODNI authority to designate the program manager responsible for information sharing across the federal government.<br /><br />Subtitle B--Other Elements </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 411) The National Security Agency Act of 1959 is amended by:&nbsp;(1) requiring that the NSA Director be a civilian&nbsp;and not serving on active duty in the Armed Forces, and (2) creating the position of NSA General Counsel, who shall be appointed by the President. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 412) The DIA shall transfer all functions and responsibilities of: (1) the Information Review Task Force and the Watchlisting Branch to the Joint Chiefs of Staff, and (2) the National Intelligence University to the ODNI. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">The DIA shall eliminate the Identity Intelligence Project Office and the Counter Threat Finance&nbsp;analysis function. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">The DIA, ODNI, and DOD shall report about the National Center for Credibility Assessment relating to the functions, current organizational effectiveness as part of the DIA, current oversight effectiveness, and resources needed for future effectiveness. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">The DIA, ODNI, and Joint Chiefs of Staff shall report about the Underground Facilities Analysis Center relating to its functions, ability to meet the needs&nbsp;of the intelligence community, current effectiveness, current oversight, and resources needed for future effectiveness. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 413) Technical corrections&nbsp;to the Atomic Energy Defense Act and National Security Act of 1947 make references to the DOE's Office of Intelligence and Counterintelligence uniform. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">TITLE V--MATTERS RELATING TO FOREIGN COUNTRIES </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 501) The ODNI must report an analysis of the most significant Russian influence campaigns in foreign elections or referendums during the past three years. The report shall include: (1) the goal and methods of each campaign, (2) a summary of any defenses&nbsp;or responses employed and their effectiveness, and (3)&nbsp;a summary of&nbsp;relevant activities by the intelligence community undertaken to assist foreign governments in defending or responding to Russian influence campaigns and their effectiveness. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 502) The ODNI, in coordination with DHS and FBI, shall provide publicly online a report about foreign counterintelligence and cybersecurity threats to elections for federal offices. The report shall include a description of the threats, and the&nbsp;best practices and any available resources for election campaigns to counter such threats. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">If the FBI and DHS determine a specific election campaign is under heightened threat, then that campaign may be given additional information. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 503)&nbsp;The ODNI must submit an assessment&nbsp;about the financing of threat activity by Russia. Threat activity includes the financing of cyber operations, global intelligence campaigns, proliferation, terrorism, and transnational crime and drug organizations. Finance activity includes the methods and entities used to evade sanctions or to spend, store, move, raise, or conceal money or items of value on behalf of threat actors. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">TITLE VI--REPORTS AND OTHER MATTERS </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 601) The Foreign Service Act of 1980 is amended to: (1) restrict to six years&nbsp;the length of a&nbsp;posting&nbsp;for a&nbsp;Foreign Service member, and&nbsp;(2) require Foreign Service members who receive certain foreign language training to serve three successive tours in positions where the specified language is needed. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 602) The National Security Act of 1947 is amended to require each head of an intelligence element and inspectors general with oversight of an intelligence element to provide semiannual reports about unauthorized public disclosures of classified information to journalists. The reports from each head and inspector general shall include the numbers of investigations opened, closed, and referred to the&nbsp;DOJ for criminal investigation. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 603) The National Security Act of 1947 is amended to require the ODNI to submit an annual report about the security clearances processed for federal employees and contractors by each element of the intelligence community in the previous year. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 604) The CIA&nbsp;must provide a report about amending the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 to expand the current 500-foot boundary that CIA&nbsp;special police&nbsp;may operate out from CIA installation. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 605) The ODNI shall provide a report about its role in preparing materials for analysis for the federal government's evaluation of national security risks in regards to potential foreign investments in the United States. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 606) The ODNI must report about establishing a voluntary cyber exchange program that would allow the intelligence community and private technology companies to detail qualified employees to each other.&nbsp;The report must include a feasibility analysis, the challenges to such a program, and an evaluation of the benefits for the intelligence community. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 607) The Office of the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community shall review the roles and responsibilities of intelligence community entities during the past three years in the determinations of&nbsp;whether an information technology vulnerability was shared with&nbsp;a&nbsp;nonfederal entity or the public.&nbsp; </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 608) The Office of the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community,&nbsp;in consultation with the&nbsp;inspectors general from the CIA, NSA, NGA, DIA, and NRO, shall review the procedures and policies of intelligence community whistle-blower matters&nbsp;in relation to the timely and effective reporting of such matters. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 609) Congress states that the National Security Act of 1947 requires the intelligence community to keep congressional intelligence committees fully and currently informed about intelligence activities and to furnish any information or material concerning intelligence activities to such committees. </p>]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
          <actionDate>2017-07-24</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2017-07-24T16:15:59Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2017-11-21T18:59:20Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <versionCode>17</versionCode>
          <name>Reported to House with amendment(s)</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on July 28, 2017. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018</b> </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto">TITLE I-- INTELLIGENCE ACTIVITIES </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto">(Sec. 101) This bill authorizes FY2018 appropriations for the conduct of intelligence and intelligence-related activities in the: </p> <ul> <li>Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI); </li> <li>Central Intelligence Agency (CIA);</li> <li>Department of Defense (DOD);Defense Intelligence Agency (DIA);</li> <li>National Security Agency (NSA);</li> <li>Departments of the Army, Navy, and Air Force;</li> <li>Coast Guard;</li> <li>Departments of State, the Treasury, Energy (DOE), Justice (DOJ), and Homeland Security (DHS);</li> <li>Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI);</li> <li>Drug Enforcement Administration;</li> <li>National Reconnaissance Office (NRO); and</li> <li>National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA). </li> </ul> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 102) The amounts authorized and the authorized personnel ceilings are those in the classified Schedule of Authorizations, which shall be made available to the congressional appropriations committees and the President.<br /><br />(Sec. 103) The ODNI, if it provides prior notice to Congress, may authorize employment of civilian personnel over the number authorized for FY2018 if necessary for the performance of important intelligence functions.<br /><br />The ODNI must establish guidelines to govern the treatment under such authorized personnel levels of employment or assignment in: (1) a student or trainee program; (2) a reserve corps or as a reemployed annuitant; or (3) details, joint duty, or long-term, full-time training. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 104) The bill authorizes FY2018 appropriations for the ODNI's Intelligence Community Management Account. Additional funds identified in the classified schedule for advanced research and development shall remain available until September 30, 2019. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">TITLE II--CENTRAL INTELLIGENCE AGENCY RETIREMENT AND DISABILITY SYSTEM </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 201) This title authorizes FY2018 appropriations for the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability Fund. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 202) The bill&nbsp;amends&nbsp;several annuity provisions in&nbsp;the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">TITLE III--GENERAL INTELLIGENCE COMMUNITY MATTERS </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 301) Appropriations authorized by this bill shall not be deemed to constitute authority to conduct any intelligence activity not otherwise authorized by the Constitution or U.S. laws. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 302) Appropriations authorized by this bill for salary, pay, retirement, and other benefits for federal employees may be increased as necessary for increases in such compensation or benefits authorized by law. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 303) The bill amends the National Security Act of 1947 to give Congress oversight of contractors in the intelligence community. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 304) The term "audit" is changed to "review" with regards to assessments of the effectiveness of enhanced personnel security programs, which relate to&nbsp;implementing security clearances of employees in the intelligence community.&nbsp; </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">TITLE IV--MATTERS RELATING TO ELEMENTS OF THE INTELLIGENCE COMMUNITY </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">Subtitle A--Office of the Director of National Intelligence </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 401) The Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 is&nbsp;expanded to allow armed CIA personnel in the United States to protect current and former personnel of the ODNI and their immediate families. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 402) The Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 is amended by: (1) substituting the ODNI for the President in relation to information sharing about terrorism among the private sector and&nbsp;federal, state, local, and tribal entities; and (2) giving the ODNI authority to designate the program manager responsible for information sharing across the federal government.<br /><br />Subtitle B--Other Elements </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 411) The National Security Agency Act of 1959 is amended by:&nbsp;(1) requiring that the NSA Director be a civilian&nbsp;and not serving on active duty in the Armed Forces, and (2) creating the position of NSA General Counsel, who shall be appointed by the President. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 412) The DIA shall transfer all functions and responsibilities of: (1) the Information Review Task Force and the Watchlisting Branch to the Joint Chiefs of Staff, and (2) the National Intelligence University to the ODNI. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">The DIA shall eliminate the Identity Intelligence Project Office and the Counter Threat Finance&nbsp;analysis function. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">The DIA, ODNI, and DOD shall report about the National Center for Credibility Assessment relating to the functions, current organizational effectiveness as part of the DIA, current oversight effectiveness, and resources needed for future effectiveness. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">The DIA, ODNI, and Joint Chiefs of Staff shall report about the Underground Facilities Analysis Center relating to its functions, ability to meet the needs&nbsp;of the intelligence community, current effectiveness, current oversight, and resources needed for future effectiveness. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 413) Technical corrections&nbsp;to the Atomic Energy Defense Act and National Security Act of 1947 make references to the DOE's Office of Intelligence and Counterintelligence uniform. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">TITLE V--MATTERS RELATING TO FOREIGN COUNTRIES </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 501) The ODNI must report an analysis of the most significant Russian influence campaigns in foreign elections or referendums during the past three years. The report shall include: (1) the goal and methods of each campaign, (2) a summary of any defenses&nbsp;or responses employed and their effectiveness, and (3)&nbsp;a summary of&nbsp;relevant activities by the intelligence community undertaken to assist foreign governments in defending or responding to Russian influence campaigns and their effectiveness. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 502) The ODNI, in coordination with DHS and FBI, shall provide publicly online a report about foreign counterintelligence and cybersecurity threats to elections for federal offices. The report shall include a description of the threats, and the&nbsp;best practices and any available resources for election campaigns to counter such threats. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">If the FBI and DHS determine a specific election campaign is under heightened threat, then that campaign may be given additional information. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 503)&nbsp;The ODNI must submit an assessment&nbsp;about the financing of threat activity by Russia. Threat activity includes the financing of cyber operations, global intelligence campaigns, proliferation, terrorism, and transnational crime and drug organizations. Finance activity includes the methods and entities used to evade sanctions or to spend, store, move, raise, or conceal money or items of value on behalf of threat actors. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">TITLE VI--REPORTS AND OTHER MATTERS </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 601) The Foreign Service Act of 1980 is amended to: (1) restrict to six years&nbsp;the length of a&nbsp;posting&nbsp;for a&nbsp;Foreign Service member, and&nbsp;(2) require Foreign Service members who receive certain foreign language training to serve three successive tours in positions where the specified language is needed. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 602) The National Security Act of 1947 is amended to require each head of an intelligence element and inspectors general with oversight of an intelligence element to provide semiannual reports about unauthorized public disclosures of classified information to journalists. The reports from each head and inspector general shall include the numbers of investigations opened, closed, and referred to the&nbsp;DOJ for criminal investigation. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 603) The National Security Act of 1947 is amended to require the ODNI to submit an annual report about the security clearances processed for federal employees and contractors by each element of the intelligence community in the previous year. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 604) The CIA&nbsp;must provide a report about amending the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 to expand the current 500-foot boundary that CIA&nbsp;special police&nbsp;may operate out from CIA installation. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 605) The ODNI shall provide a report about its role in preparing materials for analysis for the federal government's evaluation of national security risks in regards to potential foreign investments in the United States. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 606) The ODNI must report about establishing a voluntary cyber exchange program that would allow the intelligence community and private technology companies to detail qualified employees to each other.&nbsp;The report must include a feasibility analysis, the challenges to such a program, and an evaluation of the benefits for the intelligence community. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 607) The Office of the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community shall review the roles and responsibilities of intelligence community entities during the past three years in the determinations of&nbsp;whether an information technology vulnerability was shared with&nbsp;a&nbsp;nonfederal entity or the public.&nbsp; </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 608) The Office of the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community,&nbsp;in consultation with the&nbsp;inspectors general from the CIA, NSA, NGA, DIA, and NRO, shall review the procedures and policies of intelligence community whistle-blower matters&nbsp;in relation to the timely and effective reporting of such matters. </p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 10pt; LINE-HEIGHT: normal; mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; tab-stops: list .5in">(Sec. 609) Congress states that the National Security Act of 1947 requires the intelligence community to keep congressional intelligence committees fully and currently informed about intelligence activities and to furnish any information or material concerning intelligence activities to such committees. </p>]]></text>
          <actionDesc>Passed House amended</actionDesc>
          <actionDate>2017-07-28</actionDate>
          <updateDate>2017-07-28T13:49:18Z</updateDate>
          <lastSummaryUpdateDate>2017-11-21T18:11:17Z</lastSummaryUpdateDate>
          <versionCode>36</versionCode>
          <name>Passed House amended</name>
        </item>
      </billSummaries>
    </summaries>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <state>CA</state>
        <lastName>Nunes</lastName>
        <byRequestType />
        <middleName />
        <fullName>Rep. Nunes, Devin [R-CA-22]</fullName>
        <district>22</district>
        <party>R</party>
        <firstName>Devin</firstName>
        <identifiers>
          <bioguideId>N000181</bioguideId>
          <lisID>1710</lisID>
          <gpoId>7826</gpoId>
        </identifiers>
        <bioguideId>N000181</bioguideId>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. NUNES:H.R. 3180.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:The intelligence and intelligence-related activities of theUnited States Government, including those under Title 50, arecarried out to support the national security interests of theUnited States, to enable the armed forces of the UnitedStates, and to support the President in executing the foreignpolicy of the United States.Article I, section 8 of the Constitution of the UnitedStates provides, in pertinent part, that ``Congress shallhave power . . . to . . . provide for the common Defense andgeneral Welfare of the United States''; ``. . . to raise andsupport armies . . .''; to ``make Rules concerning Captureson Land and Water''; and ``To make all laws which shall benecessary and proper for carrying into Execution theforegoing Powers and all other Powers vested in thisConstitution in the Government of the United States, or inany Department or Officer thereof.''[Page H5433]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <calendarNumbers>
      <item>
        <number />
        <calendar>U00183</calendar>
      </item>
    </calendarNumbers>
    <updateDate>2018-03-30T14:13:08Z</updateDate>
    <version>1.0.0</version>
    <notes />
    <committees>
      <billCommittees>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Legislative interest</name>
              <date>2018-02-23T15:26:00Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <systemCode>hshm00</systemCode>
          <name>Homeland Security Committee</name>
          <subcommittees />
          <type>Standing</type>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
        </item>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2017-07-31T21:02:24Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <systemCode>slin00</systemCode>
          <name>Intelligence Committee</name>
          <subcommittees />
          <type>Select</type>
          <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        </item>
        <item>
          <activities>
            <item>
              <name>Reported by</name>
              <date>2017-07-24T21:27:57Z</date>
            </item>
            <item>
              <name>Referred to</name>
              <date>2017-07-11T16:01:45Z</date>
            </item>
          </activities>
          <systemCode>hlig00</systemCode>
          <name>Intelligence (Permanent Select) Committee</name>
          <subcommittees />
          <type>Select</type>
          <chamber>House</chamber>
        </item>
      </billCommittees>
    </committees>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2017-07-19T15:25:20Z</pubDate>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/52938</url>
        <title>H.R. 3180, Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018</title>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <title>Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018</title>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed House</titleType>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <title>Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018</title>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to House</titleType>
        <parentTitleType>Short Titles House of Representatives</parentTitleType>
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <title>Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <title>To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2018 for intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the United States Government, the Community Management Account, and the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System, and for other purposes.</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <title>Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <title>Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018</title>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <titleType>(Extracted from GPO) Short Titles as Passed House</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
        <title>Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018</title>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <titleType>(Extracted from GPO) Short Titles as Reported to House</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
      <item>
        <chamberName />
        <title>Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018</title>
        <chamberCode />
        <titleType>(Extracted from GPO) Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <parentTitleType />
      </item>
    </titles>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2017-07-31</actionDate>
      <links />
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Select Committee on Intelligence.</text>
    </latestAction>
    <billType>HR</billType>
    <createDate>2017-07-12T03:11:37Z</createDate>
    <amendments>
      <amendment>
        <type>HAMDT</type>
        <latestAction />
        <purpose>Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 481 the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence is considered as adopted.</purpose>
        <number>271</number>
        <description />
        <congress>115</congress>
        <cosponsors>
          <totalCount>0</totalCount>
          <currentCount>0</currentCount>
        </cosponsors>
        <createDate>2017-07-29T07:16:22Z</createDate>
        <amendments>
          <count>0</count>
        </amendments>
        <chamber>House of Representatives</chamber>
        <notes />
        <updateDate>2018-03-30T14:13:08Z</updateDate>
        <amendedBill>
          <type>HR</type>
          <originChamber>House</originChamber>
          <title>Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018</title>
          <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
          <congress>115</congress>
          <number>3180</number>
        </amendedBill>
        <submittedDate>2017-07-28T04:00:00Z</submittedDate>
        <purpose>Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 481 the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence is considered as adopted.</purpose>
        <proposedDate />
        <description />
        <number>271</number>
        <sponsors>
          <item>
            <name>Rules Committee</name>
          </item>
        </sponsors>
        <titles />
        <actions>
          <actionTypeCounts>
            <houseAmendmentOffered>1</houseAmendmentOffered>
          </actionTypeCounts>
          <actions>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2017-07-28</actionDate>
              <committee />
              <links />
              <text />
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2017-07-28</actionDate>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <links />
              <committee />
              <actionCode>71000</actionCode>
              <text>House amendment offered</text>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
          </actions>
          <actionByCounts>
            <houseOfRepresentatives>1</houseOfRepresentatives>
          </actionByCounts>
          <count>2</count>
        </actions>
        <version>1.0.0</version>
        <amendedAmendment />
        <congress>115</congress>
        <type>HAMDT</type>
        <links />
      </amendment>
    </amendments>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <firstName>ADAM</firstName>
        <identifiers>
          <gpoId>7834</gpoId>
          <lisID>1635</lisID>
          <bioguideId>S001150</bioguideId>
        </identifiers>
        <sponsorshipWithdrawnDate />
        <district>28</district>
        <middleName>B.</middleName>
        <state>CA</state>
        <lastName>SCHIFF</lastName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2017-07-11</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
        <bioguideId>S001150</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Schiff, Adam B. [D-CA-28]</fullName>
        <party>D</party>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <laws />
    <title>Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018</title>
    <billNumber>3180</billNumber>
    <congress>115</congress>
    <actions>
      <actionTypeCounts>
        <introducedInTheHouse>1</introducedInTheHouse>
        <passageOfAMeasure>1</passageOfAMeasure>
        <unionCalendarAssignment>1</unionCalendarAssignment>
        <ruleForConsiderationOfBillReportedToHouse>1</ruleForConsiderationOfBillReportedToHouse>
        <motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>1</motionMadeToSuspendTheRules>
        <motionForPreviousQuestion>1</motionForPreviousQuestion>
        <generalDebate>3</generalDebate>
        <considerationByHouse>3</considerationByHouse>
        <placeholderTextForHL>1</placeholderTextForHL>
        <failedOfPassageNotAgreedToInHouse>1</failedOfPassageNotAgreedToInHouse>
        <placeholderTextForH>1</placeholderTextForH>
        <passedAgreedToInHouse>1</passedAgreedToInHouse>
        <reportedToHouse>1</reportedToHouse>
        <introducedInHouse>1</introducedInHouse>
        <finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>1</finalPassageUnderSuspensionOfTheRulesResults>
        <motionToReconsiderResults>1</motionToReconsiderResults>
        <billReferrals>1</billReferrals>
        <referredToCommittee>1</referredToCommittee>
        <committeeReportOfABill>1</committeeReportOfABill>
      </actionTypeCounts>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-31</actionDate>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>slin00</systemCode>
          <name>Intelligence Committee</name>
        </committee>
        <links />
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>0</code>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Select Committee on Intelligence.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-28</actionDate>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <links />
        <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
        <actionCode>H38310</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>12:46:15</actionTime>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-28</actionDate>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H6547-6552</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-163/house-section/page/H6547-6552</url>
          </link>
          <link>
            <name>Roll no. 437</name>
            <url>http://clerk.house.gov/evs/2017/roll437.xml</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 380 - 35 (Roll no. 437). (text: CR H6547-6552)</text>
        <actionCode>H37100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>12:46:13</actionTime>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-28</actionDate>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>Roll no. 437</name>
            <url>http://clerk.house.gov/evs/2017/roll437.xml</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 380 - 35 (Roll no. 437).</text>
        <actionCode>8000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>12:46:13</actionTime>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-28</actionDate>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <links />
        <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
        <actionCode>H35000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>12:21:15</actionTime>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-28</actionDate>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H.R. 3180</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-bill/3180</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 3180.</text>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>11:53:55</actionTime>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-28</actionDate>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H.R. 3180</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-bill/3180</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3180 with 1 hour of general debate. The resolution provides for a closed rule. The resolution provides for an amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence now printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted, and the bill as amended, shall be considered as read.</text>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>11:52:35</actionTime>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-28</actionDate>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H. Res. 481</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-resolution/481</url>
          </link>
          <link>
            <name>H6547-6557</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-163/house-section/page/H6547-6557</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 481. (consideration: CR H6547-6557)</text>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>11:52:30</actionTime>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-28</actionDate>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H. Res. 481</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-resolution/481</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Rule H. Res. 481 passed House.</text>
        <actionCode>H1L220</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>10:28:31</actionTime>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-27</actionDate>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H. Res. 481</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-resolution/481</url>
          </link>
          <link>
            <name>H.R. 3180</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-bill/3180</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 481 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3180 with 1 hour of general debate. The resolution provides for a closed rule. The resolution provides for an amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence now printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted, and the bill as amended, shall be considered as read.</text>
        <actionCode>H1L210</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>18:41:30</actionTime>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-24</actionDate>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>Roll no. 407</name>
            <url>http://clerk.house.gov/evs/2017/roll407.xml</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 241 - 163 (Roll no. 407).</text>
        <actionCode>H37300</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>18:55:30</actionTime>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-24</actionDate>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>Roll no. 407</name>
            <url>http://clerk.house.gov/evs/2017/roll407.xml</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Failed of passage/not agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 241 - 163 (Roll no. 407).</text>
        <actionCode>9000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>18:55:30</actionTime>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-24</actionDate>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H6196</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-163/house-section/page/H6196</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Considered as unfinished business. (consideration: CR H6196)</text>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>18:32:32</actionTime>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-24</actionDate>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <links />
        <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
        <actionCode>H37220</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>17:43:28</actionTime>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-24</actionDate>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H.R. 3180</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/house-bill/3180</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3180.</text>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>17:28:37</actionTime>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-24</actionDate>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H6187-6193</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-163/house-section/page/H6187-6193</url>
          </link>
          <link>
            <name>H6187-6195</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-record/volume-163/house-section/page/H6187-6195</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR H6187-6195; text of measure as reported: CR H6187-6193)</text>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>17:28:36</actionTime>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-24</actionDate>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <links />
        <text>Mr. Nunes moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
        <actionCode>H30300</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
        <actionTime>17:28:21</actionTime>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-24</actionDate>
        <type>Calendars</type>
        <links />
        <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 183.</text>
        <actionCode>H12410</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-24</actionDate>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H. Rept. 115-251</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/115th-congress/house-report/251</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Intelligence. H. Rept. 115-251.</text>
        <actionCode>H12200</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hlig00</systemCode>
          <name>Intelligence (Permanent Select) Committee</name>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-24</actionDate>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H. Rept. 115-251</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/congressional-report/115th-congress/house-report/251</url>
          </link>
        </links>
        <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Intelligence. H. Rept. 115-251.</text>
        <actionCode>5000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hlig00</systemCode>
          <name>Intelligence (Permanent Select) Committee</name>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-11</actionDate>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select).</text>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee>
          <systemCode>hlig00</systemCode>
          <name>Intelligence (Permanent Select) Committee</name>
        </committee>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-11</actionDate>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2017-07-11</actionDate>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <links />
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committee />
      </item>
      <actionByCounts>
        <houseOfRepresentatives>22</houseOfRepresentatives>
        <senate>1</senate>
      </actionByCounts>
    </actions>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>

