<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3498" measure-id="id115hr3498" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-27" update-date="2018-02-09">
<title>Extraordinary Measures Transparency Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3498v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-09">
<action-date>2017-07-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Extraordinary Measures Transparency Act </b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of the Treasury to report to Congress regarding extraordinary measures used to avoid exceeding the statutory debt limit. </p> <p>Extraordinary measures include suspensions and delays of debt sales and auctions, suspending or redeeming investments in certain government funds, and issuing debt to enter into an exchange transaction for debt that is subject to the limit. </p> <p>If Treasury determines that the public debt will reach the limit in 30 days, Treasury must submit a report to Congress that includes: </p> <ul> <li> a description of the extraordinary measures that Treasury intends to use if the debt limit is not raised, </li> <li> an estimate of the cost of the measures, </li> <li> a projection of how long the measures will fund the federal government, and </li> <li> a projection of the administrative cost of taking the measures. </li> </ul> <p>Treasury must also submit specified daily reports to Congress when the measures are being used. After using the measures, Treasury must report to Congress regarding the measures that were used and the administrative cost of the measures. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
