<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3524" measure-id="id115hr3524" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-27" update-date="2018-01-03">
<title>Settlement Trust Improvement Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3524v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-03">
<action-date>2017-07-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Settlement Trust Improvement Act of 2017 </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the tax treatment of Alaska Native Settlement Trusts, to: (1) allow an Alaska Native Corporation to assign certain payments referenced in the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to a trust without including the payments in the gross income of the corporation, (2) allow the corporation to elect annually to deduct contributions made to a trust, (3) allow a trust to elect to defer the recognition of gains related to contributions of property other than cash until the sale or exchange of the property, and (4) establish information reporting requirements for deductible contributions to a trust. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
