<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1562" measure-id="id115hr1562" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-16" update-date="2018-02-22">
<title>SAFE Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1562v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-22">
<action-date>2017-03-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Secure America's Future Elections Act or the SAFE Act</b></p>  <p>This bill directs the National Protection and Programs Directorate of the Department of Homeland Security to designate the infrastructure used to administer elections as critical infrastructure.</p> <p>The bill amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 with respect to:</p> <ul> <li>funding for states to upgrade the security of the information technology and cybersecurity elements of voting systems, voter registration lists, and voter registration processes;</li> <li> voting systems and cybersecurity standards;</li> <li>paper ballot and manual counting requirements;</li> <li>accessibility to voting systems and ballot verification for individuals with disabilities;</li> <li>durability and readability requirements for ballots; and</li> <li>mandatory manual audits of results of elections.</li> </ul> <p>The National Science Foundation shall make grants to study, test, and develop accessible paper ballot voting mechanisms and best practices to enhance the accessibility of paper ballot voting for voters with disabilities, voters whose primary language is not English, and voters with difficulties in literacy.</p> <p>The National Institute for Standards and Technology shall establish guidance for states that wish to establish alternative audit mechanisms.</p> <p>The Election Assistance Commission is made permanent.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
