<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4139" measure-id="id115hr4139" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-26" update-date="2017-10-31">
<title>End Outsourcing Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4139v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-31">
<action-date>2017-10-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>End Outsourcing Act </b></p> <p>This bill modifies provisions of tax, labor, and federal contracting laws related to the outsourcing of jobs. </p> <p>The bill amends the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act to require employers to include an outsourcing statement in the notice that must be provided to employees, state dislocated worker units, and local governments prior to plant closings and mass layoffs. The statement must specify whether part or all of the positions held by affected employees will be moved outside of the United States, regardless of whether the positions are moved within the business enterprise involved or to another business enterprise. </p> <p>The Department of Labor must publish on its website a list of employers that have included an outsourcing statement in the notice or have incurred liability for failing to provide the required notice.</p> <p>The bill also amends the Internal Revenue Code to: </p> <ul> <li> deny certain tax deductions and accounting methods for outsourcing employers; </li> <li> require the recapture of certain tax credits and grants that were provided to outsourcing employers and were related to the design, construction, operation, or maintenance of an outsourced facility; and </li> <li> grant business taxpayers a tax credit for up to 20% of insourcing expenses incurred for eliminating a business located outside the United States and relocating it within the United States if there is an increase in the taxpayer's employment of full-time employees in the United States. </li> </ul> <p>Federal contracting officers must: (1) require contractors submitting bids or proposals to disclose specified details regarding the outsourcing of jobs, and (2) take the disclosure into account in awarding contracts. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
