<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1567" measure-id="id115hr1567" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-16" update-date="2017-10-16">
<title>United States-Mexico Economic Partnership Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1567v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-16">
<action-date>2017-03-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>United States-Mexico Economic Partnership Act</strong></p> <p>This bill declares that it shall be U.S. policy to increase U.S.-Mexico academic exchanges at the secondary, post-secondary, and post-graduate levels. The United States and Mexico should seek to contribute to doubling the number of students studying in each other's country within five years.</p> <p>Priority should be given to strengthening ties between communities and academic institutions in those portions of the United States and Mexico that are within 100 kilometers of the international boundary between those countries. </p> <p>The President shall develop a plan to implement policies and programs that support cooperation, training, and mentoring of entrepreneurs. Such policies and programs should seek to provide not less than 100 grants of not more than $25,000 each for program participants to better leverage participation by the private sector.</p> <p>The President shall develop a plan to implement policies and programs that promote U.S.-Mexico energy infrastructure coordination and cooperation through support of vocational-level education, internships, and exchanges between the two countries. Such policies and programs should seek to provide education, internships, and exchanges for at least 1,000 program participants. </p> <p>The President shall develop a plan to implement a pilot program to develop a pipeline between undergraduate colleges and universities in the United States and medical school programs in Mexico. Such program should be utilized to prepare medical students to become doctors who can pass U.S. medical licensing board exams. The pilot program should seek to increase the number of bilingual medical professionals in a cost-effective manner who can practice in U.S. underserved communities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
