<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3366" measure-id="id115hr3366" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-24" update-date="2018-01-05">
<title>Senior Housing IRA Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3366v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-05">
<action-date>2017-07-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Senior Housing Improvement and Retirement Accounts Act of 2017 or the Senior Housing IRA Act of 2017 </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the tax treatment of gains from the sale or exchange of a principal residence, to: (1) allow a qualified individual to contribute the gains from the sale or exchange to a Roth Individual Retirement Arrangement (IRA) as a qualified rollover contribution which is exempt from contribution limits, and (2) increase the $250,000 limit on the exclusion from gross income for gains from the sale of a principal residence by the amount of the rollover contribution. </p> <p>The bill applies to individuals who: (1) have attained the age of 55 before the date of the sale or exchange, (2) have owned and used the property as a principal residence for at least 20 years, and (3) have not previously elected to treat a contribution to a Roth IRA as a qualified rollover contribution under the authority provided by this bill. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
