<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1682" measure-id="id115hr1682" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-22" update-date="2017-10-16">
<title>Energy Star Program Integrity Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1682v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-16">
<action-date>2017-03-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Energy Star Program Integrity Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to revise the Energy Star program. Specifically, the bill prohibits breach of warranty claims or private claims or rights of action against manufacturers of products that are disqualified from the program if: (1) the product has been certified by a certification body recognized by the program, (2) the Environmental Protection Agency has approved corrective measures, and (3) the responsible party has fully complied with all such measures.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
