<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1785" measure-id="id115hr1785" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-29" update-date="2017-12-04">
<title>Comprehensive Strategy to Destroy ISIS Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1785v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-04">
<action-date>2017-03-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Comprehensive Strategy to Destroy ISIS Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Defense (DOD) and the Department of State to jointly develop and submit to Congress: (1) a strategy to destroy the Islamic State of Iraq and al-Sham (ISIS) and its affiliates, (2) a biennial update of such strategy, and (3) a strategy to bring the civil war in Syria to a sustainable end.</p> <p>The Office of the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to Congress an assessment of:</p> <ul> <li>the willingness and capabilities of coalition members and allies to defeat ISIS with their own military assets;</li> <li>the presence of ISIS or its affiliates in countries other than Syria, Iraq, Libya, Egypt, and Afghanistan;</li> <li>preventing radicalization of citizens of regional countries by ISIS;</li> <li>the number of foreign fighters joining ISIS and tactics to prevent further recruitment; and</li> <li>significant U.S. intelligence gaps concerning ISIS and the ability to carry out a regional strategy to defeat it.</li> </ul> <ul> </ul> <ul> </ul> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
