<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="808" measure-id="id115hr808" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-01" update-date="2017-06-01">
<title>Iran Nonnuclear Sanctions Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr808v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-01">
<action-date>2017-02-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Nonnuclear Iran Sanctions Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill prescribes requirements for sanctions with respect to: (1) Iran's Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) and related entities; (2) Mahan Air; (3) Iran's support of terrorism; (4) Iran's human rights abuses; (5) certain Iranian individuals; (6) persons who conduct transactions with or on behalf of certain Iranian individuals; (7) financial institutions that engage in certain transactions on behalf of persons involved in human rights abuses or that export sensitive technology to Iran; (8) Iran's ballistic missile program and persons and Iranian sectors that support such program; and (9) certain entities owned by the Aerospace Industries Organization, the Shahid Hemmat Industrial Group, or the Shahid Bakeri Industrial Group.</p> <p>The Department of the Treasury shall publish in the Federal Register an IRGC watch list. </p> <p>The President shall designate within the State Department a Special Coordinator on Human Rights and Democracy in Iran. </p> <p>The Iran-Iraq Arms Non-Proliferation Act of 1992 is amended to cover ballistic missiles and related technology.</p> <p>The bill requires Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty and the Voice of America to increase programing services to Iran. </p> <p> The bill prescribes prohibitions and limitations with respect to Iran's access to the U.S. financial system. </p> <p> The bill modifies the requirements that the President must follow to rescind the designation of a country as a state sponsor of terrorism.</p> <p> The bill expresses the sense of Congress with respect to: (1) human rights in Iran, (2) state and local divestment from IRGC-related business activities, and (3) Iran's ballistic missile program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
