<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2165" measure-id="id115hr2165" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-26" update-date="2018-01-18">
<title>TSA Misconduct Accountability Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2165v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-18">
<action-date>2017-04-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>TSA Misconduct Accountability Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to:</p> <ul> <li>revise its employee code of conduct policy to include a process for disciplining an employee who has received a certain number of disciplinary or adverse actions for violations of such policy within a certain timeframe, as well as guidance on how employees should report misconduct;</li> <li> identify methods for addressing employee misconduct, including revising the agency-wide baseline table of offenses and penalties used for both non-disciplinary and disciplinary actions regarding misconduct; </li> <li>submit to the Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) such policy and table;</li> <li>identify a senior TSA official responsible for overseeing such policy and table; </li> <li>instruct TSA managers on how to appropriately administer discipline for employee misconduct; and </li> <li>identify and address causes of misconduct.</li> </ul> <p>TSA shall implement human capital initiatives to address employee misconduct by: (1) modifying the performance plans of Federal Security Directors to include the extent to which such directors ensure that disciplinary actions administered at the airport for which they are responsible are consistent with TSA policy, (2) notifying applicants of disqualifying offenses to ensure that appropriately qualified candidates apply and are hired, and (3) delivering training and on-the-job resources for supervisors to address misconduct issues in accordance with TSA policy.</p> <p>DHS's Chief Human Capital Officer shall monitor, through FY2020, the implementation of the TSA employee code of conduct.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
