<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3198" measure-id="id115hr3198" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-12" update-date="2017-11-02">
<title>FLIGHT R&amp;D Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3198v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-02">
<action-date>2017-07-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>FAA Leadership in Groundbreaking High-Tech Research and Development Act or the FLIGHT R&amp;D Act</b></p> <p>This bill reauthorizes Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) research and development (R&amp;D) programs for FY2018-FY2023. </p> <p>No funds are authorized to be appropriated for a fiscal year for: (1) Environmental Sustainability Research and Development programs unless the full amount authorized for that fiscal year is appropriated for Safety Research and Development programs, Economic Competitiveness Research and Development programs, and Mission Support programs; or (2) the FAA's Office of the Administrator unless the Secretary of Transportation has submitted the National Aviation Research Plan to Congress no later than the submission of the President's budget request for that fiscal year.</p> <p>The FAA shall appoint an Associate Administrator for Research and Development.</p> <p>The FAA shall develop a plan in the event of the transition of FAA R&amp;D activities to a non-federal entity.</p> <p>The bill amends the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 to revise requirements with respect to the FAA's five-year roadmap for the introduction of civil unmanned aircraft systems (drones) into the national airspace system. The roadmap shall include, at a minimum, a description of how the FAA plans to use R&amp;D to integrate drones into the system. No funds are authorized to be appropriated for the Office of the Administrator for a fiscal year unless the Secretary has submitted the unmanned aircraft systems roadmap to Congress on an annual basis. The FAA shall coordinate with the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to research the collision of drones with manned aircraft. The bill prohibits the FAA, with a specified exception, from promulgating regulations regarding the operation of drones for R&amp;D purposes. </p> <p>The FAA shall establish R&amp;D programs:</p> <ul> <li>to improve the cybersecurity of civil aircraft and the system,</li> <li>on civilian air traffic surveillance over oceans and other remote locations, </li> <li>in support of single-piloted cargo aircraft with remote piloting and computer piloting, and</li> <li>regarding the use of the electromagnetic spectrum in the civil aviation domain.</li> </ul> <p>The FAA shall submit to Congress a research plan for certification and implementation of new technologies (including Next Generation) into the system.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
