<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3288" measure-id="id115hr3288" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-18" update-date="2017-11-17">
<title>Northern Border Regional Commission Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3288v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-17">
<action-date>2017-07-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Northern Border Regional Commission Reauthorization Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill provides that the share of the administrative expenses of the Southeast Crescent Regional Commission, the Southwest Border Regional Commission, or the Northern Border Regional Commission to be paid by each state of such commission shall be determined by a majority (currently, unanimous) vote of the state members of such commission. </p> <p>A commission must include in the 40% of any economic and infrastructure development grant amounts provided to states or local governments, Indian tribes, or public or nonprofit organizations for the development of the transportation infrastructure, basic public infrastructure, or telecommunications infrastructure amounts for the development of renewable and alternative energy sources in its region. </p> <p>Such economic and infrastructure development grants may be used to attract businesses to a region from outside of the United States.</p> <p>The bill reauthorizes each commission through FY2023. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
