<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3639" measure-id="id115hr3639" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-08-01" update-date="2017-11-08">
<title>Science Laureates of the United States Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3639v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-08">
<action-date>2017-08-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Science Laureates of the United States Act of 2017 </b></p> <p>This bill directs the National Science Foundation (NSF) to establish the position of Science Laureate of the United States to honor the service of scientists. </p> <p> The NSF shall appoint a Science Laureate from three individuals to be nominated each year by the National Academy of Sciences on the basis of merit, particularly the ability to foster public awareness and interest in science and to provide ongoing significant scientific contributions. </p> <p>Each Science Laureate shall engage the public to increase public awareness about science and is encouraged to continue his or her scientific work. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
