<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2749" measure-id="id115hr2749" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-26" update-date="2017-10-25">
<title>Protecting Business Opportunities for Veterans Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2749v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-25">
<action-date>2017-07-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protecting Business Opportunities for Veterans Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill applies certain small business subcontracting limitations to a small business concern owned and controlled by a veteran or a veteran with a service-connected disability.</p> <p>The Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) may award a contract only after obtaining a certification from the offeror that it will comply with such subcontracting limitations if awarded the contract. Such certification shall: (1) specify the applicable performance requirements, and (2) explicitly acknowledge that the certification is subject to criminal penalties for making false statements in any matter within the jurisdiction of the U.S. government.</p> <p>The VA Director of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization and the VA Chief Acquisition Officer shall jointly refer any violation or suspected violation to the VA Inspector General.</p> <p>If the VA determines that a contract recipient did not act in good faith, such recipient shall be subject to any or all of the following: (1) referral to the VA Debarment and Suspension Committee, (2) a criminal fine, and (3) criminal prosecution.</p> <p>The Inspector General shall submit an annual report to Congress for each of 2018-2022 that includes: (1) the number of referred and suspected violations; and (2) the disposition of such violations, including the number of small business concerns suspended or debarred from federal contracting or referred for Department of Justice prosecution. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2749v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-24">
<action-date>2017-05-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protecting Business Opportunities for Veterans Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill applies certain small business subcontracting limitations to a small business concern owned and controlled by a veteran or a veteran with a service-connected disability.</p> <p>The Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) may award a contract only after obtaining a certification from the offeror that it will comply with such subcontracting limitations if awarded the contract. Such certification shall: (1) specify the applicable performance requirements, and (2) explicitly acknowledge that the certification is subject to criminal penalties for making false statements in any matter within the jurisdiction of the U.S. government.</p> <p>The VA Director of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization and the VA Chief Acquisition Officer shall jointly refer any violation or suspected violation to the VA Inspector General.</p> <p>If the VA determines that a contract recipient did not act in good faith, such recipient shall be subject to any or all of the following: (1) referral to the VA Debarment and Suspension Committee, (2) a criminal fine, and (3) criminal prosecution.</p> <p>The Inspector General shall submit an annual report to the appropriate congressional committees that includes: (1) the number of referred violations and suspected violations; and (2) the disposition of such violations, including the number of small business concerns suspended or debarred from federal contracting or referred for Department of Justice prosecution. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
