<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2951" measure-id="id115hr2951" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-20" update-date="2017-11-22">
<title>To allow Members of Congress to carry a concealed handgun anywhere in the United States, with exceptions.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2951v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-22">
<action-date>2017-06-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill allows a Member of Congress to carry a concealed handgun for any lawful purpose anywhere in the United States, except on the grounds of the White House, wherever the U.S. Secret Service is prohibiting the possession of a firearm, or on an air carrier (unless the Member has successfully completed the federal flight deck officer training program), provided that such Member:</p> <ul> <li>is carrying the photographic identification issued by a chamber of Congress that identifies him or her as a Member;</li> <li>has been issued a license or permit to carry a concealed handgun by a state or the United States Capitol Police; and </li> <li>is not otherwise prohibited under federal law from transporting, shipping, or receiving a firearm.</li> </ul> <p>The Chief of the U.S. Capitol Police is authorized to issue such a license or permit.</p> <p>The Senators' Official Personnel and Office Expense Account and the House of Representatives' Members' Representational Allowance may be used to pay for a a Member's participation in the federal flight deck officer training program, which the Department of Homeland Security must make available.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
