<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1232" measure-id="id115hr1232" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-27" update-date="2017-09-13">
<title>Save America's Science Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1232v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-13">
<action-date>2017-02-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Save America's Science Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires each federal agency to: (1) maintain each data asset of the agency, including any asset collected for the agency under a contract, in accordance with its records management program; (2) establish safeguards against the removal or loss of such assets; and (3) make any requirements and penalties related to such removal or loss known to agency officials and employees.</p> <p>Each agency shall: (1) notify the Archivist of the United States and Congress of any actual or threatened unlawful removal, defacing, alteration, or other destruction of data assets in the agency's custody; and (2) initiate action through the Attorney General for the recovery of such assets.</p> <p>In any case in which an agency does not initiate recovery within a reasonable period after being notified of any such unlawful action, or is believed to be participating in any such unlawful action, the Archivist shall request the Attorney General to initiate recovery and notify Congress when such a request has been made.</p> <p>Each data asset that has been made available to the public by an agency shall remain available to the public.</p> <ul> </ul> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
