<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2399" measure-id="id115hr2399" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-08" update-date="2017-06-12">
<title>LEAP Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2399v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-12">
<action-date>2017-05-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Leveraging and Energizing America's Apprenticeship Programs Act or the LEAP Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow employers a business-related tax credit of $1,500 for hiring&nbsp;an apprenticeship employee who has not attained age 25&nbsp;at the close of the taxable year or $1,000 for an apprenticeship employee who has attained age 25. The bill allows such credit for no more than&nbsp;two taxable years with respect to any apprenticeship employee. An "apprenticeship employee" is an employee who is employed in an officially-recognized apprenticeable occupation pursuant to an apprentice agreement registered with the Office of Apprenticeship of the Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor or a state apprenticeship agency. </p> <p> The Office of Management and Budget must coordinate with federal departments and independent agencies to: (1) determine which government publications could be available on government websites and no longer printed, (2) devise a strategy to reduce overall government printing costs over the 10-year period beginning with FY2016, (3) establish government-wide guidelines on employee printing, and (4) issue guidelines for publicly disclosing information about the publication of government documents.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
