<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3284" measure-id="id115hr3284" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-18" update-date="2017-11-21">
<title>Joint Counterterrorism Awareness Workshop Series Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3284v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-21">
<action-date>2017-09-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Joint Counterterrorism Awareness Workshop Series Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act to direct the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to establish a Joint Counterterrorism Awareness Workshop Series to address emerging terrorist threats and to enhance the ability of state and local jurisdictions to prevent, protect against, respond to, and recover from terrorist attacks.</p> <p>The workshop series shall include:</p> <ul> <li>reviewing terrorism preparedness, response, and interdiction plans, policies, and procedures of the participating jurisdictions and identifying gaps in such plans, operational capabilities, response resources, and authorities; </li> <li>identifying federal, state, and local resources available to address such gaps; </li> <li>providing assistance to build or sustain the capabilities to close such gaps; </li> <li>examining the roles and responsibilities of participating agencies and respective communities in the event of a terrorist attack; </li> <li>improving situational awareness and information sharing among all participating agencies in the event of such an attack; and </li> <li>identifying and sharing best practices and lessons learned from each workshop series. </li></ul> <p>FEMA shall select jurisdictions to host a workshop series from cities that have received or are receiving funding under the Urban Area Security Initiative and have requested to be considered. Individuals from state and local jurisdictions and emergency response providers in cities selected shall be eligible to participate in the series.</p> <p>FEMA must report, each year for the next six years, to all participating agencies and to Congress regarding key findings or themes, lessons learned, and best practices identified.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3284v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-13">
<action-date>2017-09-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>Joint Counterterrorism Awareness Workshop Series Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to establish a Joint Counterterrorism Awareness Workshop Series to address emerging terrorist threats and to enhance the ability of state and local jurisdictions to prevent, protect against, respond to, and recover from terrorist attacks.</p> <p>The workshop series shall include:</p> <ul> <li>reviewing terrorism preparedness, response, and interdiction plans, policies, and procedures of the participating jurisdictions and identifying gaps in such plans, operational capabilities, response resources, and authorities; </li> <li>identifying federal, state, and local resources available to address such gaps; </li> <li>providing assistance to build or sustain the capabilities to close such gaps; </li> <li>examining the roles and responsibilities of participating agencies and respective communities in the event of a terrorist attack; </li> <li>improving situational awareness and information sharing among all participating agencies in the event of such an attack; and </li> <li>identifying and sharing best practices and lessons learned from each workshop series. </li></ul> <p>FEMA shall select jurisdictions to host a workshop series from cities that: (1) have received or are receiving funding under the Urban Area Security Initiative, and (2) have requested to be considered. Individuals from state and local jurisdictions and emergency response providers in cities selected shall be eligible to participate in the series.</p> <p>FEMA must report to all participating agencies and to Congress regarding key findings or themes, lessons learned, and best practices identified.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3284v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-13">
<action-date>2017-07-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Joint Counterterrorism Awareness Workshop Series Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to establish a Joint Counterterrorism Awareness Workshop Series to address emerging terrorist threats and to enhance the ability of state and local jurisdictions to prevent, protect against, respond to, and recover from terrorist attacks.</p> <p>The workshop series shall include:</p> <ul> <li>reviewing terrorism preparedness, response, and interdiction plans, policies, and procedures of the participating jurisdictions and identifying gaps in such plans, operational capabilities, response resources, and authorities; </li> <li>identifying federal, state, and local resources available to address such gaps; </li> <li>providing assistance to build or sustain the capabilities to close such gaps; </li> <li>examining the roles and responsibilities of participating agencies and respective communities in the event of a terrorist attack; </li> <li>improving situational awareness and information sharing among all participating agencies in the event of such an attack; and </li> <li>identifying and sharing best practices and lessons learned from each workshop series. </li></ul> <p>FEMA shall select jurisdictions to host a workshop series from cities that: (1) have received or are receiving funding under the Urban Area Security Initiative, and (2) have requested to be considered. Individuals from state and local jurisdictions and emergency response providers in cities selected shall be eligible to participate in the series.</p> <p>FEMA must report to all participating agencies and to Congress regarding key findings or themes, lessons learned, and best practices identified.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
