<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1222" measure-id="id115hr1222" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-27" update-date="2018-01-18">
<title>Congenital Heart Futures Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1222v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-18">
<action-date>2017-09-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Congenital Heart Futures Reauthorization Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to replace the authorization for a National Congenital Heart Disease Surveillance System with a requirement for the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), regarding congenital heart disease, to enhance and expand research and surveillance infrastructure. (Congenital heart disease is a condition caused by a heart defect that is present at birth.)</p> <p>HHS must award grants to nonprofit entities to conduct a study of congenital heart disease, from birth to adulthood, that considers health care utilization, demographic factors, and outcomes. Data from the study must be made available to the public.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute must report on its ongoing research efforts regarding congenital heart disease, future plans for such research, and areas of greatest need for such research.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1222v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-03">
<action-date>2017-02-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Congenital Heart Futures Reauthorization Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to replace the authorization for a National Congenital Heart Disease Surveillance System with a requirement for the Department of Health and Human Services, regarding congenital heart disease, to enhance and expand research and surveillance infrastructure, and plan and implement a public outreach and education campaign. (Congenital heart disease is a condition caused by a heart defect that is present at birth.)</p> <p>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention must award grants to nonprofit entities to conduct: (1) a study of congenital heart disease, from birth to adulthood, that considers health care utilization, demographic factors, and outcomes; and (2) an awareness, outreach, and education campaign regarding congenital heart disease. Data from the study must be made available to the public.</p> <p>The National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute must report on its ongoing research efforts regarding congenital heart disease, future plans for such research, and areas of greatest need for such research.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
