<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1726" measure-id="id115hr1726" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-27" update-date="2018-03-22">
<title>Coast Guard Improvement and Reform Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1726v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-22">
<action-date>2017-05-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Coast Guard Improvement and Reform Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill reorganizes several provisions of title 14 (Coast Guard) of the United States Code, including U.S. Coast Guard acquisitions, and other provisions.</p> <p>The bill expands the duties of several federal advisory committees that provide advice to the Coast Guard, including the National Commercial Fishing Safety Advisory Committee, by requiring that each committee meet at least once per year.Additionally, each committee must terminate on September 30, 2027. Currently, some committees are permanent and some have earlier termination dates.</p> <p>The bill also repeals the provision that allows enlisted members of the Coast Guard who are discharged for bad conduct, undesirability, unsuitability, or inaptitude to be furnished civilian clothing at a cost not to exceed $30 per person.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1726v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-22">
<action-date>2017-03-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Coast Guard Improvement and Reform Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill reorganizes several provisions of title 14 (Coast Guard) of the United States Code, including U.S. Coast Guard acquisitions, and other provisions.</p> <p>The bill expands the duties of several federal advisory committees that provide advice to the Coast Guard, including the National Commercial Fishing Safety Advisory Committee, by requiring that each committee meet at least once per year.Additionally, each committee must terminate on September 30, 2027. Currently, some committees are permanent and some have earlier termination dates.</p> <p>The bill also repeals the provision that allows enlisted members of the Coast Guard who are discharged for bad conduct, undesirability, unsuitability, or inaptitude to be furnished civilian clothing at a cost not to exceed $30 per person.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
