<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3344" measure-id="id115hr3344" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-20" update-date="2017-11-13">
<title>STEM to STEAM Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3344v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-13">
<action-date>2017-07-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>STEM to STEAM Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the STEM Education Act of 2015 to include: (1) among the purposes for which the National Science Foundation shall award competitive, merit-reviewed grants the support of the integration of art and design in STEM (science, technology, engineering, and mathematics) educational programs; and (2) among activities supported by such grants the design and testing of programming that integrates art and design in STEM education in order to promote creativity and innovation. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
