<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5078" measure-id="id115hr5078" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2018-02-23" update-date="2018-03-20">
<title>TRID Improvement Act of 2018</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr5078v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-20">
<action-date>2018-02-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>TRID Improvement Act of</strong> <b>2018</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Real Estate Settlement Procedures of 1974 to modify disclosure requirements&nbsp;applicable to mortgage loan transactions. Specifically, the disclosed charges for any title insurance premium shall be equal to the amount charged for each individual title insurance policy, subject to any discounts as required by either state regulation or the title company rate filings. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to allow the reporting of certain positive consumer-credit information to consumer reporting agencies. Specifically, a person or the Department of Housing and Urban Development may report information related to a consumer's performance in making payments either under a lease agreement for a dwelling or pursuant to a contract for a utility or telecommunications service. However, information about a consumer's usage of any utility or telecommunications service may be reported only to the extent that the information relates to payment by the consumer for such service or other terms of the provision of that service. Furthermore, an energy-utility firm may not report a consumer's outstanding balance as late if the firm and the consumer have entered into a payment plan and the consumer is meeting the obligations of that plan. </p> <p>Specified provisions of the Consumer Credit Protection Act that establish civil liability with respect to furnishers of information to consumer reporting agencies shall not apply to any violation of the bill. </p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must report on the consumer impact of such reporting.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr5078v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-05">
<action-date>2018-02-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>TRID Improvement Act of</strong> <b>2018</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Real Estate Settlement Procedures of 1974 to modify disclosure requirements&nbsp;applicable to mortgage loan transactions. Specifically, the disclosed charges for any title insurance premium shall be equal to the amount charged for each individual title insurance policy, subject to any discounts as required by either state regulation or the title company rate filings. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
