<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2275" measure-id="id115hr2275" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-01" update-date="2017-08-23">
<title>Giving Workers a Fair Shot Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2275v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-23">
<action-date>2017-05-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Giving Workers a Fair Shot Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to require employers to provide their employees with specified information concerning their pay, leave time, and eligibility for the minimum wage and overtime pay. Employers who fail to provide required information are subject to fines. </p> <p>The bill revises the definition of "supervisor" under the National Labor Relations Act to prevent the over classification of employees as supervisors for the purpose of limiting the number of employees eligible to join a union. </p> <p>The bill increases civil penalties for intentional violations of requirements under the National Labor Relations Act, the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970, the Migrant and Seasonal Agricultural Worker Protection Act, and the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977, and imposes criminal penalties for violating certain requirements of those Acts, including violations of mandatory health or safety standards and for retaliation against employees who provide information about health or safety violations. </p> <p>The bill expedites the establishment of an initial collective bargaining agreement by allowing either an employer or a union to seek mediation under the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service if an agreement is not reached within 90 days after bargaining begins. </p> <p>The bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to: (1) require repeat votes by shareholders on executive compensation until a vote is binding, (2) prohibit the chief executive officer and the chairman of the board of directors at publicly traded companies from being the same person (except for small capitalization companies), and (3) impose restrictions the sale of stock by company directors or officers. </p> <p>The bill disallows the reimbursement of costs incurred by a contractor in attempting to persuade its employees not to exercise their rights to organize or bargain collectively (union busting). </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
