<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2795" measure-id="id115hr2795" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-07" update-date="2018-03-01">
<title>Yemen Security and Humanity Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2795v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-01">
<action-date>2017-06-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Yemen Security and Humanity Act</b> </p> <p>This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) addressing the famine conditions in Yemen is in U.S. national security interests, (2) U.S.-supported interventions to advance national security should consider the impact of military engagement on humanitarian operations, and (3) bureaucratic procedures with respect to humanitarian aid must be improved.</p> <p>The Global Food Security Act of 2016 is amended to include in the U.S. global comprehensive food security strategy, with respect to famine-risk areas, coordination among the U.S. Agency for International Development, the United Nations Office for the Coordination of Humanitarian Affairs, and the U.S. military.</p> <p>The Department of State and the Department of Defense shall jointly report to Congress regarding U.S. security and humanitarian interests in Yemen, including: (1) U.S. strategic objectives, including humanitarian support to famine-threatened civilian populations; (2) efforts to coordinate civilian and military efforts; and (3) the diplomatic strategy with respect to regional partners seeking to end Yemen's civil war.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
