<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4545" measure-id="id115hr4545" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-12-04" update-date="2018-03-28">
<title>Financial Institutions Examination Fairness and Reform Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4545v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-28">
<action-date>2018-03-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Financial Institutions Examination Fairness and Reform Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1978 to apply&nbsp;specified procedures&nbsp;related&nbsp;to reporting and review, as established by the bill, to&nbsp;a nondepository covered person that is subject to Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) supervision. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill sets deadlines for final examination reports and exit interviews of a financial institution by a federal financial regulatory agency. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The Office of Independent Examination Review is established to adjudicate appeals and investigate complaints from financial institutions concerning examination reports. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) Financial institutions have the right to an independent review of a material supervisory determination. The bill also establishes a limited review by the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council (FFIEC) if there is evidence that the final decision reached by the office would pose an imminent threat to the financial institution's safety and soundness. Certain retaliatory actions by regulatory agencies with respect to such review are prohibited.&nbsp;</p> <p>(Sec. 6) The bill also requires the establishment of an independent internal agency appellate process at the CFPB for the review of supervisory determinations made at institutions supervised by the CFPB. The proportion of FFIEC costs covered by regulatory agencies is raised. </p> <p>(Sec. 7) The bill amends the Federal Reserve Act to lower the maximum allowable amount of surplus funds of the Federal Reserve banks. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4545v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-16">
<action-date>2018-03-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Financial Institutions Examination Fairness and Reform Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1978 to: &nbsp;</p> <ul> <li>set deadlines for final examination reports and exit interviews of a financial institution by a federal financial regulatory agency, and </li> <li>establish the Office of Independent Examination Review to adjudicate appeals and investigate complaints from financial institutions concerning examination reports. </li></ul> <p>The bill also requires the establishment of an independent internal agency appellate process at the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) for the&nbsp;review of supervisory determinations made at institutions supervised by the CFPB. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4545v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-16">
<action-date>2017-12-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Financial Institutions Examination Fairness and Reform Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1978 to: &nbsp;</p> <ul> <li>set deadlines for final examination reports and exit interviews of a financial institution by a federal financial regulatory agency, and </li> <li>establish the Office of Independent Examination Review to adjudicate appeals and investigate complaints from financial institutions concerning examination reports. </li></ul> <p>The bill also requires the establishment of an independent internal agency appellate process at the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) for the&nbsp;review of supervisory determinations made at institutions supervised by the CFPB. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
