<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1916" measure-id="id115hr1916" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-05" update-date="2017-09-05">
<title>Patriot Inventory Protection Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1916v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-05">
<action-date>2017-04-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Patriot Inventory Protection Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Army to evaluate its ability to meet war fighter requirements and operational needs, if GEM-T interceptors are removed from its operational inventory, by either: (1) recertifying GEM-T interceptors; or (2) developing, testing, and fielding a new low-cost interceptor that can be placed on the Army's operational inventory prior to the retirement of GEM-T interceptors. GEM-T interceptors are surface-to-air Patriot Guided Enhanced Missiles.</p> <p>The bill prohibits funds made available for the Army for FY2018 or thereafter from being obligated or expended to demilitarize any GEM-T interceptor or to remove any such interceptor from its operational inventory until the Army submits such evaluation to the congressional defense committees. Such limitation shall not apply to activities that the Army determines are critical to the safety of GEM-T interceptors.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
