<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3144" measure-id="id115hr3144" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-29" update-date="2018-01-29">
<title>To provide for operations of the Federal Columbia River Power System pursuant to a certain operation plan for a specified period of time, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3144v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-29">
<action-date>2017-06-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill requires the Bureau of Reclamation, the Bonneville Power Administration, and the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to operate the Federal Columbia River Power System (FCRPS) in a manner consistent with the Endangered Species Act Section 7(a)(2) Supplemental Biological Opinion, dated January 17, 2014, (Supplemental Opinion) until the later of: (1) September 30, 2022; or (2) the date upon which a subsequent final biological opinion for the FCRPS operations is issued (after completion of the final environmental impact statement on a record of decision for a new operations plan for the FCRPS) and is in effect, with no pending further judicial review.</p> <p>Such entities may amend portions of the Supplemental Opinion and operate the FCRPS in accordance with such amendments, before such date if all of the entities determine that: (1) the amendments are necessary for public safety or transmission and grid reliability; or (2) the actions, operations, or other requirements that the amendments would remove are no longer warranted.</p> <p>No structural modification, action, study, or engineering plan that restricts electrical generation at any FCRPS hydroelectric dam or that limits navigation on the Snake River in Washington, Oregon, or Idaho shall proceed unless such proposal is specifically and expressly authorized by an Act of Congress.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
