<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3620" measure-id="id115hr3620" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-28" update-date="2017-09-05">
<title>Affordable Coverage for More Americans Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3620v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-05">
<action-date>2017-07-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b> Affordable Coverage for More Americans Act of 2017 </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the health care premium assistance refundable tax credit, to: (1) expand eligibility for the credit by defining an &quot;applicable taxpayer&quot; as a taxpayer whose household income for the year does not exceed 600% of the federal poverty line (currently 400%), (2) specify the applicable premium percentages for the credit for taxpayers with incomes that are from 400% to 600% of the federal poverty line, and (3) specify the dollar limitations for the recapture of excess advance payments of the credit from such taxpayers. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
