<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="872" measure-id="id115hr872" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-06" update-date="2017-07-26">
<title>DEVICE Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr872v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-26">
<action-date>2017-02-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Disclosure; and Encouragement of Verification, Innovation, Cleaning, and Efficiency Act of </b> <b>2017 or the DEVICE Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require medical device manufacturers to notify the Food and Drug Administration (FDA): (1) before making changes to the design or reprocessing instructions of a device, and (2) no more than five days after widely disseminating to health care providers in a foreign country communications regarding changes to the design or reprocessing instructions of a device or regarding a safety concern about a device. A device may not be sold if the manufacturer violates these notification requirements.</p> <p>Rapid assessment tests intended to ensure the proper reprocessing of reusable medical devices are defined as medical devices. The FDA must publish a list of the types of rapid assessment tests for which premarket notification must include validated instructions for use and validation data.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
