<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4243" measure-id="id115hr4243" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-11-03" update-date="2017-11-15">
<title>To establish a commission for the purpose of making recommendations regarding the modernization or realignment of facilities of the Veterans Health Administration, to improve construction and management leases of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to amend and appropriate funds for the Veterans Choice Program, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4243v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-15">
<action-date>2017-11-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><i>VA Asset and Infrastructure Review Act of 2017</i></p> <p>This bill establishes the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission, which shall make recommendations to the President regarding the closure, modernization, and/or realignment of Veterans Health Administration (VHA) facilities based upon its own and Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) recommendations. The President shall transmit to the commission and to Congress a report containing the President's approval or disapproval of such recommendations by February 15, 2023. Within three years after transmittal of such report, the commission shall begin to implement the recommendations approved by the President and not disapproved by Congress.</p> <p>The commission shall: (1) carry out appropriate environmental restoration and historic preservation in connection with facility closures or realignments, and (2) consult with state and local governments with respect to the treatment of roads or the disposal of surplus real property or infrastructure.</p> <p>The VA may transfer the title of a VHA facility to the facility's redevelopment authority for lease to the VA or another federal agency.</p> <p>The bill establishes in the Treasury the Department of Veterans Affairs Asset and Infrastructure Review Account.</p> <p>The bill revises the definitions of: (1) &quot;major medical facility project,&quot; and (2) &quot;major medical facility lease.&quot;</p> <p>The VA may enter into agreements with other federal agencies for the planning, designing, constructing, or leasing of shared medical facilities.</p> <p>The Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 is amended to exclude recruitment, relocation, or retention incentives from the limitation on awards and bonuses. </p> <p>The bill provides funds for: (1) the Veterans Choice Program, and (2) medical facility minor construction and nonrecurring maintenance. </p> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
