<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2410" measure-id="id115hr2410" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-11" update-date="2018-03-22">
<title>Sickle Cell Disease Research, Surveillance, Prevention, and Treatment Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2410v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-22">
<action-date>2018-02-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House reported version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Sickle Cell Disease Research, Surveillance, Prevention, and Treatment Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Department of Health and Human Services to make grants to states to: (1) collect data on the prevalence and distribution of sickle cell disease, (2) conduct sickle cell disease public health initiatives to improve access to care and health outcomes, and (3) identify and evaluate strategies for prevention and treatment of sickle cell disease complications.</p>(Sec. 4) The demonstration program to improve the prevention and treatment of sickle cell disease is revised, reauthorized through FY2022, and moved from the American Jobs Creation Act of 2004 to the Public Health Service Act.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2410v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-23">
<action-date>2017-10-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Sickle Cell Disease Research, Surveillance, Prevention, and Treatment Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Department of Health and Human Services to make grants to states to: (1) collect data on the prevalence and distribution of sickle cell disease, (2) conduct sickle cell disease public health initiatives to improve access to care and health outcomes, and (3) identify and evaluate strategies for prevention and treatment of sickle cell disease complications.</p>(Sec. 4) The demonstration program to improve the prevention and treatment of sickle cell disease is revised, reauthorized through FY2022, and moved from the American Jobs Creation Act of 2004 to the Public Health Service Act.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2410v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-22">
<action-date>2017-05-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Sickle Cell Disease Research, Surveillance, Prevention, and Treatment Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Department of Health and Human Services to make grants to states to: (1) collect data on the prevalence and distribution of sickle cell disease, (2) conduct sickle cell disease public health initiatives to improve access to care and health outcomes, and (3) identify and evaluate strategies for prevention and treatment of sickle cell disease complications.</p> The demonstration program to improve the prevention and treatment of sickle cell disease is revised, reauthorized through FY2022, and moved from the American Jobs Creation Act of 2004 to the Public Health Service Act.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
