<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1974" measure-id="id115hr1974" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2017-08-09">
<title>National Opportunity for Lead Exposure Accountability and Deterrence Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1974v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-09">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>National Opportunity for Lead Exposure Accountability and Deterrence Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to require the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to revise the national primary drinking water regulations for lead and copper. The rule must direct:</p> <ul> <li>public water systems (the systems) to meet certain reporting requirements;</li> <li> the EPA to develop a sampling protocol and develop instructions for compliance with the protocol;</li> <li> the EPA, or the state exercising primary enforcement responsibility, to require on-site investigations for identifying the source of lead in all residential or nonresidential facilities when their individual samples have concentrations of lead or copper contamination exceeding specified levels;</li> <li>the systems to meet certain notification and reporting requirements when lead or copper concentration levels are exceeded;</li> <li>the systems to develop and make publicly available an inventory of the material composition of the service lines at residential and nonresidential facilities;</li> <li>the systems to collect and make publicly available information about the ownership of those service lines; and </li> <li>the systems to replace an entire lead service line (instead of partially replacing them) when they are replaced.</li> </ul> <p>The EPA must also revise the rule to lower the allowable level of lead that may be contained in drinking water.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
