<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2498" measure-id="id115hr2498" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-17" update-date="2017-06-14">
<title>Freedom from Discrimination in Credit Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2498v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-14">
<action-date>2017-05-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Freedom from Discrimination in Credit Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Equal Credit Opportunity Act (ECOA) to expand the categories of prohibited discrimination when extending credit to include discrimination on account of sexual orientation or gender identity. (Currently, such discrimination in credit is prohibited only on the basis of race, color, religion, national origin, sex or marital status, or age.)</p> <p>The bill defines: (1) "gender identity" as the gender-related identity, appearance, or mannerisms or other gender-related characteristics of an individual with or without regard to the individual's designated sex at birth; and (2) "sexual orientation" as homosexuality, heterosexuality, or bisexuality.</p> <p>The bill specifies that for purposes of the ECOA's protections against sex discrimination, the term &quot;sex&quot; includes: (1) a sex stereotype; (2) pregnancy, childbirth, or a related medical condition; and (3) sexual orientation or gender identity.</p> <p>The bill also extends ECOA's protections against discrimination to include: (1) an association with another person who is a member of a class protected against discrimination; and (2) a perception or belief, even if inaccurate, that the individual is a member of such a protected class.</p> <p>Under a current provision of the ECOA, a request for the signature of both parties to a marriage for the purpose of creating a valid lien, passing clear title, waiving inchoate rights to property, or assigning earnings does not constitute discrimination. The bill prohibits this provision from being construed to permit a creditor to take sexual orientation or gender identity into account in connection with the evaluation of creditworthiness of an applicant.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
