<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3612" measure-id="id115hr3612" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-28" update-date="2018-03-23">
<title>Prioritizing Education in Conflict Zones Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3612v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-23">
<action-date>2017-07-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Prioritizing Education in Conflict Zones Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to authorize the Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), through the Director of Refugee Educational Assistance (to be designated by USAID), to provide long-term assistance to expand and improve primary and secondary education for displaced children from areas of conflict.</p> <p>Such assistance shall be used to: (1) build the capacity for private sector and civil society organizations to develop and strengthen primary and secondary curricula, coordinate with host country educational facilities, and strengthen technical capacities; (2) establish and expand U.S.-host country educational partnerships; and (3) assist efforts to educate women and girls. </p> <p> The director shall seek to use funding appropriated for the purposes of this bill to leverage private sector funding for such purposes and shall prioritize efforts to identify such sources of such private sector funding.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
