<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3455" measure-id="id115hr3455" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-27" update-date="2017-12-26">
<title>Fairness for Agricultural Machinery and Equipment Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3455v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-26">
<action-date>2017-07-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fairness for Agricultural Machinery and Equipment Act</b></p> <p> This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) make permanent the five-year recovery period for the depreciation of certain farming business machinery and equipment by eliminating the requirement that the property be placed in service before 2010; and (2) expand the machinery and equipment that qualifies as five-year property to include a grain bin, cotton ginning asset, or fence used in a farming business. The original use of the five-year property must commence with the taxpayer after the enactment of this bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
