<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2097" measure-id="id115hr2097" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-14" update-date="2018-02-14">
<title>ATF Wrongful Reclassification Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2097v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-14">
<action-date>2017-04-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong></strong><b>ATF Wrongful Reclassification Act</b> </p> <p>This bill amends the federal criminal code to modify the definition of &quot;armor piercing ammunition.&quot; Currently, armor piercing ammunition includes certain projectiles or projectile cores that may be used in a handgun. The bill limits that definition of armor piercing ammunition to certain projectiles or projectile cores that are designed and intended by the manufacturer solely for use in a handgun. <p>The bill also revises the standard for determining when armor piercing ammunition is exempt from federal prohibitions on import, manufacture, and distribution. Current law exempts armor piercing ammunition that is primarily intended to be used for sporting purposes, as determined by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives. This bill replaces the &quot;sporting purposes&quot; standard with a new standard that exempts armor piercing ammunition that is primarily intended by the manufacturer to be used for lawful purposes.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
