<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1345" measure-id="id115hr1345" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-02" update-date="2017-09-18">
<title>Protect Children from Theft Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1345v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-18">
<action-date>2017-03-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protect Children from Theft Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to require a consumer reporting agency, upon request by the legal guardian or custodian of a minor consumer, to either create a blocked credit report for the minor or convert the minor's existing report to blocked status. With respect to a minor's blocked report, a consumer reporting agency: (1) must block the input of any information, except with permission from the minor's legal guardian or custodian; and (2) may not provide any person with a consumer report of the minor.</p> <p>A consumer reporting agency shall: (1) upon request by a minor's legal guardian or custodian, or on the minor's 18th birthday,&nbsp;unblock the minor's blocked report; and (2) if a&nbsp;minor consumer was a victim of fraud or identity theft before the minor's&nbsp;18th birthday, include an alert statement in the minor's unblocked report. With respect to&nbsp;a minor consumer who was a victim of fraud or identity theft prior to the minor's 18th birthday, a consumer reporting agency may not charge a fee to create, convert, or unblock the minor's report. </p> <p>The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau must establish specified procedures&nbsp;related to&nbsp;the bill's implementation. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
