<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3651" measure-id="id115hr3651" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-08-11" update-date="2018-03-22">
<title>To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a feasibility study on renovating or replacing the Lyndon B. Johnson Tropical Medical Center with a new or updated facility.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3651v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-22">
<action-date>2017-08-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill directs the Government Accountability Office to evaluate and report on the feasibility and costs of renovating or replacing the Lyndon B. Johnson Tropical Medical Center, which is in American Samoa. The report must include specified information, including: (1) the cost to equip the facility to meet the care standards of the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Department of Defense, and the Department of Health and Human Services; (2) the feasibility of making the center a teaching hospital; and (3) the ability to include a tropical disease research center at the facility.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
