<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2761" measure-id="id115hr2761" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-26" update-date="2017-06-17">
<title>Healthcare Opportunities for Patriots in Exile (HOPE) Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2761v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-17">
<action-date>2017-05-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Healthcare Opportunities for Patriots in Exile (HOPE) Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to authorize the Department of Homeland Security to parole into the United States an alien veteran who: (1) is seeking temporary admission to receive health care from the Department of Veterans Affairs, and (2) resides permanently abroad after having been removed or voluntarily departed from the United States.</p> <p>Such parole shall not be available for an alien who is inadmissible due to a criminal conviction for: (1) a crime of violence for which the alien has served at least five years in prison, or (2) a crime that endangers U.S. national security for which the alien has served at least five years in prison.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
