<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3558" measure-id="id115hr3558" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-28" update-date="2018-03-23">
<title>Improve Access to Care for Our Female Veterans Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3558v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-23">
<action-date>2017-07-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Improve Access to Care for Our Female Veterans Act</b></p> <p>This bill instructs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to strengthen the environment and oversight of the care inspections process by:</p> <ul> <li>expanding the list of requirements that facility staff inspect for compliance with the women's health handbook of the Veterans Health Administration (VHA); </li> <li>ensuring that all patient care areas of VA medical facilities are inspected as required;</li> <li>clarifying the roles and responsibilities of VA medical facility staff responsible for identifying and addressing compliance; and </li> <li>establishing a process to verify that the noncompliance information reported by such facilities to the VHA central office is accurate and complete. </li> </ul> <p>To improve care for women veterans, the VA shall monitor women veterans' access to sex-specific care services (mammography, maternity care, and gynecology) under community care contracts. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
