<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2928" measure-id="id115hr2928" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-15" update-date="2018-01-19">
<title>To direct the Secretary of Transportation to issue regulations to require air carriers to disclose to consumers the actual wheels-off and wheels-on times for certain domestic passenger flight segments, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2928v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-19">
<action-date>2017-06-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill directs the Department of Transportation to modify federal consumer disclosure regulations to ensure that a reporting carrier: (1) discloses, upon the reasonable request of a consumer during the course of a reservation or ticketing discussion, the projected period between the actual wheels-off and wheels-on times for a reportable flight; and (2) displays on its public website information on such times for the most recent calendar month for a reportable flight. </p> <p>A &quot;reporting carrier&quot; is an air carrier that accounts for at least 1% of domestic scheduled-passenger revenues in the most recently reported 12-month period.</p> <p>A &quot;reportable flight&quot; is a nonstop flight to or from any airport within the 48 states that accounts for 1% of domestic scheduled-passenger enplanements in the previous calendar year.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
