<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1841" measure-id="id115hr1841" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-30" update-date="2018-01-02">
<title>Regulate Marijuana Like Alcohol Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1841v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-02">
<action-date>2017-03-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Regulate Marijuana Like Alcohol Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Justice to issue a final order that removes marijuana in any form from all schedules of controlled substances under the Controlled Substances Act (CSA).</p> <p>Marijuana is exempted from the CSA except as provided in this bill. The definition of &quot;felony drug offense&quot; does not include conduct related to marijuana. Marijuana is not included in the provisions setting forth penalties applicable to prohibited conduct under the CSA.</p> <p>It shall be unlawful to ship or transport marijuana from any place outside a jurisdiction of the United States into such a jurisdiction in which its possession, use, or sale is prohibited.</p> <p>The bill eliminates marijuana from regulation under various federal laws including the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act, the National Forest System Drug Control Act of 1986, the federal Wiretap Act, and the Office of National Drug Control Policy Reauthorization Act of 1998. Further, it subjects marijuana to the provisions that apply to: (1) intoxicating liquors under the Original Packages Act, the Webb-Kenyon Act, and the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000; and (2) distilled spirits under the Federal Alcohol Administration Act.</p> <p>The Food and Drug Administration shall have the same authorities with respect to marijuana as it has for alcohol. Functions of the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration relating to marijuana enforcement shall be transferred to the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives (ATF). The ATF is renamed the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Marijuana, Firearms and Explosives and the Alcohol and Tobacco Tax and Trade Bureau is renamed the Alcohol, Tobacco, and Marijuana Tax and Trade Bureau.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
