<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1384" measure-id="id115hr1384" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-07" update-date="2017-09-13">
<title>Reserve Component Benefits Parity Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1384v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-13">
<action-date>2017-03-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Reserve Component Benefits Parity Act</b></p> <p>This bill makes reserve component members who are deployed to support pre planned operations of a combatant command eligible for: (1) pre-mobilization health care, (2) transitional health care, (3) consideration of active duty service to reduce the age for retired pay, (4) the high-deployment allowance for lengthy or numerous deployments and frequent mobilizations, (5) Post-9/11 educational assistance, and (6) non-reduction in pay while serving in the uniformed services or National Guard. </p> <p>The bill makes reserve component members who are deployed in response to a major disaster or emergency eligible for Post-9/11 educational assistance.</p> <p>The bill makes all such reserve component members eligible for extension of the time limitation during deployment with respect to: (1) educational assistance, and (2) training and rehabilitation assistance for veterans with service-connected disabilities. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
