<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="357" measure-id="id115hr357" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-06" update-date="2017-07-11">
<title>Overseas Outsourcing Accountability Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr357v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-11">
<action-date>2017-01-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Overseas Outsourcing Accountability Act</b></p> <p>This bill requires the President to develop a comprehensive national strategy to prevent U.S. employers from overseas outsourcing and offshoring practices that impact the U.S. workforce.</p> <p> The strategy shall:</p> <ul> <li>delineate quantifiable short-term and long-term goals for preventing such practices;</li> <li>describe specific actions and means to achieve such goals; and</li> <li>identify necessary new authorities or changes in existing authorities.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
