<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="765" measure-id="id115hr765" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-31" update-date="2017-05-17">
<title>Increase Transportation Alternatives Investment Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr765v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-17">
<action-date>2017-01-31</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Increase Transportation Alternatives Investment Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to ensure that states give preference, under the Surface Transportation Block Grant Program, to eligible projects that are located in areas that are undergoing extensive repair or reconstruction of transportation infrastructure, including federal-aid highways, federally owned roads open for public travel, passenger rail facilities, and public transportation facilities and that will provide transportation alternatives related to the closure of transportation infrastructure in such areas.</p> <p>DOT shall: (1) carry out a competitive grant program to support community efforts to invest in transportation alternatives; and (2) give grant preference to projects located in such areas. Entities eligible for grants include state and local governments, metropolitan planning organizations, and rural planning organizations.</p> <p>Grants may be used to plan for, facilitate, and provide initial support for: </p> <ul> <li>transportation demand management programs;</li> <li>carpool or telecommuting projects; and </li> <li>planning, design, acquisition of rights-of-way, construction, improvement, and management of streets, pathways, and public transportation facilities to facilitate expanded bicycle and pedestrian mobility and access.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
