<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4345" measure-id="id115hr4345" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-11-09" update-date="2018-01-24">
<title>Veteran Treatment Court Coordination Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4345v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-24">
<action-date>2017-11-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Veteran Treatment Court Coordination Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill expresses the sense of Congress that veterans treatment courts are a successful program aimed at helping veterans charged with non-violent crimes receive the help and the benefits for which they are entitled.</p> <p>The Department of Justice shall establish a Veteran Treatment Court Program to provide grants and technical assistance to state circuit court systems that have adopted or filed a notice of intent to establish such a program. </p> <p>Such program shall include specified veterans treatment court grant programs.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
