<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="732" measure-id="id115hr732" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-30" update-date="2018-01-25">
<title>Stop Settlement Slush Funds Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr732v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-25">
<action-date>2017-10-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Stop Settlement Slush Funds Act of</b> <b>2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill prohibits government officials from entering into or enforcing a settlement agreement on behalf of the United States (resolving a civil action, a plea agreement, a deferred prosecution agreement, or a nonprosecution agreement) that provides for a payment or a loan to any person or entity other than the United States. The bill provides exceptions to allow payments or loans that: (1) remedy actual harm (including to the environment) caused by the party making the payment or loan and suffered by the payee, or (2) constitute a payment for services rendered in connection with the case or a payment that a court may order for restitution to victims in certain criminal cases or other persons in plea agreements.</p> <p>Amounts remaining after all claims have been satisfied must be repaid proportionally to each party who contributed to the original payment. </p> <p>Government officials or agents who violate this prohibition may be removed from office or required to forfeit to the government any money they hold for such purposes to which they may otherwise be entitled.</p> <p>Federal agencies must report annually for seven years to the Congressional Budget Office about the parties, funding sources, and distribution of funds for their settlement agreements permitted by the exceptions in this bill. </p> <p>Agency inspectors general must report annually to Congress about any of their agency's settlement agreements that violate this bill. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr732v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-04">
<action-date>2017-03-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Stop Settlement Slush Funds Act of</b> <b>2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill prohibits government officials from entering into or enforcing a settlement agreement on behalf of the United States (resolving a civil action, a plea agreement, a deferred prosecution agreement, or a nonprosecution agreement) that provides for a payment or a loan to any person or entity other than the United States. The bill provides exceptions to allow payments or loans that: (1) remedy actual harm (including to the environment) caused by the party making the payment or loan, or (2) constitute a payment for services rendered in connection with the case or a payment that a court may order for restitution to victims in certain criminal cases or other persons in plea agreements.</p> <p>Government officials or agents who violate this prohibition may be removed from office or required to forfeit to the government any money they hold for such purposes to which they may otherwise be entitled.</p> <p>Federal agencies must report annually for seven years to the Congressional Budget Office about the parties, funding sources, and distribution of funds for their settlement agreements permitted by the exceptions in this bill. </p> <p>Agency inspectors general must report annually to Congress about any of their agency's settlement agreements that violate this bill. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr732v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-02-15">
<action-date>2017-01-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Stop Settlement Slush Funds Act of</b> <b>2017</b></p> <p>This bill prohibits government officials from entering into or enforcing a settlement agreement on behalf of the United States (resolving a civil action, a plea agreement, a deferred prosecution agreement, or a nonprosecution agreement) that provides for a payment to any person or entity other than the United States. The bill provides exceptions to allow payments that: (1) remedy actual harm (including to the environment) caused by the party making the payment, or (2) constitute a payment for services rendered in connection with the case or a payment that a court may order for restitution to victims in certain criminal cases or other persons in plea agreements.</p> <p>Government officials or agents who violate this prohibition may be removed from office or required to forfeit to the government any money they hold for such purposes to which they may otherwise be entitled.</p> <p>Federal agencies must report annually for seven years to the Congressional Budget Office about the parties, funding sources, and distribution of funds for their settlement agreements permitted by the exceptions in this bill. </p> <p>Agency inspectors general must report annually to Congress about any of their agency's settlement agreements that violate this bill. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
