<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1740" measure-id="id115hr1740" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-27" update-date="2017-12-01">
<title>Faith-Based Community Center Protection Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1740v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-01">
<action-date>2017-03-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Faith-Based Community Center Protection Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to: (1) permit the use of Urban Area Security Initiative or State Homeland Security Grant Program grant funds to protect a faith-based community center or vulnerable populations, including children or the elderly; and (2) define &quot;faith-based community center&quot; as a facility operated by a nonprofit faith-based community organization for the provision of recreational, social, or education services to the general public.</p> <p>The bill amends the federal criminal code to increase the term of imprisonment from 5 to 10 years for engaging in conduct with intent to convey false or misleading information that indicates that an activity has taken, is taking, or will take place that would constitute a violation of specified prohibitions, including certain prohibtions under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954.</p> <ul> <ul> </ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
