<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="95" measure-id="id115hr95" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-03" update-date="2017-09-19">
<title>Veterans' Access to Child Care Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr95v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-19">
<action-date>2017-07-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Veterans' Access to Child Care Act</strong></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide child care assistance to an eligible veteran for any period that the veteran: (1) receives covered health care services at a VA facility, and (2) is required to travel to and return from such facility for the receipt of such services.</p> <p>The bill defines: (1) &quot;covered health care services&quot; to mean regular mental health care services, intensive mental health care services, or such other intensive health care services to which the VA determines that provision of child care assistance would improve the veteran's access; and (2) &quot;eligible veteran&quot; as a veteran who is the primary caretaker of a child and who is receiving covered health care services from the VA or who is in need of, and who would receive, such services from the VA but for lack of child care.</p> <p>Included among child care assistance to be provided under this bill are:</p> <ul> <li>a stipend for the payment of the full cost of child care offered by a licensed child care center, which shall be modeled after the VA's Child Care Subsidy Program;</li> <li>direct provision of child care at an on-site VA facility;</li> <li>a payment made directly to a private child care agency; and </li> <li>collaboration with a facility or program of another federal department or agency. </li> </ul> <p> (Sec. 3) The bill extends through September 30, 2026, the $90 monthly limit on a VA pension paid to veterans residing in nursing homes when their nursing costs are paid through title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill extends through December 31, 2024, VA authority to collect funding fees for certain VA, VA-guaranteed, or VA-insured housing loans.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr95v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-01-12">
<action-date>2017-01-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Veterans' Access to Child Care Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide child care assistance to an eligible veteran for any period that the veteran: (1) receives covered health care services at a VA facility, and (2) is required to travel to and return from such facility for the receipt of such services.</p> <p>The bill defines: (1) &quot;covered health care services&quot; to mean regular mental health care services, intensive mental health care services, or such other intensive health care services to which the VA determines that provision of child care assistance would improve the veteran's access; and (2) &quot;eligible veteran&quot; as a veteran who is the primary caretaker of a child and who is receiving covered health care services from the VA or who is in need of, and who would receive, such services from the VA but for lack of child care.</p> <p>Included among child care assistance to be provided under this bill are:</p> <ul> <li>a stipend for the payment of the full cost of child care offered by a licensed child care center, which shall be modeled after the VA's Child Care Subsidy Program;</li> <li>direct provision of child care at an on-site VA facility;</li> <li>a payment made directly to a private child care agency; and </li> <li>collaboration with a facility or program of another federal department or agency. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
