<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2147" measure-id="id115hr2147" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-26" update-date="2017-08-02">
<title>Veterans Treatment Court Improvement Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2147v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-02">
<action-date>2017-04-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Veterans Treatment Court Improvement Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to hire at least 50 Veterans Justice Outreach Specialists, place each one at an eligible VA medical center, and ensure that each one serves as part of a justice team in a veterans treatment court or other veteran-focused court.</p> <p>An eligible VA medical center is one that:</p> <ul> <li> complies with all VA guidelines and regulations for placement of a specialist; </li> <li> works with a veteran with active, ongoing, or recent contact with some component of a local criminal justice system;</li> <li> maintains an affiliation with one or more veterans treatment courts or other veteran-focused courts; and </li> <li> either routinely provides specialists, or establishes a VA-approved plan to provide specialists, to serve as part of a justice team in such a court.</li> </ul> <p>The VA shall prioritize the placement of specialists at eligible VA medical centers that have an affiliation with such a court that: (1) was established after the date of this bill's enactment, or (2) was established before such date and is not fully staffed with specialists.</p> <ul> </ul> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
