<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3165" measure-id="id115hr3165" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-06" update-date="2018-02-27">
<title>REVAMP Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3165v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-27">
<action-date>2017-07-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Renovate and Enhance Veterans Meeting Halls and Posts Act of 2017 or the REVAMP Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out a pilot program to award grants to veterans service organizations in rural areas to: (1) repair or rehabilitate a facility in a rural area, and (2) acquire or upgrade computers and technology for such a facility. </p> <p>An organization may not receive a grant in any fiscal year in an amount exceeding the lesser of: (1) the aggregate cost of such proposed activities and uses, or (2) $75,000. </p> <p>An organization that receives such a grant for a fiscal year shall be ineligible for any such grant for the next five fiscal years.</p> <p>Grants awarded under this bill may not be used for the construction or acquisition of new facilities. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
