<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3275" measure-id="id115hr3275" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-17" update-date="2018-01-12">
<title>Water and Energy Sustainability through Technology Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3275v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-12">
<action-date>2017-07-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Water and Energy Sustainability through Technology Act</b></p> <p> This bill addresses the link between energy and water systems (energy-water nexus), including: (1) the water needed to produce energy; (2) the energy needed to transport, reclaim, treat, store, and reuse water and wastewater; (3) the energy available in organic wastewaters and wet waste streams (e.g., methane); and (4) the waste heat available in industrial process and cooling water discharges, steam system condensate and cooling water, and thermoelectric cooling water discharge.</p> <p> The bill provides support for increasing:</p> <ul> <li>the availability of energy-water nexus data about surface water, groundwater, or recycled water;</li> <li>the use of energy-water nexus technology;</li> <li>the energy efficiency of certain water systems;</li> <li>the use of water efficiency methods and products;</li> <li>water quality;</li> <li>the recharge of groundwater;</li> <li>the ability of water systems to address climate-related impacts on water quality or quantity; and </li> <li>the infrastructure of water and wastewater systems.</li> </ul> <p> In addition, the bill establishes a United States-Israel Water Cooperation Working Group to seek to strengthen dialogue between the United States and Israel in order to: (1) improve the use of water resources through water-saving technologies and practices; (2) counter water shortages; (3) modernize pipeline and other applicable infrastructure; and (4) pursue best practices in drip irrigation, water recycling, and desalination.</p> <p>The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to eliminate certain tax incentives related to the extraction of oil, gas, or certain minerals.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
