<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3506" measure-id="id115hr3506" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-27" update-date="2018-01-30">
<title>Article I Restoration Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3506v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-30">
<action-date>2017-07-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Article I Restoration Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill requires any covered rule issued by an executive agency after&nbsp;this bill's enactment to sunset three years after its effective date unless specifically reauthorized by Congress. </p> <p>A "covered rule" does not include a rule:</p> <ul> <li>issued in accordance with specified formal rulemaking provisions of the Administrative Procedure Act; </li> <li>issued with respect to a military or foreign affairs function of the United States; </li> <li>that the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs certifies is necessary for the enforcement of federal criminal laws; </li> <li>that is limited to agency organization, management, or personnel matters; or </li> <li>that is necessary due to an imminent threat to human health or safety or any other emergency. </li></ul> <p>An agency may not reissue, enforce, revise, or take other regulatory action related to a covered rule that has sunset.</p> <p>The Office of Management and Budget or the relevant agency may oversee the sunset of covered rules.</p> <p>If the agency that issues covered rules wants to request a reauthorization for such rules, such agency shall, by the December 1 that is one year before the rule is scheduled to sunset, submit to Congress a report that includes: (1) a justification for such reauthorization, (2) any related covered rules, and (3) any recommendation or request made by the chair or ranking member of an appropriate committee. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
