<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1669" measure-id="id115hr1669" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-22" update-date="2017-06-19">
<title>Partnership to Build America Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1669v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-19">
<action-date>2017-03-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Partnership to Build America Act of 2017</b></p> <p> This bill establishes the American Infrastructure Fund (AIF) as a wholly-owned government corporation to provide bond guarantees and make loans to state and local governments, non-profit infrastructure providers, private parties, and public-private partnerships for state or local government sponsored transportation, energy, water, communications, or educational facility infrastructure projects (Qualified Infrastructure Projects [QIPs]). The AIF may also to make equity investments in QIPs.</p> <p>The Department of the Treasury, acting through the AIF, shall issue American Infrastructure Bonds with an aggregate face value of $50 billion. The proceeds from the sale of the bonds shall be deposited into the AIF.</p> <p>The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow U.S. corporations to exclude from gross income qualified cash dividend amounts received during a taxable year from a foreign-controlled corporation equal to the face value of qualified infrastructure bonds the corporation has purchased.</p> <p>The bill prohibits allowance of:</p> <ul> <li> a foreign tax credit for the excluded portion of any dividend received by a U.S. corporation, and</li> <li> a deduction for expenses directly allocable to that excludable portion.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
