<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2048" measure-id="id115hr2048" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2017-08-14">
<title>Eliminating Health Disparities Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2048v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-14">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Eliminating Health Disparities Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to allow a state to establish a Health Disparities Elimination Program, through which the state shall provide incentive payments to qualified community health systems (i.e., hospitals or affiliated groups of health care providers) for approved initiatives to reduce health disparities. In selecting qualified community health systems for participation, a state shall give priority to those that: (1) have included, in their required action plans, the use of evidence-based interventions; (2) have had relevant prior experience; and (3) demonstrate a long-term commitment to serving the target populations, a need for additional financial resources, and the potential for high impact relative to the amount of funding requested.</p> <p>Federal funding for program support shall be allocated based on each state's share of total federal Medicaid expenditures.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
