<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1558" measure-id="id115hr1558" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-16" update-date="2017-11-13">
<title>Repeatedly Flooded Communities Preparation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1558v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-13">
<action-date>2017-08-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Repeatedly Flooded Communities Preparation Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to require a community that participates in the National Flood Insurance Program (NFIP) and has been repeatedly flooded&nbsp;to: (1) assess the continuing risks to community areas repeatedly damaged by floods; and (2) develop and implement&nbsp;a publicly available, community-specific plan for mitigating continuing flood risks to such areas.</p> <p>The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) must, upon request, provide&nbsp;a community with data to assist in preparation of the required plan.</p> <p>In making decisions with respect to awarding mitigation grants under the Act, FEMA may consider the extent to which a community&nbsp;has complied with these requirements and is working to remedy problems with repeatedly flooded areas.</p> <p>A community that does not comply with these requirements shall be subject to sanctions.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) FEMA's implementation of monthly premium payment schedules is exempted from rulemaking. FEMA may implement this schedule as a pilot program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1558v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-06">
<action-date>2017-03-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Repeatedly Flooded Communities Preparation Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to require a community that participates in the National Flood Insurance Program and has been repeatedly flooded, as specified by the bill,&nbsp;to: (1) assess the continuing risks to community areas repeatedly damaged by floods; and (2) develop and implement&nbsp;a publicly available, community-specific plan for mitigating continuing flood risks to such areas.</p> <p>The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) must, upon request, provide&nbsp;a community with appropriate data to assist in preparation of the required plan.</p> <p>In making decisions with respect to awarding mitigation grants under the Act, FEMA may consider the extent to which a community&nbsp;has complied with these requirements and is working to remedy problems with repeatedly flooded areas.</p> <p>A community that does not comply with these requirements shall be subject to appropriate sanctions, including suspension from the National Flood Insurance Program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
