<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2444" measure-id="id115hr2444" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-16" update-date="2017-12-20">
<title>TRUMP Special Counsel Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2444v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-20">
<action-date>2017-05-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Trusted, Reliable, Unquestioned Method of Procedure for Special Counsel Appointment, Limitations, and Powers Act of 2017 or the TRUMP Special Counsel Act </b></p> <p>This bill requires the Attorney General to appoint a special counsel when the Attorney General determines that the investigation or prosecution of a person or matter would present a conflict of interest for the Department of Justice (DOJ) or other extraordinary circumstances exist. Extraordinary circumstances exist in any criminal investigation of the President, Vice President, and their spouses or children, or which involves the activities of agents or entities under the control of a foreign state acting in concert with agents associated with the President or Vice President.</p> <p>The jurisdiction of a special counsel is established by the Attorney General, who shall include a specific factual statement of the matter to be investigated. The special counsel's jurisdiction also includes the authority to investigate and prosecute federal crimes committed with the intent to interfere with the investigation. </p> <p>A special counsel may request the assignment of appropriate DOJ employees to assist him or her. If necessary, the special counsel may request that additional personnel be hired or assigned from outside DOJ. </p> <p>The special counsel shall exercise, within the scope of his or her jurisdiction, the full power and independent authority to exercise all investigative and prosecutorial functions of any U.S. Attorney.</p> <p>The special counsel and staff shall be subject to disciplinary action for misconduct under the same standards as other employees of DOJ.</p> <p>At the conclusion of the special counsel's work, the special counsel must provide the Attorney General with a confidential report explaining prosecution or declination decisions.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
