<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3867" measure-id="id115hr3867" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-28" update-date="2018-02-09">
<title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to create care management demonstration programs for chronic kidney disease under the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3867v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-09">
<action-date>2017-09-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to establish two care-management demonstration programs for chronic kidney disease (CKD) under the Medicare program: (1) the CKD Early Detection and Treatment Demonstration Program, and (2) the Demonstration Program for Advanced CKD. A practitioner's participation in either program&nbsp;shall be&nbsp;optional.</p> <p>Through&nbsp;each program, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS)&nbsp;shall provide to&nbsp;an enrollee's participating primary-care practitioner a single, monthly, performance-based payment for covered CKD care-management services furnished to the enrollee. The amount of&nbsp;this payment shall be greater than the amount that the practitioner would otherwise have received under Medicare for furnishing such services to the enrollee.&nbsp; The CMS shall specify applicable performance measures, in accordance with clinical guidelines.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
