<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="722" measure-id="id115hr722" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-30" update-date="2017-02-09">
<title>No Funds for Unconstitutional Executive Orders Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr722v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-02-09">
<action-date>2017-01-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>No Funds for Unconstitutional Executive Orders Act</b></p> <p>This bill prohibits any federal agency funds, resources, or fees from being used to carry out any of the policy changes set forth in the executive order entitled &quot;Protecting the Nation from Foreign Terrorist Entry into the United States,&quot; signed by President Donald J. Trump on January 27, 2017. Among the order's major provisions are restrictions on the entry of immigrants and nonimmigrants from seven countries (Iran, Iraq, Libya, Somalia, Sudan, Syria, and Yemen) and additional limitations on refugee admissions to the United States.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
