<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1402" measure-id="id115hr1402" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-07" update-date="2017-05-22">
<title>Macadamia Tree Health Initiative</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1402v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-22">
<action-date>2017-03-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Macadamia Tree Health Initiative</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to authorize the Department of Agriculture to provide competitive research and extension grants for a macadamia tree health initiative to: (1) develop and disseminate science-based tools and treatments to combat the insect known as the macadamia felted coccid (Eriococcus ironsidei); and (2) establish an area-wide integrated pest management program in areas affected, or at risk of being affected by, the insect. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
