<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1645" measure-id="id115hr1645" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-21" update-date="2018-04-02">
<title>Fostering Innovation Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1645v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-04-02">
<action-date>2017-11-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fostering Innovation Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 to establish a temporary exemption&nbsp;to the requirement that each registered public accounting firm that prepares or issues an audit report for an issuer of securities (other than an emerging growth company) shall attest to, and report on, the internal control assessment made by the management of the issuer. Specifically, this requirement shall not apply with respect to an audit report prepared for an issuer that:</p> <ul> <li>ceased to be an emerging growth company on the last day of its fiscal year following the fifth anniversary of its first sale of common equity securities, </li> <li>had average annual gross revenues of less than $50 million as of its most recently completed fiscal year, and </li> <li>is not a large accelerated filer. </li></ul> <p>An issuer shall&nbsp;cease to be eligible for the&nbsp;exemption at the earliest of: (1) the last day of the fiscal year following the&nbsp;10th anniversary of its&nbsp;first sale of common equity securities, (2) the last day of the fiscal year in which its average annual gross revenues exceed $50 million, or (3) when the issuer becomes a large accelerated filer. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1645v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-28">
<action-date>2017-03-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fostering Innovation Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 to establish a temporary exemption&nbsp;to the requirement that each registered public accounting firm that prepares or issues an audit report for an issuer of securities (other than an emerging growth company) shall attest to, and report on, the internal control assessment made by the management of the issuer. Specifically, this requirement shall not apply with respect to an audit report prepared for an issuer that:</p> <ul> <li>ceased to be an emerging growth company on the last day of its fiscal year following the fifth anniversary of its first sale of common equity securities, </li> <li>had average annual gross revenues of less than $50 million as of its most recently completed fiscal year, and </li> <li>is not a large accelerated filer. </li></ul> <p>An issuer shall&nbsp;cease to be eligible for the&nbsp;exemption at the earliest of: (1) the last day of the fiscal year following the&nbsp;10th anniversary of its&nbsp;first sale of common equity securities, (2) the last day of the fiscal year in which its average annual gross revenues exceed $50 million, or (3) when the issuer becomes a large accelerated filer. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
