<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3428" measure-id="id115hr3428" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-26" update-date="2017-08-08">
<title>APP Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3428v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-08">
<action-date>2017-07-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Advancing and Promoting Programming or the APP Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the General Services Administration (GSA) to establish a publicly available website that includes a database of federal funding opportunities for the creation of apps (software applications that enable the performance of specific tasks that may be run on a computer, a mobile device, the Internet, or any other electronic device) and allows the public to download a federal government app that includes:</p> <ul> <li>a list of each funding source for the creation and maintenance of government apps and instructions on how an applicant may apply for such funding;</li> <li>the ability for the public to rate and review any such app;</li> <li>a page that prominently displays apps that have been recently updated or that receive a high user review average;</li> <li>a page that features government projects that provide application developers with tools to improve private apps;</li> <li>resources for education and training related to the creation of apps; and </li> <li>a page that features outstanding, educational, computer science programs and resources to replicate such programs. </li> </ul> <p> The GSA shall review any app for which an update has not been released in more than two years and shall remove any app from the website that is no longer functional or compatible. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
