<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2299" measure-id="id115hr2299" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-02" update-date="2018-01-26">
<title>Currency Optimization, Innovation, and National Savings Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2299v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-26">
<action-date>2017-05-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Currency Optimization, Innovation, and National Savings Act of 2017</b></p>  <p> <p>This bill directs the Government Accountability Office to study the production cost of the one-cent coin and ways the production cost could be lowered while maintaining the utility of the coin.</p> <p>The bill provides for the replacement of $1 notes with $1 coins as the only $1 monetary unit in circulation. Treasury will no longer be authorized to issue $1 notes two years after passage of this bill and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall ensure that all $1 Federal Reserve notes are destroyed within this time.</p> <p>Notwithstanding this bill, $1 Federal Reserve notes shall remain legal tender in the United States.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
