<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1900" measure-id="id115hr1900" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-04" update-date="2017-11-09">
<title>National Veterans Memorial and Museum Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1900v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-09">
<action-date>2017-11-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>National Veterans Memorial and Museum Act</strong></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill designates the Veterans Memorial and Museum currently being constructed in Columbus, Ohio, as the National Veterans Memorial and Museum.</p> <p> Such designation may be withdrawn no earlier than five years after the date the museum opens to the public if the museum's progress and operation are found to be unsatisfactory based on the report required by this bill.</p> <p> As a condition of designation, the director of the museum shall report to Congress regarding: (1) a projected five-year budget, (2) outreach to veterans about the design and contents of the museum, (3) the exhibit decision-making process, (4) organizational structure, (5) bylaws and rules, and (6) organizations that have accredited the museum. </p> <p> The museum is not a unit of the National Park System, and its designation under this bill shall not be construed to require federal funds to be expended for it. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1900v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-11">
<action-date>2017-04-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>National Veterans Memorial and Museum Act</strong></p> <p>This bill designates the Veterans Memorial and Museum currently being constructed in Columbus, Ohio, as the National Veterans Memorial and Museum.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
