<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2846" measure-id="id115hr2846" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-08" update-date="2017-12-19">
<title>Federal Agency Customer Experience Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2846v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-19">
<action-date>2017-06-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Federal Agency Customer Experience Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill exempts an agency's authority to collect information that is voluntary feedback from the federal information resources management activities authority of the the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) under the Paperwork Reduction Act. &quot;Voluntary feedback&quot; is defined as any submission of information, opinion, or concern that is: (1) voluntarily made by a specific individual or entity relating to a particular service of or transaction with an agency, and (2) specifically solicited by that agency.</p> <p>Each agency that solicits voluntary feedback shall ensure that:</p> <ul> <li> responses to the solicitation remain anonymous,</li> <li> individuals who decline to participate shall not be treated differently by the agency for purposes of providing services or information,</li> <li> the voluntary nature of the solicitation is clear, and </li> <li> the proposed solicitation of voluntary feedback will contribute to improved customer service.</li> </ul> <p>Each agency shall: (1) collect voluntary feedback with respect to its services and transactions, (2) annually publish such feedback on its website and report on such feedback to OMB, and (3) publish aggregated reports on the solicitation of such feedback. </p> <p>OMB shall: (1) develop a set of standardized questions for use by agencies in collecting such feedback on service satisfaction, timeliness, and professionalism; and (2) include and maintain on a publicly available website links to the information provided on the agency websites.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office shall make publicly available and submit to Congress a scorecard report assessing the quality of services provided to the public by each agency.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
