<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3185" measure-id="id115hr3185" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-11" update-date="2018-03-12">
<title>REVAMP Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3185v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-12">
<action-date>2017-07-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Reforms to Encourage VA Meaningful Progress Act of 2017 or the REVAMP Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs' (VA's) Under Secretary for Health to implement a process to evaluate reviews of the organizational structure of the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) conducted by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Inspector General of the VA, the Government Accountability Office, the Commission on Care, or an independent entity.</p> <p>The Under Secretary shall use such process to: (1) assess the results of the evaluation to be conducted of the Veterans Integrated Service Network with respect to the implementation of realignments and the identification of deficiencies that require corrective action, and (2) implement actions to improve the network. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
