<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4293" measure-id="id115hr4293" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-11-07" update-date="2018-03-22">
<title>Stress Test Improvement Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4293v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-22">
<action-date>2018-03-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Stress Test Improvement Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to modify testing requirements applicable to bank holding companies and certain nonbank financial companies, including by: (1) establishing limitations on Comprehensive Capital Analysis and Review by the Federal Reserve Board, (2) reducing the frequency of stress testing from semiannual to annual, and (3) otherwise revising provisions related to stress testing. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4293v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-16">
<action-date>2017-11-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Stress Test Improvement Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to modify testing requirements applicable to bank holding companies and certain nonbank financial companies, including by: (1) requiring the Federal Reserve Board (FRB) to revise its&nbsp;regulations regarding specified conditions, methodologies, and models&nbsp;for stress testing; (2) establishing limitations on Comprehensive Capital Analysis and Review by the FRB; and (3) reducing the frequency of stress testing from semiannual to annual. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
