<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="970" measure-id="id115hr970" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-07" update-date="2017-08-17">
<title>Improving Corporate Governance Through Diversity Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr970v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-17">
<action-date>2017-02-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Improving Corporate Governance Through Diversity Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill directs executive agencies to require any covered contractor (a for-profit business with gross receipts exceeding $1 billion for the previous year) awarded a contract of $5 million or more to submit, within 60 days:</p> <ul> <li>data on the racial, ethnic, and gender composition of such contractor's board of directors and senior executives;</li> <li>data on the affiliation of any such board member or executive to a historically underrepresented group, including veterans and individuals with disabilities; and </li> <li>any plan or strategy to improve the diversity of such board members or executives.</li> </ul> <p>Each agency shall submit quarterly reports on such data to the General Services Administration, which shall report to Congress annually on the diversity of such contractor boards and executives.</p> <p>The Securities Exchange Act of 1934 is amended to require each issuer of a registered security to disclose such data, plan, and strategy in its required annual report.</p>  <p>The Securities and Exchange Commission must revise corporate governance regulations to require that when the description is presented in a proxy or information statement relating to the election of directors, the nominee's qualities and skills, along with the nominee's gender, race, ethnicity, and affiliation with a historically underrepresented group, are presented in a chart or matrix form.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
