<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2903" measure-id="id115hr2903" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-15" update-date="2018-03-09">
<title>Rural Reasonable and Comparable Wireless Access Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2903v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-09">
<action-date>2017-06-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Rural Reasonable and Comparable Wireless Access Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to develop regulations that would establish a national standard for determining whether mobile service, mobile data service,&nbsp;and broadband service in rural areas are reasonably comparable to the services provided in urban areas.</p> <p>The FCC shall gather data about&nbsp;the average signal strengths and speeds of mobile services and the average speeds of broadband Internet services from the 20 most-populated urban areas. The services provided in rural areas shall be deemed reasonably comparable to urban area if the signal strengths and/or speeds meet or exceed the averages in the most-populated areas.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
