<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="758" measure-id="id115hr758" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-31" update-date="2017-02-16">
<title>GI Internship Program Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr758v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-02-16">
<action-date>2017-01-31</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>GI Internship Program Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs theDepartment of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish a career transition internship program to match individuals who are eligible for veterans' educational assistance with employers to: (1) provide such individuals with work experience in the civilian sector, (2) address the growing skills gap in the U.S. economy, (3) increase the marketable skills of such individuals, and (4) assist such individuals in obtaining long-term employment.</p> <p>The VA shall establish criteria employers must meet to participate in the program. Program employers shall not include: (1) government agencies; (2) employers who cannot provide the VA with certain assurances, including their intention to retain interns after their internship ends; and (3) employers that have previously participated in the program and failed to abide by its requirements.</p> <p>The VA shall pay individuals who are full-time participants in such an internship the amount of educational assistance they are due.</p> <p>Each internship shall last for at least 180 days but for no more than one year.</p> <p>Each intern shall be considered to be an employee of the VA for purposes of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</p> <p>Each intern and employer shall provide the VA with a monthly certification that the intern worked at least 35 hours each week performing functions that provided the individual with valuable experience.</p> <p>The VA and the Department of Labor shall create and publicize a website to serve as a portal for the program. Individuals may apply within 180 days of their expected discharge or release from the Armed Forces.</p> <p>The VA shall minimize the administrative burdens incurred by employers due to their participation in the program and ensure that employer participation is at no cost to the employer.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
