<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4324" measure-id="id115hr4324" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-11-09" update-date="2018-01-09">
<title>Strengthening Oversight of Iran's Access to Finance Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4324v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-09">
<action-date>2017-11-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Strengthening Oversight of Iran's Access to Finance Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of the Treasury, not later than 30 days after authorizing a U. S. or foreign financial institution to export or re-export a commercial passenger aircraft to Iran (or, for an authorization made after January 16, 2016, but before the enactment of this bill, not later than 60 days after such enactment) and every 180 days thereafter for the duration of the authorization, to submit to Congress a report containing: </p> <ul> <li> a list of financial institutions that have, since January 16, 2016, conducted transactions authorized in connection with such export or re-export; and either</li> <li> a certification that such transaction does not pose a significant money laundering or terrorism financing risk to the U. S. financial system and will not benefit an Iranian person who for the one year preceding the certification has knowingly transported weapons of mass destruction or has knowingly provided transportation services or material support to terrorists, and that any such institution had appropriate policies, procedures, and processes in place to avoid engaging in sanctionable activities; or </li> <li>a statement that the Treasury is unable to make such a certification and will, within 60 days after such determination, issue a report on non-certification to Congress.</li> </ul> <p>The President may waive the requirements of this bill for up to one year at a time upon certifying to Congress that: </p> <ul> <li>the Government of Iran has made substantial progress toward combating money laundering and terrorism financing risk emanating from Iran or has significantly reduced its destabilizing activities in the region or material support for terrorist groups; or</li> <li>such waiver is important to U.S. national interests.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
