<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3251" measure-id="id115hr3251" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-14" update-date="2017-09-05">
<title>National Discovery Trails Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3251v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-05">
<action-date>2017-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>National Discovery Trails Act</b></p> <p> This bill amends the National Trails System Act to establish as part of the national trails system national discovery trails, which shall be extended, continuous interstate trails located to provide for outdoor recreation and travel and to connect representative examples of America's trails and communities. </p> <p>The bill authorizes the designation of such trails on federal lands and, with the owner's consent, on nonfederal lands. </p> <p> The 6,000-mile American Discovery Trail extending from Cape Henlopen State Park in Delaware to Point Reyes National Seashore in California, splitting into northern and southern routes at Cincinnati, Ohio, and rejoining at Denver, Colorado, is designated as a national discovery trail. </p> <p>The bill sets forth requirements for designation of a trail as a national discovery trail. </p> <p> The appropriate federal department for each national discovery trail shall: (1) administer the trail in cooperation with a competent trailwide volunteer-based organization; and (2) submit a comprehensive plan for the trail's protection, management, development, and use. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
