<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1585" measure-id="id115hr1585" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-16" update-date="2018-01-25">
<title>Fair Investment Opportunities for Professional Experts Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1585v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-25">
<action-date>2017-10-31</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fair Investment Opportunities for Professional Experts Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Securities Act of 1933 to modify the definition of &quot;accredited investor&quot; for purposes of participating in private offerings to include: </p> <ul> <li>an individual whose net worth or joint net worth with their spouse exceeds $1 million (adjusted for inflation), excluding from the calculation of their net worth their primary residence and a mortgage secured by that residence in certain circumstances; </li> <li>an individual whose income over the last two years exceeded $200,000 (adjusted for inflation) or joint spousal income exceeded $300,000 (adjusted for inflation) and who has a reasonable expectation of reaching the same income level in the current year; </li> <li>an individual who is licensed as a broker or investment advisor by certain entities; and </li> <li>an individual determined by the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to have qualifying education or experience. </li> </ul> <p>(Certain unregistered securities may only be offered to accredited investors.)</p> <p>The SEC is directed to revise the definition of &quot;accredited investor&quot; in Regulation D (which exempts certain offerings from SEC registration requirements) to conform to changes in this bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1585v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-31">
<action-date>2017-03-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Securities Act of 1933 to modify the definition of &quot;accredited investor&quot; for purposes of participating in private offerings to include:</p> <ul> <li>an individual whose net worth, or joint net worth with their spouse, exceeds $1 million, excluding their primary residence;</li> <li>an individual whose income over the last two years exceeded $200,000, or joint spousal income exceeded $300,000;</li> <li>an individual who holds a state-issued financial services license; and</li> <li>an individual determined by the Securities and Exchange Commission to have qualifying education or experience.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
