<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1756" measure-id="id115hr1756" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-28" update-date="2017-10-17">
<title>Virginia Jobs and Energy Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1756v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-17">
<action-date>2017-03-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> <b>Virginia Jobs and Energy Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of the Interior to conduct an oil and gas lease sale off the coast of Virginia within one year, and conduct at least two lease sales in the area during the 2017-2022 Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Program. During each of Interior's five-year leasing programs, two lease sales must be conducted off the coast of Virginia.</p> <p>The bill prohibits oil or natural gas exploration, development, or production off the Virginia coast that would conflict with a military operation. </p> <p>The bill allocates 37.5% of new leasing revenues received each fiscal year by the federal government for payment to states affected with respect to the leases that generate these revenues.Additionally, the bill sets forth the minimum and maximum revenues that an affected state may receive.</p> <p>Interior must require any applicant seeking to conduct an offshore meteorological site testing and monitoring project to obtain a permit and right-of-way.(An offshore meteorological site testing and monitoring project is carried out on or in the waters of the outer Continental Shelf to test or monitor weather using towers, buoys, or other temporary ocean infrastructure).These projects shall be exempt from environmental impact statement requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</p> </p> <p> <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
