<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1420" measure-id="id115hr1420" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-08" update-date="2017-11-02">
<title>Know Before You Fly Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1420v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-02">
<action-date>2017-03-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Know Before You Fly Act</b></p> <p>This bill makes it an unfair or deceptive practice for an air carrier, foreign air carrier, or ticket agent to fail to disclose in its Internet fare quotation a clear and prominent statement of checked baggage and carry-on baggage fees, along with a prominent website link to a list of all such fees.</p> <p> A covered air carrier shall publish on its website a clear statement indicating whether it will provide passengers whose travel is interrupted due to a widespread disruption:</p> <ul> <li>hotel accommodations;</li> <li>ground transportation;</li> <li>meal vouchers;</li> <li>transportation on another air carrier to the passenger's destination; and </li> <li>sleeping facilities, food, and water inside the airport terminal.</li> </ul> <p>A &quot;covered air carrier&quot; is defined as an air carrier that provides scheduled or public charter air transportation in an aircraft designed for a passenger capacity of 30 or more. </p> <p>The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) shall designate a FAA office to receive and analyze reports involving fumes in the air conditioning and pressurization systems of commercial aircraft.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
