<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3429" measure-id="id115hr3429" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-26" update-date="2018-03-14">
<title>Repatriate Our Patriots Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3429v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-14">
<action-date>2017-07-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> <b>Repatriate Our Patriots Act</b></p> <p>This bill prohibits a special veteran from being removed from the United States.</p> <p>A special veteran: (1) is an alien veteran who was discharged or released from military service under conditions other than dishonorable; (2) includes only an honorably discharged or released individual; and (3) excludes an individual convicted of voluntary manslaughter, murder, rape, sexual abuse of a minor, or terrorism-related offenses or an individual determined to be a child abuser or a pedophile. </p> <p>DHS: (1) shall process naturalization applications for special veterans within 90 days; and (2) may permit special veterans to file naturalization applications from abroad and take the oath of allegiance at U.S. embassies, consulates, and military installations.</p> <p>DHS shall: (1) cancel the removal of a special veteran in removal proceedings, and (2) allow a special veteran whose permanent resident status was rescinded to adjust back to such status.</p> <p>The Department of Justice, in the case of a special veteran who was ordered removed, shall rescind any outstanding order of removal and any finding that the individual is subject to removal or is inadmissible.</p> <p>DHS shall create a program to allow a special veteran who was removed to return to the United States as a lawfully admitted permanent resident.</p> <p>A special veteran who has been naturalized or who has obtained lawful permanent resident status pursuant to this bill shall be eligible for all military and veterans benefits for which such individual would have been eligible otherwise. </p> <p>DHS shall identify and maintain records of immigration cases involving special veterans.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
