<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="952" measure-id="id115hr952" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-07" update-date="2017-07-14">
<title>Food Donation Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr952v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-14">
<action-date>2017-02-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Food Donation Act of 2017 </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Bill Emerson Good Samaritan Food Donation Act to expand the liability protections for the donation of food. </p> <p>The bill expands the liability protections to include donations of an apparently fit grocery product or apparently wholesome food: </p> <ul> <li> that is mislabeled in a manner that is not related to safety and safety-related labeling standards and regulations; </li> <li> meets safety and safety-related labeling standards and regulations but is past the date label; </li> <li> for which the recipient is charged a &quot;good Samaritan reduced&quot; price that is no greater than the cost of handling, administering, and distributing the product; or </li> <li> that is donated directly to a needy individual by a retail grocer, wholesaler, agricultural producer, restaurant, caterer, school food authority, or institution of higher education. </li> </ul> <p>The Department of Agriculture must: (1) issue regulations with respect to the safety and safety-related labeling standards of apparently wholesome food and an apparently fit grocery product under the Bill Emerson Good Samaritan Food Donation Act, (2) promote awareness of food donation under the Act, and (3) issue guidance with respect to the amendments made by this bill. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
