<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2592" measure-id="id115hr2592" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-22" update-date="2018-01-29">
<title>Expanding the Impact of the HUBZone Program Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2592v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-29">
<action-date>2017-05-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Expanding the Impact of the HUBZone Program Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Small Business Act to redefine terms relating to the Historically Underutilized Business Zone (HUBZone) program as follows:</p> <ul> <li>&quot;HUBZone&quot; as any area designated on a map by the Small Business Administration (SBA) within one or more specified locations,</li> <li>&quot;base closure area&quot; and &quot;qualified disaster area&quot; to repeal the eight-year limitation on HUBZone eligibility, and</li> <li>&quot;qualified HUBZone small business concern&quot; to require SBA certification for up to 10 years.</li> </ul> <p>The SBA must determine whether or not to designate a qualified census tract or qualified nonmetropolitan county as a HUBZone immediately after the Census Bureau publicly releases the first results from the decennial census that occurs after enactment of this bill.</p> <p>The bill amends the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2005 to repeal the five-year limitation on HUBZone status of base closure areas.</p> <p>The SBA must publish performance metrics to measure the success of the HUBZone program in promoting economic development in economically distressed areas.</p> <p>A small business concern that was qualified as a HUBZone small business concern on or before the enactment of this bill shall be deemed a &quot;qualified HUBZone small business concern&quot; for up to 10 years beginning on its first qualification and may reapply for SBA certification at the end of such period. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
