<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3224" measure-id="id115hr3224" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-13" update-date="2017-09-19">
<title>CARE Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3224v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-19">
<action-date>2017-07-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Critical Access and Rural Equity Act of 2017 or the CARE Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to specify that, for purposes of determining Medicare payment and reasonable costs for both inpatient and outpatient critical access hospital (CAH) services, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) shall recognize as allowable costs those&nbsp;related to specified emergency, diagnostic, anesthetist, community health, and off-campus clinical services.</p> <p>Furthermore, in&nbsp;determining payment and reasonable costs for both inpatient and outpatient CAH services, CMS shall not disallow payment to&nbsp;a CAH on the basis that such payment offsets the cost of a current permissible health care-related tax imposed on and paid by the CAH.&nbsp;CMS&nbsp;must make specified payment adjustments to account for such a tax.&nbsp;</p> <p>Generally, under current law,&nbsp;a facility&nbsp;must be located beyond a specified driving distance from another hospital or facility in order to be designated as a CAH. The bill specifies that this requirement does not apply with respect to a CAH's off-campus provider-based clinic.</p> <p>Current law further requires a facility to provide&nbsp;certain 24-hour emergency care services as a condition of designation as a CAH. The bill allows CMS to waive this requirement with respect to a facility that coordinates with a nearby&nbsp;facility or hospital that provides such services.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
