<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1473" measure-id="id115hr1473" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-09" update-date="2017-07-08">
<title>Prohibit Expansion of U.S. Combat Troops into Syria Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1473v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-08">
<action-date>2017-03-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Prohibit Expansion of U.S. Combat Troops into Syria Act</strong></p> <p>This bill prohibits the obligation or expenditure of Department of Defense funds for the purpose of:</p> <ul> <li> deploying members of the Armed Forces to Syria to engage in ground combat operations; </li> <li> awarding a contract to a private security contractor to conduct any activity on the ground of Syria; or </li> <li> otherwise establishing or maintaining any presence of members of the Armed Forces or private security contractors on the ground of Syria, unless the purpose of such presence is limited solely to rescuing or protecting members of the Armed Forces from imminent danger. </li> </ul> <p> The prohibition does not apply to the deployment of the Armed Forces to protect, rescue, or remove U.S. personnel.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
