<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1668" measure-id="id115hr1668" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-22" update-date="2017-03-29">
<title>Bureau of Land Management Foundation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1668v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-03-29">
<action-date>2017-03-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Bureau of Land Management Foundation Act</b></p> <p> This bill establishes the Bureau of Land Management Foundation as a charitable, nonprofit organization to encourage, accept, obtain, administer, and use private gifts of money, devises, and bequests of real and personal property for the benefit of, or in connection with, the activities and services of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM). </p> <p>The foundation shall conduct and encourage programs and activities, including by awarding grants, that support:</p> <ul> <li>educational, technical, scientific, and other assistance or activities to support the management of BLM lands with regard to wild free-roaming horses and burros, fish and wildlife and their habitats, National Conservation Lands, and recreation, cultural, and historic resources; and </li> <li>activities that support the reclamation and remediation of specified abandoned mine lands, specified orphaned oil and gas well sites, or public lands impacted by development connected to mineral exploration and development activities. </li> </ul> <p>Reclamation activities are to include the remediation of soil and water contamination; the restoration of wildlife habitat in order to restore the natural, scenic, historic, cultural, and ecological values of those areas; or promotion of the areas' economic potential.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
