<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1968" measure-id="id115hr1968" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2017-10-18">
<title>Military Asset Protection Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1968v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-18">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Military Asset Protection Act</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Defense (DOD), in order to mitigate the threat of an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft to the safety or security of a covered facility or asset or to classified information, to take actions or authorize the Armed Forces or DOD contractors to take actions to: (1) disrupt, seize control of, or confiscate the system or aircraft; (2) use reasonable force to disable or destroy the system or aircraft; or (3) disrupt, alter, or intercept any communications to or from the system or aircraft. DOD may provide exceptions to such provisions.</p> <p>The bill provides that: (1) DOD shall develop such actions with Department of Transportation assistance, consistent with the protection of sensitive defense information; and (2) any such system or aircraft shall be subject to U.S. seizure and forfeiture.</p> <p>&quot;Covered facility, asset, or classified information&quot; means any facility, asset, or classified information that is: (1) so identified by DOD; (2) located in the United States or its territories and possessions; and (3) relating to DOD's missions of nuclear deterrence, missile defense, national space security, or homeland defense or other DOD missions involving vital security or infrastructure assets or information. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
