<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1664" measure-id="id115hr1664" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-22" update-date="2017-06-21">
<title>Investing in America: A Penny for Progress Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1664v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-21">
<action-date>2017-03-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Investing in America: A Penny for Progress Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to require federal taxes on gasoline and diesel fuel or kerosene to be increased annually after 2017 to account for: (1) highway construction costs, and (2) reduced fuel usage due to Corporate Average Fuel Economy (CAFE) standards. The bill exempts kerosene fuels used in aviation from the increases and limits the annual increases to 1.5 cents. </p> <p>The bill also requires the Department of the Treasury to issue 30-year Invest in America Bonds in specified amounts annually through FY2030. The revenue from the bonds must be transferred to the Highway Trust Fund (HTF), with 80% allocated to the Highway Account and 20% allocated to the Mass Transit Account. The bill specifies requirements for allocating the additional funding from the HTF.</p> <p>Treasury must repay the bonds using the revenues that are attributable to the increased taxes required by this bill. After all of the bonds have been redeemed, additional revenues attributable to the increases must be transferred to the HTF.</p> <p>The bill also modifies Department of Transportation reporting requirements regarding: (1) infrastructure investment needs, and (2) public transportation investment needs. </p> <p>The bill amends the Fixing America's Surface Transportation Act (FAST Act) to repeal a rescission of certain unobligated federal-aid highway funds apportioned among the states. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
