<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3317" measure-id="id115hr3317" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-19" update-date="2018-02-12">
<title>SAFE Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3317v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-12">
<action-date>2017-12-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Stopping Abusive Female Exploitation Act of 2017 or the SAFE Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the federal criminal code to increase from 5 to 15 years the maximum prison term for an individual who is convicted of female genital mutilation. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) It expresses the sense of Congress that states should have in place laws that require health care professionals, teachers, and other school employees to report to local law enforcement agencies any instance of suspected female genital mutilation. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3317v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-21">
<action-date>2017-07-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Stopping Abusive Female Exploitation Act or the SAFE Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the federal criminal code to increase from 5 to 15 years the maximum prison term for an individual who is convicted of female genital mutilation. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
