<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2863" measure-id="id115hr2863" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-08" update-date="2017-12-13">
<title>LAND Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2863v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-13">
<action-date>2017-06-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Land and National Park Deferred Maintenance Act or the LAND Act</b></p> <p>This bill extends the Land and Water Conservation Fund (LWCF) through FY2024. </p> <p>From the amounts deposited into the LWCF, $450 million shall be available in each fiscal year for expenditure to carry out the purposes of the Act establishing the LWCF and the purposes of the LWCF. Remaining amounts in the LWCF shall be available subject to appropriations. </p> <p> The bill specifies the use of amounts for federal purposes for certain land and water acquisitions (as currently) and financial assistance to states for LWCF purposes and outdoor recreation, the Forest Legacy Program, cooperative endangered species grants, and the American Battlefield Protection Program. </p> <p>The President must submit to Congress, as part of the annual budget submission, the account, program, and project allocations for funds that are made available from the LWCF for federal purposes. </p> <p>The bill prohibits the use of any funding made available to a state under this bill from being used for the acquisition of lands, waters, or interests in lands or waters by eminent domain. </p> <p>At least 1.5% of appropriated or expended LWCF funds must be available for projects that secure recreational public access to existing federal public land for hunting, fishing, and other recreational purposes. </p> <p>The bill establishes a National Park Service and Related Agencies Maintenance and Revitalization Conservation Fund in the Treasury for the deposit through FY2024 of $450 million from mineral revenues that are not otherwise credited, covered, or deposited under federal law. Of amounts made available from this fund, the Department of the Interior shall use specified amounts for high priority deferred maintenance needs that support critical infrastructure and visitor services. The Department of Agriculture shall use a specified amount for federal lands administered by the Forest Service for such high priority deferred maintenance needs.</p>  <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
