<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3076" measure-id="id115hr3076" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-27" update-date="2017-09-27">
<title>Creating Advanced Streamlined Electronic Services (CASES) for Constituents Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3076v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-27">
<action-date>2017-06-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Creating Advanced Streamlined Electronic Services (CASES) for Constituents Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Privacy Act of 1974 to require each executive agency to establish a system that allows an individual, or an entity authorized to act on such individual's behalf, to electronically submit a release form that grants another entity access to information in such system pertaining to the individual.</p> <p> The Office of Management and Budget shall establish a uniform release form to be used across agencies for such electronic submission.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
