<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1596" measure-id="id115hr1596" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-17" update-date="2017-11-16">
<title>Commission to Study the Creation of a National Museum of Irish American History</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1596v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-16">
<action-date>2017-03-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Commission to Study the Creation of a National Museum of Irish American History</b></p> <p>This bill establishes a commission to study the potential for creating a National Museum of Irish American History. </p> <p>The commission shall report to the President and Congress on:</p> <ul> <li> its recommendations for a plan of action for the establishment of the museum in Washington, DC;</li> <li>the availability and cost of the collections to be acquired and housed;</li> <li>the impact of the museum on regional Irish-American-related museums;</li> <li>whether the museum should be located within the Smithsonian Institution;</li> <li>the governance and organizational structure of the museum; </li> <li>how to engage the Irish-American community in the museum's development and design; and </li> <li>the cost of constructing, operating, and maintaining the museum. </li> </ul> <p>The commission shall: (1) develop and obtain an independent review of a fund-raising plan to support the museum through public contributions, and (2) submit recommendations for a legislative plan of action for the creation and construction of the museum. </p> <p>The commission may host a national conference on the museum for individuals who are committed to the advancement of Irish-American life, art, history, and culture. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
