<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3623" measure-id="id115hr3623" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-28" update-date="2017-11-14">
<title>Securing and Heightening the Integrity of our Elections and Lawful Democracy Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3623v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-14">
<action-date>2017-07-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Securing and Heightening the Integrity of our Elections and Lawful Democracy Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to include among the Department of Homeland Security's (DHS's) responsibilities relating to intelligence and analysis and infrastructure protection the coordination of cybersecurity efforts between DHS and political campaign committees in order to:</p> <ul> <li> develop a program to update computer security at political campaign committees,</li> <li> share information on cybersecurity risks with such committees,</li> <li> provide guest lecturer programs in which professional computer security experts instruct campaign professionals on how best to defend against cybersecurity risks, and </li> <li> establish an Election Security Board of Advisors to make recommendations about securing elections against cybersecurity risks. </li> </ul> <ul> <ul> </ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
