<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="369" measure-id="id115hr369" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-09" update-date="2017-06-05">
<title>To eliminate the sunset of the Veterans Choice Program, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr369v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-05">
<action-date>2017-03-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> (Sec. 1) This bill amends the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 to eliminate the August 7, 2017, sunset date for the Veterans Choice Program, which would allow the program to operate until all of the money in the Veterans Choice Fund is expended.</p> <p> (Sec. 2) The bill makes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) the primary payer (the VA is currently the secondary payer) for medical care relating to non-service connected disabilities and recovery of costs from third parties for certain care under the program.</p> <p> (Sec. 3) The VA may share medical information with a non-VA entity (including private entities and other federal agencies) that provides veterans with hospital care or medical services. Such entity may not redisclose or use such information for a purpose other than that for which the disclosure was made.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr369v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-05">
<action-date>2017-01-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 to eliminate the August 7, 2017, sunset date for the Veterans Choice Program, which would allow the program to operate until all of the money in the Veterans Choice Fund is expended.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
