<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4852" measure-id="id115hr4852" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2018-01-19" update-date="2018-03-26">
<title>Pay Our Protectors Not Our Politicians Act of 2018</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4852v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-26">
<action-date>2018-01-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Pay Our Protectors Not Our Politicians Act of 2018 </b></p> <p>This bill provides FY2018 appropriations for military pay during any period in which interim or full-year appropriations for FY2018 are not in effect. </p> <p>The appropriations provided by this bill are available until the earlier of: (1) the enactment into law of specified appropriations legislation, or (2) January 1, 2019. </p> <p>The bill provides continuing appropriations for pay and allowances of: </p> <ul> <li> members of the Armed Forces, including reserve components, who perform active service; </li> <li> members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces who perform inactive-duty training; </li> <li> civilian personnel or contractors of the Department of Defense (and the Department of Homeland Security [DHS] in the case of the Coast Guard) who are providing support to members of the Armed Forces; and </li> <li> DHS employees who are performing national security activities. </li> </ul> <p>It also provides continuing appropriations for payments related to:</p> <ul> <li>death gratuities, </li> <li> funeral and burial expenses, </li> <li> authorized funeral travel and travel related to the dignified transfer of remains and unit memorial services, and </li> <li> the temporary continuation of a basic allowance of housing for dependents of members dying on active duty. </li> </ul> <p>The bill also prohibits Members of Congress from being paid when a government shutdown is in effect during the 116th and succeeding Congresses. During the 115th Congress, congressional pay must be withheld during a government shutdown and released at the end of the Congress. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
