<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1910" measure-id="id115hr1910" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-05" update-date="2017-10-16">
<title>Support Our Military Caregivers Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1910v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-16">
<action-date>2017-04-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Support Our Military Caregivers Act</strong></p> <p>This bill permits an individual to elect to have an independent contractor perform an external clinical review of any of the following: </p> <ul> <li>a Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) denial of an individual's application to be a caregiver or family caregiver eligible for the VA program of comprehensive assistance for family caregivers of eligible veterans; </li> <li>with respect to an approved application, a VA determination of the level or amount of personal care services that a veteran requires; </li> <li>a request by a caregiver or family caregiver for a reconsideration of the level or amount of personal care services that a veteran requires based on post-application changes; and </li> <li>a revocation of such assistance administered by the VA. </li> </ul> <p>The VA shall ensure that each external clinical review is completed and the individual is notified in writing of the results within 120 days of the election.</p> <p>The VA shall issue directives regarding the policies, procedures, and operational requirements for the such program and the VA program of general caregiver support services. The Government Accountability Office shall report to Congress on the VA's processes for determining eligibility for participation in such programs.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
