<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3591" measure-id="id115hr3591" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-28" update-date="2017-09-06">
<title>American Hope Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3591v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-06">
<action-date>2017-07-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>American Hope Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to allow a state to extend higher-education benefits to&nbsp;state residents&nbsp;regardless of whether they are lawfully present in the United States.</p> <p>In addition, the bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS)&nbsp;to cancel the removal, and adjust the status, of certain residents who entered the United States as children&nbsp;prior to&nbsp;2017. An individual whose status has been so adjusted shall be considered to have obtained conditional permanent-resident status, valid for a period of eight years and subject to termination&nbsp;on the basis of&nbsp;specified deportable conduct.</p> <p>In order for an individual's conditional status to become permanent, the individual must timely file with DHS a petition indicating, among other specified information, that the individual has maintained conditional permanent-resident status for at least three years. Any period of time in which the individual was granted deferred action pursuant to the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals policy shall count toward this three-year period. Information furnished by an individual in such a petition may not be used by an officer or employee of the United States to initiate removal proceedings.</p> <p>The bill also: (1) allows DHS&nbsp;to establish a competitive grant program&nbsp;for the provision of nonprofit assistance to eligible applicants for conditional permanent-resident status; (2) establishes the Presidential Award for Business Leadership in Promoting American Citizenship; (3) allows the Department of Education to develop an open-source, electronic English-learning program; (4) specifies&nbsp;requirements related to&nbsp;federal higher-education assistance&nbsp;for individuals with conditional permanent-resident status; and (5) requires the Government Accountability Office to report on specified&nbsp;data related to the bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
