<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3755" measure-id="id115hr3755" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-13" update-date="2018-01-09">
<title>Comprehensive Consumer Credit Reporting Reform Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3755v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-09">
<action-date>2017-09-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Comprehensive Consumer Credit Reporting Reform Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to revise requirements for disputes regarding consumer credit information reported by a consumer reporting agency (CRA).</p> <p>The bill prescribes requirements for:</p> <ul type="disc"> <li>record maintenance by furnishers of credit information,</li> <li>CRA action when notified of inaccurate or incomplete information from furnishers, and</li> <li>injunctive relief for consumers in the event of noncompliance.</li> </ul> <p>The bill limits the circumstances in which a CRA may furnish a consumer report for employment purposes.</p> <p>No CRA may furnish a consumer report containing any adverse item of information relating to a delinquent or defaulted private education loan of a borrower who has a specified demonstrated history of loan repayment.</p> <p>The bill revises requirements relating to information contained in credit reports, requires removal of adverse information that resulted from specified fraudulent lending activity, and shortens the time period adverse information stays on reports.</p> <p>The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) must issue final regulations for development of credit scoring models.</p> <p>CRAs must disclose free credit scores to consumers with their free annual consumer reports.</p> <p>Specified lenders must give consumers free copies of any consumer reports and credit scores they used for underwriting before consumers sign the respective loan agreements.</p> <p>The bill establishes requirements related to credit report sales, required disclosures, and credit freezes. </p> <p>The CFPB is directed to create a nationwide CRA registry.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
