<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2924" measure-id="id115hr2924" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-15" update-date="2017-11-07">
<title>To amend the National Security Act of 1947 to establish the National Russian Threat Response Center within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2924v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-07">
<action-date>2017-06-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the National Security Act of 1947 to establish within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (DNI) a National Russian Threat Response Center.</p> <p>The primary missions of the center shall be:</p> <ul> <li>to serve as the primary U.S. government organization for analyzing and integrating all intelligence pertaining to threats posed by the Russian Federation to the national security, political sovereignty, and economic activity of the United States and its allies;</li> <li>to synchronize the efforts of the intelligence community regarding countering efforts by Russia to undermine such security, sovereignty, and activity;</li> <li>in coordination with the relevant elements of the Department of State, the Department of Defense, the intelligence community, and other U.S. agencies, to develop policy recommendations for the President to detect, deter, and respond to such threats and to monitor and assess Russian efforts to carry out such threats;</li> <li>in coordination with the Global Engagement Center, to examine Russian efforts to use propaganda and information operations relating to such threats; and</li> <li>to identify and close gaps across federal agencies with respect to expertise, readiness, and planning to address such threats.</li> </ul> <p>The Director of the center shall be appointed by the DNI with the concurrence of the State Department. The Director shall: (1) ensure that the relevant federal agencies participate in the center's mission, and (2) have primary responsibility for establishing requirements for collecting intelligence regarding threats posed by Russia. </p> <p>A Board of the center is established to conduct oversight. </p> <p>The Director may convene biannual conferences to coordinate international efforts against such threats.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
