<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="301" measure-id="id115hr301" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-05" update-date="2017-02-01">
<title>NIST Plumbing Research Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr301v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-02-01">
<action-date>2017-01-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>NIST Plumbing Research Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to:</p> <ul> <li>establish or designate a laboratory to conduct research on premise plumbing in relation to water safety, security, efficiency, sustainability, and resilience;</li> <li>conduct an organizational review of all research and other activities related to premise plumbing conducted by federal entities; and </li> <li>appoint one or more officers or employees of the NIST to liaise with non-federal entities that are conducting research or other activities related to premise plumbing. </li> </ul> <p>The bill defines &quot;premise plumbing&quot; as the water distribution system within the property lines of a property, including all buildings and permanent structures on such property. This term also includes building supply and distribution pipes, fixtures, fittings, water heaters, water-treating and water-using equipment, and all respective joints, connections, devices, and appurtenances. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
