<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="971" measure-id="id115hr971" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-07" update-date="2017-07-31">
<title>Surviving Spouse Contracting Preference Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr971v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-31">
<action-date>2017-02-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Surviving Spouse Contracting Preference Act</strong></p> <p>This bill treats a small business owned by the surviving spouse of member of the Armed Forces killed in the line of duty as a small business concern owned and controlled by a service-disabled veteran for purposes of contracting goals and preferences of the Department of Veterans Affairs. </p> <p>The company shall be so considered beginning on the date on which the member of the Armed Forces dies and ending on the earlier of the date on which the surviving spouse: (1) remarries, or (2) relinquishes ownership in such business. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
