<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="309" measure-id="id115hr309" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-05" update-date="2017-01-17">
<title>National Clinical Care Commission Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr309v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-01-17">
<action-date>2017-01-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>National Clinical Care Commission Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to establish within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) a National Clinical Care Commission to evaluate and recommend solutions regarding better coordination and leveraging of federal programs that relate to supporting clinical care for individuals with complex metabolic or autoimmune disease, diabetes, or complications caused by such diseases. </p> <p>The duties of the commission include:</p> <ul> <li>evaluating HHS programs regarding the utilization of preventive health benefits,</li> <li>identifying current activities and gaps in federal efforts to support clinicians in providing integrated care,</li> <li>making recommendations regarding the development and coordination of federally funded clinical practice support tools,</li> <li>recommending clinical pathways for new technologies and treatments,</li> <li>evaluating and expanding education and awareness activities provided to health care professionals, and</li> <li>reviewing and recommending methods for outreach and dissemination of educational resources.</li> </ul> <p>The commission must submit an operating plan to HHS and Congress within 90 days of its first meeting. The commission is terminated after it submits a final report, but not later than the end of FY2021.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr309v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-01-11">
<action-date>2017-01-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>National Clinical Care Commission Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to establish within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) a National Clinical Care Commission to evaluate and recommend solutions regarding better coordination and leveraging of federal programs that relate to supporting clinical care for individuals with complex metabolic or autoimmune disease, diabetes, or complications caused by such diseases. </p> <p>The duties of the commission include:</p> <ul> <li>evaluating HHS programs regarding the utilization of preventive health benefits,</li> <li>identifying current activities and gaps in federal efforts to support clinicians in providing integrated care,</li> <li>making recommendations regarding the development and coordination of federally funded clinical practice support tools,</li> <li>recommending clinical pathways for new technologies and treatments,</li> <li>evaluating and expanding education and awareness activities provided to health care professionals, and</li> <li>reviewing and recommending methods for outreach and dissemination of educational resources.</li> </ul> <p>The commission must submit an operating plan to HHS and Congress within 90 days of its first meeting. The commission is terminated after it submits a final report, but not later than the end of FY2021.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
