<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="884" measure-id="id115hr884" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-06" update-date="2017-10-03">
<title>Children's Consignment Event Recognition Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr884v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-03">
<action-date>2017-02-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Children's Consignment Event Recognition Act of 2017 </b></p> <p> This bill amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to exclude from the meaning of "employee" subject to minimum wage and maximum hours requirements any individuals who volunteer their services at a children's consignment event with or without the assistance of a facilitator and meet certain other conditions.</p> <p> This bill defines "children's consignment event" to mean a sale or other event in which: (1) at least 90% of the aggregate fair market value of items offered for sale are children's or maternity clothing, and resale items are offered for sale on consignment; and (2) the event is held open to the public in a single location for the sale of goods for 8 or fewer sale days within any 30-day period.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
