<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1079" measure-id="id115hr1079" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-15" update-date="2017-05-01">
<title>Campus Gun Policy Transparency Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1079v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-01">
<action-date>2017-02-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Campus Gun Policy Transparency Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to modify campus security reporting requirements for an institution of higher education (IHE) that participates in federal student aid programs.</p> <p>Currently, an IHE must annually report certain crime statistics in the following categories: (1) criminal offenses; (2) criminal offenses motivated by bias (i.e., hate crimes); (3) domestic violence, dating violence, and stalking; and (4) arrests and referrals for disciplinary action. This bill expands the categories of reportable crime statistics to also include criminal offenses in which a firearm was present at the scene of the crime.</p> <p>Additionally, it requires an IHE to include, in its annual security report provided to students and employees, a statement of its current policy on concealed carry or open carry of firearms. </p> <p>An IHE must also disclose that policy on its website and in promotional materials. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
