<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2194" measure-id="id115hr2194" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-27" update-date="2017-12-21">
<title>Cigarette Smoking Reduction and Electronic Vapor Alternatives Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2194v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-21">
<action-date>2017-04-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Cigarette Smoking Reduction and Electronic Vapor Alternatives Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to authorize the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to regulate electronic cigarettes&nbsp;through regulation of e-liquids (solutions used in electronic&nbsp;cigarettes)&nbsp;and personal electronic vaporizers (products that&nbsp;convert e-liquids into inhalable vapor).</p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 0pt">E-liquids and personal electronic vaporizers are excluded from the definition of tobacco products.</p> <p>The bill sets forth requirements for the sale and manufacturing of e-liquids and personal electronic vaporizers including: (1) prohibiting sales to persons younger than 18, (2) establishing manufacturing standards, and (3) requiring certification of compliance with manufacturing standards.</p> <p>The FDA may prohibit advertising of e-liquids and vaporizers to minors. The Office of E-Liquid and Personal Vaporizer Standards Compliance is created in the FDA's Center for Tobacco Products and&nbsp;Tobacco Harm Reduction.</p> <p>State and local laws on e-liquids and personal electronic vaporizers are preempted by this bill.</p> <p>The FDA shall provide Congress&nbsp;a comparative health risk assessment of tobacco products and other nicotine delivery alternatives and rank them based on morbidity and mortality risk as compared to smoking cigarettes.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
