<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3746" measure-id="id115hr3746" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-12" update-date="2018-01-09">
<title>Business of Insurance Regulatory Reform Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3746v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-09">
<action-date>2017-09-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Business of Insurance Regulatory Reform Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to revise the authority of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) over activities regulated by a state insurance regulator. The CFPB may not enforce the Act against any person regulated by a state insurance regulator and offering a consumer financial product or service, to the extent that person is engaged in the business of insurance. If a person engaged in the business of insurance is regulated by a state insurance regulator but otherwise subject to the Act, the CFPB must construe its authority narrowly.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
