<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3159" measure-id="id115hr3159" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-29" update-date="2017-11-16">
<title>Family Business Preservation Estate Tax Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3159v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-16">
<action-date>2017-06-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Family Business Preservation Estate Tax Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the estate tax, to allow the value of the taxable estate to be reduced by the adjusted value of family-owned business interests that: (1) are included in determining the value of the gross estate, and (2) are acquired by or passed to an heir from the decedent. </p> <p>The deduction may not exceed the greater of: (1) the basic exclusion amount in effect for the calendar year that includes the death of the decedent ($5.49 million for 2017), or (2) the value of farmland which constitutes the family-owned business interest. </p> <p>The bill imposes a specified additional estate tax if, within 10 years of the decedent's death and before the heir's death: (1) material participation requirements are not met with respect to the family-owned business interest, (2) the heir disposes of any portion of the family-owned business interest (other than by a disposition to a member of the heir's family or through a qualified conservation contribution), (3) the heir loses U.S. citizenship or ceases to be a lawful permanent resident and the interest was not acquired or is not held in a qualified trust, or (4) the principal place of business of a trade or business of the family-owned business ceases to be located in the United States. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
