<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2219" measure-id="id115hr2219" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-27" update-date="2017-08-23">
<title>End Banking for Human Traffickers Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2219v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-23">
<action-date>2017-04-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>End Banking for Human Traffickers Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000 to add the Secretary of the Treasury as a member of the President's Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking. The task force must submit to Congress recommendations&nbsp;for the revision of&nbsp;anti-money laundering programs to specifically target money laundering related to human trafficking.</p> <p>The Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council&nbsp;must review and enhance, where necessary: (1) training and procedures to improve the ability of anti-money laundering programs to target human trafficking operations, and (2) procedures for referring potential human trafficking cases to the appropriate law enforcement agency.</p> <p>The Department of State must report on: (1)&nbsp;efforts to eliminate money laundering related to human trafficking; and (2) the number of investigations, arrests, indictments, and convictions in money laundering cases related to human trafficking.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
