<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2199" measure-id="id115hr2199" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-27" update-date="2018-01-03">
<title>Federal Land Asset Inventory Reform Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2199v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-03">
<action-date>2017-09-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Federal Land Asset Inventory Reform Act of 2017</b></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of the Interior to develop and maintain a current, accurate multipurpose cadastre (inventory) of federal real property to assist with federal land management activities, including, but not limited to, resource development and conservation, agricultural use, active forest management, environmental protection, and use of real property. Interior may enter into cost-sharing agreements with states to include any nonfederal lands in this cadastre. The federal share of any such agreement shall be up to 50% of the total cost to a state for the development of a cadastre of the nonfederal lands. </p> <p>Interior must submit a report, covering all cadastres and inventories authorized, operated, or maintained by all executive agencies, on: (1) existing real property inventories or any components of any cadastre; (2) consolidation of inventories and components; (3) the use of existing inventories and components of any cadastre; (4) cost savings that will be achieved; (5) a plan for implementation of this bill, including a cost estimate and the feasibility of using revenue from any authorized transactional activity to offset such costs; and (6) recommendations for legislation. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) Interior must: (1) make the cadastre available on the Internet in a graphically geo-enabled and searchable format; (2) ensure that the inventory required by this bill includes the identification of all lands and parcels suitable for disposal by Resource Management Plans conducted pursuant to the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976; and (3) prevent the disclosure of any parcels of land, buildings or facilities thereon, or related information, if this would impair or jeopardize national security or homeland defense.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2199v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-09">
<action-date>2017-04-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Federal Land Asset Inventory Reform Act of 2017</b></p> <p> This bill directs the Department of the Interior to develop and maintain a current, accurate multipurpose cadastre (inventory) of federal real property to assist with federal land management activities, including, but not limited to, resource development and conservation, agricultural use, active forest management, environmental protection, and use of real property. Interior may enter into cost-sharing agreements with states to include any nonfederal lands in this cadastre. The federal share of any such agreement shall be up to 50% of the total cost to a state for the development of a cadastre of the nonfederal lands. </p> <p>Interior shall report on: (1) existing executive agency real property inventories or any components of any cadastre; (2) consolidation of inventories and components; (3) the use of existing inventories and components of any cadastre; (4) cost savings that will be achieved; (5) a plan for implementation of this bill, including a cost estimate and the feasibility of using revenue from any authorized transactional activity to offset such costs; and (6) recommendations for legislation.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
