<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3822" measure-id="id115hr3822" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-25" update-date="2017-10-06">
<title>CBO Show Your Work Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3822v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-06">
<action-date>2017-09-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>CBO Show Your Work Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) to make available to Congress and the public each fiscal model, policy model, and data preparation routine that the CBO uses to estimate the costs and other fiscal, social, or economic effects of legislation. </p> <p>For each estimate of the costs and other fiscal effects of legislation, the CBO must also disclose, in a manner sufficient to permit replication by individuals not employed by the CBO, the data, programs, models, assumptions, and other details of the computations used to prepare the estimate. </p> <p>For data that is not required to be disclosed, the CBO must make available to Congress and the public: </p> <ul> <li> a complete list of all data variables for the data; </li> <li> descriptive statistics for all data variables for the data, to the extent that the descriptive statistics do not violate the rule against disclosure; </li> <li> a reference to the statute requiring that the data not be disclosed; and </li> <li> contact information for the individual or entity who has unrestricted access to the data. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
