<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3824" measure-id="id115hr3824" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-25" update-date="2018-03-23">
<title>Texas Flood Accountability Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3824v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-23">
<action-date>2017-09-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Texas Flood Accountability Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to submit to Congress and make publicly available a report with respect to dams, reservoirs, lakes, and other water retention facilities in Texas.</p> <p> The report shall include:</p> <ul> <li>for each such facility, the maximum water capacity that would necessitate an unplanned release of water, the water level at which the facility and each spillway of the facility will overflow, and plans to notify first responders, local officials, and communities of flood emergencies and the projected water levels during such emergencies;</li> <li>a description of steps taken by the Corps of Engineers to limit or prevent unplanned releases of water or overflows from such facilities;</li> <li>recommendations of the Corps for infrastructure improvements and dredging of existing facilities needed to limit or prevent such releases or overflows;</li> <li>plans to coordinate among such facilities during a flood emergency; and</li> <li>a list identifying the such facilities under the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission's jurisdiction, which shall includes a description of the process for lowering water levels at each facility. </li> </ul> <p>The Corps may exclude information from the report for national security purposes.</p> <p>Upon the Corps' request, a non-federal entity that owns, operates, or has jurisdiction over a covered facility shall provide the maximum water capacity that would necessitate an unplanned release of water, the water level at which the facility and each spillway of the facility will overflow, and plans to notify first responders, local officials, and communities of flood emergencies and the projected water levels during such emergencies. An entity shall not be eligible for federal financial assistance until it complies with such request.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
