<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2468" measure-id="id115hr2468" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-16" update-date="2017-12-13">
<title>Unifying DHS Intelligence Enterprise Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2468v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-13">
<action-date>2017-09-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Unifying DHS Intelligence Enterprise Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Department of Homeland Security's (DHS's) Chief Intelligence Officer (CIO), in coordination with intelligence components of DHS, the Office of the General Counsel, the Privacy Office, and the Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties, to develop and disseminate written DHS-wide guidance for the processing, analysis, production, and dissemination of homeland security information and terrorism information.</p> <p> The guidance shall include:</p> <ul> <li>a description of guiding principles and purposes of DHS's intelligence enterprise;</li> <li>a summary of the roles and responsibilities of each DHS intelligence component and component program in the processing, analysis, production, or dissemination of such information, including relevant authorities and restrictions applicable to each DHS intelligence component and programs of each such component;</li> <li>guidance for the processing, analysis, production, and dissemination of such information; and</li> <li>an assessment of how the dissemination of such information assists intelligence community and federal law enforcement entities in carrying out their missions.</li> </ul> <p> DHS shall, for each of the next five fiscal years, review and revise such guidance.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) DHS shall provide a staff having appropriate expertise and experience to assist the CIO.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2468v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-12">
<action-date>2017-05-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Unifying DHS Intelligence Enterprise Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Department of Homeland Security's (DHS's) Chief Intelligence Officer (CIO) to develop and disseminate written DHS-wide guidance for the processing, analysis, production, and dissemination of homeland security information and terrorism information.</p> <p> The guidance shall include:</p> <ul> <li>a description of guiding principles and purposes of DHS's intelligence enterprise;</li> <li>a summary of the roles and responsibilities of each DHS intelligence component and component program in the processing, analysis, production, or dissemination of such information;</li> <li>rules and regulations for the processing, analysis, production, and dissemination of such information; and</li> <li>an assessment of how the dissemination of such information assists intelligence community and federal law enforcement entities in carrying out their missions.</li> </ul> <p> DHS shall: (1) for each of the next five fiscal years, review and revise such guidance; and (2) provide a staff having appropriate expertise and experience to assist the CIO.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
