<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="264" measure-id="id115hr264" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-04" update-date="2017-06-26">
<title>United Nations Review and Accounting Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr264v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-26">
<action-date>2017-01-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>United Nations Review and Accounting Act</strong></p> <p>This bill prohibits funds from being obligated, expended, or transferred for assessed or voluntary U.N. contributions (or to any fund, program, or entity affiliated with the U.N.) until 180 days after the date on which all of the following reports have been submitted: </p> <ul> <li>the President's report on U.S. contributions to the U.N. relating to peacekeeping operations, </li> <li>the Office of Management and Budget's additional report on other U.S. contributions to the U.N., and </li> <li>the Government Accountability Office's comparative report on peacekeeping operations.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
