<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5377" measure-id="id115hr5377" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2018-03-21" update-date="2018-04-09">
<title>Creating An Online Platform For Instant 1099 Submissions Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr5377v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-04-09">
<action-date>2018-03-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong></strong><b>Creating An Online Platform For Instant 1099 Submissions Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to provide taxpayers with online access to IRS resources and guidance that will allow them to: (1) prepare and file Forms 1099, (2) prepare Forms 1099 for distribution to recipients other than the IRS, and (3) create and maintain necessary taxpayer records. </p> <p>The IRS must ensure that the online services required by this bill: (1) are a supplement to, and not a replacement for, other services provided to taxpayers by the IRS; and (2) comply with security standards developed by the National Institute of Standards and Technology. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
