<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2259" measure-id="id115hr2259" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-01" update-date="2017-11-28">
<title>Sam Farr Peace Corps Enhancement Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2259v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-28">
<action-date>2017-05-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Sam Farr Peace Corps Enhancement Act</strong></p> <p>This bill increases the monthly pay rate for Peace Corps volunteers.</p> <p>The Peace Corps shall provide initial medical care to a former volunteer for a service-related condition for 180 days after termination of service, which period may be extended under specified circumstances.</p> <p>The bill grants the government jurisdiction over, and imposes penalties upon, persons who commit certain crimes outside of the United States against a volunteer.</p> <p>The Peace Corps Act is amended to authorize the designation of a position as a critical management support position if the position requires specialized technical or professional skills and knowledge of Peace <ich shall > Corps operations. </p> <p>The President shall ensure that each overseas post has appropriate medical services, including by detailing to such a post the licensed medical staff of other U.S. agencies.</p> <p>Each volunteer applicant shall be provided with information regarding crime and health risks and volunteer satisfaction with respect to the country in which the applicant has been invited to serve.</p> <p>The Office of Victim Advocacy in the Peace Corps headquarters is made permanent.</p> <p>The bill: (1) expands membership of the Sexual Assault Advisory Council, (2) requires at least one council member to have mental health field expertise, and (3) extends the council through October 1, 2023. </p> <p>The President shall conduct annual volunteer surveys through September 30, 2023 (currently through September 30, 2018).</p> <p>The Inspector General of the Peace Corps may hire an expert, consultant, or organization without regard to certain daily salary requirements.</p> <p> The Peace Corps shall periodically report to Congress on volunteer access to health care benefits.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
