<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1186" measure-id="id115hr1186" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-16" update-date="2017-06-21">
<title>Investing in America's Small Manufacturers Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1186v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-21">
<action-date>2017-02-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Investing in America's Small Manufacturers Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Small Business Act to authorize the Small Business Administration (SBA) to guarantee 90% of a loan to a small business manufacturing concern.</p> <p>The SBA may not collect a guarantee fee for a loan of not more than $350,000. For loans exceeding that amount, the fee shall be 50% of the guarantee fee that the SBA would otherwise collect for the loan.</p> <p>The SBA must provide training to small manufacturers in obtaining SBA assistance, including on the application process and partnering with participating lenders.</p> <p>This bill authorizes the SBA and its partners to establish partnerships to facilitate outreach to small manufacturers with respect to the application process for SBA loan guarantees.</p> <p>A state or local development company's debenture issued to a small manufacturer for an SBA loan guarantee may not exceed 50% of the project's cost, subject to certain exceptions.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
