<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4200" measure-id="id115hr4200" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-11-01" update-date="2018-03-01">
<title>Healthcare Market Certainty and Mandate Relief Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4200v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-01">
<action-date>2017-11-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Healthcare Market Certainty and Mandate Relief Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill appropriates such sums as necessary to pay through health care plan year 2019 the cost-sharing reductions authorized in the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act. (A cost-sharing reduction&nbsp;is a&nbsp;discount that lowers the amount&nbsp;an individual&nbsp;pays for deductibles, copayments, and coinsurance; the federal government pays the difference directly to insurers.) The bill excludes payments to insurers that cover abortions other than abortions necessary to save the life of the pregnant woman or abortions of a pregnancy resulting from rape or incest.</p> <p>The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to suspend for 2017-2021 the individual mandate to maintain minimum health care coverage.</p> <p>The bill suspends the employer health care mandate for 2015-2017, thereby exempting employers from penalties for failing to provide mandated coverage during that time period.</p> <p>The bill increases the monthly contribution limit for health savings accounts through 2022.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
