<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3694" measure-id="id115hr3694" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-07" update-date="2018-03-24">
<title>Future of the Nunn-Lugar Program Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3694v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-24">
<action-date>2017-09-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Future of the Nunn-Lugar Program Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to: (1) seek to enter into an agreement with a federally funded research and development center to assess requirements for cooperative threat reduction, and (2) provide such center with access to necessary information and resources. </p> <p>The center shall provide DOD with an interim and a final report that shall include: (1) a discussion of the requirements and capabilities necessary for reducing the threats of nuclear, chemical, and biological weapons; (2) identification of capability gaps for cooperative threat reduction efforts; (3) recommendations for actions to modernize the DOD's Cooperative Threat Reduction Program; and (4) recommendations to modernize the command and control enterprise and the role of the Director of the Defense Threat Reduction Agency. </p> <p>The Cooperative Threat Reduction Program, with respect to foreign countries, is intended to facilitate the elimination and the safe and secure transportation and storage of nuclear, chemical, biological, or other weapons and prevent their proliferation. </p> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
