<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2686" measure-id="id115hr2686" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-25" update-date="2018-02-07">
<title>To codify the Small Business Administration's Growth Accelerator Fund Competition, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2686v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-07">
<action-date>2017-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Small Business Act to codify provisions establishing the Growth Accelerator Fund Competition program, under which the Small Business Administration (SBA) shall award prizes competitively to covered entities (private entities that are incorporated in and maintain a primary place of business in the United States) that:</p> <ul> <li>assist small business concerns in accessing capital, mentors, and networking opportunities; and</li> <li> advise small business concerns, including on market analysis, company strategy, revenue growth, and securing funding.</li> </ul> The SBA must develop metrics to evaluate the the program's effectiveness and benefits to the people of the United States that: (1) are science-based and statistically driven, (2) reflect the SBA mission, and (3) include factors relating to the program's economic impact.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
