<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2493" measure-id="id115hr2493" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-17" update-date="2018-03-29">
<title>Conflicts from Political Fundraising Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2493v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-29">
<action-date>2017-05-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Conflicts from Political Fundraising Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to revise financial disclosure requirements for federal personnel, including: (1) the disclosure of contributions made or solicited by, or on behalf of, individuals nominated or appointed to high level executive positions or to positions of a confidential or policymaking character to political action committees and tax-exempt social welfare or business organizations; and (2) the disclosure of certain gifts to appointees, their spouses, or dependent children.</p> <p>The Office of Government Ethics shall, upon request, provide to the Chairman or Ranking Member of a House or Senate committee or subcommittee with jurisdiction over the agency to which an individual has been nominated or appointed to a covered position (certain Executive Schedule or Senior Executive Service positions) or is serving in a covered position, each financial disclosure report filed by such individual and any ethics agreement entered into between the agency and the individual.</p> <p>The office shall issue rules on how an executive branch agency shall address conflicts of interest identified in disclosures through ethics agreements between the agency and its appointees.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
