<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1495" measure-id="id115hr1495" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-10" update-date="2017-10-06">
<title>Fair Treatment for Families of Veterans Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1495v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-06">
<action-date>2017-03-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Fair Treatment for Families of Veterans Act</strong></p> <p>This bill changes the effective date for reductions or discontinuances of Department of Veterans Affairs dependency and indemnity compensation by reason of the death of a payee from the last day of the month before death to the last day of the month of death.</p> <p> A veteran's surviving spouse who receives both dependency/indemnity compensation and service- or non-service-connected disability/death payments for the month of the veteran's death shall be entitled to the greater of the two payments. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
