<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3764" measure-id="id115hr3764" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-13" update-date="2017-09-21">
<title>Little Shell Tribe of Chippewa Indians Restoration Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3764v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-21">
<action-date>2017-09-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Little Shell Tribe of Chippewa Indians Restoration Act of 2017</b></p> <p> This bill extends federal recognition to the Little Shell Tribe of Chippewa Indians of Montana. The tribe and its members become eligible for services and benefits provided by the United States to federally recognized tribes and their members, without regard to the existence of a reservation or the location of the residence of any member. </p> <p>The service area of the tribe is considered to be the area comprised of Blaine, Cascade, Glacier, and Hill Counties, Montana.</p> <p> The tribe, as a condition of receiving recognition, services, and benefits, must submit to the Department of the Interior, and maintain, a membership roll. </p> <p>Interior must take into trust for the benefit of the tribe 200 acres of land within the tribe's service area to be used for a tribal land base. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
