<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4602" measure-id="id115hr4602" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-12-07" update-date="2018-03-01">
<title>Defending Special Education Students and Families Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4602v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-01">
<action-date>2017-12-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Defending Special Education Students and Families Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA)&nbsp;to authorize appropriations for grants to assist states in providing special education and related services to children with disabilities. For FY2018-FY2022, the bill authorizes specified amounts. For FY2023 and each subsequent fiscal year, the bill authorizes amounts using a specified formula.</p> <p>The bill also amends the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to modify the discretionary spending limits for FY2018-FY2021. For each fiscal year, the bill decreases the limit for security spending by a specified amount and increases the limit for nonsecurity spending by the same amount.&nbsp;The&nbsp;nonsecurity spending increases are the same amounts as are authorized in the&nbsp;bill&nbsp;for additional funding under the IDEA in&nbsp;those fiscal years.&nbsp;</p> <p class="MsoNormal" style="MARGIN: 0in 0in 0pt"></p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
