<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4313" measure-id="id115hr4313" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-11-08" update-date="2018-02-14">
<title>Fair Credit Reporting for Servicemembers Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4313v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-14">
<action-date>2017-11-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> <b>Fair Credit Reporting for Servicemembers Act</b> <p>This bill amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to: (1) specify that to be considered an active duty military consumer, a consumer must be assigned away from the usual duty station for a period of at least 90 days, and (2) allow a consumer to provide proof to a consumer reporting agency that an adverse credit report item occurred while on active duty.</p> <p>The bill requires a consumer reporting agency to provide an active duty military consumer's relevant active duty status on adverse credit report items. A consumer reporting agency must issue alerts to an active duty military consumer regarding negative information received about that consumer.</p> <p>The bill expresses the sense of Congress that users of consumer reports should take into account active duty military status when evaluating a consumer's creditworthiness.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
