<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1800" measure-id="id115hr1800" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-30" update-date="2018-04-03">
<title>To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to transfer certain Federal land to facilitate scientific research supporting Federal space and defense programs.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1800v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-04-03">
<action-date>2017-12-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to convey to the Utah State University Research Foundation, without consideration, a specified parcel of real property, including improvements, located outside the boundaries of the Wasatch-Cache National Forest in Rich County, Utah, for the purpose of permitting the foundation to use the property for scientific and educational purposes. </p> <p>Conveyed property not being used in accordance with the purposes of the conveyance shall revert to and become the property of the United States, and the federal government shall have the right of immediate entry onto it. </p> <p>USDA shall require the foundation to cover the costs (except any costs for environmental remediation of the property) incurred by USDA, or to reimburse USDA for the actual costs incurred, to carry out such conveyance. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1800v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-31">
<action-date>2017-03-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill directs the Department of Agriculture to convey to the Utah State University Research Foundation, without consideration, a parcel of real property of approximately 80 acres located outside the boundaries of the Wasatch-Cache National Forest in Rich County, Utah. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
