<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="843" measure-id="id115hr843" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-03" update-date="2017-07-20">
<title>See Something, Say Something About Violent Behavior Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr843v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-20">
<action-date>2017-02-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>See Something, Say Something About Violent Behavior Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill grants immunity from civil liability to an employer who reports, to a potential future employer, the violent or threatening behavior of an employee or former employee. The report must be made in good faith and based on objectively reasonable suspicion.</p> <p>Also, it grants immunity from civil liability to a potential employer who responds, with a reasonable action in good faith, to a report of violent or threatening behavior by an employee or potential employee. <p>Finally, the bill grants qualified immunity from civil liability to a federal, state, or local law enforcement officer or to an officer, employee, or agent of the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Transportation, or the Department of Justice who responds with a reasonable action in good faith to a report of violent or threatening behavior. <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
