<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3149" measure-id="id115hr3149" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-29" update-date="2017-07-17">
<title>Renewable Chemicals Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3149v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-17">
<action-date>2017-06-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Renewable Chemicals Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a business-related tax credit for the production of renewable chemicals. The bill defines "renewable chemical" as any chemical that: (1) is produced in the United States from renewable biomass; (2) is sold or used for the production of chemical products, polymers, plastics, or formulated products or as chemicals, polymers, plastics, or formulated products; (3) has a biobased content of not less than 95%; (4) is the product of, or reliant upon, biological or thermal conversion of renewable biomass; (5) is not sold or used for the production of any food, feed, or fuel; and (6) is not a combination of certain specified renewable chemicals. </p> <p>The bill also allows a tax credit for investment in renewable chemical production facilities.</p> <p>The bill requires the Department of the Treasury to establish a program to allocate renewable chemical tax credit amounts to eligible taxpayers and imposes an aggregate limit on the amount of credits that may be allocated to not more than $500 million during the 5-year period after enactment of this bill. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
