<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1188" measure-id="id115hr1188" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-16" update-date="2017-12-28">
<title>Adam Walsh Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1188v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-28">
<action-date>2017-05-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Adam Walsh Reauthorization Act of </b><b>2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act to reauthorize through FY2022 the Sex Offender Management Assistance program.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill reauthorizes through FY2022 the activities of the U.S. Marshals Service to locate and apprehend sex offenders who violate sex offender registration requirements.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) It reduces from 25 years to 15 years the required registration period for certain juvenile delinquent sex offenders who maintain a clean record.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) It allows a state, Indian tribe, or territory to exempt from disclosure on a public website information about juvenile delinquent sex offenders.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) The bill specifies how to calculate the allocation of Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant (JAG) program funds for local governments after a state's JAG funds are reduced for failure to comply with sex offender registration and notification standards.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) It amends the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 to require the Department of Justice (DOJ) to include additional data in its annual report on the enforcement of sex offender registration requirements.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) The bill amends the federal criminal code to broaden the duties of probation and pretrial services officers to include, when directed by a court, supervision of a sex offender conditionally released from civil commitment subject to court-ordered compliance with a prescribed regimen of medical, psychiatric, or psychological treatment.</p> <p>(Sec. 9) It extends the statute of limitations for a minor victim of a federal sex offense to file a civil action to 10 years (currently, 3 years) from the date such individual reaches age 18.</p> <p>(Sec. 10) It authorizes DOJ to provide technical assistance to tribal governments to promote access to federal criminal information databases. DOJ's Working Capital Fund may be reimbursed by federally recognized tribes for such technical assistance.</p> <p>(Sec. 11) The bill allows a state, Indian tribe, or territory to establish an alternative method for a registered sex offender to comply with the in-person verification requirement. DOJ must approve an alternative verification method before it is implemented. <p>(Sec. 12) It limits the aggravated sex abuse offenses that trigger sex offender registration requirements for a juvenile at least 14 years old who is adjudicated delinquent for a comparable or more severe sex offense. <p>(Sec. 13) The National Institute of Justice must report to Congress on the public safety impact, recidivism, and collateral consequences of long-term registration of juvenile sex offenders.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1188v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-03">
<action-date>2017-02-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Adam Walsh Reauthorization Act of </b><b>2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act to:</p> <ul> <li>reauthorize through FY2022 the Sex Offender Management Assistance program;</li> <li>reauthorize through FY2022 the activities of the U.S. Marshals Service to locate and apprehend sex offenders who violate sex offender registration requirements;</li> <li>reduce from 25 years to 15 years the required registration period for certain juvenile delinquent sex offenders who maintain a clean record;</li> <li>allow a state, Indian tribe, or territory to exempt from disclosure on a public website information about juvenile delinquent sex offenders;</li> <li>specify how to calculate the allocation of Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant (JAG) program funds for local governments after a state's JAG funds are reduced for failure to comply with sex offender registration and notification standards; and</li> <li>establish an alternative method for complying with the in-person verification requirement.</li> </ul> <p>It amends the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 to require the Department of Justice to include additional data in its annual report on the enforcement of sex offender registration requirements.</p> <p>The bill amends the federal criminal code to:</p> <ul> <li>modify the duties of probation and pretrial services officers to include, when directed by a court, supervision of a sex offender conditionally released from civil commitment subject to court-ordered compliance with a prescribed regimen of medical, psychiatric, or psychological treatment; and</li> <li>extend the statute of limitations for a minor victim of a federal sex offense to file a civil action to 10 years (currently 3 years) from the date such individual reaches age 18.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
