<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2936" measure-id="id115hr2936" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-20" update-date="2018-03-15">
<title>Resilient Federal Forests Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2936v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-15">
<action-date>2017-06-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Resilient Federal Forests Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill shall apply whenever the Department concerned, either the Department of Agriculture for National Forest System (NFS) lands or the Department of the Interior for public lands, prepares an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement pursuant to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) for specified forest management activities, including those that: </p> <ul> <li>will occur on lands identified as suitable for timber production; or </li> <li>will occur on a landscape-scale area designated by the Department concerned as part of an insect and disease treatment program on NSF land pursuant to the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003, notwithstanding whether such activity is initiated before September 30, 2018.</li> </ul> <p>In such an environmental assessment or environmental impact statement, the Department concerned shall study, develop, and describe only these two alternatives:</p> <ul> <li>the forest management activity, and </li> <li>the alternative of no action. </li> </ul> <p>In the case of the alternative of no action, the Department concerned shall evaluate: </p> <ul> <li>the effect of no action on forest health, habitat diversity, wildfire potential, insect and disease potential, and timber production; and</li> <li>the implications of a resulting decline in forest health, loss of habitat diversity, wildfire, or insect or disease infestation on domestic water supply in the project area, wildlife habitat loss, and other economic and social factors. </li> </ul> <p>The bill establishes categorical exclusions regarding certain other forest management actions. </p> <p> A process is established for declaration of a major disaster for wildfire on federal lands managed by specified federal land management agencies. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
