<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3084" measure-id="id115hr3084" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-27" update-date="2017-11-07">
<title>Empowering Employees through Stock Ownership Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3084v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-07">
<action-date>2017-06-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Empowering Employees through Stock Ownership Act </b></p> <p> This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an employee to elect to defer, for income tax purposes, income attributable to certain stock transferred to the employee by an employer. </p> <p>The employee may defer the inclusion of income from the stock until the year that includes the earliest of the dates on which: </p> <ul> <li> the stock becomes transferable; </li> <li> the employee becomes an excluded employee; </li> <li> stock of the corporation becomes readily tradable on an established securities market; </li> <li>seven years have passed after the rights of the employee in the stock are transferable or are not subject to a substantial risk of forfeiture, whichever occurs earlier; or </li> <li>the employee revokes the election with respect to the stock. </li> </ul> <p>The stock must meet specified requirements and be transferred to the employee from an eligible corporation in connection with the performance of services as an employee. </p> <p>A corporation is eligible if: (1) no stock of the corporation or a predecessor is readily tradable on an established securities market during any preceding year; and (2) it has a written plan under which at least 80% of certain employees are granted stock options, or restricted stock units, with the same rights and privileges to receive qualified stock.</p> <p>Employees are excluded if they: (1) are a 1% owner, the chief executive officer, or the chief financial officer of the corporation or have been at any time during the 10 preceding calendar years; (2) are a family member of the specified individuals; or (3) have been one of the four highest compensated officers of the corporation during any of the 10 preceding taxable years. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
