<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1493" measure-id="id115hr1493" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-10" update-date="2017-05-03">
<title>ADA Lawsuit Clarification Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1493v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-03">
<action-date>2017-03-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>ADA Lawsuit Clarification Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 to prohibit an aggrieved person from commencing a civil action for discrimination based on the failure to remove a structural barrier to entry into an existing public accommodation unless the owner or operator of such accommodation: (1) is provided a written notice specific enough to identify such barrier; and (2) has either failed, within 60 days after receipt of notice, to provide the aggrieved person with a written description outlining improvements that will be made to remove such barrier or failed, within 120 days after providing the description of improvements, to remove such barrier.</p> <p> An owner or operator may not be held civilly or criminally liable for failing to remove a structural barrier before the expiration of a 120-day that begins after the aggrieved person has been provided the description of improvements that will be made. </p> <p>The Department of Justice must make technical assistance publications relating to compliance with this bill available in all languages commonly used by owners and operators.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
