<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4392" measure-id="id115hr4392" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-11-14" update-date="2018-02-22">
<title>To provide that the provision of the Medicare Program: Hospital Outpatient Prospective Payment and Ambulatory Surgical Center Payment Systems and Quality Reporting Programs final regulation relating to changes in the payment amount for certain drugs and biologicals purchased under the 340B drug discount program shall have no force or effect, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4392v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-22">
<action-date>2017-11-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill nullifies&nbsp;a rule finalized by the&nbsp;Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid&nbsp;Services on November 13, 2017,&nbsp;that modifies payment under Medicare for certain drugs purchased&nbsp;through the 340B discount program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
