<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1865" measure-id="id115hr1865" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-03" update-date="2018-03-22">
<title>Allow States and Victims to Fight Online Sex Trafficking Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1865v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-22">
<action-date>2018-02-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Allow States and Victims to Fight Online Sex Trafficking Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill expresses the sense of Congress that section 230 of the Communications Act of 1934 was not intended to provide legal protection to websites that unlawfully promote and facilitate prostitution and websites that facilitate traffickers in advertising the sale of unlawful sex acts with sex trafficking victims. Section 230 limits the legal liability of interactive computer service providers or users for content they publish that was created by others.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill amends the federal criminal code to add a new section that imposes penalties&#8212;a fine, a prison term of up to 10 years, or both&#8212;on a person who, using a facility or means of interstate or foreign commerce, owns, manages, or operates an interactive computer service (or attempts or conspires to do so) to promote or facilitate the prostitution of another person. </p> <p>Additionally, it establishes enhanced penalties&#8212;a fine, a prison term of up to 25 years, or both&#8212;for a person who commits the offense in one of the following aggravating circumstances: (1) promotes or facilitates the prostitution of five or more persons, or (2) acts with reckless disregard that such conduct contributes to sex trafficking.</p> <p>A person injured by an aggravated offense may recover damages and attorneys' fees in a federal civil action.</p> <p>A court must order mandatory restitution, in addition to other criminal or civil penalties, for an aggravated offense in which a person acts with reckless disregard that such conduct contributes to sex trafficking. </p> <p>A defendant may assert, as an affirmative defense, that the promotion or facilitation of prostitution is legal in the jurisdiction where it was targeted. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to declare that section 230 does not limit: (1) a federal civil claim for conduct that constitutes sex trafficking, (2) a federal criminal charge for conduct that constitutes sex trafficking, or (3) a state criminal charge for conduct that promotes or facilitates prostitution in violation of this bill.</p> <p>The amendments apply regardless of whether alleged conduct occurs before, on, or after this bill's enactment. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) The bill amends the federal criminal code to define a phrase related to the prohibition on sex trafficking. Currently, it a crime to knowingly benefit from participation in a venture that engages in sex trafficking. This bill defines &quot;participation in a venture&quot; to mean knowingly assisting, supporting, or facilitating a sex trafficking violation.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) A state may file a federal civil action to enforce federal sex trafficking violations.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) This section states that this bill does not limit federal or state civil actions or criminal prosecutions that are not preempted by section 230 of the Communications Act of 1934.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) The Government Accountability Office must report to Congress on information related to damages and mandatory restitution for aggravated offenses under this bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1865v18" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-26">
<action-date>2018-02-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended, Part I</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Allow States and Victims to Fight Online Sex Trafficking Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill expresses the sense of Congress that section 230 of the Communications Act of 1934 was not intended to provide legal protection to websites that unlawfully promote and facilitate prostitution and contribute to sex trafficking. Section 230 limits the legal liability of interactive computer service providers or users for content they publish that was created by others.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill amends the federal criminal code to add a new section that imposes penalties&#8212;a fine, a prison term of up to 10 years, or both&#8212;on a person who uses or operates (or attempts to use or operate) a facility or means of interstate or foreign commerce to promote or facilitate the prostitution of another person. </p> <p>Additionally, it establishes enhanced penalties&#8212;a fine, a prison term of up to 25 years, or both&#8212;for a person who uses or operates a facility of interstate or foreign commerce to promote or facilitate the prostitution of another person in one of the following aggravating circumstances: (1) promoting or facilitating the prostitution of five or more persons, or (2) acting with reckless disregard that such conduct contributes to sex trafficking.</p> <p>A court must order mandatory restitution, in addition to other criminal or civil penalties. </p> <p>A person injured by an aggravated offense may recover damages and attorneys' fees in a federal civil action.</p> <p>A defendant may assert, as an affirmative defense, that the promotion or facilitation of prostitution is legal in the jurisdiction where it was targeted. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit construing section 230 to limit state criminal charges for conduct: (1) that promotes or facilitates prostitution in violation of this bill, or (2) that constitutes child sex trafficking.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) Additionally, it prohibits construing this bill to limit federal or state civil actions or criminal prosecutions that are not preempted by section 230 of the Communications Act of 1934.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1865v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-04">
<action-date>2017-04-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Allow States and Victims to Fight Online Sex Trafficking Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to specify that communications decency provisions protecting providers or users of interactive computer services from liability for the private blocking or screening of offensive material shall not be construed to impair the enforcement of, or limit availability of victim restitution or civil remedies under, state or federal criminal or civil laws relating to sexual exploitation of children or sex trafficking. </p> <p>The bill amends the federal criminal code to specify that the violation for benefiting from &quot;participation in a venture&quot; engaged in sex trafficking of children, or by force, fraud, or coercion, includes knowing or reckless conduct by any person or entity and by any means that furthers or in any way aids or abets the violation.</p> <p>A provider of an interactive computer service that publishes information provided by an information content provider with reckless disregard that the information is in furtherance of a sex trafficking offense shall be subject to a criminal fine or imprisonment for not more than 20 years.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
