<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2700" measure-id="id115hr2700" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-25" update-date="2017-09-27">
<title>Workforce Development Investment Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2700v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-27">
<action-date>2017-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Workforce Development Investment Act of 2017 </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow employers a business-related tax credit of $5,000 for each community college, other institution of higher education, or area career and technical education school engaged in a qualified partnership with the employer. The bill allows a maximum credit of $20,000 in any taxable year. </p> <p>Within six months of the enactment of this bill, the Department of Education must define the term &quot;qualified partnership.&quot; The term must include a partnership through which an employer: (1) collaborates with an educational institution to help develop curriculum in order to improve workforce development and job training for students; (2) helps provide instruction to students in the classroom; and (3) provides internships, apprenticeships, or other similar educational opportunities in the workplace for students. </p> <p>This bill also allows employers a worker training tax credit equal to the lesser of: 50% of the job training program expenditures for a full-time employee participating in a qualified training program, or $5,000. A &quot;qualified training program&quot; is: (1) a qualified partnership, or (2) an apprenticeship program registered and certified with the Department of Labor under the National Apprenticeship Act. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
