<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1365" measure-id="id115hr1365" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-06" update-date="2017-07-19">
<title>Department of Homeland Security Acquisition Innovation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1365v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-19">
<action-date>2017-03-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on March 20, 2017. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><strong>Department of Homeland Security Acquisition Innovation Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the Department of Homeland Security's (DHS's) Under Secretary for Management to:</p> <ul> <li> designate an individual within DHS to manage DHS acquisition innovation efforts,</li> <li> test emerging acquisition best practicess,</li> <li> develop and distribute best practices and lessons learned regarding acquisition innovations, </li> <li> establish metrics to measure the effectiveness of acquisition innovation efforts, and</li> <li>determine impacts of acquisition innovation efforts on the private sector by obtaining feedback from it and incorporating such feedback into future acquisition innovation efforts.</li> </ul> <p>The bill requires DHS, by 90 days after it submits the annual budget justification for DHS for each of FY2018-FY2022, to provide information to specified congressional committees on:</p> <ul> <li>emerging acquisition best practices that were tested within DHS,</li> <li>efforts to distribute best practices and lessons learned within DHS,</li> <li>utilization of best practices by DHS components,</li> <li>performance as measured by the metrics established under this bill,</li> <li>outcomes of efforts to distribute best practices and lessons learned within DHS,</li> <li>impacts of the utilization of innovative acquisition mechanisms by DHS on the private sector,</li> <li>the criteria used to identify specific acquisition programs or activities to be included in acquisition innovation efforts and the outcomes of such programs or activities, and</li> <li>recommendations to enhance acquisition innovation in DHS.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1365v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-19">
<action-date>2017-03-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Department of Homeland Security Acquisition Innovation Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the Department of Homeland Security's (DHS's) Under Secretary for Management to:</p> <ul> <li> designate an individual within DHS to manage DHS acquisition innovation efforts,</li> <li> test emerging acquisition best practicess,</li> <li> develop and distribute best practices and lessons learned regarding acquisition innovations, </li> <li> establish metrics to measure the effectiveness of acquisition innovation efforts, and</li> <li>determine impacts of acquisition innovation efforts on the private sector by obtaining feedback from it and incorporating such feedback into future acquisition innovation efforts.</li> </ul> <p>The bill requires DHS, by 90 days after it submits the annual budget justification for DHS for each of FY2018-FY2022, to provide information to specified congressional committees on:</p> <ul> <li>emerging acquisition best practices that were tested within DHS,</li> <li>efforts to distribute best practices and lessons learned within DHS,</li> <li>utilization of best practices by DHS components,</li> <li>performance as measured by the metrics established under this bill,</li> <li>outcomes of efforts to distribute best practices and lessons learned within DHS,</li> <li>impacts of the utilization of innovative acquisition mechanisms by DHS on the private sector,</li> <li>the criteria used to identify specific acquisition programs or activities to be included in acquisition innovation efforts and the outcomes of such programs or activities, and</li> <li>recommendations to enhance acquisition innovation in DHS.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1365v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-19">
<action-date>2017-03-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Department of Homeland Security Acquisition Innovation Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the Department of Homeland Security's (DHS's) Under Secretary for Management to:</p> <ul> <li> designate an individual within DHS to manage DHS acquisition innovation efforts;</li> <li> test emerging acquisition best practices; </li> <li> develop and distribute best practices and lessons learned regarding acquisition innovation; and </li> <li> establish metrics to measure the effectiveness of acquisition innovation efforts, including with respect to collaboration with the private sector. </li> </ul> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
