<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1221" measure-id="id115hr1221" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-27" update-date="2017-06-07">
<title>International Fund for Israeli-Palestinian Peace Authorization Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1221v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-07">
<action-date>2017-02-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>International Fund for Israeli-Palestinian Peace Authorization Act of 2017</strong></p> <p> This bill urges the President to make every effort, in conjunction with the government of Israel, the Palestinian Authority, and the international community, to establish an International Fund for Israeli-Palestinian Peace to promote and support contact, cooperation, dialogue, shared community building, peaceful coexistence, joint economic development, and reconciliation between Israelis and Palestinians.</p> <p>The bill authorizes appropriations for U.S. contributions to the fund following the committee of jurisdictions' agreement to the structure of the fund and its board.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
