<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1729" measure-id="id115hr1729" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-27" update-date="2017-05-04">
<title>Statutes at Large Modernization Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1729v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-04">
<action-date>2017-03-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Statutes at Large Modernization Act</b></p> <p> This bill directs the Government Publishing Office (GPO) to make the Statutes at Large available to the public at no cost on a website in a searchable, non-proprietary format.</p> <p>The GPO must ensure that the searchable online edition is prepared in coordination with the National Archives and Records Administration and congressional support offices that develop formatting conventions used for enrolled bills and other legislative materials.</p> <p> The bill amends the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1996 to require relevant Statutes at Large electronic information made available by the GPO to be incorporated into the Library of Congress's legislative information retrieval system. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
