<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1392" measure-id="id115hr1392" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-07" update-date="2017-11-20">
<title>TechCorps Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1392v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-20">
<action-date>2017-03-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><STRONG>TechCorps Act</STRONG></p> <p>This bill requires the Office of Personnel Management to establish and maintain an electronic database of job vacancies across the government relating to information technology (IT). The database shall be published on the USAJobs website and shall describe such vacancies as TechCorps-eligible positions.</p> <p>The National and Community Service Act of 1990 is amended to direct the Corporation for National and Community Service to enter into an agreement with a federal agency to carry out a TechCorps program, under which:</p> <UL> <LI>individuals apply to service as TechCorps members prior to or after graduating from a program of study at an institution of education leading to a degree or certificate relating to IT, <LI>individuals are recruited in their last academic year, <LI>TechCorps members commit to employment with the federal agency in an IT-related job for at least two years, and <LI>individuals accepting such employment shall be TechCorps members for up to four years. </LI> </UL> <p>The Higher Education Act of 1965 is amended to provide that a borrower of a loan under the William D. Ford Federal Direct Loan Program shall be eligible to defer payments for any period during which the borrower is serving as a TechCorps member. The Department of Education shall carry out a program of canceling a specified amount of the loan obligation amount of borrowers who: (1) serve as a TechCorps member for at least two years, and (2) are not in default.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office shall study and report to Congress on projected staffing needs for IT-related jobs in the federal government over the next ten years.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
