<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2847" measure-id="id115hr2847" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-08" update-date="2018-03-06">
<title>Improving Services for Older Youth in Foster Care Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2847v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-06">
<action-date>2017-06-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Improving Services for Older Youth in Foster Care Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act to revise the John H. Chafee Foster Care Independence Program to:</p> <ul> <li>authorize states electing to extend foster care eligibility up to age 21 to extend assistance and services to youths who have aged out of foster care but have not yet reached age 23, </li> <li>authorize redistribution of unexpended amounts among states that apply for additional program funds, </li> <li>allow states to make individuals eligible for participation in the educational and training voucher program through age 25 (but no more than 5 years), and </li> <li>modify congressional reporting requirements. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2847v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-22">
<action-date>2017-06-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> <b>Improving Services for Older Youth in Foster Care Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act to revise the John H. Chafee Foster Care Independence Program to:</p> <ul> <li>authorize states electing to extend foster care eligibility up to age 21 to extend assistance and services to youths who have aged out of foster care but have not yet reached age 23, </li> <li>authorize redistribution of unexpended amounts among states that apply for additional program funds, </li> <li>allow states to make individuals eligible for participation in the educational and training voucher program through age 25 (but no more than 5 years), and </li> <li>modify congressional reporting requirements. </li> </ul> <UL> </UL>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
