<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3922" measure-id="id115hr3922" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-03" update-date="2018-03-12">
<title>CHAMPIONING HEALTHY KIDS Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3922v18" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-12">
<action-date>2017-10-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended, Part I</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Community Health And Medical Professionals Improve Our Nation Act of 2017 or the CHAMPION Act</strong></p> <p>TITLE I--EXTENSION OF PUBLIC HEALTH PROGRAMS</p> <p>(Sec. 101) This bill amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to extend funding through FY2019 for community health centers and the National Health Service Corps. </p> <p>Health centers that serve medically underserved populations may receive supplemental grant funds to increase access to primary care services.</p> <p>In awarding health center operating grants, special consideration may be given to a new center that&nbsp;is located in a sparely populated area or in an area that has a higher level of unmet need.</p> <p>Loan guarantees are no longer made to assist health centers to plan and&nbsp;develop a managed care network or to plan and develop practice management networks.</p> <p>The bill provides funds for FY2018 to support the participation of health centers in the All of Us Research Program&nbsp;in the National Institutes of Health's&nbsp;Precision Medicine Initiative.</p> <p>(Sec. 102) The bill amends the Public Health Service Act to extend funding through FY2019 for type I diabetes research and the prevention and treatment of diabetes&nbsp;in Native Americans.</p> <p>(Sec. 103) The bill increases and extends funding through FY2019 for teaching health centers that sponsor graduate medical residency training programs. Priority is given to teaching health centers that serve health professional shortage areas, serve medically underserved communities, or are in rural areas.</p> <p>The Department of Health and Human Services must report on expenses associated with graduate medical residency training programs.</p><p>(Sec. 104) The bill amends the Social Security Act to increase and extend funding through FY2019 for family-to-family health information centers, which assist families of children with disabilities or special health needs.</p> <p>(Sec. 105) The bill creates, and makes appropriations in FY2018 and FY2019 for, the Youth Empowerment Program. The program shall fund allotments to states or other entities to implement education exclusively&nbsp;about sexual risk avoidance (voluntarily refraining from sexual activity). Up to 20% of&nbsp;an allotment may be used to build evidence for sexual&nbsp;risk avoidance education.</p> <p>The bill extends funding for the grant program&nbsp;for personal responsibility education through FY2019.</p> <p>TITLE II--OFFSETS</p> <p>(Sec. 201) The bill revises the grace period that health insurers must provide to recipients of premium subsidies before discontinuing health coverage for nonpayment of premiums. The grace period is shortened from three months to one month unless state law includes an&nbsp;applicable grace period.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must report about the effects on consumers of aligning grace periods for Medicaid, Medicare, and plans offered on health insurance exchanges, including whether such an alignment may reduce fraud, waste, and abuse under Medicaid.</p> <p>(Sec. 202) The bill reduces appropriations for the Prevention and Public Health Fund through FY2025 and continues funding through FY2027.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3922v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-15">
<action-date>2017-10-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Community Health And Medical Professionals Improve Our Nation Act of 2017 or the CHAMPION Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to extend funding through FY2019 for community health centers and the National Health Service Corps. Health centers that serve medically underserved populations may receive supplemental grant funds to increase access to primary care services.</p> <p>The bill reduces appropriations for the Prevention and Public Health Fund through FY2025 and continues funding through FY2027.</p> <p>The bill amends the Public Health Service Act to extend funding through FY2019 for type I diabetes research and the prevention and treatment of diabetes&nbsp;in Native Americans.</p> <p>The bill increases and extends funding through FY2019 for teaching health centers that sponsor graduate medical residency training programs.</p> <p>The bill amends the Social Security Act to increase and extend funding through FY2019 for family-to-family health information centers, which assist families of children with disabilities or special health needs.</p> <p>The bill creates, and makes appropriations for, the Youth Empowerment Program. The program shall fund allotments to states or other entities to implement education exclusively&nbsp;about sexual risk avoidance (voluntarily refraining from sexual activity). Up to 20% of&nbsp;an allotment may be used to build evidence for sexual&nbsp;risk avoidance education.</p> <p>The bill extends funding for the grant program&nbsp;for personal responsibility education through FY2019.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
