<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4085" measure-id="id115hr4085" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-19" update-date="2018-03-23">
<title>Tax Policy Transparency Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4085v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-23">
<action-date>2017-10-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Tax Policy Transparency Act </b></p> <p>This bill requires the Joint Committee on Taxation (JCT) to make publicly available an analysis of the effects of major tax legislation, including: (1) a distributional analysis, (2) a dynamic distributional after-tax wage income analysis, and (3) a written summary of the results of the analyses. </p> <p>During the ten-year period after major tax legislation is enacted into law, the JCT must submit to Congress annual updates for the estimates included in the analyses.</p> <p>&quot;Major tax legislation&quot; includes legislation, for which the estimate provided by the JCT and the Congressional Budget Office under the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 incorporates the budgetary effects of changes in economic output, employment, capital stock, and other macroeconomic variables (commonly known as dynamic scoring). </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
