<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2809" measure-id="id115hr2809" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-07" update-date="2017-09-25">
<title>American Space Commerce Free Enterprise Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2809v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-25">
<action-date>2017-06-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>American Space Commerce Free Enterprise Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill grants the Office of Space Commerce of the Department of Commerce the authority to issue certifications to U.S. nationals and nongovernmental entities for the operation of: (1) specified human-made objects manufactured or assembled in outer space, including on the Moon and other celestial bodies, with or without human occupants, that were launched from Earth; and (2) all items carried on such objects that are intended for use in outer space. To be eligible for certification, each entity's application must include a space debris mitigation plan for the space objects. </p> <p>The office shall establish a Private Space Activity Advisory Committee to: (1) analyze the status and recent developments of nongovernmental space activities, and (2) advise on matters relating to U.S. private sector activities in outer space. </p> <p>The bill authorizes the office to issue permits to persons for the operation of space-based remote sensing systems. </p> <p>The office shall establish an Advisory Committee on Commercial Remote Sensing to advise on matters relating to the U.S. commercial space-based remote sensing industry. </p> <p>The bill abolishes the Commercial Remote Sensing Regulatory Affairs Office of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
