<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="376" measure-id="id115hr376" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-09" update-date="2017-04-03">
<title>Shareholder Protection Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr376v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-04-03">
<action-date>2017-01-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Shareholder Protection Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require shareholder authorization with respect to certain political expenditures by an issuer.</p> <p>A violation of this requirement shall be considered&nbsp;a breach of fiduciary duty, and the officers and directors who authorized the expenditure shall be subject to joint and several liability.</p> <p>The Securities and Exchange Commission must direct the national securities exchanges and associations to prohibit the listing of any equity security of an issuer whose corporate bylaws do not require a board vote with respect to political expenditures in excess of $50,000. An issuer must, within 48 hours, make publicly available the individual votes of each board member with respect to such expenditures.</p> <p>The bill establishes various reporting requirements.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
