<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1049" measure-id="id115hr1049" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-14" update-date="2017-08-04">
<title>Department of Defense Emergency Response Capabilities Database Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1049v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-04">
<action-date>2017-02-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Department of Defense Emergency Response Capabilities Database Enhancement Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the John Warner National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007 to require the Department of Defense (DOD) to establish and maintain within one year a database of DOD emergency response capabilities that includes the cyber capabilities of the reserves and the National Guard of each state and territory that are important to national security and for response to domestic natural or man made disasters. </p> <p>DOD may use or modify a current database or tracking system if that will expedite and achieve compliance at a cost not greater than the cost of establishing a new database. </p> <p>DOD shall identify and revise the database information at least once every two years.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
