<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2055" measure-id="id115hr2055" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2017-05-08">
<title>Lifetime Income Disclosure Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2055v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-08">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Lifetime Income Disclosure Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to require pension benefit statements to include a lifetime income disclosure at least once during any 12-month period. </p> <p>The disclosure must set forth the lifetime income stream equivalent of the total benefits accrued with respect to the participant or beneficiary. The &quot;lifetime income stream equivalent of the total benefits accrued&quot; is the amount of monthly payments the participant or beneficiary would receive if the total accrued benefits were used to provide lifetime income streams based on certain assumptions, including that the participant or beneficiary has a spouse of equal age and a single life annuity. </p> <p>The Department of Labor must issue a model lifetime income disclosure, assumptions that plan administrators may use in converting total accrued benefits into lifetime income stream equivalents, and related rules. </p> <p>No plan fiduciary, sponsor, or other person may be liable under ERISA solely due to the provision of lifetime income stream equivalents derived in accordance with the assumptions and related rules issued by Labor, including explanations contained in the model lifetime income disclosure. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
