<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1966" measure-id="id115hr1966" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2017-04-15">
<title>REAL Protection Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1966v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-04-15">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Resurveys Entitle Adjacent Landowners to Protection Act or the REAL Protection Act</b></p> <p> This bill directs the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) to notify all property owners with land abutting or adjacent to federal land being resurveyed of the pending resurvey. A resurvey is an official rerunning and remarking intended to supersede the records of the original survey.</p> <p> The BLM shall notify affected landowners within 30 days of completion of the resurvey if it extends the boundaries of federal land. </p> <p>If a resurvey results in private land being reclassified as federal land, the affected landowners shall be given the right of first refusal to purchase the land for fair market value minus the value of any significant improvements made to such lands, or be reimbursed for the fair market value of any such improvements. Affected landowners may not be charged with willful trespass onto the land unless they used such lands with the knowledge that they should be classified as federal land. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
