<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="627" measure-id="id115hr627" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-24" update-date="2017-07-10">
<title>Streamlining Energy Efficiency for Schools Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr627v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-10">
<action-date>2017-06-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act by directing the Department of Energy's Office of Energy and Renewable Energy to establish a clearinghouse for disseminating information regarding available programs and financing mechanisms that may be used to help initiate, develop, and finance energy efficiency, distributed generation, and energy retrofitting projects for schools. </p> <p>The office must: (1) consult with appropriate agencies to develop a list of programs and financing mechanisms that are, or may be, used for the projects; and (2) coordinate with appropriate agencies to develop a collaborative education and outreach effort to streamline communications and promote the programs and financing mechanisms.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr627v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-02-03">
<action-date>2017-01-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Streamlining Energy Efficiency for Schools Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act by directing the Department of Energy's Office of Energy and Renewable Energy to establish a clearinghouse for disseminating information regarding available programs and financing mechanisms that may be used to help initiate, develop, and finance energy efficiency, distributed generation, and energy retrofitting projects for schools. </p> <p>The office must: (1) consult with appropriate agencies to develop a list of programs and financing mechanisms that are, or may be, used for the projects; and (2) coordinate with appropriate agencies to develop a collaborative education and outreach effort to streamline communications and promote the programs and financing mechanisms.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
