<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1906" measure-id="id115hr1906" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-05" update-date="2018-01-03">
<title>REDEEM Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1906v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-03">
<action-date>2017-04-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Record Expungement Designed to Enhance Employment Act of 2017 or the REDEEM Act </b></p> <p>This bill creates a mechanism by which certain eligible individuals may file a petition to seal federal criminal records with respect to covered nonviolent offenses. If an individual is eligible for such a sealing order, the court must notify the person in writing of their potential eligibility. The bill establishes a set of rules and procedures for assessing a sealing petition. If granted, the offense, criminal proceeding, conviction, or sentence shall be treated as if it never occurred.</p> <p>A judge shall issue a sealing order three years after the date on which a person is adjudicated delinquent for a juvenile nonviolent offense if certain conditions are met.</p> <p>The use of room confinement (defined as involuntary placement of a juvenile alone in a cell) for discipline, other than a temporary response to a juvenile's behavior that presents harm to others, is prohibited.</p> <p>The bill removes possession and use of controlled substance as a disqualifying activity under federal welfare laws. Further, the prohibition from access to federal welfare benefits for drug-related offenses shall not apply to persons who, among other things, have completed a certified substance abuse treatment program.</p> <p>When awarding grants under the Community-Oriented Policing Services (COPS) program, the Department of Justice (DOJ) may give preference to states that have laws similar to this bill's provisions.</p> <p>DOJ shall establish and enforce procedures to ensure the prompt release of accurate records exchanged for employment-related purposes through the records system created by this bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
