<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="138" measure-id="id115hr138" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-03" update-date="2017-05-16">
<title>Protecting Employees and Retirees in Business Bankruptcies Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr138v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-16">
<action-date>2017-01-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protecting Employees and Retirees in Business Bankruptcies Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends federal bankruptcy law to modify provisions related to&nbsp;Chapter 11 bankruptcy, which typically involves the reorganization of&nbsp;a debtor company's assets and debts. Specifically, the bill modifies provisions governing: (1)&nbsp;employee and retiree recoveries and losses,&nbsp;and (2) executive compensation programs.</p> <p>With respect to employee and retiree&nbsp;recoveries and losses, the bill:</p> <ul> <li>increases the maximum&nbsp;value and age&nbsp;of specified wage and benefit claims entitled to priority payment; </li> <li>allows certain claims for losses&nbsp;related to&nbsp;defined contribution plans, if the employer or plan sponsor has committed fraud or otherwise breached its fiduciary duty; </li> <li>allows, as an administrative expense of the estate, severance pay owed to employees; </li> <li>establishes&nbsp;certain restrictions&nbsp;regarding the rejection or amendment of a collective bargaining agreement;<strike> </strike></li> <li>revises specified procedures related to the reduction or denial of retiree benefits;<strike> </strike></li> <li>requires a court, in approving a sale of business assets, to consider the extent to which a bidder has offered to maintain existing jobs and assume benefit obligations; and<strike></strike> </li> <li>modifies other provisions.</li></ul> <p>With respect to&nbsp;executive compensation, the bill:</p> <ul> <li>establishes&nbsp;specified limitations related to executive compensation enhancements,</li> <li>prohibits executives from receiving certain retiree benefits if such benefits were reduced or eliminated for other employees or retirees, and<strike></s></strike></li> <li><strike></s></strike><strike></strike>revises other requirements related to court approval of such compensation.</li></ul> <p>In addition, the bill grants creditor status to labor organizations for purposes of filing a proof of claim.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
