<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2997" measure-id="id115hr2997" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-22" update-date="2017-10-24">
<title>21st Century AIRR Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2997v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-24">
<action-date>2017-06-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>21st Century Aviation Innovation, Reform, and Reauthorization Act or the 21st Century AIRR Act</b></p> <p>This bill reauthorizes the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) through FY2020 and specified FAA programs for FY2018-FY2023.</p> <p>The bill revises requirements for the pilot program for passenger facility charges at nonhub airports and airport improvement program.</p> <p>The bill amends the Vision 100--Century of Aviation Reauthorization Act to extend through FY2023 the authorization for airport development at Midway Island Airport.</p> <p>The Department of Transportation (DOT):</p> <ul> <li> shall carry out an environmental mitigation pilot grant program for sponsors of public-use airports, and</li> <li> may make grants to such sponsors for environmental mitigation projects to reduce or mitigate aviation impacts on noise, air quality, or water quality at the airport or within five miles of the airport.</li> </ul> <p>The bill establishes the American Air Navigation Services Corporation as a federally chartered, not-for-profit corporation. </p> <p> DOT shall transfer to the corporation:</p> <ul> <li>by a certain deadline FAA employees, property, and facilities; and</li> <li>on October 1, 2020, operational control of FAA air traffic services.</li> </ul> <p>DOT shall establish a Safety Oversight and Certification Advisory Committee.</p> <p>The FAA shall establish:</p> <UL> <LI>the FAA Task Force on Flight Standards Reform, and <LI>a Regulatory Consistency Communications Board. </LI> </UL> <p>The FAA shall establish a safety workforce training strategy. </p> <p>DOT shall take appropriate actions to promote U.S. aerospace standards, products, and services abroad.</p> <p>DOT shall modify FAA's final rule published August 19, 1994, relating to flight duty limitations and rest requirements to ensure that:</p> <ul> <li>a flight attendant scheduled for a duty period of 14 hours or less is given a scheduled rest period of at least 10 consecutive hours, and</li> <li>the rest period is not reduced under any circumstances.</li> </ul> <p>DOT shall develop a comprehensive plan to accelerate the integration of civil unmanned aircraft systems (drones) into the national airspace system.</p> <p>The bill prescribes certain requirements for improving passenger air service.</p> <p>The bill also reauthorizes for FY2018-FY2023 the essential air service program and the small community air service development program.</p> <p>DOT shall:</p> <ul> <li>establish a regional air transportation pilot grant program, and</li> <li>provide grants to air carriers to maintain air service to communities not receiving sufficient air service.</li> </ul> <p>The FAA shall initiate a review of its strategic aviation cybersecurity plan.</p> <p>DOT shall establish a remote air traffic control tower pilot program for rural or small communities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
