<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1101" measure-id="id115hr1101" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-16" update-date="2017-11-02">
<title>Small Business Health Fairness Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1101v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-02">
<action-date>2017-03-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Small Business Health Fairness Act of 2017</strong></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to provide for the establishment and governance of association health plans (AHPs), which are group health plans sponsored by business associations.</p> <p>The bill establishes requirements for AHPs relating to certification, sponsors and boards of trustees, participation and coverage, nondiscrimination, contribution rates, and voluntary termination.</p> <p>AHPs offering benefits that are not health insurance must: (1) establish and maintain sufficient reserves and stop-loss insurance to cover those benefits, and (2) make annual payments to a fund to be used to pay for stop-loss insurance for such AHPs for which there is a reasonable expectation that claims would not be satisfied without such insurance. AHPs that fail to meet these requirements are subject to termination.</p> <p>The Department of Labor must establish a Solvency Standards Working Group.</p> <p>States may tax contributions to AHPs, with certain conditions.</p> <p>The bill preempts state laws that preclude health insurers from: (1) offering health insurance in connection with a certified AHP; or (2) offering health insurance of the same policy type to other employers in the state that are eligible for coverage under AHPs.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill establishes criminal penalties for willfully making false representations regarding an AHP.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1101v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-03-16">
<action-date>2017-02-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Small Business Health Fairness Act of 2017</strong></p> <p> This bill amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to provide for the establishment and governance of association health plans (AHPs), which are group health plans sponsored by business associations.</p> <p>The bill establishes requirements for AHPs relating to certification, sponsors and boards of trustees, participation and coverage, nondiscrimination, contribution rates, and voluntary termination.</p> <p>AHPs offering benefits that are not health insurance must: (1) establish and maintain sufficient reserves and stop-loss insurance to cover those benefits, and (2) make annual payments to a fund to be used to pay for stop-loss insurance for such AHPs for which there is a reasonable expectation that claims would not be satisfied without such insurance. AHPs that fail to meet these requirements are subject to termination.</p> <p>The Department of Labor must establish a Solvency Standards Working Group.</p> <p>States may tax contributions to AHPs, with certain conditions.</p> <p>The bill preempts state laws that preclude health insurers from: (1) offering health insurance in connection with a certified AHP; or (2) offering health insurance of the same policy type to other employers in the state that are eligible for coverage under AHPs.</p> <p>The bill establishes criminal penalties for willfully making false representations regarding an AHP.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
