<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2131" measure-id="id115hr2131" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-25" update-date="2017-10-25">
<title>Fixing Internal Response to Misconduct Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2131v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-25">
<action-date>2017-06-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Fixing Internal Response to Misconduct Act or the DHS FIRM Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to implement a DHS-wide policy related to discipline and adverse actions, which shall provide guidance:</p> <ul> <li>to the senior human resources official overseeing discipline and adverse actions for headquarters personnel and non-component entities and relevant component heads regarding informing the public about how to report employee misconduct; </li> <li>on how DHS employees should report employee misconduct; </li> <li>on the type, quantity, and frequency of data regarding discipline and adverse actions to be submitted by such official to such officer; </li> <li>on how to implement any such policy in a manner that promotes greater uniformity and transparency in the administration of such policy across DHS; and </li> <li>on prohibited personnel practices, employee rights, and related procedures and processes. </li></ul> <p>Such officer shall review and approve any necessary development of or changes to tables of offenses and penalties for DHS components to comply with DHS policy.</p> <p>Component heads shall comply with DHS-wide policy regarding discipline and adverse actions for DHS's workforce, and such officer shall implement a process to oversee such compliance.</p> <p>Such officer: (1) may establish working groups to address employee misconduct within DHS, (2) shall conduct follow-up reviews of components regarding implementation of working group recommendations, and (3) may request the DHS Inspector General to investigate any concerns identified through the oversight process that components have not addressed. </p> <p>A working group shall seek to identify any trends in misconduct, review component processes for addressing misconduct, and develop possible alternate strategies to address such misconduct.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2131v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-24">
<action-date>2017-04-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Fixing Internal Response to Misconduct Act or the DHS FIRM Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to implement a DHS-wide policy related to discipline and adverse actions, which shall provide guidance:</p> <ul> <li> to the senior human resources official overseeing discipline and adverse actions for headquarters personnel and non-component entities and relevant component heads regarding informing the public about how to report employee misconduct; </li> <li> on how DHS employees should report employee misconduct; and </li> <li> on the type, quantity, and frequency of data regarding discipline and adverse actions to be submitted by such official to such officer.</li> </ul> <p>Such officer shall review and approve any necessary development of or changes to tables of offenses and penalties for DHS components to comply with DHS policy.</p> <p>Component heads shall comply with DHS-wide policy regarding discipline and adverse actions for DHS's workforce, and such officer shall implement a process to oversee such compliance.</p> <p>Such officer: (1) may establish working groups to improve employee relations within DHS, (2) shall conduct follow-up reviews of components with respect to which misconduct has been identified, and (3) may request the DHS Inspector General to investigate any concerns identified through the oversight process that components have not addressed. The Inspector General may issue management alerts regarding misconduct.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
