<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2014" measure-id="id115hr2014" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2017-07-05">
<title>Tax Pollution, Not Profits Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2014v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-05">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Tax Pollution, Not Profits Act </strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose an excise tax on certain greenhouse gas emissions. The tax is equal to $30 per metric ton of carbon dioxide or carbon dioxide equivalent in 2018, increasing each subsequent year at 4% above inflation.</p> <p>The Internal Revenue Service must: (1) provide certain refunds of the tax to account for the capture and permanent sequestration of greenhouse gas emissions, and (2) adjust the tax to account for goods that are exported or imported.</p> <p>The bill amends the Social Security Act to establish a Low-Income Energy Cost Mitigation Program to provide an energy refund amount to certain low and middle-income households to compensate such households for increases in energy costs due to this bill.</p> <p>The Department of Labor may use up to 2% of the revenues generated by this bill to implement a program to assist displaced workers in the coal industry.</p> <p>The bill also provides for a gradual reduction in the corporate income tax rate to 32% in taxable years beginning in 2018 and 28% in taxable years beginning after 2021. </p> <p>The bill requires the Department of the Treasury to establish a website to make information regarding the amount and sources of revenue attributable to this bill publicly available. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
