<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1574" measure-id="id115hr1574" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-16" update-date="2017-05-03">
<title>Protecting Dissenting Viewpoints and Voices Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1574v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-03">
<action-date>2017-03-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protecting Dissenting Viewpoints and Voices Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) from using the viewpoints that a person broadcasts or otherwise disseminates on issues of public importance as a basis for: (1) revoking the person's licenses or authorizations; (2) taking action against the person; or (3) placing conditions on the FCC's approval of the assignment or transfer of a station license or construction permit or the construction, extension, acquisition, operation, or discontinuation of a communications line.</p> <p>The bill also prohibits the President from directing an agency to take actions against a person, or to condition agency approvals, based on a person's broadcasted or disseminated viewpoints.</p> <p>Nothing in this bill affects the authority of the FCC or the President to take action against violations concerning the broadcast of: (1) obscene or indecent language, fraudulent schemes, or lottery information; or (2) content constituting incitement under the First Amendment. </p> <p>The FCC may continue to enforce broadcast requirements that: (1) permit candidates to federal elective office to purchase reasonable broadcast time, (2) allow equal broadcast opportunities for all candidates for public office, and (3) require disclosures of paid broadcasts. </p> <p>The President may continue to direct agencies to take actions to execute the President's legal duties.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
