<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2220" measure-id="id115hr2220" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-27" update-date="2017-05-20">
<title>Military Pay Protection Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2220v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-20">
<action-date>2017-04-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Military Pay Protection Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of the Treasury, during a government shutdown, to make available to the Department of Defense (DOD) and to the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), in the case of the Coast Guard, such amounts as necessary to continue to provide: (1) pay and allowances to members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard, including reserve components, who perform active service during the shutdown and, at DOD's discretion, to DOD civilian and contractor personnel providing direct support to such members; and (2) funding necessary to prevent interruptions or delays in the performance of domestic disaster relief and recovery operations during the shutdown.</p> <p>The bill defines &quot;government shutdown&quot; as any portion of a fiscal year for which funds have not been appropriated for such purposes.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
