<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1377" measure-id="id115hr1377" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-07" update-date="2018-01-02">
<title>Transitioning to Integrated and Meaningful Employment Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1377v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-02">
<action-date>2017-03-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Transitioning to Integrated and Meaningful Employment Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to: (1) prohibit the Department of Labor from issuing new special wage certificates for individuals whose earning or productive capacity is impaired by age, physical or mental deficiency, or injury, and (2) repeal the authority for issuing such certificates six years after the enactment of this bill, at which time any outstanding special wage certificates shall be revoked. </p> <p>Labor shall not renew any special certificate previously provided to an employer unless the employer provides, on an annual basis: (1) individualized assessments of each employee paid subminimum wages under any such special certificate; (2) individualized assessments of each employee that identify how obstacles related to disability prevent each employee paid subminimum wages from transitioning into available job opportunities that pay at or above the minimum wage and the resources provided to each such employee in order to mitigate those disability-related obstacles; and (3) a transition plan for each such employee.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
