<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2722" measure-id="id115hr2722" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-25" update-date="2017-07-17">
<title>SWINE Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2722v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-17">
<action-date>2017-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Swine Waste Infrastructure and Natural Environment Act or the SWINE Act </b></p> <p>This bill establishes a program to certify environmentally sustainable swine waste disposal technologies and authorizes related tax credits and grants. </p> <p>The Department of Agriculture (USDA) must certify technologies that: </p> <ul> <li> eliminate animal discharge into surface waters and groundwater through direct discharge, seepage, or runoff;</li> <li>substantially eliminate atmospheric emissions of ammonia from swine waste; </li> <li> substantially eliminate the emission of odor from swine waste that is detectable beyond the boundaries of the parcel or tract of land on which the swine farm is located; </li> <li> substantially eliminate the release of disease-transmitting vectors and airborne pathogens from swine waste; </li> <li> substantially eliminate nutrient and heavy metal contamination of soil and groundwater from swine waste; and </li> <li> are cost-effective. </li> </ul> <p>States may not issue permits, pursuant to any federal law, to a swine farm that is a concentrated animal feeding operation unless the farm disposes of swine waste using a certified technology. </p> <p>The bill amends several agricultural laws to: </p> <ul> <li>require USDA to make competitive grants for activities to identify, evaluate, and demonstrate environmentally superior swine waste management technologies; </li> <li> permit the Pork Promotion Board to use its funding for activities related to the grants; and</li> <li> make the installation and maintenance of a certified technology on a swine farm eligible for the Environmental Quality Incentives Program.</li> </ul> <p>The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow tax credits for: (1) the installation of a certified swine waste disposal technology, and (2) the disposal of swine waste using certified technology. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
