<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2223" measure-id="id115hr2223" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-28" update-date="2017-10-16">
<title>Community Protection and Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2223v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-16">
<action-date>2017-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Community Protection and Preparedness Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Transportation (DOT), annually, to impose a $1,500 fee for each DOT-111 specification railroad tank car used to transport Class 3 flammable liquids during the previous fiscal year that did not meet DOT-117, DOT-117P, or DOT-117R specifications at the time it was used. Such fee shall be paid by each person who causes such liquids to be transported by such car in commerce and not by the railroad carrier that transports such liquids.</p> <p>Collected fees shall be deposited into a Rail Account established within the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund and shall be available only for: </p> <ul> <li> the payment of removal and remediation costs and other costs, expenses, claims, and damages related to an accident or incident involving the transportation of Class 3 flammable liquids by rail; and </li> <li> DOT grants to states and Indian tribes to develop emergency plans and to train regional hazardous material emergency response teams and public employees responding to such an accident or incident. </li> </ul> <p>The Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration shall issue a final rule relating to the notice of proposed rulemaking issued on July 29, 2016, &quot;Hazardous Materials: Oil Spill Response Plans and Information Sharing for High-Hazard Flammable Trains.&quot;</p> <p>Necessary amounts are authorized for the Federal Railroad Administration to hire at least two additional track safety specialists per region.</p> <p>DOT shall:</p> <ul> <li>assess the adequacy of railroad track inspections, training provided to railroad track inspectors and related personnel, railroad compliance with federal track safety regulations, and federal oversight of railroad track safety; and</li> <li>evaluate the leading causes of track defects, particularly along train routes traversed by passengers and hazardous materials.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
