<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2005" measure-id="id115hr2005" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2017-05-01">
<title>Offshoring Prevention Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2005v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-01">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Offshoring Prevention Act</strong> </p> <p> This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to include imported property income in foreign base company income, for purposes of determining the income of controlled foreign corporations. </p> <p>The bill defines "imported property income" as, with certain exceptions, income derived in connection with:</p> <ul> <li>manufacturing, producing, growing, or extracting imported property;</li> <li> the sale, exchange, or other disposition of imported property; or</li> <li>the lease, rental, or licensing of imported property.</li> </ul> <p>The bill also provides for a separate application of limitations on the foreign tax credit for imported property income.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
