<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3532" measure-id="id115hr3532" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-28" update-date="2017-11-07">
<title>No Conflict of Interest Presidency Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3532v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-07">
<action-date>2017-07-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>No Conflict of Interest Presidency Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the President: (1) immediately after assuming office, to convert any private businesses and investments owned or held by the President into cash; and (2) upon making such conversion, to purchase Treasury bills, notes, or bonds, widely diversified mutual funds, or any other holding that does not give rise to a financial conflict of interest. </p> <p> A violation of this bill shall constitute a high crime and misdemeanor under the U.S. Constitution.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
