<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2511" measure-id="id115hr2511" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-18" update-date="2018-02-09">
<title>Defense Acquisition Streamlining and Transparency Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2511v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-09">
<action-date>2017-05-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Defense Acquisition Streamlining and Transparency Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Defense (DOD) to establish a program to procure commercial off-the-shelf products through online marketplaces to expedite procurement and ensure reasonable pricing. A contract may be made without full and open competition.</p> <p>DOD shall comply with commercially accepted standards of risk and materiality in performing an incurred cost audit.</p> <p>DOD shall emphasize sustainment factors: (1) early in a weapon system's development, and (2) in the development of capabilities requirements. </p> <p>A weapon system contract shall include clearly defined requirements for reliability and maintainability. </p> <p>DOD shall establish: (1) contract performance best practices, which shall include incentive fees and recovery options; and (2) an investment program for funding weapon system design changes. </p> <p>DOD shall negotiate the price of technical data before selecting a contractor for the development or production of a major weapon system.</p> <p>The bill establishes an Office of Intellectual Property within the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment. </p> <p>DOD shall ensure that: (1) sufficient data is collected and evaluated in support of a services contract, and (2) certain funding requirements are displayed separately for major defense acquisition programs.</p> <p>DOD shall evaluate its strategy for developing and expanding the use of tools designed to facilitate the cost effectiveness and efficiency of developmental testing.</p> <p>DOD shall: (1) implement a program to develop civil program managers for major defense acquisition programs, and (2) contract with an independent research entity to carry out a study of financial incentives for such managers.</p> <p>The DOD acquisition workforce demonstration project is extended through December 31, 2023.</p> <p>The defense business enterprise architecture shall include one or more common enterprise data structures to facilitate DOD-wide analysis.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
