<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4094" measure-id="id115hr4094" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-23" update-date="2018-02-15">
<title>Medicare-X Choice Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4094v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-15">
<action-date>2017-10-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Medicare-X Choice Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Social Security Act to create the Medicare Exchange health plan, which the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) must offer in&nbsp;certain individual health insurance exchanges in 2020 and offer in all individual health insurance exchanges by 2023. Any individual who is a resident of a state where the plan is offered and who is not eligible for Medicare benefits may enroll in the plan. CMS must offer the plan in the small group market&nbsp;in all areas for 2024.</p> <p>The plan must meet the same requirements, including essential&nbsp;health benefits, as health insurance exchange plans under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</p> <p>Health care providers enrolled under Medicare or under a state Medicaid plan shall also&nbsp;be participating providers for the plan&nbsp;and shall be reimbursed at Medicare&nbsp;rates. </p> <p>The bill eliminates the restriction on the Department of Health and Human Services to negotiate prescription drug prices for Medicare.&nbsp;</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
