<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="379" measure-id="id115hr379" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-09" update-date="2017-07-22">
<title>Justice for Yazidis Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr379v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-22">
<action-date>2017-01-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Justice for Yazidis Act</strong></p> <p>This bill states that Syrian and Iraqi nationals who are members of a religious minority in their country of origin: (1) shall be classified as refugees of special humanitarian concern, (2) shall be eligible for priority-2 refugee resettlement processing, and (3) may apply directly to the U.S. refugee admissions program. </p> <p>No alien shall be denied the opportunity to apply for admission under this bill solely because he or she: (1) qualifies as an immediate relative, (2) is eligible for any other immigrant classification, or (3) was referred to apply for refugee admission by a U.S. nonprofit organization. </p> <p>Each such alien who, after June 1, 2014, and before the date of the enactment of this bill, was denied refugee status may reapply for such status.</p> <p> <he Department of Staste> The Department of State shall: (1) submit and implement a plan to expedite priority-2 refugee processing, and (2) submit annual program reports through 2020.</p> <p>The Department of Defense shall report on U.S. military efforts in Islamic State (ISIS)-controlled regions to incorporate the rescue and care of religious or minority group captives.</p> <p>The State Department shall establish a program to provide health care and psychosocial support for members of the Yazidi, Christian, Shabak, and Turkmen communities displaced by ISIS. Such program shall provide mental health and psychosocial support for children from such communities, with a particular focus on services to survivors of sexual slavery.</p> <p>The State Department shall establish a program to provide training on trauma-informed care to psychologists, social workers, and physical therapists based in Iraq, Syria, or any country that hosts Yazidi, Christian, Shabak, or Turkmen refugees. </p> <p>Funds for such State Department programs are transferred from amounts available for assistance to Egypt.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
