<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1248" measure-id="id115hr1248" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-28" update-date="2017-05-01">
<title>Make Our Government Safe Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1248v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-01">
<action-date>2017-02-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Make Our Government Safe Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the National Security Act of 1947 to prohibit the President from designating as an attendee or participant in the National Security Council (or in any meeting of the Principals Committee) any individual who threatens to destroy the government, including in speech or written form or through action. </p> <p>The bill expresses the sense of Congress that a federal department or agency that issues a security clearance for an employee, including for an employee of the Executive Office of the President, should consider suspending the security clearance of an employee who threatens to destroy the state or to take hostile actions against the United States.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
