<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1751" measure-id="id115hr1751" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-28" update-date="2017-12-15">
<title>Counteracting Russian Hostilities Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1751v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-15">
<action-date>2017-03-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Counteracting Russian Hostilities Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the President to impose U.S. entry and property blocking sanctions against: (1) a person that engages in significant activities for the government of the Russian Federation that undermine U.S. or allied cyber security, or (2) a foreign person responsible for serious human rights abuses in any territory occupied or controlled by Russia.</p> <p>The President shall impose specified financial and property sanctions against a person that: (1) engages in a significant transaction on behalf of Russian defense or intelligence sectors; (2) invests specified amounts in Russian petroleum or natural gas resources, energy export pipelines, or civil nuclear projects; (3) purchases or facilitates the issuance of Russian sovereign debt; or (4) contributes to Russia's ability to privatize state-owned assets.</p> <p>The Department of Homeland Security shall conduct public service campaigns to educate the people of the United States on cyber security threats and protective online practices. </p> <p>No federal agency shall take any action that recognizes: (1) Russian sovereignty over Crimea, or (2) the independence of South Ossetia or Abkhazia from Georgia. </p> <p>It is U.S. policy to assist Ukraine in restoring its sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p> <p>Specified executive orders imposing Ukraine-related sanctions shall remain in effect. </p> <p>The bill expresses the sense of Congress that the countries of Europe and Eurasia should redouble efforts to build resilience within their political systems and civil society to counter Russian efforts to undermine democratic institutions.</p> <p>The Department of State shall report to Congress regarding Russian-controlled media outlets. </p> <p>The bill establishes in the Treasury the Europe and Eurasia Democracy and Anti-Corruption Fund.</p> <p>The Department of the Treasury shall establish a task force within the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network that focuses on illicit Russian-linked financial flows that interact with the U.S. financial system.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
