<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2231" measure-id="id115hr2231" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-28" update-date="2017-07-29">
<title>To establish a joint commission on North Korea, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2231v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-29">
<action-date>2017-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> This bill authorizes the Department of State to seek to establish a joint commission with countries in the Indo-Asia Pacific region to: </p> <ul> <li>support professional dialogues to coordinate the detection of North Korean violations of United Nations Security Council resolutions, develop responses, and enhance monitoring of nuclear weapons proliferation capabilities;</li> <li>coordinate sub-cabinet level political discussions on contingency responses to such violations;</li> <li>facilitate technical discussions among the Departments of State, Defense (DOD), Energy, and the Treasury, the Intelligence Community, and their counterparts in countries in the region on technical aspects of North Korea's nuclear program and accompanying U.S. sanctions;</li> <li>coordinate information sharing among the intelligence services of the participating countries to identify immediate threats; and</li> <li>create guidelines for coordinating multilateral direct action against shared threats. </li> </ul> <p>The bill declares that it is U.S. policy: (1) to continue to maintain robust and multifaceted diplomatic engagement in the region, to include promoting U.S. values and economic interests and a strong military posture; and (2) that diplomacy, development, and defense should be used to enhance U.S. national security, promote U.S. interests, reassure U.S. allies, deter aggression, and respond swiftly to crises. </p> <p>DOD may conduct routine and enhanced ports of call with key allies in the region.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
