<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4254" measure-id="id115hr4254" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-11-06" update-date="2017-12-15">
<title>Women in Aerospace Education Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4254v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-15">
<action-date>2017-11-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Women in Aerospace Education Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the National Science Foundation Authorization Act of 2002 to require the National Science Foundation (NSF) to encourage eligible entities that administer a fellowship program using grant funds awarded on or after October 1, 2018, under the Robert Noyce Teacher Scholarship Program to include in such fellowship program opportunities for the placement of fellows in research or education internship opportunities at national laboratories and National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) centers. The NSF may give priority to proposals for placements that provide female fellows with research experience in aerospace engineering and related fields in which women are underrepresented. </p> <p>By October 1, 2018, NASA must institute a process to prioritize the promotion and recruitment of qualified candidates who are women or individuals who are historically underrepresented in the fields of science, technology, engineering, mathematics, and computer science for internships and fellowships that are relevant to the aerospace sector and related fields. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
