<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2367" measure-id="id115hr2367" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-04" update-date="2017-10-11">
<title>Department of Defense Waste Reduction Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2367v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-11">
<action-date>2017-05-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Department of Defense Waste Reduction Act</strong></p> <p>This bill prohibits the appropriation to the Department of Defense (DOD) of supplemental funds for FY2017 or funds for FY2018 if the total for such fiscal year exceeds the amount authorized to be appropriated for DOD by the National Defense Authorization Act for FY 2017, unless: (1) DOD certifies to the congressional defense committees that it has evaluated and is implementing each recommendation for DOD cost savings contained in the Defense Business Board study titled &quot;Transforming Department of Defense's Core Business Processes for Revolutionary Change&quot;; or (2) if DOD is unable to make such certification, it submits a report explaining why it is not implementing any such recommendation and 30 days elapse following the report's submission.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
