<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4873" measure-id="id115hr4873" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2018-01-20" update-date="2018-01-25">
<title>DACA Compromise Act of 2018</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4873v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-25">
<action-date>2018-01-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>DACA Compromise Act of 2018</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to cancel the removal of, and adjust to permanent resident status the status of, an alien: (1) who has been continuously present in the United States since June 15, 2012; (2) who was granted deferred removal as an undocumented alien pursuant to the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) program, unless the individual engaged in subsequent conduct that would have rendered the alien ineligible for program renewal; (3) who applies for adjustment not earlier than two years after he or she was granted such deferred removal; (4) who otherwise satisfies the requirements of this bill, and (5) to whom an immigrant visa is available. </p> <p>The bill reallocates specified family, employment, and diversity visas for such approved individuals.</p> <p>DHS shall allow eligible individuals, including minors, to apply for relief without requiring: (1) placement in removal proceedings, or (2) immediate immigrant visa availability.</p> <p>DHS shall provide a reasonable opportunity to apply for relief under this bill to any alien who: (1) requests such an opportunity, or (2) appears prima facie eligible for relief if the alien is in removal proceedings or is the subject of a final removal or voluntary departure order. </p> <p>An applicant for permanent resident status shall: (1) submit biometric and biographic data, (2) undergo law enforcement and security background checks and a medical examination, and (3) meet applicable selective service registration requirements.</p> <p>The Department of Justice may not remove certain individuals who: (1) have a pending application and appear prima facie eligible for relief, (2) have an approved application and are awaiting the availability of an immigrant visa, or (3) are ineligible to apply for relief solely due to the date limitation for applying for adjustment under this bill. DHS shall provide provisional protected status to such individuals whose DACA grant has ended.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
