<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4577" measure-id="id115hr4577" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-12-06" update-date="2018-01-09">
<title>Domestic Explosives Detection Canine Capacity Building Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4577v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-09">
<action-date>2017-12-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Domestic Explosives Detection Canine Capacity Building Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to establish a working group to determine ways to develop a decentralized domestic canine breeding network to produce high quality explosives detection canines and modernize canine training standards.</p>  <p>The working group shall submit to the TSA preliminary behavioral standards, medical standards, and technical standards for such network and training, including recommendations on how the TSA can engage stakeholders to further the development of such network and training. The TSA shall submit a strategy for expanding the network based on such recommendations.</p> <p>The TSA shall issue baseline behavioral standards for explosives detection canines. Such standards, as well as the preliminary medical and technical standards issued pursuant to this bill, shall be incorporated into all statements of work for the TSA explosive detection canine contracts and reflect the detection capabilities required to effectively mitigate terrorist threats. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
