<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1678" measure-id="id115hr1678" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-22" update-date="2017-06-14">
<title>To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act concerning the statute of limitations for actions to recover disaster or emergency assistance payments, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1678v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-14">
<action-date>2017-05-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(Sec. 1) This bill amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to prohibit any administrative action to recover any payment made to a state or local government for disaster or emergency assistance initiated in any forum (with exceptions for fraud) after three years following the transmission of the final expenditure report for project completion, as certified by the grantee (currently, after three years following the transmission of the final expenditure report for the disaster or emergency). </p> <p>Such revised prohibition shall apply to any such payment provided on or after January 1, 2004. Any administrative action to recover such a payment that is pending on the date of enactment of this bill shall be terminated.</p> <p>The bill makes the same report change with respect to the deadline: (1) for any dispute arising under such Act for which there shall be a presumption that accounting records were maintained that adequately identify the source and application of funds provided for financially assisted activities, and (2) by which the inability of the government to produce source documentation supporting expenditure reports shall not constitute evidence to rebut such presumption.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1678v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-14">
<action-date>2017-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p>(Sec. 1) This bill amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to prohibit any administrative action to recover any payment made to a state or local government for disaster or emergency assistance initiated in any forum (with exceptions for fraud) after three years following the transmission of the final expenditure report for project completion, as certified by the grantee (currently, after three years following the transmission of the final expenditure report for the disaster or emergency). </p> <p>Such revised prohibition shall apply to any such payment provided on or after January 1, 2004. Any administrative action to recover such a payment that is pending on the date of enactment of this bill shall be terminated.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1678v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-14">
<action-date>2017-03-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to prohibit any administrative action to recover any payment made to a state or local government for disaster or emergency assistance initiated in any forum (with exceptions for fraud) after three years following the transmission of the final expenditure report for project completion, as certified by the grantee (currently, after three years following the transmission of the final expenditure report for the disaster or emergency). </p> <p>Such revised prohibition shall apply to any such payment provided on or after January 1, 2004. Any administrative action to recover such a payment that is pending on the date of enactment of this bill shall be terminated.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
