<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1736" measure-id="id115hr1736" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-27" update-date="2017-08-29">
<title>To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to improve the process for inspections of device establishments and for granting export certifications.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1736v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-29">
<action-date>2017-03-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to revise provisions regarding Food and Drug Administration (FDA): (1) inspections of establishments that manufacture or process medical devices, and (2) certification of medical devices for export.</p> <p>The biannual inspection schedule for medical device establishments handling higher risk devices is replaced with a risk-based schedule. In establishing the risk-based schedule, the FDA must consider an establishment's participation in international medical device audit programs.</p> <p>The FDA must adopt a uniform process and uniform standards for inspections of domestic and foreign medical device establishments.</p> <p>Upon request, the FDA must provide to the person in charge of a medical device establishment feedback regarding the person's proposals to address issues identified during an inspection.</p> <p>The FDA must provide the basis for denying requests for certification of products for export as meeting FDA requirements for domestic products. A person denied such a certification may request supervisory review of that decision.</p> Products from a medical device establishment that an inspector found to be contaminated or insanitary may be certified for export if the person in charge of the establishment has agreed to a plan to correct the issues identified during the inspection.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
