<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2497" measure-id="id115hr2497" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-17" update-date="2018-02-22">
<title>End Subsidizing Palestinian Terrorism Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2497v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-22">
<action-date>2017-05-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>End Subsidizing Palestinian Terrorism Act</strong></p> <p>This bill declares that Congress:</p> <ul> <li>condemns incitement and acts of violence against Israeli citizens;</li> <li>calls on Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas to publicly condemn incitement and acts of violence against Israeli citizens and to discontinue incitement in Palestinian Authority-controlled media outlets, and calls on the international community to condemn such incitement and acts of violence;</li> <li>expresses the belief that any chance at lasting peace can only happen through peaceful, bilateral, discussions and sound consultation with peaceful allies;</li> <li>expresses support for individuals and organizations working to encourage Israeli-Palestinian cooperation and for the many activists within Israel and the Palestinian territories working to bring an end to the conflict; and</li> <li>reaffirms the friendship between Israel and the United States. </li> </ul> <p>No funds made available for purposes of assistance for the Palestinian Authority or the West Bank and Gaza may be obligated or expended unless the Department of State certifies to Congress that the Palestinian Authority:</p> <ul> <li> is taking credible steps to end terrorist acts against U.S. and Israeli citizens perpetrated by individuals under its jurisdictional control; </li> <li> has publicly condemned acts of violence and is taking steps to investigate, or is cooperating with investigations of, such acts to bring the perpetrators to justice; and </li> <li> has terminated payments for acts of terrorism against U.S. and Israeli citizens to any individual who has been imprisoned after being fairly tried and convicted for such acts and to any individual who died committing such acts, or to a family member of such an individual. </li> </ul> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
