<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4178" measure-id="id115hr4178" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-31" update-date="2018-04-05">
<title>HEART Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4178v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-04-05">
<action-date>2017-10-31</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Healthcare Enhancement for Americas Rural Towns Act or the HEART Act</strong></p> <p>This bill permanently extends&nbsp;and otherwise revises&nbsp;the Medicare-Dependent Hospital program (which provides increased payments to certain smaller, rural hospitals&nbsp;that serve a proportionally&nbsp;high number of Medicare patients).&nbsp;The bill also&nbsp;extends through FY 2019 the program for increased payments under Medicare for low-volume hospitals. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
