<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2200" measure-id="id115hr2200" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-27" update-date="2017-11-22">
<title>Frederick Douglass Trafficking Victims Prevention and Protection Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2200v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-22">
<action-date>2017-04-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Frederick Douglass Trafficking Victims Prevention and Protection Reauthorization Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes local educational agencies to establish programs to educate children on the dangers of severe forms of trafficking in persons. </p> <p>Diplomatic or consular posts shall designate an employee to receive information from any person who was a victim of a severe form of trafficking in persons while in the United States. </p> <p>The Department of Health and Human Services may carry out a Human Trafficking Victims Reintegration Through Employment Program. </p> <p>Department of Justice (DOJ) victim services grants may be used for programs that provide trauma-informed care or long-term housing for: (1) youth transitioning from foster care, and (2) women or girls in underserved populations.</p> <p>Airlines that contract with the federal government shall provide personnel with training in recognizing human trafficking incidents.</p> <p>Federal Acquisition Institute curricula for the acquisition workforce shall include a course on the law relating to human trafficking and government contracting.</p> <p>The United States Advisory Council on Human Trafficking Council is extended to September 30, 2020. </p> <p>The bill sets forth agency actions to prevent funding of human trafficking.</p> <p>DOJ law enforcement grants may be used to designate at least one prosecutor for cases of severe forms of trafficking in persons.</p> <p>Civil damages awarded in an action brought for slavery or trafficking in persons are excluded from gross income.</p> <p>The Secretary of the Treasury and the United States Trade Representative are included in the Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking.</p> <p>The bill provides for transparency in U.S. Agency for International Development anti-trafficking expenditures. </p> <p>The bill authorizes appropriations through FY2021 for: (1) specified anti-trafficking programs and entities, and (2) U.S. Customs and Border Protection for on-site anti-trafficking training for airport and airline personnel.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
