<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3387" measure-id="id115hr3387" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-25" update-date="2018-04-10">
<title>Drinking Water System Improvement Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3387v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-04-10">
<action-date>2017-11-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Drinking Water System Improvement Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to provide support for public water systems and promote compliance by the systems with drinking water regulations.</p> <p>The bill expands requirements concerning consumer confidence reports issued by community water systems.</p> <p> The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) or a state with primary enforcement authority responsibility under the Act may require the owners or operators of certain public water systems that have repeatedly violated national primary drinking water regulations to consolidate or transfer ownership.</p> <p>The EPA must develop a strategic plan for improving the accuracy and availability of compliance monitoring data.</p> <p>The bill expands risk assessment requirements for community water systems to include risks from natural hazards. The bill creates a grant program within the EPA called the Drinking Water Infrastructure Risk and Resilience Program.</p> <p>The bill: (1) reauthorizes through FY2022 the public water system supervision grant program and the source water petition program, and (2) reauthorizes through FY2022 and revises the drinking water state revolving fund.</p> <p>The bill expands requirements for public water systems to monitor unregulated containments.</p> <p>The EPA must establish a grant program for the replacement of drinking water fountains that contain lead in schools and day care facilities.</p> <p>This bill amends the Emergency Planning and Community Right-To-Know Act of 1986 to ensure that states and community water systems are notified of a release of a contaminant into their source waters.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3387v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-04-09">
<action-date>2017-07-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Drinking Water System Improvement Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to address the infrastructure of public water systems and compliance by the systems with drinking water regulations.</p> <p>Community water systems must include in their consumer confidence reports information about: (1) corrosion control efforts, (2) any exceedances of the lead action level for which corrective action has been required, and (3) violations that occurred. The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) must revise regulations for consumer confidence reports as outlined by the bill.</p> <p>The EPA must develop a strategic plan for improving the accuracy and availability of compliance monitoring data.</p> <p>Within five years and every five years thereafter, the EPA must review, and if appropriate, update educational materials concerning best practices for asset management strategies that may be used by public water systems.</p> <p>The bill: (1) reauthorizes through FY2022 the public water system supervision grant program and the source water petition program, and (2) reauthorizes through FY2022 and revises the drinking water state revolving fund.</p> <p>The EPA must review and report to the public on existing and potential methods, means, equipment, and technologies for the treatment and distribution of drinking water.</p> <p>The EPA must also establish a grant program for the replacement of drinking water fountains that contain lead in schools and day care facilities.</p> <p>This bill amends the Emergency Planning and Community Right-To-Know Act of 1986 to ensure that states and community water systems are notified of a release of a contaminant into their source waters.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
