<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1687" measure-id="id115hr1687" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-22" update-date="2017-06-14">
<title>Tax Relief for Guard and Reserve Training Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1687v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-14">
<action-date>2017-03-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Tax Relief for Guard and Reserve Training Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the tax deductions for expenses in connection with the performance of services as a member of a reserve component of the Armed Forces, to: (1) reduce from 100 miles to 50 miles (without regard to whether such period includes an overnight stay) the distance from home requirement for the above-the-line deduction; and (2) exempt from the 2% floor on miscellaneous itemized deductions the deductions allowed that consist of expenses paid or incurred in connection with the performance of such services for any period (without regard to whether such period includes an overnight stay) during which the individual is more than 50 miles away from home in connection with the services. </p> <p>(Above-the-line deductions are subtracted from gross income to arrive at adjusted gross income. Under current law, miscellaneous itemized deductions are only allowed if the aggregate of the deductions exceeds 2% of the taxpayer's adjusted gross income.)</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
