<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3461" measure-id="id115hr3461" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-27" update-date="2017-09-05">
<title>Improving Care for Vulnerable Older Citizens through Workforce Advancement Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3461v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-05">
<action-date>2017-07-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Improving Care for Vulnerable Older Citizens through Workforce Advancement Act of 2017 </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Older Americans Act of 1965 to direct the Administration on Aging to award grants for eligible&nbsp;consortia of health care providers and facilities to carry out six separate demonstration projects that focus on care coordination and service delivery for older individuals who have&nbsp;chronic illness or are at risk of institutional placement. Specifically, demonstration projects shall focus on: (1) using the abilities of direct-care workers to promote smooth transitions in care and help prevent unnecessary hospital readmissions, (2) maintaining and improving the health status of those with multiple chronic conditions and long-term needs, and (3) training direct-care workers to take on deeper clinical responsibilities</s>.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
