<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1076" measure-id="id115hr1076" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-15" update-date="2017-08-07">
<title>Protect Our Sanctuary Cities Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1076v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-07">
<action-date>2017-02-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Protect Our Sanctuary Cities Act</strong></p> <p>This bill: (1) nullifies section 9 of Executive Order 13768 (Enhancing Public Safety in the Interior of the United States), and (2) prohibits using appropriations to promulgate or enforce any executive order that compels state, city, or local officials to assist federal authorities in the removal of aliens from the United States. </p> <p>Section 9 authorizes: (1) the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to designate a state or local subdivision that fails to make required communications with the Immigration and Naturalization Service regarding the citizenship or immigration status of any individual as a sanctuary jurisdiction, and (2) DHS and the Department of Justice (DOJ) to deny such jurisdictions federal grants, except as deemed necessary for law enforcement purposes. It also directs DOJ to take appropriate enforcement action against any such jurisdiction or any entity that has in effect a statute, policy, or practice that prevents or hinders the enforcement of federal law. </p> <p> DHS shall submit a report on ways to strengthen immigrant community trust in DHS. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
