<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="789" measure-id="id115hr789" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-01" update-date="2017-08-04">
<title>No Bonuses for Terrorists Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr789v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-04">
<action-date>2017-02-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>No Bonuses for Terrorists Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to prohibit the provision of assistance to the Palestinian Authority (PA) and the Palestinian Liberation Organization (PLO) until the Department of State has certified that the PA and the PLO have ceased paying financial compensation or any other benefit not generally available to the Palestinian population at large to the families of Palestinians killed in connection with an act of terrorism. Recertification is required every six months.</p> <p>If the State Department is unable to make such a certification: (1) it shall report to Congress why it is unable to do so, and (2) funds that otherwise would have been provided to the PA and the PLO shall be transferred and made available to the Department of Defense for assistance to Israel for procurement of the Iron Dome defense system.</p> <p> The State Department shall annually report on the amount of bonuses, financial compensation, or other benefits that have been disbursed by the PA and the PLO in the preceding 12 months. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
