<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2966" measure-id="id115hr2966" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-20" update-date="2017-10-06">
<title>United States-Cuba Normalization Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2966v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-06">
<action-date>2017-06-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>United States-Cuba Normalization Act of 2017</strong> <p>This bill repeals the embargo on trade with Cuba. <p>The bill: (1) makes ineffective certain prohibitions on exports to Cuba; (2) extends nondiscriminatory treatment (normal trade relations) to Cuban products; (3) prohibits regulation or banning of travel to and from Cuba, or of any transactions incident to such travel, by U.S. citizens or residents; and (4) repeals the President's authority to continue direct restrictions on trade with Cuba. <p>The President shall take steps necessary to: (1) conduct negotiations with Cuba on settling claims of U.S. nationals for the taking of property by the Cuban government, and (2) engage in bilateral dialogue with Cuba on securing the protection of internationally recognized human rights.<p>The President may establish specified export controls and trade restrictions with respect to Cuba as of the effective date of this bill. <p> The President may impose export controls and exercise certain emergency economic authorities with respect to Cuba only if there is an unusual threat to U.S. national security. <p> The bill repeals: (1) the Cuban Democracy Act of 1992, (2) the Cuban Liberty and Democratic Solidarity (LIBERTAD) Act of 1996, (3) the prohibition against allocation of the annual sugar quota to a country unless such country verifies that it does not import Cuban sugar for reexport to the United States, and (4) the prohibition on transactions or payments respecting certain U.S. intellectual property. <p> Cuba is removed from the list of state sponsors of terrorism subject to agricultural and medical export restrictions. <p>Common carriers may provide telecommunications services, including installations and repairs, between the United States and Cuba. <p> The Department of the Treasury may not limit the amount of remittances to Cuba that may be made by any person subject to U.S. jurisdiction. <p> <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
