<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4779" measure-id="id115hr4779" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2018-01-11" update-date="2018-04-04">
<title>REFER Act of 2018</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4779v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-04-04">
<action-date>2018-01-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Restraining Excessive Federal Enforcement &amp; Regulations of Cannabis Act of 2018 or the REFER Act of 2018</b></p> <p>This bill prohibits the use of funds made available by Congress to a federal department or agency:</p> <ul> <li> to restrict a state or local law that authorizes the use, distribution, possession, or cultivation of cannabis;</li> <li>to detain, prosecute, sentence, or initiate civil proceedings against an individual, business, or property involved in cannabis-related activities in accordance with state or local law; or</li> <li>to penalize a financial institution for providing financial services to a business engaged in cannabis-related activities in compliance with state or local law.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
