<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4951" measure-id="id115hr4951" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2018-02-06" update-date="2018-02-15">
<title>Monuments Protection Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4951v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-15">
<action-date>2018-02-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Monuments Protection Act</b> </p> <p>This bill directs the Departments of the Interior and Agriculture (USDA) to enter into an agreement with a state, the District of Columbia, a federally recognized Indian tribe, a U.S. territory or possession, or a political subdivision that offers to assume activities to resume or continue operations and public access to any covered unit when those activities would not otherwise be carried out: (1) because there is a lapse in available federal funds as a result of a failure to enact appropriations, or (2) because of a failure of the federal government to make sufficient funds available to operate such unit. </p> <p>The bill defines a &quot;covered unit&quot; to mean:</p> <ul> <li>public lands;</li> <li>units of the National Park System, the National Wildlife Refuge System, and the National Forest System; </li> <li>federally owned open air monuments and memorials; and </li> <li>federally owned roads and off ramps on all such lands. </li> </ul> <p>The bill requires Interior and USDA to reimburse an entity for such activities once funds are made available. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
