<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2941" measure-id="id115hr2941" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-20" update-date="2018-01-25">
<title>Kisatchie National Forest Land Conveyance Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2941v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-25">
<action-date>2017-10-31</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House reported version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Kisatchie National Forest Land Conveyance Act</b></p> <p> (Sec. 4) The bill authorizes the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to sell specified federal land in the Kisatchie National Forest in Winn Parish, Louisiana, for fair market value. USDA shall convey a portion of that land to Collins Camp Properties, Inc. </p> <p>USDA may configure the federal land to be conveyed so as to maximize the marketability of the conveyance or to achieve management objectives. </p> <p>Consideration for a conveyance of federal land under this bill shall be in cash. </p> <p>In any conveyance of federal land under this bill, USDA shall meet disclosure requirements for hazardous substances but shall not otherwise be required to remediate or abate such substances. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) USDA shall deposit the proceeds from such conveyances in the fund established under the Sisk Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 6) USDA shall require Collins Camp Properties to pay at closing reasonable appraisal costs and the cost of any administrative and environmental analyses required by law. </p> <p>An offer by Collins Camp Properties for acquiring the federal land must be accompanied by a written statement from each holder of a Forest Service special use authorization with respect to such land specifying that the holder agrees to relinquish that authorization upon the conveyance of such land to Collins Camp Properties. If a holder fails to furnish such a written statement, USDA shall require Collins Camp Properties to administer that authorization in accordance with its terms until it expires.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2941v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-18">
<action-date>2017-10-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Kisatchie National Forest Land Conveyance Act</b></p> <p> (Sec. 4) The bill authorizes the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to sell specified federal land in the Kisatchie National Forest in Winn Parish, Louisiana, for fair market value. USDA shall convey a portion of that land to Collins Camp Properties, Inc. </p> <p>USDA may configure the federal land to be conveyed so as to maximize the marketability of the conveyance or to achieve management objectives. </p> <p>Consideration for a conveyance of federal land under this bill shall be in cash. </p> <p>In any conveyance of federal land under this bill, USDA shall meet disclosure requirements for hazardous substances but shall not otherwise be required to remediate or abate such substances. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) USDA shall deposit the proceeds from such conveyances in the fund established under the Sisk Act. </p> <p>(Sec. 6) USDA shall require Collins Camp Properties to pay at closing reasonable appraisal costs and the cost of any administrative and environmental analyses required by law. </p> <p>An offer by Collins Camp Properties for acquiring the federal land must be accompanied by a written statement from each holder of a Forest Service special use authorization with respect to such land specifying that the holder agrees to relinquish that authorization upon the conveyance of such land to Collins Camp Properties. If a holder fails to furnish such a written statement, USDA shall require Collins Camp Properties to administer that authorization in accordance with its terms until it expires.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2941v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-05">
<action-date>2017-06-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Kisatchie National Forest Land Conveyance Act</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to sell specified federal land in Winn Parish, Louisiana. USDA shall convey a portion of that land to Collins Camp Properties, Inc.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
