<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3247" measure-id="id115hr3247" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-14" update-date="2018-03-19">
<title>Protect United States Security in the Arctic Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3247v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-19">
<action-date>2017-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protect United States Security in the Arctic Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill instructs the President to submit to Congress a strategy to protect U.S. interests in the Arctic region. </p> <p>Such strategy shall include goals to:</p> <ul> <li>improve telecommunications, navigation, ocean and coastal mapping, and Coast Guard and other infrastructure to support a sustained security and emergency response presence for Alaska;</li> <li>direct the U.S. representative to the Arctic Council to use the voice and vote of the United States to conduct increased confidence-building and cooperative security measures with other member countries;</li> <li>support climate resilience efforts across the Arctic region; and </li> <li>sustain robust research funding to understand the ongoing climate changes in the Arctic region and their global impact. </li> </ul> <p>The Government Accountability Office (GAO) shall submit a report that assesses the cost and procurement schedule for new U.S. icebreakers. </p> <p>Consistent with the recapitalization plan for the acquisition of heavy and medium icebreakers to meet Coast Guard statutory missions in the polar regions, the department in which the Coast Guard is operating: (1) may enter into a contract to procure up to three Coast Guard heavy icebreakers for the defense of U.S. interests in the Arctic region, beginning In FY2018; and (2) shall report on its plans to procure and sustain icebreakers in addition to the vessels authorized to be procured under such contract and to ensure that at least three Coast Guard icebreakers are ready for operations at all times. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
