<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2704" measure-id="id115hr2704" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-25" update-date="2017-09-27">
<title>Purple Heart Heroes Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2704v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-27">
<action-date>2017-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Purple Heart Heroes Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill permits Purple Heart veterans and their dependents to use commissary stores and MWR retail facilities on the same basis as members of the Armed Forces entitled to retired or retainer pay and their dependents. </p> <p>A &quot;Purple Heart veteran&quot; is a veteran who has a disability that is: (1) attributable to an injury for which the veteran was awarded the Purple Heart, and (2) compensable under the laws administered by the Department of Veterans Affairs. </p> <p>An "MWR retail facility" means an exchange store or other revenue-generating facility operated by nonappropriated fund activities of the Department of Defense for the morale, welfare, and recreation of members of the Armed Forces.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
