<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2702" measure-id="id115hr2702" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-25" update-date="2018-02-07">
<title>SBIR Commercialization Assistance Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2702v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-07">
<action-date>2017-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>SBIR Commercialization Assistance Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Small Business Act to require a federal agency required to have a Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) program (covered agency) to implement a commercialization assistance pilot program (CAPP), under which an eligible entity may received a subsequent Phase II SBIR award through FY2022, unless the Small Business Administration determines that the agency already has a program sufficiently similar to a CAPP.</p> <p>An eligible entity is a small business concern that has received a Phase II award under an SBIR program and an additional Phase II SBIR award from the covered agency to which such small business concern is applying for the subsequent award.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must evaluate and report to Congress on CAPP, including a summary of activities and results and recommendations for CAPP improvement.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
