<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1344" measure-id="id115hr1344" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-02" update-date="2017-05-01">
<title>State Cyber Resiliency Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1344v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-01">
<action-date>2017-03-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>State Cyber Resiliency Act</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to administer a State Cyber Resiliency Grant Program to assist state, local, and tribal governments in preventing, preparing for, protecting against, and responding to cyber threats.</p> <p>The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) may award states with planning and biennial implementation grants under the program to:</p> <ul> <li>adopt cybersecurity best practices; </li> <li>mitigate talent gaps in government workforces; </li> <li>protect public safety answering points, emergency communications, and continuity of communications during catastrophic disruption; </li> <li>mitigate threats to critical infrastructure or key resources; </li> <li>coordinate with neighboring states or countries, National Guard units, or information sharing and analysis organizations; and</li> <li>establish scholarships or apprenticeships to provide financial assistance to state residents pursuing cybersecurity education who commit to working for state government. </li> </ul> <p>The bill sets forth requirements for distribution of awarded amounts to local and tribal governments within states and for consultation with local and regional officials. </p> <p>The Committee for Cyber Resiliency Grants is established to: (1) promulgate guidance for states to develop applications for such cyber resiliency grants; (2) provide DHS and states with recommendations regarding the approval of state plans or applications; and (3) evaluate, and report to Congress regarding, the progress of states in implementing plans.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
