<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1738" measure-id="id115hr1738" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-27" update-date="2017-04-04">
<title>Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta National Heritage Area Establishment Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1738v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-04-04">
<action-date>2017-03-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta National Heritage Area Establishment Act</b></p> <p>This bill establishes the Sacramento-San Joaquin Delta National Heritage Area in California. </p> <p> The Delta Protection Commission is designated as the local coordinating entity for the heritage area. </p> <p> The Commission shall submit a proposed management plan for the heritage area to the Department of the Interior for approval. </p> <p> The management plan shall not be approved until Interior has received certification from the Commission that the Delta Stewardship Council has reviewed such plan for consistency with the plan adopted by the Council pursuant to state law. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
