<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2850" measure-id="id115hr2850" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-08" update-date="2018-03-06">
<title>Military Patron Protection Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2850v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-06">
<action-date>2017-06-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Military Patron Protection Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill establishes the Military Resale Patron Benefits Advisory Commission to advise the Department of Defense (DOD) on:</p> <ul> <li>the effects of military commissary and exchange operations on their patrons and on morale, welfare, and recreation programs;</li> <li>the sources and uses of commissary and exchange revenues; and </li> <li>fulfillment of the requirement to implement a comprehensive strategy to optimize management practices across the defense commissary and exchange systems. </li> </ul> <p>The Commission shall advise DOD on proposed reforms to commissary and exchange operations that could affect: </p> <ul> <li>the use of revenue;</li> <li>the morale, welfare, and recreation programs provided for, and the morale of, military members and dependents; and</li> <li>philanthropic programs that benefit members and their families. </li> </ul> <p>The bill requires DOD to: (1) report annually on the use of funds generated by commissaries and exchanges, the constitution and purpose of the boards of directors of the Military Exchanges and Commissary Operations and any determination to use such funds, and DOD responses to any commission proposals; (2) notify Congress before expending certain funds; and (3) notify Congress before taking action that would reduce a contract awarded by the Defense Commissary Agency to a small, veteran-owned, woman-owned, or disadvantaged business concern or a qualified nonprofit agency for the blind or other severely disabled.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
