<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3210" measure-id="id115hr3210" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-12" update-date="2017-09-08">
<title>SECRET Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3210v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-08">
<action-date>2017-07-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on July 25, 2017. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Securely Expediting Clearances Through Reporting Transparency Act of 2017 or the SECRET Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Office of Personnel Management's National Background Investigations Bureau (NBIB) to report on the backlog of security clearance investigations. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) Additionally, the NBIB must report on the process for conducting and adjudicating security clearance investigations for personnel in the Executive Office of the President.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) Finally, the NBIB must report on the duplicative costs of implementing a plan for the Defense Security Service to conduct, after October 1, 2017, security investigations for Department of Defense (DOD) personnel whose investigations are adjudicated by DOD's Consolidated Adjudication Facility. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3210v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-05">
<action-date>2017-07-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Securely Expediting Clearances Through Reporting Transparency Act of 2017 or the SECRET Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Office of Personnel Management's National Background Investigations Bureau (NBIB) to report on the backlog of security clearance investigations. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) Additionally, the NBIB must report on the process for conducting and adjudicating security clearance investigations for personnel in the Executive Office of the President.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) Finally, the NBIB must report on the duplicative costs of implementing a plan for the Defense Security Service to conduct, after October 1, 2017, security investigations for Department of Defense (DOD) personnel whose investigations are adjudicated by DOD's Consolidated Adjudication Facility. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3210v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-25">
<action-date>2017-07-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Securely Expediting Clearances Through Reporting Transparency Act of 2017 or the SECRET Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Office of Personnel Management's National Background Investigations Bureau to report on the backlog of security clearance investigations. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
