<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3887" measure-id="id115hr3887" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-28" update-date="2018-01-29">
<title>SAFE at Home Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3887v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-29">
<action-date>2017-09-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Safeguarding Addresses From Emerging at Home Act or the SAFE at Home Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires each federal agency and federal court to accept, for any purpose for which an individual is required to provide an address to the agency or court, an address designated to that individual pursuant to an address confidentiality program. An individual who provides an address pursuant to such a program shall not be subject to any federal regulatory, civil, or criminal penalties for providing such address in lieu of the individual's actual physical address.</p> <p>An address confidentiality program is a state-implemented program that provides a designated address in lieu of the individual's actual physical address to an individual who: (1) is determined to be at risk to be a victim of domestic violence, rape, sexual assault, human trafficking, or stalking or who otherwise fears for their safety; or (2) resides in the same household as such an individual.</p> <p>An agency or court seeking to acquire such individual's actual address shall comply with applicable procedures of such a program. Such address shall be considered confidential and shall not be subject to a Freedom of Information Act request.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
