<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1471" measure-id="id115hr1471" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-09" update-date="2017-07-17">
<title>To suspend assistance to countries denying or delaying accepting aliens ordered removed from the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1471v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-17">
<action-date>2017-03-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill directs: (1) the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to annually submit to Congress a list of each country that it determines denies or unreasonably delays accepting an alien who is a citizen, subject, national, or resident of that country after DHS asks whether the government will accept the alien ordered removed under the Immigration and Nationality Act; and (2) the President to suspend assistance to each country on such list.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
