<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4567" measure-id="id115hr4567" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-12-06" update-date="2018-02-09">
<title>DHS Overseas Personnel Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4567v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-09">
<action-date>2017-12-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>DHS Overseas Personnel Enhancement Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), by 90 days after the submission of the three-year strategy for DHS international programs required under the National Defense Authorization Act for FY2017, to brief Congress regarding DHS personnel with primary duties that take place outside of the United States.</p> <p>The briefing shall include:</p> <ul> <li>a detailed summary of each type of personnel position with such duties and how each such position contributes to DHS's counterterrorism mission, </li> <li>information related to how the geographic and regional placement of such positions contributes to such mission, </li> <li>information related to the position-specific training received by such personnel before and during placement at a foreign location, and </li> <li>challenges that may impede the communication of counterterrorism information between DHS personnel at foreign locations and DHS entities in the United States. </li></ul> <p>DHS shall submit to Congress a plan to enhance the effectiveness of DHS personnel at foreign locations. The plan shall include proposals to:</p> <ul> <li>improve efforts of such personnel for purposes of providing foreign partner capacity development and furthering DHS's counterterrorism mission; </li> <li>redeploy DHS personnel as appropriate to respond to changing threats to the United States; </li> <li>enhance collaboration among DHS personnel at foreign locations, other federal personnel at foreign locations, and foreign partners; and </li> <li>improve the communication of counterterrorism information between DHS personnel at foreign locations and DHS entities in the United States. </li></ul> <ul></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
