<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1258" measure-id="id115hr1258" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-28" update-date="2017-08-22">
<title>HSA Technical Corrections Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1258v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-22">
<action-date>2017-04-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>HSA Technical Corrections Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill makes technical corrections to the Homeland Security Act of 2002.</p> <p>The bill includes among those appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate: (1) the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, and (2) a Commandant of the Coast Guard.</p> <p>References to U.S. Customs and Border Protection, U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement are updated.</p> <p>"Nuclear Incident Response Team" is defined as a resource that includes: (1) those entities of the Department of Energy that perform nuclear or radiological emergency support functions (including accident response, search response, advisory, and technical operations functions), radiation exposure functions at the medical assistance facility known as the Radiation Emergency Assistance Center/Training Site (REAC/TS), radiological assistance functions, and related functions; and (2) those entities of the Environmental Protection Agency that perform such support functions (including radiological emergency response functions) and related functions. </p> <p>The bill updates references to: (1)&nbsp;the Director of Central Intelligence to read as the Director of National Intelligence, and (2) "Hawaiian native-serving" to read as "Native Hawaiian-serving."</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1258v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-12">
<action-date>2017-02-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>HSA Technical Corrections Act</strong></p> <p>This bill makes technical corrections to the Homeland Security Act of 2002.</p>  <p>The bill includes among those appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate: (1) the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, and (2) a Commandant of the Coast Guard.</p> <p>References to U.S. Customs and Border Protection, U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement are updated.</p> <p>&quot;Nuclear Incident Response Team&quot; is defined as a resource that includes: (1) those entities of the Department of Energy that perform nuclear or radiological emergency support functions (including accident response, search response, advisory, and technical operations functions), radiation exposure functions at the medical assistance facility known as the Radiation Emergency Assistance Center/Training Site (REAC/TS), radiological assistance functions, and related functions; and (2) those entities of the Environmental Protection Agency that perform such support functions (including radiological emergency response functions) and related functions. </p> <p>The bill updates references to: (1) the Director of Central Intelligence to read as the Director of National Intelligence, and (2) &quot;Hawaiian native-serving&quot; to read as &quot;Native Hawaiian-serving.&quot;</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
