<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1809" measure-id="id115hr1809" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-30" update-date="2018-03-15">
<title>Juvenile Justice Reform Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1809v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-15">
<action-date>2017-05-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Juvenile Justice Reform Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 (JJDPA) to modify and reauthorize juvenile justice programs and activities.</p> <p>Specifically, it:</p> <ul> <li> revises and reauthorizes through FY2022 programs and activities under title II of the JJDPA, including the State Formula Grant Program and the activities of the Department of Justice's Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention (OJJDP);</li> <li>revises and expands the purpose areas of the JJDPA;</li> <li>expands membership on the Coordinating Council on Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention to include the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use and the Secretary of the Interior;</li> <li>expands requirements for the OJJDP's annual report on juveniles in custody;</li> <li>modifies the required components of a state's juvenile justice and prevention plan;</li> <li>modifies the four core requirements with which a state must comply to receive a full allocation of funds under the State Formula Grant Program; and</li> <li>repeals the Juvenile Delinquency Prevention Block Grant program.</li> </ul> <p>The bill revises, restructures, and reauthorizes through FY2022 programs under title V of the JJDPA, including the Incentive Grants for Local Delinquency Prevention Program.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must evaluate the OJJDP's performance and audit selected grant recipients.</p> <p>The bill subjects juvenile justice grants to accountability provisions.</p> <p>Finally, it reauthorizes through FY2022 programs and activities: (1) for missing and exploited children, under title IV of the JJDPA; and (2) for runaway and homeless youth, under title III of the JJDPA.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1809v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-08">
<action-date>2017-03-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Juvenile Justice Reform Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 (JJDPA) to modify and reauthorize juvenile justice programs and activities. </p> <p>Specifically, it: </p> <ul> <li> revises and reauthorizes through FY2022 programs and activities under title II of the JJDPA, including the State Formula Grant Program and the activities of the Department of Justice's Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention (OJJDP); </li> <li>revises and expands the purpose areas of the JJDPA; </li> <li>expands membership on the Coordinating Council on Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention to include the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use and the Secretary of the Interior; </li> <li>expands requirements for the OJJDP's annual report on juveniles in custody; </li> <li>modifies the required components of a state's juvenile justice and prevention plan; </li> <li>modifies the four core requirements with which a state must comply to receive a full allocation of funds under the State Formula Grant Program; and </li> <li>repeals the Juvenile Delinquency Prevention Block Grant program. </li> </ul> <p>The bill revises, restructures, and reauthorizes through FY2022 programs under title V of the JJDPA, including the Incentive Grants for Local Delinquency Prevention Program. </p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must evaluate the OJJDP's performance and audit selected grant recipients.</p> <p>The bill subjects juvenile justice grants to accountability provisions.</p> <p>Finally, it reauthorizes through FY2022 programs and activities: (1) for missing and exploited children, under title IV of the JJDPA; and (2) for runaway and homeless youth, under title III of the JJDPA. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
