<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1342" measure-id="id115hr1342" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-02" update-date="2017-06-19">
<title>FILCCA of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1342v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-19">
<action-date>2017-03-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Federal Immigration Law Campus Compliance Act of 2017 or the FILCCA of 2017</strong></p> <p> This bill withholds reimbursement for indirect costs associated with federal research and development grants from an institution of higher learning that does not comply with a lawful request for information about, or a detainer pertaining to, an alien made by a federal immigration officer or employee. </p> <p>A state or political subdivision that complies with a detainer is deemed to be an agent of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), has authority available to DHS to take actions to comply with the detainer, and shall not be liable for such actions. </p> <p>DHS may issue a detainer for an alien who is in federal, state, or local custody requesting: (1) all relevant information collected pertaining to such alien and notification of his or her future release, or (2) continued detention until DHS assumes custody. </p> <p>DHS may request from any entity that receives federal funds other immigration-related information pertaining to an alien that is not otherwise precluded from disclosure. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
