<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2428" measure-id="id115hr2428" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-16" update-date="2017-11-16">
<title>Accurate Workplace Injury and Illness Records Restoration Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2428v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-16">
<action-date>2017-05-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Accurate Workplace Injury and Illness Records Restoration Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to specify that the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) may issue a citation for a violation of workplace safety requirements within the six-month period following an employer satisfying the requirements. Current law includes a limitation period that prevents OSHA from issuing citations six months after the occurrence of a violation. Thus, this bill specifies that the statute of limitations is tolled if there is a continuing violation of the requirements. </p> <p>OSHA must issue a rule that amends its record keeping regulations to clarify that the duty to make and maintain accurate records of work-related injuries and illnesses: (1) is an ongoing obligation, (2) continues for as long as the employer is required to keep records of the recordable injury or illness, and (3) does not expire solely because the employer fails to create the necessary records when first required to do so.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
