<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3910" measure-id="id115hr3910" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-02" update-date="2018-04-04">
<title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make lifetime income and managed account options of defined contribution retirement savings plans portable.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3910v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-04-04">
<action-date>2017-10-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow distributions from certain tax-favored employer-sponsored retirement plans if a lifetime income investment or managed account investment is no longer authorized to be held as an investment option under the plan. </p> <p>If a lifetime income or managed account investment is no longer authorized to be held as an investment option under the plan, the bill allows: (1) qualified distributions of a lifetime income investment or a managed account investment, or (2) distributions of a lifetime income investment in the form of a qualified plan distribution annuity contract. </p> <p>A &quot;qualified distribution&quot; is a direct trustee-to-trustee transfer to an eligible retirement plan. A &quot;qualified plan distribution annuity contract&quot; is an annuity contract purchased for a participant and distributed to the participant by an employer-sponsored retirement plan. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
