<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2906" measure-id="id115hr2906" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-15" update-date="2017-09-20">
<title>Ensuring Access to General Surgery Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2906v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-20">
<action-date>2017-06-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Ensuring Access to General Surgery Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to study access by underserved populations to general surgeons, including: (1) whether the health professional shortage area designation under the National Health Service Corps program accurately assesses adequacy of access and whether another measure would be more accurate, and (2) potential methodologies for designating general surgery shortage areas.</p> <p>HHS must publish data comparing the availability and need of general surgery services in urban, suburban, and rural areas. </p> <p>HHS may establish a methodology for designating general surgery shortage areas and make such designations. HHS must publish a list of general surgery shortage areas.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
