<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1125" measure-id="id115hr1125" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-16" update-date="2017-08-07">
<title>VISA Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1125v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-07">
<action-date>2017-02-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Visa Investigation and Social Media Activity Act of 2017 or the VISA Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to prohibit a petition or application filed with the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) or with a consular officer for the issuance of a visa or the admission of an alien from being approved unless a background check to determine whether the alien is a national security threat or is otherwise ineligible for such visa or admission is completed for: (1) the petitioner or applicant, and (2) each beneficiary or derivative of the petition or application. </p> <p>Such background check shall include a review of the alien's publicly available interactions on, and posting of material to, the Internet (including social media services). </p> <p>An applicant must provide an English translation of his or her documentation.</p> <p>No petition or application for any immigration benefit, except for work authorization, may be approved for an alien who is at least 11 years old unless DHS conducts an in-person interview with such alien. </p> <p>DHS shall begin implementation of an analytics software plan to detect fraud in immigration benefits applications and petitions and to ensure that an applicant or petitioner does not pose a national security threat.</p> <p>The bill requires the deployment of DHS employees to all visa-issuing embassies and consulates.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
