<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4459" measure-id="id115hr4459" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-11-28" update-date="2018-03-20">
<title>Charitable Conservation Easement Program Integrity Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4459v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-20">
<action-date>2017-11-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Charitable Conservation Easement Program Integrity Act of 2017 </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to limit the aggregate amount of a partner's annual tax deductions for qualified conservation contributions of a partnership to 2.5 times the partner's adjusted basis in the partnership. (Under current law, a &quot;qualified conservation contribution&quot; is the contribution of a qualified real property interest to a qualified organization exclusively for conservation purposes.) </p> <p>The limitation applies for the first five years after the individual becomes a partner in the partnership. It does not apply to certain family partnerships. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
