<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2024" measure-id="id115hr2024" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2017-07-05">
<title>End Discriminatory State Taxes for Automobile Renters Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2024v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-05">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>End Discriminatory State Taxes for Automobile Renters Act of 201</strong><b>7</b></p> <p>This bill prohibits state or local taxes that discriminate against the rental of motor vehicles, the business of renting motor vehicles, or motor vehicle rental property, except where such tax is imposed as of the enactment date of this bill, the tax does not lapse, the tax rate does not increase, and the tax base for such tax does not change. </p> <p>A tax that is imposed on the rental of motor vehicles or a motor vehicle rental business is discriminatory if: (1) it is not generally applicable to more than 51% of other rentals of tangible personal property or businesses within a state or locality, or (2) the rate exceeds the generally applicable tax rate on at least 51% of the other rentals of tangible personal property or businesses within the jurisdiction. </p> <p> A tax discriminates against motor vehicle rental property if a state or locality: (1) assesses the property at a value that has a higher ratio to the true market value of the property than the ratio applicable to commercial and industrial property, or (2) levies or collects either a tax on an assessment prohibited by this bill or an ad valorem property tax on motor vehicle rental property at a generally applicable rate that exceeds the rate for commercial and industrial property in the jurisdiction.</p> <p> A person who is aggrieved by a discriminatory tax may bring a civil action in a U.S. district court for damages, injunctive relief, other legal or equitable relief, or declaratory relief. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
