<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4218" measure-id="id115hr4218" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-11-01" update-date="2018-02-09">
<title>Upholding the Integrity of Public Officials Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4218v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-09">
<action-date>2017-11-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Upholding the Integrity of Public Officials Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the federal criminal code to revise the definition of &quot;official act&quot; for purposes of an offense involving bribery of public officials. </p> <p>Currently, an official act is any decision or action on a question, matter, cause, suit, proceeding, or controversy, which may at any time be pending, or which may by law be brought before a public official, in their official capacity. This bill specifies that an official act includes any action taken or to be taken under color of official authority by a public official or person who has been selected to be a public official.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
