<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4610" measure-id="id115hr4610" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-12-11" update-date="2018-01-09">
<title>Receiving Electronic Statements To Improve Retiree Earnings Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4610v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-09">
<action-date>2017-12-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Receiving Electronic Statements To Improve Retiree Earnings Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) and the Internal Revenue Code to authorize the electronic delivery of pension plan documents required to be furnished to a plan participant, beneficiary, or other individual.</p> <p>The system for furnishing such a document must: (1) be designed to result in effective access to the document, (2) permit the recipient to select the electronic means through which the document is received or request paper documents, and (3) protect the confidentiality of personal information. </p> <p>An annual paper notice must be provided describing:</p> <ul> <li>the selection of electronic means for furnishing documents,</li> <li>the right to modify the selection or to elect to receive paper versions of the documents at no additional direct cost and how to make the election, and </li> <li>any election that has been made to receive paper documents. </li> </ul> <p>An electronically furnished document must be prepared and furnished in a manner that is consistent with the style, format, and content requirements for the document. It must also include a notice that apprises the individual of the significance of the document when it is not otherwise reasonably evident as transmitted. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
