<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3607" measure-id="id115hr3607" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-28" update-date="2017-11-14">
<title>To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to establish fees for medical services provided in units of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3607v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-14">
<action-date>2017-07-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill authorizes the Department of the Interior to establish and collect fees for medical services provided to persons in units of the National Park System. </p> <p>The bill establishes the National Park Medical Services Fund, to consist of donations and the fees collected for such services and to be available to Interior for:</p> <ul> <li>providing such services;</li> <li>preparing programmatic analyses and developing management plans for medical facilities, equipment, vehicles, and other needs for, and costs of, such services;</li> <li>providing training related to furnishing such services; and </li> <li>obtaining or improving medical facilities, equipment, vehicles, and other needs and costs of such services. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
