<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3501" measure-id="id115hr3501" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-27" update-date="2017-10-02">
<title>Family-Owned Business Multiemployer Pension Correction Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3501v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-02">
<action-date>2017-07-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Family-Owned Business Multiemployer Pension Correction Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of the Treasury to establish a program to limit the liability of retail employers who do not employ more than 100 employees who are multiemployer pension plan participants (covered small employer) for withdrawing from a multiemployer pension plan to begin making contributions to a collectively bargained plan. A covered small employer is not eligible for such benefit unless Treasury determines that the affected multiemployer plan liabilities do not exceed 1% of total plan liabilities during a specified 3-year period.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
