<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2139" measure-id="id115hr2139" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-25" update-date="2017-11-09">
<title>To amend the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 and title 49, United States Code, with respect to disadvantaged business enterprises, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2139v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-09">
<action-date>2017-04-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 to extend through FY2017 and periodically thereafter the requirement that the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Transportation report annually to Congress on the number of new small business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, including those owned by veterans, that participated in the programs and activities of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA). </p> <p>The list of the top 25 and bottom 25 large and medium hub airports giving disadvantaged small business concerns opportunities to participate in FAA programs and activities, which each such report must contain, shall be drawn only from large and medium hub airports participating in the airport disadvantaged business enterprise (DBE) program.</p> <p>The Department of Transportation shall develop a training program for FAA employees providing guidance and training to entities that certify a small business as a small business concern owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals.</p> <p>Applications for authority to impose a passenger facility charge at a covered airport shall include a detailed description of the airport's good faith efforts to contract with DBEs and small businesses (including those owned by veterans).</p> <p>Beginning in FY2017, the FAA shall require a covered airport to report annually on the number of new DBEs that were awarded a contract or concession during the previous fiscal year. </p> <p>The FAA shall update annually DBE-Connect (or any successor online reporting system) to include information on the number of new DBEs awarded a contract or concession at a covered airport during the previous fiscal year.</p> <p>The FAA shall:</p> <ul> <li>ensure that each covered airport tracks the number of complaints alleging failure of payment to DBE firms performing contract work at that airport, </li> <li>take actions to assess and improve airport compliance with prompt payment regulations, and</li> <li>make such assessment available on an appropriate FAA website.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
