<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3361" measure-id="id115hr3361" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-24" update-date="2018-02-28">
<title>SECURE Firearm Storage Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3361v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-28">
<action-date>2017-07-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Safety Enhancements for Communities Using Reasonable and Effective Firearm Storage Act or the SECURE Firearm Storage Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the federal criminal code to require that all licensed importers, licensed manufacturers, or licensed dealers of firearms shall keep and store all firearms in the business inventory of the licensee at the premises covered by the license. When the premises are not open for business, the licensee shall secure all firearms by complying with prescribed security measures, including trigger guards and safes. Further, when such premises are not open for business, the licensee shall store certain paper records in a secure location. </p> <p>The Department of Justice shall promulgate regulations prescribing additional security requirements as deemed necessary.</p> <p>The bill includes a set of civil penalties, including fines and potential license suspension or revocation, for noncompliance with the foregoing security requirements.</p> <p>An application for a firearms license must describe how the applicant plans to comply with these security requirements.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
