<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3050" measure-id="id115hr3050" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-23" update-date="2018-03-30">
<title>Enhancing State Energy Security Planning and Emergency Preparedness Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3050v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-30">
<action-date>2017-07-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Enhancing State Energy Security Planning and Emergency Preparedness Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec.2)This bill amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to provide financial assistance to states for the implementation, review, and revision of a state energy security plan that assesses the state's existing circumstances and proposes methods to strengthen the ability of the state to have a reliable, secure, and resilient energy infrastructure.</p> <p>A state energy security plan must:</p> <ul> <li>address all fuels, including petroleum products, other liquid fuels, coal, electricity, and natural gas, as well as regulated and unregulated energy providers;</li> <li>provide a state energy profile, including an assessment of energy production, distribution, and end-use;</li> <li>address potential hazards to each energy sector or system, including physical threats and cybersecurity threats and vulnerabilities;</li> <li>provide a risk assessment of energy infrastructure and cross-sector interdependencies;</li> <li>provide a risk mitigation approach to enhance reliability and end-use resilience; and</li> <li>address multi-state, Indian tribe, and regional coordination planning and response and encourage mutual assistance in cyber and physical response plans.</li> </ul> <p>In developing an energy security plan, a state must coordinate with entities responsible for maintaining fuel or electric reliability, including public utilities and private energy providers.</p> <p>Upon request of a state, the Department of Energy (DOE) may provide assistance in the development, implementation, or revision of a state energy security plan.</p> <p>DOE's authority to carry out this bill's provisions expires on October 31, 2022. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3050v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-30">
<action-date>2017-07-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Enhancing State Energy Security Planning and Emergency Preparedness Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec.2)This bill amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to provide financial assistance to states for the implementation, review, and revision of a state energy security plan that assesses the state's existing circumstances and proposes methods to strengthen the ability of the state to have a reliable, secure, and resilient energy infrastructure.</p> <p>A state energy security plan must:</p> <ul> <li>address all fuels, including petroleum products, other liquid fuels, coal, electricity, and natural gas, as well as regulated and unregulated energy providers;</li> <li>provide a state energy profile, including an assessment of energy production, distribution, and end-use;</li> <li>address potential hazards to each energy sector or system, including physical threats and cybersecurity threats and vulnerabilities;</li> <li>provide a risk assessment of energy infrastructure and cross-sector interdependencies;</li> <li>provide a risk mitigation approach to enhance reliability and end-use resilience; and</li> <li>address multi-state, Indian tribe, and regional coordination planning and response and encourage mutual assistance in cyber and physical response plans.</li> </ul> <p>In developing an energy security plan, a state must coordinate with entities responsible for maintaining fuel or electric reliability, including public utilities and private energy providers.</p> <p>Upon request of a state, the Department of Energy (DOE) may provide assistance in the development, implementation, or revision of a state energy security plan.</p> <p>DOE's authority to carry out this bill's provisions expires on October 31, 2022. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3050v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-19">
<action-date>2017-06-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Enhancing State Energy Security Planning and Emergency Preparedness Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to provide financial assistance to states for the implementation, review, and revision of a state energy security plan that assesses the state's existing circumstances and proposes methods to strengthen the ability of the state to have a reliable, secure, and resilient energy infrastructure.</p> <p>A state energy security plan must contain specified content, including a risk assessment of energy infrastructure and cross-sector interdependencies, and address potential hazards to each energy sector or system, including physical threats and cybersecurity threats.</p>  <p>Upon request of a state, the Department of Energy may provide information and technical assistance, and other assistance, in the development, implementation, or revision of a state energy security plan.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
