<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2835" measure-id="id115hr2835" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-08" update-date="2017-12-06">
<title>To amend the Small Business Act to waive the guarantee fee for loans of not more than $150,000 provided to veterans and spouses of veterans under the Export Working Capital, International Trade, and Export Express programs.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2835v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-06">
<action-date>2017-06-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Small Business Act to prohibit the Small Business Administration (SBA) from assessing a guarantee fee in connection with a loan of not more than $150,000 made to a veteran or spouse of a veteran beginning the first fiscal year after enactment of this bill under the SBA's Export Working Capital, International Trade, or Export Express programs.</p> <p>If the President's budget for the upcoming fiscal year includes a cost for such a program that is above zero, this prohibition shall not apply to loans made during such upcoming fiscal year.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
