<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2112" measure-id="id115hr2112" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-20" update-date="2017-07-18">
<title>Federal Government Decentralization Commission Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2112v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-18">
<action-date>2017-04-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Federal Government Decentralization Commission Act</strong></p> <p>This bill establishes in the General Services Administration the Federal Government Decentralization Commission to study and submit a plan for the relocation of executive agencies or divisions of executive agencies outside the Washington metropolitan area.</p> <p>The plan shall include:</p> <ul> <li>an identification of such new locations, prioritized by relocation to low-income communities or to areas with expertise in the mission and goal of the agency or division;</li> <li>a consideration of national security implications;</li> <li>an economic and workforce development study on how the relocation would impact the new location; and </li> <li>a list of potential site acquisitions and a partial prospectus for such agencies or divisions, including a brief description of the building to be constructed, altered, or leased, the location of the building, and an estimate of the maximum cost of the acquisition and the relocation. <p> </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
