<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3372" measure-id="id115hr3372" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-24" update-date="2018-03-14">
<title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for the restoration of entitlement to educational assistance and other relief for veterans affected by school closure or disapproval, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3372v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-14">
<action-date>2017-07-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill provides that if a veteran or reservist is forced to discontinue a certain course or program as a result of a school closure or disapproval of a necessary course and did not receive credit or lost training time toward completion of the education program, Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) educational assistance payments shall not, for a specified period, be: </p> <ul> <li> charged against the individual's entitlement to educational assistance, or </li> <li> counted against the aggregate period for which such assistance may be provided.</li> </ul> <p>The bill, with an exception, applies to education courses and programs discontinued after January 1, 2015.</p> <p>The VA may continue to pay educational assistance and subsistence allowances to eligible veterans and eligible persons enrolled in specified courses for up to 4 weeks in any 12-month period when schools are temporarily closed under an established policy based on a presidential executive order or due to an emergency.</p> <p> The VA shall, within five business days after receiving notice of a closure or intended closure, notify each affected individual of such closure and its effect on the individual's entitlement to educational assistance. </p> <p>The VA may also continue to pay a monthly housing stipend following a permanent school closure or disapproval of a course of study, but only until the earlier of: (1) the end of the term, quarter, or semester during which the school closure or disapproval occurred; and (2) 120 days after the closure or disapproval.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
