<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3483" measure-id="id115hr3483" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-27" update-date="2017-12-18">
<title>EITC Eligibility Verification Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3483v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-18">
<action-date>2017-07-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>EITC Eligibility Verification Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the earned income tax credit, to specify that the taxpayer identification number required to be included on the tax returns of eligible individuals is a Social Security number issued to an individual by the Social Security Administration, but only if the number is issued to: (1) a U.S. citizen, or (2) a noncitizen who is permitted to engage in employment in the United States. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
