<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3672" measure-id="id115hr3672" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-05" update-date="2017-09-06">
<title>Making supplemental appropriations for disaster relief requirements for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2017.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3672v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-06">
<action-date>2017-09-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill provides $7.85 billion in FY2017 supplemental appropriations to the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) and the Small Business Administration (SBA) for disaster relief requirements, such as response and recovery efforts from Hurricane Harvey. </p> <p>The bill provides $7.4 billion for FEMA's Disaster Relief Fund and $450 million for the SBA's Disaster Loans Program Account to remain available until expended. </p> <p>The bill designates the funds as an emergency requirement and provides that the funds are only available if the President subsequently designates the funds and transmits the designation to Congress. (Emergency spending is exempt from discretionary spending limits and other budget enforcement rules.) </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
