<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="723" measure-id="id115hr723" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-30" update-date="2017-05-05">
<title>Energy Savings Through Public-Private Partnerships Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr723v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-05">
<action-date>2017-01-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Energy Savings Through Public-Private Partnerships Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the National Energy Conservation Policy Act to revise requirements for energy savings performance contracts and utility energy service contracts (performance contracts). These contracts allow federal agencies to work with private contractors on energy efficiency upgrades to federal facilities, unless the facilities are dams, reservoirs, or hydropower facilities owned or operated by federal agencies.</p> <p>Current law requires federal facility energy managers to evaluate and identify energy and water efficiency measures for federal facilities, but agencies are not required to implement the measures. The bill requires agencies to implement the measures if they are cost-effective.</p> <p>The Department of Energy must report to the President and Congress on each agency's performance contracts, including their investment value and their energy savings.</p> <p>The energy conservation measures that may be contained in performance contracts are expanded by including those involving energy consuming devices and required support structures.</p> <p>Agencies may not limit recognition of operation and maintenance savings associated with energy systems that were modernized or replaced with energy conservation measures and water conservation measures (e.g., lower energy and water bills due to energy efficiency and conservation measures).</p> <p>Agencies may sell or transfer energy savings and apply the proceeds to fund a performance contract.</p> <p>The energy savings that may be contained in performance contracts are expanded to include: (1) the use, sale, or transfer of energy incentives, rebates, or credits (including renewable energy credits) from governments or utilities; and (2) any revenue generated from a reduction in energy or water use, more efficient waste recycling, or additional energy generated from more efficient equipment. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
