<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2865" measure-id="id115hr2865" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-08" update-date="2017-09-13">
<title>Better Education and Skills Training for America's Workforce Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2865v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-13">
<action-date>2017-06-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Better Education and Skills Training for America's Workforce Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow tax credits for: (1) qualified training expenses paid with respect to U.S.-based positions for job trainees who have been unemployed for at least 90 days before enrolling in a training program and have not been employed by the taxpayer during the two-year period before the trainee was hired, and (2) investment in a qualified job training partnership between a private business and an institution of higher education or a labor organization. </p> <p>The bill defines "qualified training expenses" as an eligible trainee's qualified tuition costs, which may include costs for books and enrollment in a training program at an institution of higher education that may include a single course, multiple courses, or a combination of work training and study and that is reasonably necessary for employment with the taxpayer. It terminates the credit for qualified training expenses of job trainees after December 31, 2028.</p> <p>The bill also: (1) requires the Department of the Treasury to establish a Qualified Job Training Partnership program to consider and award certifications for qualified investments eligible for credits to qualified job training partnerships, and (2) authorizes Treasury to make grants to individuals who make an investment in a qualified job training partnership, in lieu of a tax credit. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
