<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3270" measure-id="id115hr3270" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-17" update-date="2017-11-22">
<title>Historic Routes Preservation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3270v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-22">
<action-date>2017-07-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Historic Routes Preservation Act</b></p> <p>This bill allows any state, county, political subdivision or agency of a state, company, or other person asserting the public acceptance of an open-ended grant or dedication of land by the United States for a right-of-way allowing public use and passage for the construction of highways over public lands to file a claim within the 25-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this bill if such claimant, before enactment of this bill: (1) filed a notice of an intent to file suit with respect to a claim asserting the public acceptance of such a right-of-way; or (2) filed suit with respect to such a claim under the Quiet Title Act. </p> <p>The bill sets forth: (1) a procedure for conclusively verifying, proving, and establishing the acceptance of such rights-of-way; and (2) provisions governing judicial review of a denial of such a claim.</p> <p>This bill and the procedures and process implemented under it are applicable to: (1) claims filed after this bill's enactment, and (2) claims filed before this bill's enactment for which a final determination has not been issued. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
