<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3813" measure-id="id115hr3813" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-21" update-date="2018-03-23">
<title>Combating Human Trafficking in Commercial Vehicles Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3813v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-23">
<action-date>2017-12-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<b><br />Combating Human Trafficking in Commercial Vehicles Act</b> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to designate an official to: (1) coordinate human trafficking prevention efforts across DOT modal administrations and with other federal agencies, and (2) take into account the unique challenges of combating human trafficking within different transportation modes.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The bill expands the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration's outreach and education program and DOT's commercial driver's license financial assistance program to include activities for the recognition, prevention, and reporting of human trafficking.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) DOT shall establish an advisory committee on human trafficking. The committee shall: (1) make recommendations on actions DOT can take to help combat human trafficking, and (2) develop recommended best practices for states and state and local transportation stakeholders in combating human trafficking.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3813v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-19">
<action-date>2017-09-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Combating Human Trafficking in Commercial Vehicles Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to designate an official to: (1) coordinate human trafficking prevention efforts across DOT modal administrations and with other federal agencies, and (2) take into account the unique challenges of combating human trafficking within different transportation modes.</p> <p>The bill expands the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration's outreach and education program and DOT's commercial driver's license financial assistance program to include activities for the recognition, prevention, and reporting of human trafficking.</p> <p>DOT shall establish an advisory committee on human trafficking. The committee shall: (1) make recommendations on actions DOT can take to help combat human trafficking, and (2) develop recommended best practices for states and state and local transportation stakeholders in combating human trafficking.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
