<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="49" measure-id="id115hr49" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-03" update-date="2017-07-17">
<title>American Energy Independence and Job Creation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr49v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-17">
<action-date>2017-01-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>American Energy Independence and Job Creation Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) to implement a competitive leasing program for the exploration, development, and production of the oil and gas resources on the Coastal Plain, Arctic National Wildlife Refuge (ANWR), Alaska.</p> <p>The bill amends the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act of 1980 to repeal the prohibition against leasing or other development leading to production of oil and gas from ANWR.</p> <p>The bill requires BLM to conduct its first lease sale within 22 months. This bill also prescribes terms and conditions governing Coastal Plain lease sales, including the establishment of environmental protection standards and the prohibition of exporting oil produced under the lease.</p> <p>The bill establishes the ANWR Alternative Energy Trust Fund, into which shall be deposited 50% of the amount of revenues from federal oil and gas leasing and operations authorized under this bill.The fund must be used to provide grants and incentives for certain energy programs, including grants for clean coal power and renewable energy initiatives, and incentives for hydroelectric production.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
