<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2069" measure-id="id115hr2069" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2017-07-20">
<title>Fostering Stable Housing Opportunities Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2069v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-20">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fostering Stable Housing Opportunities Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to include within the definition of "families" a child who is in foster care and has attained an age such that the provision of foster care for such child will end by reason of the age of the child within six months.</p> <p>Preference is given, subject to certain terms and conditions, for public housing occupancy and section 8 housing assistance under such Act to certain otherwise eligible children who are aging out of foster care and are at-risk for homelessness.</p> <p>The bill amends the Housing Act of 1949 to give preference for rural rental assistance to certain otherwise eligible children who are aging out of foster care and are at-risk of homelessness.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
