<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1824" measure-id="id115hr1824" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-30" update-date="2018-02-21">
<title>Responsibly Addressing the Marijuana Policy Gap Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1824v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-21">
<action-date>2017-03-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Responsibly Addressing the Marijuana Policy Gap Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends various provisions of law and sets forth new provisions: </p> <ul> <li>to eliminate regulatory controls and administrative, civil, and criminal penalties under the Controlled Substances Act for marijuana-related activities authorized by state or tribal law (i.e., state-authorized); </li> <li> to allow businesses that sell marijuana in compliance with state or tribal law to claim certain federal tax credits and deductions; </li> <li>to eliminate restrictions on print and broadcast advertising of state-authorized marijuana-related activities; </li> <li>to create protections for depository institutions that provide financial services to marijuana-related businesses; </li> <li> to specify that a marijuana-related business is entitled to federal bankruptcy protections; </li> <li>to establish a process to expunge criminal records related to certain marijuana-related convictions; </li> <li> to reestablish federal student aid eligibility for certain students convicted of a misdemeanor offense for marijuana possession; </li> <li> to exempt real property from civil forfeiture due to state-authorized marijuana-related conduct; </li> <li>to prohibit the inadmissibility or deportability of aliens for state-authorized marijuana-related conduct; </li> <li> to specify that drug-related criminal activity, which is prohibited in federally assisted housing, does not include state-authorized marijuana-related conduct; </li> <li>to establish a new, separate registration process to facilitate medical marijuana research; </li> <li> to authorize health care providers employed by the Department of Veterans Affairs to recommend participation in state marijuana programs; and </li> <li>to authorize medical providers through an Indian health program to make medical recommendations regarding marijuana. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
