<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3204" measure-id="id115hr3204" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-12" update-date="2017-07-20">
<title>On-the-Job Training Tax Credit Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3204v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-20">
<action-date>2017-07-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>On-the-Job Training Tax Credit Act of 201</strong><b>7</b></p> <p> This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow&nbsp;employers who employ an average of not more than 500 full-time employees during the taxable year an on-the-job training tax credit equal to the lesser of: 50% of the job training program&nbsp;expenditures for a full-time&nbsp;employee participating in a qualified training program, or $5,000. </p> <p>A &quot;qualified training program&quot; is a written plan of study and training that is either: (1) an apprenticeship program registered and certified with the Department of Labor under the National Apprenticeship Act; (2) a program licensed, registered, or certified by the workforce investment board or apprenticeship agency or council of a state or administered in compliance with state apprenticeship laws; (3) a program conducted by a vocational or technical education school, community college, industrial or trade training organization, or labor organization; (4) a program that conforms to apprentice training programs developed or administered by an employer trade group or committee; or (5) an industry-sponsored or -administered program that is clearly identified and commonly recognized. </p> <p>The bill terminates such credit after 2019.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
