<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2201" measure-id="id115hr2201" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-27" update-date="2017-11-03">
<title>Micro Offering Safe Harbor Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2201v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-03">
<action-date>2017-11-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Micro Offering Safe Harbor Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill&nbsp;amends the Securities Act of 1933 to&nbsp;exempt certain micro-offerings from: (1) state regulation of securities offerings, and (2) federal prohibitions&nbsp;related to&nbsp;interstate solicitation. </p> <p>The exempted micro-offerings must meet all of the following requirements:</p> <ul> <li>the purchaser has a substantive pre-existing relationship with the issuer, </li> <li>during the 12-month period preceding the transaction there are no more than 35 purchasers relying on the exemption, and </li> <li>the amount of all securities sold by the issuer (including any amount sold in reliance upon the exemption) during the 12-month period preceding the transaction does not exceed $500,000.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2201v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-16">
<action-date>2017-04-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Micro Offering Safe Harbor Act</strong></p> <p>This bill&nbsp;amends the Securities Act of 1933 to&nbsp;exempt certain micro-offerings from: (1) state regulation of securities offerings, and (2) federal prohibitions&nbsp;related to&nbsp;interstate solicitation.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
