<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1477" measure-id="id115hr1477" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-09" update-date="2017-10-17">
<title>No Taxpayer Funding for the Wall Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1477v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-17">
<action-date>2017-03-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>No Taxpayer Funding for the Wall Act</strong></p> <p>This bill prohibits: (1) any federal agency from obligating or expending any federal funds to carry out provisions of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 regarding barriers at the border or any related provision of law or to otherwise build a border fence, wall, or related physical barriers along the U.S. southern border; and (2) a state from using federal grant funds for such purpose.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office (GAO) must conduct an audit each fiscal year to assess compliance with such prohibition. If the GAO is unable to confirm compliance, the Office of Management and Budget and federal agencies must take specified actions to reduce funds for federal agencies and states until the GAO is able to confirm compliance.</p> <p>The bill authorizes the President to enter into a treaty, approved by the Senate, with a foreign country to pay for the costs associated with carrying out such border barrier activities. The Inspector General of the federal agency responsible for carrying out such treaty shall oversee the use of funds received and expended pursuant to such treaty.</p> <p>The OMB shall: (1) include a statement of budgetary impact of and related to any executive order or presidential memorandum issued relating to border security during FY2017-FY2021; and (2) establish a publicly available website to track and display funds received from other non-federal sources, including foreign governments, to build a barrier along the souther border. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
