<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5283" measure-id="id115hr5283" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2018-03-14" update-date="2018-04-05">
<title>To make technical amendments to update statutory references to certain provisions classified to title 7, title 20, and title 43, United States Code.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr5283v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-04-05">
<action-date>2018-03-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill makes technical amendments to the U.S. Code to revise references to statutory provisions classified to the following titles:</p> <ul> <li>Title 7 (Agriculture),</li> <li>Title 11 (Bankruptcy),</li> <li>Title 16 (Conservation),</li> <li>Title 20 (Education),</li> <li>Title 21 (Food and Drugs),</li> <li>Title 26 (Internal Revenue Code),</li> <li>Title 42 (The Public Health and Welfare),</li> <li>Title 43 (Public Lands), and</li> <li>Title 48 (Territories And Insular Possessions).</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
