<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1140" measure-id="id115hr1140" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-16" update-date="2017-08-25">
<title>WMATA Improvement Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1140v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-25">
<action-date>2017-02-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>WMATA Improvement Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Transportation to provide additional grants for each of FY2018-FY2028 to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA) for financing approved capital and preventive maintenance projects.</p> <p>No grants may be provided until:</p> <ul> <li>the WMATA Board of Directors certifies that amendments have been made to the existing collective bargaining agreement between WMATA and a collective bargaining unit allowing WMATA to implement necessary operational changes required to provide a high level of service, reliability, and safety as well as lower costs through competitive bidding for certain capital improvements; and </li> <li>the WMATA Compact includes amendments requiring WMATA Board members to have a primary fiduciary obligation to WMATA, newly appointed Board members to have at least one of specified expert qualifications, and the Board to be composed of nine voting members, including the CEO of the Transit Authority and two appointed by each of the District of Columbia, Virginia, Maryland, and the Secretary of Transportation.</li> </ul> <p>Congressional consent for the Compact shall be withdrawn if Compact signatories (the District of Columbia, Virginia, and Maryland) fail to enact such amendments.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
