<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2107" measure-id="id115hr2107" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-20" update-date="2018-01-17">
<title>Fairness for Pilots Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2107v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-17">
<action-date>2017-04-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fairness for Pilots Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Pilot's Bill of Rights to revise the authorization for appeal to a federal court by a substantially affected individual from a decision of the National Transportation Safety Board to uphold an adverse Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) order or final decision. The bill specifies the suspension or revocation of an airman certificate as the punitive civil action which may be appealed.</p> <p>A U.S. district court shall review de novo an FAA denial, suspension, or revocation of an airman certificate.</p> <p>The bill prescribes requirements for FAA reexamination of airmen certificates where there are reasonable grounds to question an airman's lack of competence or believe a certificate was obtained through fraud.</p> <p>The FAA may not take enforcement action against an individual for violation of a Notice to Airmen (NOTAM) regarding airspace system information until the FAA certifies its compliance with certain NOTAM Improvement Program requirements. </p> <p>The FAA, upon receiving a request for a covered flight record of air traffic data not in its possession, shall request the record from a FAA contract tower or other FAA contractor possessing it. </p> <p>The FAA shall revise certain regulations for FAA administrative disposition of a case under the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 or the Hazardous Materials Transportation Act to authorize the FAA legal counsel to close covered enforcement actions with a warning notice, letter of correction, or other administrative action. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
