<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1948" measure-id="id115hr1948" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-05" update-date="2017-10-27">
<title>Small Bank Holding Company Relief Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1948v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-27">
<action-date>2017-04-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Small Bank Holding Company Relief Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Federal Reserve Board (FRB) to&nbsp;revise&nbsp;its Small Bank Holding Company Policy Statement on Assessment&nbsp;of Financial and Managerial Factors (which allows smaller bank companies to have higher debt levels than are generally allowed). Specifically, the FRB must raise the consolidated asset threshold at which the statement applies from $1 billion to $10 billion.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
