<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3289" measure-id="id115hr3289" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-18" update-date="2017-11-16">
<title>To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to require identification and description on the website of the Federal Communications Commission of items to be decided on authority delegated by the Commission.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3289v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-16">
<action-date>2017-07-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require identification and description on the website of the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) of items the FCC has delegated to commissioner panels, employee boards, or individual commissioners or employees, unless the publication is likely to lead to the disclosure of certain classified national defense or foreign policy matters, internal personnel practices, trade secrets, personal information, investigatory records for law enforcement, or other deliberation information exempt from disclosure under federal administrative procedure laws.</p> <p>The bill requires such identification and description be published on the FCC website at least 48 hours before an order, decision, report, or action is made or taken pursuant to such a delegation of authority by the FCC.</p> <p>The bill does not apply to an order, decision, report, or action that: (1) does not receive a delegated authority number, (2) is delegated to an administrative law judge, or (3) is taken to address an immediate threat to health or safety that constitutes an emergency requiring an expedited response from the FCC.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
