<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4768" measure-id="id115hr4768" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2018-01-11" update-date="2018-03-06">
<title>National Strategy for Combating the Financing of Transnational Criminal Organizations Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4768v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-06">
<action-date>2018-02-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>National Strategy for Combating the Financing of Transnational Criminal Organizations Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of the Treasury, in consultation with various U.S. agencies and departments, to develop a national strategy to combat the financial networks of transnational organized criminals.</p> <p>Treasury must submit to Congress and regularly update the national strategy.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The national strategy must: </p> <ul> <li>identify and assess the most significant transnational organized crime threats;</li> <li>identify the individuals, entities, and networks that financially support or facilitate transnational organized criminals and assess the scope of such support;</li> <li>assess the methods by which transnational organized crime groups launder illicit proceeds;</li> <li>describe the roles of U.S. agencies and departments to combat the financing and financial facilitation of transnational organized crime groups; and</li> <li>review current efforts and proposed changes to combat the financing or financial facilitation of transnational organized crime.</li> </ul> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4768v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-05">
<action-date>2018-01-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>National Strategy for Combating the Financing of Transnational Criminal Organizations Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of the Treasury to develop a national strategy to combat the financial networks of transnational organized criminals.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
