<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1182" measure-id="id115hr1182" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-16" update-date="2017-09-12">
<title>Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces (INF) Treaty Preservation Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1182v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-12">
<action-date>2017-02-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces (INF) Treaty Preservation Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill states U.S. policy that: (1) Russian actions in violation of the the Treaty between the United States of America and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics on the Elimination of their Intermediate-Range and Shorter-Range Missiles (INF treaty) constitute a material breach, (2) the United States is legally entitled to suspend the treaty, and (3) the United States should take certain actions to bring Russia into compliance. </p> <p>The bill authorizes additional appropriations for: (1) development of active defenses to counter ground launched missile systems, (2) counterforce and countervailing capabilities, and (3) missile system transfers to allied countries. </p> <p>The Department of Defense shall: (1) establish a program to develop a dual-capable road-mobile ground-launched cruise missile system with a range of 500 to 5,500 kilometers; (2) report on the feasibility of modifying the tomahawk, standard missile-3, standard missile-6, long-range stand off cruise missile, and Army tactical missile for ground-launch with such range; and (3) report on the AEGIS Ashore sites with anti-air warfare capability necessary in Asia and Europe to defend U.S. forces and allies from Russian ground launched missile systems.</p> <p>The Director of National Intelligence, every 90 days for five years, shall determine whether Russia has flight tested, produced, or possesses a system that is inconsistent with the treaty and that has reached initial operational capability and is, or is about to be, deployed.</p> <p>No funds may be obligated or expended to extend the New START Treaty after 2021, permit Russian flights over the United States or U.S. allies pursuant to the Open Skies Treaty, permit the approval of new implementation decisions through the Open Skies Consultative Commission, or approve any license to export an item or technology to a Russian person or entity unless the President certifies that Russia has eliminated all missiles that are in violation of, or inconsistent with, the INF treaty.</p> <p>The Department of State shall conduct a review of Russia's RS-26 ballistic missile system.</p> <p>Upon a determination that Russia has flight-tested, produced, or is in possession of certain missiles, the President shall suspend the application of the INF treaty to the United States and notify the other state parties to the treaty of Russia's material breach of, and the U.S. decision to suspend, the treaty. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
