<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4170" measure-id="id115hr4170" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-31" update-date="2018-03-02">
<title>Disclosing Foreign Influence Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4170v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-02">
<action-date>2017-10-31</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Disclosing Foreign Influence Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 (FARA): </p> <ul> <li>to repeal an exemption from registration under FARA for agents of foreign persons and entities in the private sector who register under the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (LDA); </li> <li>to require such agents, after initial registration under FARA, to file subsequent statements at the same time, and in the same frequency, as reports filed with Congress under the LDA; and </li> <li>to authorize the Department of Justice (DOJ) to issue civil investigative demands to compel the production of documents relevant to FARA investigations before initiating criminal or civil proceedings. </li> </ul> <p>DOJ must develop and implement a comprehensive strategy to improve FARA enforcement and administration. The DOJ Inspector General must review: (1) the development and implementation of a comprehensive strategy; and (2) the use, effectiveness, and potential abuse of DOJ's authority to issue civil investigative demands.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must analyze the effectiveness of FARA enforcement and administration. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
