<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3352" measure-id="id115hr3352" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-20" update-date="2017-11-13">
<title>Second Chance for Service Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3352v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-13">
<action-date>2017-07-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Second Chance for Service Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide that an applicant for citizenship who served honorably in the Armed Forces is not barred from becoming a U.S. citizen on the grounds of not being a person of good moral character based upon specified behaviors or having committed certain crimes, excluding crimes relating to murder, rape, sexual abuse of a minor, child pornography, prostitution, trafficking in persons, and national security. </p> <p>In determining whether an applicant is of good moral character, the applicant's honorable service shall be weighed against any finding of having committed such behaviors or crimes.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
