<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4566" measure-id="id115hr4566" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-12-06" update-date="2018-03-28">
<title>Alleviating Stress Test Burdens to Help Investors Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4566v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-28">
<action-date>2018-03-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Alleviating Stress Test Burdens to Help Investors Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to: (1) eliminate the Federal Reserve Board's authority to conduct stress tests of nonbank financial companies more than once annually, and (2) exempt certain financial companies not primarily regulated by either a federal banking agency or the Federal Housing Finance Agency from requirements to conduct stress tests.</p> <p>The Securities and Exchange Commission and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission may issue separate regulations requiring specified financial companies&nbsp;with more than $10 billion in total consolidated assets&nbsp;to conduct financial-condition analyses. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4566v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-19">
<action-date>2017-12-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Alleviating Stress Test Burdens to Help Investors Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act to: (1)&nbsp;exempt certain nonbank financial companies from requirements to conduct stress tests, and (2) eliminate the Federal Reserve Board's authority to conduct stress tests of nonbank financial companies more than once annually.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
