<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2226" measure-id="id115hr2226" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-28" update-date="2018-04-02">
<title>Portfolio Lending and Mortgage Access Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2226v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-04-02">
<action-date>2018-03-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Portfolio Lending and Mortgage Access Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Truth in Lending Act to allow a depository institution or credit union with assets below a specified threshold to forgo certain ability-to-pay requirements regarding residential mortgage loans. Specifically, those requirements are waived if a loan: (1) is originated by and continuously retained by the institution, (2) complies with requirements regarding prepayment penalties and points and fees, and (3) does not have negative amortization or interest-only terms. Furthermore, for such requirements to be waived, the institution must consider and verify the debt, income, and financial resources of the consumer.</p> <p>The bill also provides for circumstances in which&nbsp;such requirements&nbsp;shall be waived&nbsp;with respect to&nbsp;a&nbsp;loan that is&nbsp;transferred: (1) by reason of bankruptcy or failure of the originating institution, (2) to a similar institution, (3) in the event of a merger, or (4) to a wholly owned subsidiary of the institution. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2226v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-28">
<action-date>2018-02-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Portfolio Lending and Mortgage Access Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Truth in Lending Act to allow a depository institution or credit union with assets below a specified threshold to forgo certain ability-to-pay requirements regarding residential mortgage loans. Specifically, those requirements are waived if a loan: (1) is originated by and continuously retained by the institution, (2) complies with requirements regarding prepayment penalties and points and fees, and (3) does not have negative amortization or interest-only terms. Furthermore, for such requirements to be waived, the institution must consider and verify the debt, income, and financial resources of the consumer.</p> <p>The bill also provides for circumstances in which&nbsp;such requirements&nbsp;shall be waived&nbsp;with respect to&nbsp;a&nbsp;loan that is&nbsp;transferred: (1) by reason of bankruptcy or failure of the originating institution, (2) to a similar institution, (3) in the event of a merger, or (4) to a wholly owned subsidiary of the institution. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2226v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-16">
<action-date>2017-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Portfolio Lending and Mortgage Access Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Truth in Lending Act to modify provisions related to residential mortgage loans. In general, a creditor that is a depository institution shall not be subject to suit for&nbsp;violating specified ability-to-pay requirements with respect to a residential mortgage loan if: (1) the creditor has consistently&nbsp;held the loan on its balance sheet, and (2) prepayment penalties&nbsp;associated with&nbsp;the loan comply with specified limitations. Similarly, a mortgage originator shall not be subject to suit for such a violation&nbsp;if: (1) the creditor is a depository institution; and (2) the creditor informs the mortgage originator, which informs the consumer, that the creditor intends to hold the loan on its balance sheet for the life of the loan.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
