<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2061" measure-id="id115hr2061" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2017-10-12">
<title>North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2061v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-12">
<action-date>2017-09-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill expresses the sense of Congress concerning access to and protection of North Korean refugees and defectors, the forcible repatriation by China of North Koreans, and the Department of State position of Special Envoy for North Korean Human Rights Issues.</p>   <p> <p> (Sec. 4) The North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004 is amended to reauthorize through FY2022: (1) programs that promote human rights, democracy, rule of law, and the development of a market economy in North Korea; (2) actions to promote freedom of information in North Korea; and (3) humanitarian assistance to North Koreans who are outside of North Korea without the government's permission.</p>  <p>The bill extends through 2022 the requirements for annual reports from: (1) the State Department on freedom of information inside North Korea, (2) the Special Envoy on North Korean human rights issues, (3) the U.S. Agency for International Development on U.S. humanitarian assistance activities both inside North Korea and for North Koreans outside of North Korea, and (4) the State Department and Department of Homeland Security on North Korean refugees and immigration.</p> <p> (Sec. 5) The President may provide electronic information sharing media to increase the availability of nongovernment-controlled information inside North Korea. </p> <p>The President may: (1) provide grants to distribute information receiving devices, electronically readable devices, and other informational sources into North Korea; and (2) establish a grant program to develop or distribute new products or methods to allow North Koreans easier access to outside information. </p>  <p>The Broadcasting Board of Governors: (1) may broadcast popular music, television, movies, and popular cultural references as part of its programming; and (2) shall broadcast in Korean to North Korea information on rights, laws, and freedoms afforded through the North Korean Constitution and applicable treaties or international agreements. </p> <p> The State Department shall: (1) submit a plan to Congress for reaching additional audiences and increasing consumption of uncensored news and information; and (2) report annually on the effectiveness of actions taken pursuant to these information dissemination requirements, including data reflecting audience and listenership, device distribution and usage, and technological development and advancement usage.</p>  <p> (Sec. 7) The board shall report to Congress regarding: (1) the status of current U.S. broadcasting to North Korea and the extent to which it has achieved the goal of 12-hour-per-day broadcasting, and (2) a strategy to overcome obstacles to communication with the North Korean people. </p> <p> (Sec. 8) The State Department shall report to Congress regarding efforts to: (1) resume the repatriation from North Korea of U.S. Armed Forces members missing or unaccounted for during the Korean War, (2) reunite Korean Americans with their relatives in North Korea, and (3) assess the security risks to U.S. citizens posed by travel to North Korea. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2061v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-12">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2017</b></p> <p> This bill amends the North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004 to reauthorize through FY2022: (1) programs that promote human rights, democracy, rule of law, and the development of a market economy in North Korea; (2) actions to promote freedom of information in North Korea; and (3) humanitarian assistance to North Koreans who are outside of North Korea without the permission of the government.</p> <p>The bill extends through 2022 the requirements for annual reports from: (1) the Department of State on freedom of information inside North Korea, (2) the Special Envoy on North Korean human rights issues, (3) the U.S. Agency for International Development on U.S. humanitarian assistance activities both inside North Korea and for North Koreans outside of North Korea, and (4) the State Department and Department of Homeland Security on North Korean refugees and immigration. </p> <p> The Broadcasting Board of Governors shall report to Congress regarding: (1) the status of current U.S. broadcasting to North Korea and the extent to which the Board has achieved the goal of 12-hour-per-day broadcasting to North Korea; and (2) a strategy to overcome obstacles to communication with the North Korean people, including through electronic means. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
