<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2314" measure-id="id115hr2314" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-03" update-date="2018-01-04">
<title>Security Clearance Family Review Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2314v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-04">
<action-date>2017-05-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Security Clearance Family Review Act</b></p> <p>This bill prohibits specified federal agencies, including the Department of Defense, from granting access to classified information to a relative of the President for purposes of federal employment unless the Office of Government Ethics makes a favorable determination during a review process regarding the relative's suitability for such access. In conducting a review, the Office of Government Ethics must determine whether the relative of the President has any ongoing and substantial commercial relationships with state-owned or privately owned foreign enterprises or financial institutions, and, if so, whether the relative is ineligible for access to classified information because of such relationships.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
