<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2209" measure-id="id115hr2209" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-27" update-date="2017-08-17">
<title>Helping to Encourage Real Opportunities (HERO) for At-Risk Youth Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2209v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-17">
<action-date>2017-04-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Helping to Encourage Real Opportunities (HERO) for At-Risk Youth Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the work opportunity tax credit, to: </p> <ul> <li> change the credit for summer youth employees to a credit for youth employees who will be employed for not more than 20 hours per week during any period between September 16 and April 30 in which the individual is regularly attending any secondary school, </li> <li> increase the amount of the credit for youth employees, and </li> <li> expand the credit to include at-risk youth.</li> </ul> <p>An &quot;at-risk youth&quot; is any individual who is certified by the designated local agency as: </p> <ul> <li> having attained age 16 but not age 25 on the hiring date, </li> <li> having not regularly attended specified schools or been employed during the six-month period preceding the hiring date, and </li> <li>not readily employable by reason of lacking a sufficient number of basic skills. </li> </ul> <p>The term also includes individuals who have been certified as having attained the age of 16 but not age 21 on the hiring date and as an eligible foster child who was in foster care during the 12-month period ending on the hiring date. </p> <p>The bill also extends until December 31, 2019, the designation period for certain tax-favored empowerment zones. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
