<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5387" measure-id="id115hr5387" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2018-03-22" update-date="2018-04-05">
<title>Consortia-Led Energy and Advanced Manufacturing Networks Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr5387v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-04-05">
<action-date>2018-03-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Consortia-Led Energy and Advanced Manufacturing Networks Act</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Commerce to carry out a grant program for establishing consortia to enhance U.S. economic, environmental, and energy security by promoting domestic research and commercial application of clean technologies and advanced manufacturing processes. Clean technology means technologies, production processes, or methodologies that: </p><ul> <li>produce energy from renewable energy sources; </li> <li> transmit, distribute, or store energy more efficiently;</li> <li>enhance energy efficiency for buildings and industry; </li> <li>enable the development of a Smart Grid (an evolving electric power network that utilizes new information technology systems, including those that enable customers to reduce or shift their power use during peak demand periods);</li> <li> produce an advanced or sustainable material with energy or energy efficiency applications; </li> <li> improve energy efficiency for transportation; or</li> <li> enhance water security through improved water management, conservation, distribution, or end use applications. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
