<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1975" measure-id="id115hr1975" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2017-09-19">
<title>Cluster Munitions Civilian Protection Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1975v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-19">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Cluster Munitions Civilian Protection Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill prohibits federal agency funds from being obligated or expended to purchase, transfer, export, or use any cluster munitions unless: (1) the submunitions of such munitions, after arming, do not result in more than 1% unexploded ordnance across the range of intended operational environments; and (2) the policy applicable to the export or transfer of such munitions specifies that they will be used only against clearly defined military targets and not in areas normally inhabited by civilians or where civilians are known to be present.</p> <p>Expresses the sense of Congress that:</p> <ul> <li>the Department of Defense should ensure that the July 2008 Gates policy on cluster munitions is being fully implemented and that the United States will no longer use such munitions by the end of 2018 except in compliance with the 1% unexploded ordnance limit;</li> <li> the U.S. government should adopt a policy and develop a strategy to phase out the transfer, export, and use of such munitions; </li> <li> any alternatives that the government develops to replace cluster munitions should be compliant with the Convention on Cluster Munitions; and </li> <li> the United States should take all steps necessary to accede to such convention. </li> </ul> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
