<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1670" measure-id="id115hr1670" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-22" update-date="2017-06-22">
<title>Infrastructure 2.0 Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1670v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-22">
<action-date>2017-03-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Infrastructure 2.0 Act</strong> </p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the taxation of earnings and profits of a deferred foreign income corporation, to: (1) make such earnings and profits subject to taxation in the last year that ends before the enactment of this bill;&nbsp;(2) reduce the tax rate on such earnings and profits by allowing an exemption of 75% (equal to a tax of 8.75% of repatriated earnings and profits); and (3) allow corporations to pay the tax in installments. </p> <p>The bill also: </p> <ul> <li>establishes and provides appropriations for a fund to assist various public and private entities in investing in public infrastructure projects, </li> <li>appropriates revenues from this bill to the Highway Trust Fund (HTF),</li> <li>establishes a commission to make recommendations to achieve long-term solvency of the HTF and requires Congress to consider the proposed legislation using expedited procedures, and </li> <li>directs the Department of Transportation to establish a regional infrastructure accelerator pilot program to assist public entities in developing infrastructure projects. </li> </ul> <p>The bill establishes a deadline of 18 months after the enactment of this bill for the enactment of legislation to reform the international tax system by eliminating the incentive to hold earnings in low-tax foreign jurisdictions. If the legislation is not enacted by the deadline, a specified reform proposal takes effect, which includes provisions relating to subpart F income and insurance income, the taxation of repatriated offshore corporate earnings, gains and losses from the sale or exchange of stock in controlled foreign corporations, limitations on the foreign tax credit, and the tax treatment of previously deferred foreign income.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
