<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3803" measure-id="id115hr3803" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-18" update-date="2017-12-07">
<title>To amend the Reclamation Safety of Dams Act of 1978 to provide for certain cost allocations for the Boca Reservoir Dam, Truckee River Storage Project, California, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3803v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-07">
<action-date>2017-09-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Reclamation Safety of Dams Act of 1978 to provide that, in the case of the Boca Reservoir Dam, Truckee River Storage Project, California, costs incurred in the modification of structures, the cause of which results from new hydrologic or seismic data or changes in state-of-the-art criteria deemed necessary for safety purposes, shall be allocated in accordance with the authorized uses of Boca Project Water as defined and provided for in the Truckee River Operating Agreement and as determined by the Truckee River Operating Agreement Administrator.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
