<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1050" measure-id="id115hr1050" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-14" update-date="2017-04-10">
<title>Youth Access to American Jobs Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1050v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-04-10">
<action-date>2017-02-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Youth Access to American Jobs Act of 2017</b></p> <p> This bill requires the Department of Education to award grants to 10 eligible entities (partnerships among a local educational agency (LEA), a community college, and a state apprentice program or a joint-labor management training program) to carry out a program for students to: </p> <ul> <li> enroll in and complete science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) courses, STEM-focused career and technical education courses, and other courses during grades 11 and 12 at a high school served by the LEA that prepares them for community college; </li> <li> enroll in a course of study related to a high-growth skills industry, an in-demand industry or occupation, the manufacturing field, or other vocational or career and technical education field at a community college upon graduating from such high school; and </li> <li> enroll, for a two-year period, in the eligible entity's state apprenticeship program or the joint-labor management training program upon receiving an associate's degree from such community college.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
