<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2762" measure-id="id115hr2762" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-30" update-date="2017-11-20">
<title>White House Ethics Transparency Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2762v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-20">
<action-date>2017-05-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>White House Ethics Transparency Act of 2017</b></p>   <p>This bill requires an federal official who issues or approves a waiver or authorization relating to ethical standards applicable to executive branch political appointees under specified executive orders to transmit, within 30 days after issuing or approving such waiver or authorization, a written copy of the waiver or authorization to the Office of Government Ethics and make them available to the public on the websites of the agencies employing such appointees and the Office of Government Ethics. This requirement applies retroactively to January 20, 2017.</p> <UL> </UL>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
