<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4121" measure-id="id115hr4121" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-25" update-date="2018-03-08">
<title>Global Development Lab Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4121v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-08">
<action-date>2017-10-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Global Development Lab Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill establishes in the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) the United States Global Development Lab, the duties of which shall include: </p> <ul> <li> increasing the application of science, technology, innovation and partnerships to develop new solutions to end extreme poverty; </li> <li> discovering and testing development innovations to increase cost effectiveness and support U.S. foreign policy and development goals; </li> <li>leveraging the expertise, resources, and investment of businesses, nongovernmental organizations, science and research organizations, and universities to increase program impact and sustainability; </li> <li>utilizing innovation-driven competitions to expand the number and diversity of solutions to development challenges; and </li> <li>supporting USAID missions and bureaus in applying science, technology, innovation, and partnership approaches to decision making, procurement, and program design.</li> </ul> <p>The lab is authorized to provide innovation incentive awards on a competitive basis that: (1) encourages and rewards the development of solutions for a particular, well-defined problem relating to the alleviation of poverty; or (2) helps identify and promote a broad range of ideas and practices, facilitating further development of an idea or practice by third parties.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
