<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2022" measure-id="id115hr2022" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2018-01-19">
<title>LATTS Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2022v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-19">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Label and Transport Tissues Safely Act of 2017 or the LATTS Act of 2017 </b></p>  <p>This bill prohibits the sale of human tissue for research or education unless the seller has a non-transplant tissue bank license, each package of tissue is labeled with specified information, and each package is wrapped in the prescribed manner.</p> <p>The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) shall establish a process for the approval, suspension, and revocation of non-transplant tissue bank licenses.</p> <p>False labeling of packages of human tissue is prohibited.</p> <p> HHS or any accrediting body authorized by HHS is allowed to enter and inspect any facility that is subject to a non-transplant tissue bank license.</p> <p>HHS shall recall any human tissue specimen that is an imminent or substantial hazard to public health. </p> <p>The bill makes it unlawful to knowingly sell or otherwise transfer any human tissue specimen if the transfer affects interstate commerce.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
