<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1983" measure-id="id115hr1983" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2017-11-28">
<title>David's Law</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1983v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-28">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>David Ray Hate Crimes Prevention Act of 2017 or David's Law</b></p> <p> This bill makes it unlawful to willfully cause bodily injury to any person or, through the use of fire, a firearm, or an explosive device, attempting to cause such injury, whether or not acting under color of law, because of: (1) the actual or perceived race, color, religion, or national origin of that person; or (2) the actual or perceived religion, gender, sexual orientation, or disability of that person where the offense is in or affects interstate or foreign commerce. </p> <p>The U.S. Sentencing Commission is directed to study the issue of adult recruitment of juveniles to commit hate crimes and, if appropriate, to amend the federal sentencing guidelines to provide sentencing enhancements for using juveniles to assist in the commission of such hate crimes.</p> <p> The Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention of the Department of Justice (DOJ) shall make grants to state and local programs designed to combat hate crimes committed by juveniles.</p> <p>The bill authorizes the Department of the Treasury and DOJ, for FY2017-FY2019, to increase the number of personnel to protect against criminal interference with federally-protected activities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
