<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3167" measure-id="id115hr3167" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-06" update-date="2018-01-29">
<title>Debt Ceiling Alternative Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3167v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-29">
<action-date>2017-07-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Debt Ceiling Alternative Act </b></p> <p>This bill establishes requirements and authorities for notifying Congress, issuing bonds, proposing rescissions, and selling assets if the debt limit will be reached. </p> <p>The Department of the Treasury must notify Congress if it estimates that the U.S. debt will reach the statutory debt limit during a quarter. After Congress is notified, Treasury must issue bonds that: (1) have an interest rate linked to the nominal gross domestic product of the United States, (2) may only be used to pay the principal and interest on obligations of the United States held by the public or the Social Security trust funds, and (3) are exempt from the debt limit. </p> <p>Once Congress is notified that the debt limit will be reached, the President may issue a message to Congress containing a list of budget authority proposed to be rescinded. The list may only contain items related to unobligated balances of funds made available before the beginning of the fiscal year during which such notification is provided. Congress must consider the message using specified expedited legislative procedures. </p> <p>If the debt limit notice has been provided to Congress, the President may also order the sale of specified mortgage-related assets owned or held by the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae), the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Association (Freddie Mac), and the Federal Reserve. The proceeds from the sales must be deposited in the Treasury. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
