<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1940" measure-id="id115hr1940" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-05" update-date="2018-02-08">
<title>Right to Rent Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1940v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-08">
<action-date>2017-04-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Right to Rent Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill temporarily allows an eligible mortgagor who is subject to&nbsp;foreclosure proceedings&nbsp;to remain in the foreclosed home as a renter for up to five years, subject to specified requirements.&nbsp;The bill applies to&nbsp;a&nbsp;mortgage originated prior to 2009 on a single-family home that: (1) has been&nbsp;used as a primary residence for at least two years, and (2) had a purchase price that is less than the median purchase price for residences in the area.</p> <p>The bill specifies notice requirements and establishes a formula for determining fair-market rent. </p> <p>The Department of Housing and Urban Development shall: (1) monitor compliance with the bill, (2) provide assistance to eligible mortgagors in exercising their rights under the bill, and (3) conduct outreach activities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
