<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2646" measure-id="id115hr2646" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-24" update-date="2018-02-20">
<title>United States-Jordan Defense Cooperation Extension Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2646v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-20">
<action-date>2018-02-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>United States-Jordan Defense Cooperation Extension Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) Jordan plays a critical role in responding to the humanitarian needs created by the conflict in Syria; (2) Jordan, the United States, and other partners should continue working together to address such humanitarian crisis and promote regional stability, including through support for refugees in Jordan and internally displaced people along the Jordan-Syria border and the creation of conditions inside Syria that will allow for the secure and voluntary return of displaced people; and (3) the United States and Jordan should negotiate a new Memorandum of Understanding for FY2018-FY2022 to significantly enhance Jordan's military capacity and local economy. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) The United States-Jordan Defense Cooperation Act of 2015 is amended to extend Jordan's inclusion among the countries eligible for certain streamlined defense sales until December 31, 2022.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) The President is authorized to establish and operate an enterprise fund to provide assistance to Jordan. </p> <p>The Board of Directors of the fund shall annually: (1) report to Congress detailing administrative expenses (which are limited to 3% of amounts made available to such fund), and (2) publish each annual report on the Internet.</p> <p>Any amounts resulting from the fund's liquidation or dissolution shall be returned to the Treasury.</p> <p>The fund's authority to provide assistance shall terminate on the earlier of: (1) the date that is seven years after the fund's first expenditure, or (2) the date the fund is liquidated.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2646v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-25">
<action-date>2017-05-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>United States-Jordan Defense Cooperation Extension Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the United States-Jordan Defense Cooperation Act of 2015 to extend Jordan's inclusion among the countries eligible for certain streamlined defense sales until December 31, 2022.</p> <p>The bill expresses the sense of Congress that the governments of the United States and Jordan should negotiate a new Memorandum of Understanding through FY2022 to enhance Jordan's military capacity and local economy.</p> <p>The President is authorized to establish and operate an enterprise fund to provide assistance to Jordan. The fund's authority to provide assistance shall terminate on the earlier of December 31, 2022, or the date on which the fund is liquidated in accordance with this bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
