<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3101" measure-id="id115hr3101" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-28" update-date="2017-11-01">
<title>Strengthening Cybersecurity Information Sharing and Coordination in Our Ports Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3101v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-01">
<action-date>2017-10-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Strengthening Cybersecurity Information Sharing and Coordination in Our Ports Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to facilitate increased information sharing about cybersecurity among maritime interests.</p> <p>DHS must:</p><ul> <li>develop, implement, and&nbsp;continually&nbsp;review&nbsp;a maritime cybersecurity&nbsp;risk assessment model&nbsp;to evaluate current and future cybersecurity risks; </li> <li>seek input from at least one information sharing and analysis organization representing maritime interests in the National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center; </li> <li>establish voluntary reporting guidelines for maritime-related cybersecurity risks and incidents; and </li> <li>request that the National Maritime Security Advisory Committee report and make recommendations to DHS about methods to enhance cybersecurity and information sharing among security stakeholders from federal, state, local, and tribal governments; public safety and emergency response agencies; law enforcement and security organizations; maritime industry participants; port owners and operators; and maritime terminal owners and operators. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 3) Through the Coast Guard, DHS must also:</p> <ul> <li>direct each Area Maritime Security Advisory Committee to facilitate the sharing of information about, and development of plans to address, port-specific cybersecurity vulnerabilities; and&nbsp; </li> <li>require that area maritime transportation&nbsp;security plans and vessel and facility security plans approved after enactment of this Act&nbsp;include mitigation measures to prevent, manage, and respond to cyber threats and vulnerabilities.</li></ul> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill amends the federal shipping codes to include cybersecurity in facility and vessel vulnerability assessments.</p> <ul></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3101v28" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-24">
<action-date>2017-10-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment, Part I</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>Strengthening Cybersecurity Information Sharing and Coordination in Our Ports Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to facilitate increased information sharing about cybersecurity among maritime interests.</p> <p>DHS must:</p> <ul> <li>develop, implement, and&nbsp;continually&nbsp;review&nbsp;a maritime cybersecurity&nbsp;risk assessment model&nbsp;to evaluate current and future cybersecurity risks; </li> <li>seek input from at least one information sharing and analysis organization representing maritime interests in the National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center; </li> <li>establish voluntary reporting guidelines for maritime-related cybersecurity risks and incidents; </li> <li>request that the National Maritime Security Advisory Committee report and make recommendations to DHS about methods to enhance cybersecurity and information sharing among security stakeholders from federal, state, local, and tribal governments; public safety and emergency response agencies; law enforcement and security organizations; maritime industry participants; port owners and operators; and maritime terminal owners and operators; and </li> <li>ensure that maritime security risk assessments include cybersecurity risks to ports and the maritime border of the United States.</li></ul> <p>(Sec. 3) Through the Coast Guard, DHS must also:</p> <ul> <li>direct each Area Maritime Security Advisory Committee to facilitate the sharing of information about, and development of plans to address, port-specific cybersecurity vulnerabilities; and&nbsp; </li> <li>require that area maritime security plans and facility security plans approved after enactment of this Act&nbsp;include mitigation measures to prevent, manage, and respond to cyber threats and vulnerabilities.</li></ul> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill amends the federal shipping codes to include cybersecurity in facility and vessel vulnerability assessments.</p> <UL> </UL>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3101v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-28">
<action-date>2017-06-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Strengthening Cybersecurity Information Sharing and Coordination in Our Ports Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to facilitate increased information sharing about cybersecurity among maritime interests.</p> <p>DHS must:</p> <ul> <li>develop, implement, and&nbsp;continually&nbsp;review&nbsp;a maritime cybersecurity&nbsp;risk assessment model&nbsp;to evaluate current and future cybersecurity risks; </li> <li>seek input from at least one information sharing and analysis organization representing maritime interests in the National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center; </li> <li>establish voluntary reporting guidelines for maritime-related cybersecurity risks and incidents; and</li> <li>request that the National Maritime Security Advisory Committee report and make recommendations to DHS about methods to enhance cybersecurity and information sharing among security stakeholders from federal, state, local, and tribal governments; public safety and emergency response agencies; law enforcement and security organizations; maritime industry participants; port owners and operators; and maritime terminal owners and operators.</li></ul> <p>Through the Coast Guard, DHS must also:</p> <ul> <li>direct each Area Maritime Security Advisory Committee to facilitate the sharing of information about, and development of plans to address, port-specific cybersecurity vulnerabilities; and&nbsp; </li> <li>require that area maritime security plans and facility security plans approved after enactment of this Act&nbsp;include mitigation measures to prevent, manage, and respond to cyber threats and vulnerabilities.</li></ul> <p>The bill amends the federal shipping codes to include cybersecurity in facility and vessel vulnerability assessments.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
