<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3067" measure-id="id115hr3067" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-27" update-date="2018-03-07">
<title>Online Safety Modernization Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3067v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-07">
<action-date>2017-06-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Online Safety Modernization Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the federal criminal code to establish new crimes for using the mail or another facility of interstate or foreign commerce to knowingly engage in the following conduct:</p> <ul> <li>coercion of sexual acts, of sexual contact, or of the production of sexually explicit visual depictions; </li> <li>coercion or extortion involving threats to publish sexually explicit visual depictions; </li> <li>reporting of false or misleading information to cause an emergency law enforcement response; or </li> <li>publication of personally identifiable information of another person to threaten, intimidate, harass, or cause other harm. </li> </ul> <p>Additionally, the bill directs the Department of Justice (DOJ) to:</p> <ul> <li>develop a national strategy to reduce, investigate, and prosecute cybercrimes against individuals; </li> <li>publish statistics on cybercrimes against individuals; </li> <li>add operational agents, designate federal prosecutors, and implement training to improve the investigation and prosecution of cybercrimes against individuals; </li> <li>make state and local grants to prevent, enforce, and prosecute cybercrimes against individuals; and </li> <li>make a grant to establish and maintain the National Resource Center on Cybercrimes Against Individuals. </li> </ul> <p>The Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) must create a category, in the Uniform Crime Reports, for an offense that constitutes a cybercrime against individuals.</p> <p>Finally, the bill authorizes additional funding for the FBI and DOJ to hire and train law enforcement officers to investigate and assist in the prosecution of cybercrimes against individuals.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
