<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3422" measure-id="id115hr3422" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-26" update-date="2017-09-05">
<title>Interstate Teaching Mobility Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3422v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-05">
<action-date>2017-07-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Interstate Teaching Mobility Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish a&nbsp;voluntary&nbsp;interstate teaching application program for participating states. To&nbsp;participate in the program, a&nbsp;state&nbsp;must require sufficiently rigorous assessments in awarding a teaching license or certification.</p> <p>In carrying out the program, the Department of Education shall:</p> <ul> <li>create an electronic application process for eligible teachers who are licensed or certified in a participating state to apply&nbsp;for teaching positions in&nbsp;another participating state; </li> <li>require a participating state to recognize the teaching licensure or certification of each such teacher without the teacher having to complete additional licensure or certification requirements; </li> <li>ensure that a participating state maintains specified eligibility requirements; and </li> <li>provide technical assistance.</li></ul> <p>A teacher seeking to participate in the program must submit an application containing: (1)&nbsp;proof of active licensure or certification in a participating state, and (2) the teacher's results on specified assessments.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
