<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1912" measure-id="id115hr1912" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-05" update-date="2018-03-08">
<title>Black Lung Benefits Improvement Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1912v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-08">
<action-date>2017-04-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Black Lung Benefits Improvement Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Black Lung Benefits Act to revise requirements for miners' claims for pneumoconiosis (black lung) benefits.</p> <p>The Department of Labor must pay the attorneys' fees of prevailing parties on a qualifying benefit claim. </p> <p>This bill revises: (1) the standards of medical evidence that establish a presumption that a miner is totally disabled by black lung, and (2) payments to such miners (including their dependents).</p> <p>Black lung clinics may use federal funds to help individuals file claims.</p> <p>A person may not knowingly and willfully: (1) make a false statement or misrepresentation in increasing or reducing black lung benefits, or (2) threaten or mislead a participant in a proceeding regarding the benefits.</p> <p>Labor, upon request, must give a claimant the opportunity to substantiate a claim for benefits through a pulmonary evaluation of the miner. Labor must also authorize a computerized tomography scan in diagnosing complicated pneumoconiosis.</p> <p>The National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health must establish a pilot program to ensure accurate classifications of chest radiographs in black lung cases where the diagnosis is at issue.</p> <p>Labor must educate certain individuals who work on black lung benefits about medical evidence relevant to claims.</p> <p>A previously denied claimant may file a new claim for black lung benefits within one year.</p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977 to direct Labor to use data from continuous personal dust monitors to determine whether to make changes to respirable dust concentration standards, controls, and measurements.</p> <p>This bill provides statutory authority for the Office of Workers' Compensation Programs.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
