<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2053" measure-id="id115hr2053" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2018-02-28">
<title>Mining Schools Enhancement Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2053v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-28">
<action-date>2017-07-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Mining Schools Enhancement Act</b></p> <p>(Sec.2)This bill amends the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to require the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement (OSMRE) of the Department of the Interior to ensure that at least 70% of specified research fundsare expended to enhance and support programs at mining and mineral engineering schools in the United States.</p> <p>In addition, OSMRE shall ensure that research activities relate to conventional fuel resource development and production, including enhancing technologies and practices related to the mitigation of acid mine drainage, reforestation, and revegetation in the reclamation of land and water resources adversely affected by coal mining.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2053v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-18">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Mining School Enhancement Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to require the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement (OSMRE) of the Department of the Interior to ensure that at least 50% of specified research fundsare expended to enhance and support programs at mining and mineral engineering schools in the United States.</p> <p>In addition, OSMRE shall ensure that research activities relate to conventional fuel resource development and production, including enhancing technologies and practices related to the mitigation of acid mine drainage, reforestation, and revegetation in the reclamation of land and water resources adversely affected by coal mining.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
