<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3699" measure-id="id115hr3699" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-07" update-date="2018-03-22">
<title>Urban Agriculture Production Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3699v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-22">
<action-date>2017-09-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Urban Agriculture Production Act of 201</b><b>7</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish an urban agriculture outreach program to award grants for: (1) infrastructure; (2) land acquisition, land conversion, and soil and growing mechanism assistance; (3) education and training; (4) technical and financial assistance to farmers, producers, or ranchers in urban areas; and (5) other activities that support urban agriculture. USDA must give preference to grants for activities in historically underserved communities. </p> <p>USDA must establish the position of Urban Agricultural Liaison.</p> <p>USDA must award grants for scientific and community-based participatory research related to urban agriculture. The bill provides specified funds for the grants and requires USDA to give priority to outreach activities to be carried out in historically underserved communities. </p> <p>The bill amends the Farmer-to-Consumer Direct Marketing Act of 1976 to: (1) establish a program to provide loans and loan guarantees for projects or activities to establish, expand, and promote direct producer-to-consumer marketing and assist in the development of local food business enterprises; and (2) extend and provide additional funding for the Farmers' Market Promotion Program. </p> <p>The bill amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to extend the Seniors Farmers' Market Nutrition Program and provide additional funding. </p> <p>The bill amends the Census of Agriculture Act of 1997 to require additional USDA reporting on farmers' markets and agricultural production in urban areas. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
