<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1534" measure-id="id115hr1534" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-15" update-date="2017-05-03">
<title>21st Century Worker Opportunity Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1534v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-03">
<action-date>2017-03-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>21st Century Worker Opportunity Act</b></p> <p>This bill requires the National Telecommunications and Information Administration to implement a program that provides displaced workers with a subsidy or coupon for a lump sum payment of $500 that may only be applied towards: (1) broadband Internet access service, or (2) remote job training in a profession not likely to be automated in the next 20 years.</p> <p>A &quot;displaced worker&quot; is defined as an individual who, due to automation of machinery that replaces human labor, has been terminated or laid off from employment or who has received a notice of termination or layoff from employment.</p> <p>To be eligible for the program, a displaced worker who has been laid off or terminated must submit a certification from an employer that the worker was employed in the manufacturing sector and was laid off or terminated due to the automation of the position of the worker.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
