<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4251" measure-id="id115hr4251" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-11-03" update-date="2018-01-17">
<title>Rebuilding Resilient Energy Systems Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4251v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-17">
<action-date>2017-11-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Rebuilding Resilient Energy Systems Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill permits amounts awarded under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act for essential assistance, hazard mitigation, repair, restoration, and replacement of damaged facilities, federal assistance to individuals and households, and public assistance program alternative procedures to be used to build, repair, restore, reconstruct, or replace an energy system or building as a result of a major disaster or emergency designated by the President during calendar year 2017 in a manner that:</p> <ul> <li> is more resilient and more efficient; </li> <li> provides continuous flow of power to facilities critical to public health, safety, and welfare; </li> <li> maximizes the use of clean energy resources and energy storage technologies; and </li> <li> promotes lower energy bills. </li> </ul> <p>The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA): (1) shall designate a representative to coordinate with private entities interested in donating energy system technologies and services for such purposes following a major disaster or emergency, (2) is encouraged to coordinate with the Department of Energy (DOE) and the Department of Homeland Security in designating such representative, and (3) is encouraged to consult with the Department of Defense (DOD) regarding DOD's experience in building resilient power systems.</p> <p>Each National Laboratory, in coordination with DOE programs that provide assistance to states and industry, must make technical assistance available to federal, state, and local agencies and private entities interested in: (1) developing plans or providing guidance on the design of a resilient and efficient energy system or building; and (2) building, repairing, restoring, reconstructing, or replacing an energy system or building following a major disaster or emergency.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
