<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1121" measure-id="id115hr1121" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-16" update-date="2017-06-28">
<title>Pre-existing Conditions Protection Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1121v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-28">
<action-date>2017-02-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Pre-existing Conditions Protection Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill sets forth amendments that would take effect in the case of the repeal of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA) and the health care provisions of the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 and the restoration of the provisions amended by those provisions.</p> <p>If the amendments take effect, the Public Health Service Act, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), and Internal Revenue Code are revised to maintain PPACA consumer protections. Specifically, the bill would maintain the:</p> <ul> <li>requirement for health insurance to cover preexisting conditions,</li> <li>requirement for health insurers to accept every employer and every individual applying for coverage,</li> <li>prohibition against health insurers discriminating against individuals based on health status factors,</li> <li>prohibition against collecting genetic information in connection with issuing health insurance, and</li> <li>requirements for workplace wellness programs connected to health insurance.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
