<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3839" measure-id="id115hr3839" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-26" update-date="2018-03-06">
<title>Today's American Dream Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3839v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-06">
<action-date>2017-09-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Today's American Dream Act</strong></p> <p>This bill establishes new programs or amends existing programs related to workforce and community development. It directs: (1) the Department of Labor to award grants for job skills training for older individuals (older than age 45) and for workers in highly-skilled industries; and (2) the Department of Education to award scholarships to students pursuing degrees in science, technology, engineering, or mathematics (STEM) and teaching certifications. </p> <p>The bill also amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) expand and extend the work opportunity tax credit, (2) allow tax credits for wages paid to interns by small business owners, and (3) extend and increase the new markets tax credit. </p> <p>With respect to community development, the bill limits the first-time homebuyer tax credit to residences purchased in economically distressed communities. It requires the Small Business Administration to make grants for commercial investment in economically underserved communities and direct loans to small business concerns.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must report to Congress on efforts to expand access to broadband service.</p> <p>The bill establishes a Commission on Innovation in the Office of Management and Budget to study new and developing technologies. </p> <p>The Department of Health and Human Services must: (1) study characteristics of populations that do not have health insurance coverage, and (2) award grants for free dental health services in underserved communities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
