<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2803" measure-id="id115hr2803" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-07" update-date="2018-03-12">
<title>Abolish Human Trafficking Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2803v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-12">
<action-date>2017-06-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Abolish Human Trafficking Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill sets forth a variety of measures to address the prevention and punishment of human trafficking and to assist trafficking victims. Included among these are provisions concerning:</p> <ul> <li>restitution for victims;</li> <li>funding of investigations of offenses relating to sexual abuse of children;</li> <li>grants to states and localities and other entities for victim service assistance;</li> <li>training of health, victim service, and federal law enforcement personnel, including through the use of a victim screening protocol by the Department of Homeland Security;</li> <li>penalties imposed for slavery offenses, sex trafficking of children, and repeat convictions for transportation for illegal sexual activity and related crimes;</li> <li>travel for the purpose of engaging in any illicit sexual conduct;</li> <li>designation of additional Department of Justice resources for prosecution and service coordination;</li> <li>penalties for offenses involving organized human trafficking, sexual abuse, sexual exploitation, or transportation for prostitution or any illegal sexual activity; and</li> <li>studies of the physical and psychological effects of serious harm to victims.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
