<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1835" measure-id="id115hr1835" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-30" update-date="2017-07-08">
<title>Prohibition of United Nations Taxation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1835v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-08">
<action-date>2017-03-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Prohibition of United Nations Taxation Act</strong></p> <p>This bill prohibits the United States from paying any voluntary or assessed contribution to the United Nations or any of its specialized or affiliated agencies: (1) if the U.N. attempts to implement or impose any taxation or fee on any U.S. person or attempts to borrow funds from the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (World Bank), the International Monetary Fund, or any other similar or regional international financial institution; and (2) unless the President certifies to Congress by 15 days before such payment that the U.N. is not engaged in any effort to develop, advocate, promote, or publicize any proposal concerning taxation or fees on any U.S. person to raise revenue for the U.N.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
