<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1783" measure-id="id115hr1783" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-29" update-date="2017-12-05">
<title>Improving Veterans Access to Quality Care Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1783v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-05">
<action-date>2017-03-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Improving Veterans Access to Quality Care Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to: (1) develop a plan for working with institutions of higher education to develop partnerships for the establishment or expansion of programs of advanced degrees in prosthetics and orthotics in order to improve and enhance the availability of high quality prosthetic and orthotic care for veterans; and (2) provide full practice authority to advanced practice registered nurses, physician assistants, and such other licensed VA health care professionals as is consistent with the education, training, and certification of such professionals without regard to any limitation that would otherwise be imposed on the health care practice of such professionals by a state licensing or credentialing body. </p> <p>The Department of Defense (DOD) must transfer to the VA upon request the credentialing data of a DOD health care provider who is hired by the VA.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
