<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2582" measure-id="id115hr2582" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-22" update-date="2018-01-24">
<title>Confirming State Land Grants for Education Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2582v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-24">
<action-date>2017-10-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on September 12, 2017. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Confirming State Land Grants for Education Act </b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill allows the state of Utah, subject to valid existing rights, to select certain lands under the administrative jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) of the Department of the Interior that are identified as available for disposal by land exchange in the Record of Decision for the Pony Express Resource Management Plan and Rangeland Program Summary for Utah County in fulfillment of certain land grants made to Utah upon being admitted as a state to further the purposes of the State of Utah School and Institutional Trust Lands Administration, without further land use planning action by the BLM. </p> <p>The criteria listed in Decision 3 of the Lands Program of the resource management plan shall not apply to any lands selected by Utah pursuant to this bill. <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2582v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-02">
<action-date>2017-09-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Confirming State Land Grants for Education Act </b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill allows the state of Utah, subject to valid existing rights, to select certain lands under the administrative jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) of the Department of the Interior that are identified as available for disposal by land exchange in the Record of Decision for the Pony Express Resource Management Plan and Rangeland Program Summary for Utah County in fulfillment of certain land grants made to Utah upon being admitted as a state to further the purposes of the State of Utah School and Institutional Trust Lands Administration, without further land use planning action by the BLM. </p> <p>The criteria listed in Decision 3 of the Lands Program of the resource management plan shall not apply to any lands selected by Utah pursuant to this bill. <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2582v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-09">
<action-date>2017-05-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Confirming State Land Grants for Education Act </b></p> <p>This bill allows the state of Utah to select certain lands under the administrative jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) of the Department of the Interior that are identified as available for disposal by land exchange in the Record of Decision for the Pony Express Resource Management Plan and Rangeland Program Summary for Utah County, as amended by the Pony Express Plan Amendment (November 1997), in fulfillment of certain land grants made to Utah upon being admitted as a state, including for the establishment of certain state institutions, including certain local schools, under the Act of July 16, 1894, without further land use planning action by the BLM. </p> <p>The criteria listed in Decision 3 of the Lands Program of the resource management plan shall not apply to any lands selected by Utah pursuant to this bill. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
