<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="536" measure-id="id115hr536" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-13" update-date="2017-08-07">
<title>Protection From Obamacare Mandates and Congressional Equity Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr536v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-07">
<action-date>2017-01-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protection From Obamacare Mandates and Congressional Equity Act </b></p> <p>This bill withholds the salaries of Members of a house of Congress that has not agreed to a budget resolution for FY2018 by April 15, 2017, as required by the Congressional Budget Act of 1974. </p> <p>Salaries are withheld from April 16, 2017, until the house of Congress agrees to a budget resolution or the last day of the 115th Congress, whichever is earlier. </p> <p>The Inspector General of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), by three days after the President's budget is due, shall: (1) make an annual determination of whether the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) and the President are in compliance with statutory requirements for the President's annual budget submission to Congress, and (2) provide a written notification of such determination to specified congressional committees.</p> <p>No funds may be appropriated or otherwise be made available from the Treasury for the pay of the Director, Deputy Director, and Deputy Director for Management of the OMB during any period of noncompliance determined by the OPM Inspector General. Such officials may not receive pay for any period of noncompliance at any time after the end of that period. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
