<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3765" measure-id="id115hr3765" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-13" update-date="2018-02-28">
<title>To redesignate certain clinics of the Department of Veterans Affairs located in Montana.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3765v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-28">
<action-date>2017-09-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill redesignates Department of Veterans Affairs clinics in Montana at the following locations:</p> <ul> <li>2687 Palmer Street in Missoula as the &quot;David J. Thatcher Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic,&quot;</li> <li>1775 Spring Creek Lane in Billings as the &quot;Dr. Joseph Medicine Crow Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic,&quot; and </li> <li>1766 Majestic Lane in Billings as the &quot;Benjamin Charles Steele Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic.&quot;</li> </ul> <p>Any local public display of the name of the Dr. Joseph Medicine Crow Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic carried out by the United States or through the use of federal funds shall include both the English name, Dr. Joseph Medicine Crow, and the Crow name, Dakaak Baako. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
