<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3936" measure-id="id115hr3936" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-03" update-date="2018-01-09">
<title>National Flood Insurance Program Debt Forgiveness Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3936v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-09">
<action-date>2017-10-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>National Flood Insurance Program Debt Forgiveness Act of</strong><b> 2017</b></p> <p>This bill cancels all indebtedness outstanding as of September 30, 2016, of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) under any notes or other obligations issued pursuant to the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 and the Federal Flood Insurance Act of 1956.</p> <p>Such cancelled indebtedness may be treated as a public debt of the United States and is designated as an emergency pursuant to the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
