<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="238" measure-id="id115hr238" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-04" update-date="2017-01-11">
<title>Commodity End-User Relief Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr238v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-01-11">
<action-date>2017-01-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Commodity End User Relief Act</b></p> <p>This bill reauthorizes through FY2021, and revises provisions related to, operations of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC).</p> <p>In addition, the bill amends the Commodity Exchange Act to direct registered futures associations to require their futures commission merchant members to meet certain procedural and reporting requirements. </p> <p> </s>The CFTC is authorized to require that certain property of the bankruptcy estate of a commodity broker who is a debtor in Chapter 7 bankruptcy (also known as "liquidation" bankruptcy) be included in customer property to the extent that such property is insufficient to satisfy the net equity claims of the broker's public customers. </p> <p> </s>Before promulgating a regulation or issuing an order, the CFTC must publish an assessment of the costs and benefits of the action.</p> <p>The heads of the CFTC's administrative units shall serve at the pleasure of the CFTC.</p> <p>The bill establishes, within the CFTC, the Office of the Chief Economist.</p> <p>The duration of an omnibus order of investigation (authorizing the CFTC to issue subpoenas to multiple persons in relation to a particular subject matter area) shall not be indefinite.</p> <p>The bill exempts specified entities from certain&nbsp;clearing requirements applicable to swaps.</p> <p> With respect to swap dealer registration requirements, the bill: (1)&nbsp;prohibits the CFTC from modifying,&nbsp;except by affirmative rule or regulation,&nbsp;the threshold for <em>de minimus</em> (minor in quantity) swap dealing; (2) under certain circumstances, allows the use of specified financial models with respect to calculating capital requirements; and (3) modifies other provisions.</p> <p>The bill exempts certain swap activities involving non-U.S. persons&nbsp;from U.S. swaps requirements.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
