<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="263" measure-id="id115hr263" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-04" update-date="2017-06-26">
<title>United States Sovereignty and Commercial Freedom Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr263v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-26">
<action-date>2017-01-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>United States Sovereignty and Commercial Freedom Act</strong></p> <p>This bill declares that U.N. Security Council Resolution 2334 shall have no force or effect under U.S. law, and the United States shall not be bound by any provision of such resolution. </p> <p> Resolution 2334 characterizes Israeli settlements in the West Bank and East Jerusalem as illegal and demands cessation of settlement activities. </p> <p>Nothing in such resolution or in any subsequently adopted Security Council resolution relating to Israel may be used to establish or demonstrate the existence of a violation of U.S. law or an offence against the law of nations in U.S. courts, including by giving standing, a cause of action, or a source of damages. </p> <p>Any reference to Israel in U.S. law, or in any treaty or other international agreement to which both the United States and Israel are parties, shall be interpreted to include any territory over which Israel exercises civil jurisdiction, including East Jerusalem, Areas &quot;C&quot; and &quot;H2&quot; of the West Bank, and the Golan Heights. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
