<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2866" measure-id="id115hr2866" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-08" update-date="2018-02-13">
<title>Reducing Unnecessary Barriers for Relative Foster Parents Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2866v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-13">
<action-date>2017-06-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Reducing Unnecessary Barriers for Relative Foster Parents Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to identify reputable model standards for the licensing of foster family homes.</p> <p>Part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act is amended to require state plans for foster care and adoption assistance to require submission to HHS of information addressing:</p> <ul> <li>whether the state licensing standards are in accord with HHS-identified model standards, and if not, the reason for the specific deviation and a description of why having a standard that is reasonably in accord with the corresponding national model standards is not appropriate for the state;</li> <li>whether the state has elected to waive certain standards for relative foster family homes, a description of standards most commonly waived, and if the state has not so elected, the reason why;</li> <li>if the state has elected to waive such standards, how caseworkers are trained to use the waiver authority and whether the state has developed a process or offered tools to assist caseworkers in waiving nonsafety standards to quickly place children with relatives; and</li> <li>a description of the steps the state is taking to improve caseworker training or the process, if any. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2866v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-13">
<action-date>2017-06-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> <b>Reducing Barriers for Relative Foster Parents Act</b></p> <p> This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to identify reputable model standards for the licensing of foster family homes.</p> <p>Part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act is amended to require state plans for foster care and adoption assistance to require submission to HHS of information addressing:</p> <ul> <li>whether the state licensing standards are in accord with HHS-identified model standards, and if not, the reason for the specific deviation and a description of why having a standard that is reasonably in accord with the corresponding national model standards is not appropriate for the state;</li> <li>whether the state has elected to waive certain standards for relative foster family homes, a description of standards most commonly waived, and if the state has not so elected, the reason why;</li> <li>if the state has elected to waive such standards, how caseworkers are trained to use the waiver authority and whether the state has developed a process or offered tools to assist caseworkers in waiving nonsafety standards to quickly place children with relatives; and</li> <li>a description of the steps the state is taking to improve caseworker training or the process, if any. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
