<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1468" measure-id="id115hr1468" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-09" update-date="2017-09-13">
<title>Recognizing America's Children Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1468v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-13">
<action-date>2017-03-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Recognizing America's Children Act</strong></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to cancel the removal of, and adjust to conditional nonimmigrant for an initial five-year period the status of, an alien who: </p> <ul> <li>was younger than 16 years old when he or she initially entered the United States and has been physically present in the United States since January 1, 2012; </li> <li>is a person of good moral character; </li> <li>is not inadmissible or deportable on specified grounds under the Immigration and Nationality Act; </li> <li>has not participated in the persecution of any person on account of race, religion, nationality, membership in a particular social group, or political opinion; </li> <li>has not been convicted of certain offenses under federal or state law; </li> <li> is 18 years or older and has earned a high school diploma, general education development certificate, or high school equivalency diploma in the United States, has been admitted to an institution of higher education, or has a valid work authorization; and </li> <li>has never been under a final order of exclusion, deportation, or removal unless the alien has remained in the United States under color of law after such order's issuance or received the order before attaining the age of 18.</li> </ul> <p> An alien applying for relief under this bill shall: (1) register under the Military Selective Service Act if so required, (2) undergo a medical examination, (3) submit biometric and biographic data, and (4) complete security and law enforcement background checks.</p> <p> DHS shall under specified circumstances terminate or extend the conditional nonimmigrant status of an alien who is at least 18 years old. </p> <p>A conditional nonimmigrant may file an application to adjust his or her status to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence during a specified period. </p> <p> An alien who adjusts to permanent resident status may apply for naturalization upon compliance with all immigration law requirements.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
