<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5440" measure-id="id115hr5440" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2018-04-09" update-date="2018-04-10">
<title>To require notice from the Secretary of the Treasury in the case of any closure of a Taxpayer Assistance Center.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr5440v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-04-10">
<action-date>2018-04-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill requires the Department of the Treasury to provide a publicly available notice at least 90 days before the effective date of a proposed closure of a Taxpayer Assistance Center. The notice must identify: (1) the center proposed for closure, (2) the date of the proposed closure, and (3) alternative sources of taxpayer assistance which may be utilized by taxpayers affected by the closure.</p> <p>Treasury must also submit to Congress a report that includes the information in the notice and the reasons for the proposed closure. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
