<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3610" measure-id="id115hr3610" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-28" update-date="2018-02-12">
<title>Donations in Rough Years (DRY) Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3610v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-12">
<action-date>2017-07-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Donations in Rough Years (DRY) Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Food Security Act of 1985, with respect to the Conservation Reserve Program (CRP), to permit hay that is harvested in the course of an activity that is authorized under CRP and complies with the program's requirements to be donated to the owners or operators of certain farms or ranches that are in disaster areas or are experiencing a drought. </p> <p>(CRP provides payments to farmers who agree to remove environmentally sensitive land from agricultural production and plant species that will improve environmental health and quality.) </p> <p>The hay may be donated to the owner or operator of a farm or ranch that is located in: (1) the state in which the hay is harvested, and (2) a county that is either experiencing a drought with a specified intensity or with respect to which the President has issued a declaration under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act that a major disaster exists due to a fire. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
