<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3802" measure-id="id115hr3802" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-18" update-date="2017-12-20">
<title>Appalachian Regional Commission Reform Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3802v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-20">
<action-date>2017-09-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Appalachian Regional Commission Reform Act</strong></p> <p>This bill declares that the mission of the Appalachian Regional Commission shall be to focus primarily on poverty reduction and economic development in areas in the Appalachian region with the most persistent poverty. The headquarters of the commission shall be located in that region.</p> <p>The bill increases from 50% to 60% the minimum amount of the grant expenditures approved by the commission that shall support activities or projects that benefit severely and persistently distressed counties and areas.</p> <p>The commission shall: (1) allocate at least 60% of the funds made available each fiscal year for its Area Development Program for projects in counties designated as distressed, and (2) submit an annual report on the allocation of program funds to such counties. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
