<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1259" measure-id="id115hr1259" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-28" update-date="2018-04-03">
<title>VA Accountability First Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1259v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-04-03">
<action-date>2017-03-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>VA Accountability First Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill revises the authority of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to remove, demote by a reduction in grade and pay, or suspend a VA employee, including a member in a senior executive position, for reasons of performance or misconduct.</p> <p>A demoted individual shall not be placed on administrative leave during the appeals period and may receive pay only if he or she reports for duty or is approved to use certain accrued unused leave.</p> <p> An expedited appeals process is established for such VA decisions, including the right to appeal to the Merit Systems Protection Board. </p> <p>The VA may not remove, demote, or suspend an employee: (1) without the approval of the Special Counsel if the individual seeks corrective action from the Office of Special Counsel based on an alleged prohibited personnel practice, and (2) until a final decision in the case of a whistle-blower complaint. </p> <p>Whistle-blower protections are revised, including to prohibit the VA from taking any such action against a person who has a pending whistle-blower complaint. </p> <p> (Sec. 4) The VA shall reduce the federal annuity of an individual removed from the VA Senior Executive Service (SES) who is convicted of a felony that influenced his or her performance while employed in such position.</p> <p>The VA may: (1) reduce the federal annuity of an individual who was convicted of such a felony and was subject to removal or transfer from the SES but who left the VA before final action was taken; and (2) recoup an award, a bonus, or relocation expenses paid to a VA employee under specified circumstances. </p> <p>(Sec. 8) The VA may directly appoint qualifying individuals to the positions of Medical Center Director and Director of Veterans Integrated Service Network.</p> <p> (Sec. 9) The bill revises time periods for adverse action reviews with respect to physicians, dentists, podiatrists, chiropractors, optometrists, registered nurses, physician assistants, and expanded-function dental auxiliaries.</p> <p> (Sec. 10) The VA shall report to Congress annually on performance awards and bonuses awarded to certain high-level employees.</p> <p>(Sec. 11) The VA shall: (1) ensure that supervisors are evaluated on actions taken to improve employee performance, and (2) provide supervisors with training on whistle-blower protections.</p> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1259v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-18">
<action-date>2017-02-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>VA Accountability First Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to remove, demote by a reduction in grade and pay, or suspend a VA employee, including a member in a senior executive position, for reasons of performance or misconduct. </p> <p>The bill prescribes VA removal and employee appeals procedures.</p> <p>Whistle-blower protections are revised, including by prohibiting VA from taking any such action against a person who has a pending whistle-blower complaint. </p> <p>This bill provides for the reduction of federal annuities of VA employees and retirees convicted of a felony that influenced their performance while employed in such position. </p> <p>The VA may recoup certain bonuses, awards, and reallocation expenses. </p> <p>The VA may directly appoint qualifying individuals to the positions of Medical Center Director and Director of Veterans Integrated Service Network.</p> <p>The bill revises time periods for adverse action reviews with respect to physicians, dentists, podiatrists, chiropractors, optometrists, registered nurses, physician assistants, and expanded-function dental auxiliaries.</p> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
