<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2977" measure-id="id115hr2977" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-21" update-date="2017-11-22">
<title>Balanced Budget Accountability Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2977v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-22">
<action-date>2017-06-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Balanced Budget Accountability Act</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), upon adoption by a chamber of Congress of a concurrent budget resolution for a fiscal year, to determine and submit to the Speaker of the House of Representatives or the President pro tempore of the Senate a certification as to whether that chamber has adopted a balanced budget. </p> <p> &quot;Balanced budget&quot; means a concurrent budget resolution providing that for FY2027 and each succeeding fiscal year to which the resolution applies total outlays do not exceed total receipts and are not more than 18% of the gross domestic product for such fiscal year.</p> <p> If OMB does not certify that a chamber has adopted a balanced budget for FY2018 before July 28, 2017, the payroll administrator of each chamber must deposit in an escrow account all payments for compensation of Members of Congress serving in that chamber otherwise required beginning on such date. Such deposits shall be released to such Members on the earlier of: (1) the day on which OMB certifies that the chamber has adopted a balanced budget for FY2018, or (2) the last day of the 115th Congress.</p> <p> The same requirements shall apply for FY2019 if OMB does not certify that a chamber has adopted a balanced budget for FY2019 before April 16, 2018.</p> <p>If OMB does not certify that a chamber has adopted a balanced budget for FY2020, or any succeeding fiscal year, before April 16 of the prior fiscal year, each Member of that chamber shall be paid $1 annually for pay periods beginning on April 16 of the prior fiscal year and ending on the earlier of:</p> <ul> <li>the date on which OMB certifies that the chamber has adopted a balanced budget for such fiscal year, or</li> <li>the last day of the same calendar year in which such period begins.</li> </ul> <p> This bill requires legislation in the House and Senate that increases revenue to be agreed upon only by an affirmative vote of three-fifths of the Members of that chamber.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
