<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2092" measure-id="id115hr2092" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-12" update-date="2017-07-05">
<title>Promotion and Expansion of Private Employee Ownership Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2092v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-05">
<action-date>2017-04-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Promotion and Expansion of Private Employee Ownership Act of 201</strong><b>7</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) extend to all domestic corporations, including S corporations, provisions allowing deferral of tax on gain from the sale of employer securities to an S corporation-sponsored employee stock ownership plan (ESOP); and (2) allow a tax deduction for 50% of the interest incurred on loans to S corporation-sponsored ESOPs for the purchase of employer securities.</p> <p> The Department of the Treasury must establish the S Corporation Employee Ownership Assistance Office to foster increased employee ownership of S corporations.</p> <p>This bill also amends the Small Business Act to define "ESOP business concern" and allow such a concern to continue to qualify for loans, preferences, and other programs under such Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
