<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3359" measure-id="id115hr3359" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-24" update-date="2017-11-16">
<title>Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3359v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-16">
<action-date>2017-07-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Cybersecurity and Infrastructure </b><b>Security Agency Act of 201</b><b>7</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to redesignate the Department of Homeland Security's (DHS's) National Protection and Programs Directorate as the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) to be headed by a Director of National Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security to lead national efforts to protect and enhance the security and resilience of U.S. cybersecurity, emergency communications,&nbsp;and critical infrastructure. </p> <p>CISA shall be composed of DHS components reorganized as: (1) the Cybersecurity Division; (2) the Infrastructure Security Division;&nbsp;and (3) the Emergency Communications Division, which was previously the Office for Emergency Communications. The agency will also have a privacy officer to ensure compliance with relevant federal laws.</p> <p>CISA must carry out DHS's responsibilities concerning chemical facilities antiterrorism standards.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
