<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3027" measure-id="id115hr3027" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-22" update-date="2018-02-27">
<title>SERVE Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3027v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-27">
<action-date>2017-06-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Securing Experienced Returning Veterans Employment Act of 2017 or the SERVE Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs that in order to improve the accuracy and completeness of a certification or verification of job skills and experience acquired while on active duty, the Department of Defense (DOD) (and the Department of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy) shall: (1) establish a database to record all training performed by members of the armed forces that may have application to civilian sector employment, (2) make such information that is unclassified available to states and other employers so that they may allow military training to satisfy licensing or certification requirements for civilian professions, and (3) ensure that certifications and verifications of job skills and experience can be confirmed by states and other employers. </p> <p>A state may use a certification or verification provided to a member of the armed forces and request DOD or the Coast Guard to confirm its accuracy and authenticity. Such information shall be confirmed or denied within five business days.</p> <p> A certification or verification provided to a member of the armed forces and accepted by a state to satisfy licensing or certification requirements shall be valid in all states once used in the accepting states.</p> <p>Pre-separation counseling concerning licensing and certification requirements shall include state-submitted and approved lists of military training and skills that satisfy occupational certifications and licenses. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
