<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2473" measure-id="id115hr2473" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-16" update-date="2018-02-22">
<title>Put Trafficking Victims First Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2473v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-22">
<action-date>2017-05-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Enforcing Justice for Victims of Trafficking Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Justice (DOJ), in coordination with the Department of Health and Human Services, to provide training and technical assistance to help federal, state, local, and tribal governments combat, and assist victims of, human trafficking.</p> <p>The National Institute of Justice must: </p> <ul> <li>establish a working group to identify best practices for collecting data on human trafficking; </li> <li>report on efforts to develop a national methodology to determine the prevalence of human trafficking in the United States, best practices to determine the prevalence of human trafficking, and the effectiveness of current policies and procedures to address victims' needs; and </li> <li>coordinate with federal, state, local, and tribal governments, and private organizations, to conduct a census of human trafficking survivors to estimate the prevalence of human trafficking in the United States.</li> </ul> <p>DOJ must report on efforts to increase mandatory restitution orders and asset forfeiture to provide restitution to victims of trafficking.</p> <p>Finally, the bill encourages states to implement certain protections for victims of trafficking. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
