<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3567" measure-id="id115hr3567" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-28" update-date="2018-01-25">
<title>To authorize the purchase of a small parcel of Natural Resources Conservation Service property in Riverside, California, by the Riverside Corona Resource Conservation District, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3567v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-25">
<action-date>2017-10-31</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House reported version is repeated here.)</p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to sell a parcel of real property, including improvements, located at 4500 Glenwood Drive in Riverside, California, consisting of approximately 8.75 acres and administered by the Natural Resources Conservation Service, to the Riverside Corona Resource Conservation District for such property's appraised value. </p> <p>USDA and the district may survey such property to facilitate its purchase. </p> <p>USDA shall: (1) not reserve any future interest in such property except as may be acceptable to the district; and (2) be required to meet the disclosure requirements for, but shall not be required to remediate or abate any such releases of, hazardous substances, pollutants, or contaminants on such property. </p> <p>In conjunction with or in addition to the purchase of such property, USDA may enter into leases, contracts, and cooperative agreements with the district. </p> <p>USDA may lease real property from the district on a noncompetitive basis. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3567v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-18">
<action-date>2017-10-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to sell a parcel of real property, including improvements, located at 4500 Glenwood Drive in Riverside, California, consisting of approximately 8.75 acres and administered by the Natural Resources Conservation Service, to the Riverside Corona Resource Conservation District for such property's appraised value. </p> <p>USDA and the district may survey such property to facilitate its purchase. </p> <p>USDA shall: (1) not reserve any future interest in such property except as may be acceptable to the district; and (2) be required to meet the disclosure requirements for, but shall not be required to remediate or abate any such releases of, hazardous substances, pollutants, or contaminants on such property. </p> <p>In conjunction with or in addition to the purchase of such property, USDA may enter into leases, contracts, and cooperative agreements with the district. </p> <p>USDA may lease real property from the district on a noncompetitive basis. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3567v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-16">
<action-date>2017-07-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill directs the Department of Agriculture to sell and quitclaim all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to a parcel of real property, including improvements, located at 4500 Glenwood Drive in Riverside, California, consisting of approximately 8.75 acres and administered by the Natural Resources Conservation Service, to the Riverside Corona Resource Conservation District. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
