<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1535" measure-id="id115hr1535" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-15" update-date="2017-10-19">
<title>Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Wild and Scenic River Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1535v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-19">
<action-date>2017-03-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Wild and Scenic River Act</b></p> <p> This bill amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate specified segments of the Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook in Connecticut as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System. </p> <p>The Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Wild and Scenic Committee, in coordination with the Department of the Interior, shall lead and coordinate the implementation of the management plan for the designated river segments according to the amendments to the Lower Farmington River and Salmon Brook Management Plan, dated June 2011, as determined to be consistent with this bill. </p> <p> The designation made by this bill shall not be construed to: (1) prohibit, pre-empt, or abridge future licensing or re-licensing of the Rainbow Dam and Reservoir by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission as a federally licensed hydroelectric generation project; or (2) affect the operation of, or impose any flow or release requirements on, the unlicensed hydroelectric facility at the dam and reservoir. </p> <p> The Lower Farmington River shall not be administered as part of the National Park System (NPS) or be subject to NPS regulations. </p> <p>The National Park Service may not administratively change the extent of the protection afforded to the river segments designated by this bill.</p> <p> The bill also revises the description of a specified designated segment of the Farmington River in Connecticut.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
