<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="665" measure-id="id115hr665" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-24" update-date="2017-02-15">
<title>Airport Perimeter and Access Control Security Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr665v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-02-15">
<action-date>2017-01-31</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Airport Perimeter and Access Control Security Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration to:</p> <ul> <li> update the Transportation Sector Security Rick Assessment for the aviation sector, </li> <li> update the Comprehensive Risk Assessment of Perimeter and Access Control Security for airports,</li> <li>conduct conduct a system-wide assessment of airport access control points and airport perimeter security, and</li> <li>update the 2012 National Strategy for Airport Perimeter and Access Control Security.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr665v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-02-15">
<action-date>2017-01-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Airport Perimeter and Access Control Security Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration to update:</p> <ul> <li> the Transportation Sector Security Rick Assessment for the aviation sector, </li> <li> the Comprehensive Risk Assessment of Perimeter and Access Control Security for airports (as well as conduct a system-wide assessment of airport access control points and airport perimeter security), and</li> <li>the 2012 National Strategy for Airport Perimeter and Access Control Security.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
