<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1483" measure-id="id115hr1483" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-09" update-date="2017-06-19">
<title>Litigation Relief for Forest Management Projects Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1483v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-19">
<action-date>2017-03-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Litigation Relief for Forest Management Projects Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 and the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to prohibit the Department of Agriculture (USDA) or the Department of the Interior from being required to engage in any additional consultation with respect to: (1) the listing of a species as threatened or endangered, or a designation of a critical habitat, if a land management plan or land use plan, respectively, has been adopted by USDA or Interior as of the date of the listing or designation; or (2) any provision of such an adopted plan. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
