<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5375" measure-id="id115hr5375" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2018-03-21" update-date="2018-03-30">
<title>To require the Secretary of the Treasury to submit to Congress a comprehensive customer service strategy for the Internal Revenue Service.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr5375v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-30">
<action-date>2018-03-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill requires the Department of the Treasury to submit to Congress a comprehensive customer service strategy for the Internal Revenue Service. </p> <p>The strategy must include: </p> <ul> <li> a plan to provide assistance that meets reasonable taxpayer expectations and conforms with best practices of customer service provided in the private sector; </li> <li> an assessment of self-service options; </li> <li> proposals to protect taxpayer identity and reduce identity theft; </li> <li> proposals to improve customer service in the short-term, medium-term, and long-term, and</li> <li>metrics and benchmarks for quantitatively measuring progress in meeting each element of the strategy. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
