<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3571" measure-id="id115hr3571" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-28" update-date="2017-10-31">
<title>Reasonable ADA Compliance Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3571v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-31">
<action-date>2017-07-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Reasonable ADA Compliance Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 to deny jurisdiction to a state or federal court in a civil action a plaintiff commences for remedies for disability discrimination in public accommodations and certain services provided by private entities unless: (1) the plaintiff notified the defendant in writing of the alleged violations prior to filing the complaint, (2) the notice identified the specific facts that constitute the alleged violation, (3) a remedial period of 120 days elapses after the notice, (4) the notice informed the defendant that the civil action could not be commenced for 120 days, and (5) the complaint states that the defendant has not corrected the alleged violation.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
