<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2408" measure-id="id115hr2408" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-11" update-date="2017-11-08">
<title>Protecting Girls' Access to Education Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2408v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-08">
<action-date>2017-10-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>Protecting Girls' Access to Education in Vulnerable Settings Act</strong><b> or the Protecting Girls' Access to Education Act</b></p> <p> (Sec. 3) This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) it is critical to ensure that children, particularly girls, displaced by conflicts overseas are able to access educational services because such access can combat extremism and reduce exploitation and poverty; and (2) the educational needs of vulnerable women and girls should be considered in U.S. foreign assistance policies and programs. </p> <p> (Sec. 5) The Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) may advance programs that: </p> <ul> <li>provide safe, primary and secondary education for displaced children; </li> <li>build the capacity of institutions in countries hosting displaced people to prevent displaced children from facing educational discrimination; and </li> <li>help increase the access of displaced children, especially girls, to educational, economic, and entrepreneurial opportunities. </li> </ul> <p>The State Department and USAID may: </p> <ul> <li>coordinate with multilateral organizations to work with foreign governments to collect relevant data, disaggregated by age and gender, on the ability of displaced people to access education and participate in economic activity; and </li> <li>work with domestic and foreign private sector and civil society organizations to promote safe, primary and secondary education for displaced children.</li> </ul> <p> (Sec. 6) The State Department and USAID shall include in any congressional report relating to a foreign assistance program for natural or man-made disaster relief: (1) a breakdown of program beneficiaries by location, age, gender, marital status, and school enrollment status; (2) a description of how such program benefits displaced people; and (3) a description of any primary or secondary educational services supported by such program that specifically address the needs of displaced girls.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2408v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-29">
<action-date>2017-05-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Protecting Girls' Access to Education in Vulnerable Settings Act</strong><b> or the Protecting Girls' Access to Education Act</b></p> <p>This bill urges the consideration of the educational needs of vulnerable women and girls in designing, implementing, and evaluating U.S. foreign assistance policies and programs. </p> <p>The Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) may advance programs that: </p> <ul> <li>provide safe, primary and secondary education for displaced children; </li> <li>build the capacity of institutions in countries hosting displaced people to prevent displaced children from facing educational discrimination; and </li> <li>help increase the access of displaced children, especially girls, to educational, economic, and entrepreneurial opportunities. </li> </ul> <p>The State Department and USAID may: </p> <ul> <li>coordinate with multilateral organizations to work with foreign governments to collect relevant data, disaggregated by age and gender, on the ability of displaced people to access education and participate in economic activity; and </li> <li>work with domestic and foreign private sector and civil society organizations to promote safe, primary and secondary education for displaced children.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
