<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2610" measure-id="id115hr2610" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-23" update-date="2018-01-19">
<title>TRUMPED Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2610v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-19">
<action-date>2017-05-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Taxpayers Require Urgent Mandatory Protection from Egregious Debt Act of 2017 or the TRUMPED Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill allows state and local governments to recover their costs for providing protection to government officials and other individuals allowed Secret Service protection who travel to those jurisdictions for a period of more than 24 hours to visit real property in which such officials or individuals, or their spouses, have any ownership interest. The bill also grants a recovery right to any business that is significantly adversely affected by the provision of such protection.</p> <p>The Secret Service shall report to the homeland security committees of Congress detailing the costs of protecting officials and individuals granted such protection since January 20, 2017.</p> <p>The bill waives the sovereign immunity of the United States ito the extent required to enable the recovery of costs allowed by this bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
