<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2182" measure-id="id115hr2182" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-26" update-date="2017-09-19">
<title>Plum Island Preservation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2182v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-19">
<action-date>2017-07-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Plum Island Preservation Act</b></p> <p> (Sec. 3) This bill requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to submit to Congress a report on alternatives for the final disposition of Plum Island, New York, including transfer to another government or nonprofit entity for education, research, or conservation purposes. </p> <p>This report must contain, for each alternative, an analysis of: </p> <ul> <li>the effect it would have on the island's resources;</li> <li>remediation responsibilities under it;</li> <li>legislation necessary to implement it;</li> <li>possible implications and issues of implementing it;</li> <li> potential costs, including costs of the transition, hazard mitigation, and cleanup of property that would be incurred by a recipient; and </li> <li>potential revenue. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 4) No action, including any pre-sale marketing activity, may be taken to carry out the requirement under current law for the General Services Administration to sell the property and assets that support Plum Island operations until at least 180 days after such report has been submitted.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2182v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-19">
<action-date>2017-04-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Plum Island Preservation Act</b></p> <p> This bill requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to submit to Congress a report on alternatives for the final disposition of Plum Island, New York, including transfer to another government or nonprofit entity for education, research, or conservation purposes. </p> <p>This report must contain, for each alternative, an analysis of: </p> <ul> <li>the effect it would have on the island's resources;</li> <li>remediation responsibilities under it;</li> <li>legislation necessary to implement it;</li> <li>possible implications and issues of implementing it;</li> <li> potential costs, including costs of the transition, hazard mitigation, and cleanup of property that would be incurred by a recipient; and </li> <li>potential revenue. </li> </ul> <p> No action, including any pre-sale marketing activity, may be taken to carry out the requirement under current law for the General Services Administration to sell the property and assets that support Plum Island operations until at least 180 days after such report has been submitted.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
