<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1028" measure-id="id115hr1028" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-13" update-date="2017-06-07">
<title>Commute Less Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1028v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-07">
<action-date>2017-02-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Commute Less Act of 2017</b></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill requires metropolitan planning organization (MPO) transportation plans to include, among other things, employer and transportation management organization outreach activities and strategies to help create and expand employer-based commuter programs.</p> <p>An &quot;employer-based commuter program&quot; means a program implemented by employers to provide their employees with alternatives to driving to and from work in a vehicle occupied by a single individual.</p> <p>The bill revises requirements regarding the interested parties that may comment on MPO transportation plans to include representatives of employers, employer-based commuter programs, and transportation management organizations.</p> <p>The bill requires each MPO to establish an employer advisory council consisting of representatives of employers in the transportation management area. Each council shall develop and maintain a commuter trip reduction plan that identifies area goals for the reduction of vehicle miles traveled during peak commuting hours.</p> <p> MPO transportation improvement programs shall include, among other things, a list of projects identified in a commuter trip reduction plan that help achieve such reduction goals.</p> <p>The Department of Transportation (DOT) is authorized to make a grant to a national nonprofit organization or other entity engaged in efforts relating to employer-based commuter programs to establish and operate an information clearinghouse for employer investment in transportation and employer-based commuter programs.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) Recipients of federal assistance for the construction of federal-aid highway projects costing $75 million or more, or that will reduce traffic flow for more than 120 days, shall prepare congestion mitigation plans that include funding for projects to reduce vehicle miles traveled during peak commuting hours along impacted corridors.</p> <p> (Sec. 4) DOT shall: </p> <ul> <li> develop and implement a plan to expand and promote employer-based commuter programs; and</li> <li> report to Congress recommendations on how to better integrate such programs into disaster emergency planning, preparedness, and response activities.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
