<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1694" measure-id="id115hr1694" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-23" update-date="2017-06-14">
<title>Fannie and Freddie Open Records Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1694v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-14">
<action-date>2017-04-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fannie and Freddie Open Records Act of 2017</b></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill applies the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) to the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) during any period either such enterprise is under conservatorship or receivership of the Federal Housing Finance Agency. The FOIA exemption for trade secrets and commercial or financial information shall apply without regard to whether such information was obtained from a person outside Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac. </p> <p>The FOIA requirements apply to records requests filed after the effective date of this bill that relate to any Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac record created before, on, or after the effective date.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) To cover the cost of administering FOIA, Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac shall establish fee schedules to collect fees from requests for records intended for a commercial use.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1694v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-14">
<action-date>2017-04-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fannie and Freddie Open Records Act of 2017</b></p> <p> This bill amends the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) to require the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac), during any period in which they are under conservatorship or receivership of the Federal Housing Finance Agency, to comply with FOIA's public information disclosure requirements that apply to federal agencies.</p> <p>The requirement applies to FOIA requests filed after enactment of this bill that relate to any record created before, on, or after the enactment of this bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1694v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-04">
<action-date>2017-03-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fannie and Freddie Open Records Act of 2017</b></p> <p><strong></strong></p> <p> This bill amends the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) to require the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) to be subject to FOIA's public information disclosure requirements during any period in which they are under conservatorship or receivership.</p> <p>The requirement applies to FOIA requests filed after enactment of this bill that relate to any record created before, on, or after the enactment of this bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
