<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="195" measure-id="id115hr195" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-03" update-date="2018-01-24">
<title>Making further continuing appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr195v49" currentChamber="BOTH" update-date="2018-01-24">
<action-date>2018-01-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Public Law</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<b><p /></b> <p>DIVISION A--FEDERAL REGISTER PRINTING SAVINGS ACT OF 2017 </p> <p><em>Federal Register Printing Savings Act of 2017 </em> </p> <p>(Sec. 2) This division bars the Government Publishing Office from furnishing a printed copy of the Federal Register without charge to any Member of Congress or any other office of the United States during a year unless the Member or office requests: (1) a printed copy of a specific issue of the Federal Register, or (2) a subscription to printed copies of the Federal Register for that year. </p> <p>DIVISION B--EXTENSION OF CONTINUING APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2018 </p> <p><em>Extension of Continuing Appropriations Act, 2018 </em></p> <p>(Sec. 2001) This division amends the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2018 to provide continuing FY2018 appropriations to federal agencies through February 8, 2018 (January 19, 2018, under current law). </p> <p>It ends the government shutdown that began when the existing continuing resolution (CR) expired because none of the 12 FY2018 regular appropriations bills that fund the federal government have been enacted. </p> <p>This division also adds provisions to the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2018 that: </p> <ul> <li> permit funds appropriated by the Department of Defense Missile Defeat and Defense Enhancements Appropriations Act, 2018 to be obligated and expended notwithstanding a provision of the National Security Act of 1947 that requires a specific authorization of appropriations for intelligence activities; </li> <li> provide the Department of Agriculture with funding flexibility to ensure that certain demonstration projects for providing meals to low-income children during the summer will be fully operational by May 2018; </li> <li> provide the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) with funding flexibility to maintain the planned launch capability schedules for the Space Launch System launch vehicle, Exploration Ground Systems, and Orion Multi-Purpose Crew Vehicle programs; </li> <li> provide the Department of Energy with funding flexibility to maintain the June 30, 2017, staffing levels of the Office of Inspector General; </li> <li> provide the Small Business Administration with funding flexibility to accommodate increased demand for general business loans authorized under section 7(a) of the Small Business Act; </li> <li>permit the Department of Housing and Urban Development to make certain adjustments to the Section 8 housing choice voucher annual renewal funding allocations and administrative fee eligibility determinations for public housing agencies in an area for which the President declared a disaster in 2017 or 2018 under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act;</li> <li>compensate employees furloughed as a result of any lapse in appropriations which began on or about January 20, 2018; and</li> <li>require certain states, federal grantees, and furloughed state employees to be compensated or reimbursed for periods in which there is a lapse in FY2018 appropriations.</li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 2002) This section amends the Further Additional Continuing Appropriations Act, 2018 to strike a provision that extended certain authorities provided by the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) through the duration of the CR. (The FISA Amendments Reauthorization Act of 2017 was signed into law on January 19, 2018.) </p> <p>(Sec. 2003) This section specifies that the time covered by the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2018 includes the period that began on or about January 20, 2018, during which there was a lapse in appropriations.</p> <p>DIVISION C--HEALTHY KIDS ACT</p> <p><em>Helping Ensure Access for Little Ones, Toddlers, and Hopeful Youth by Keeping Insurance Delivery Stable Act or the HEALTHY KIDS Act</em></p> <p>(Sec. 101) This division extends funding through FY2023 for the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP) and the Child Enrollment Contingency Fund.</p> <p>In addition, the bill reauthorizes through FY2023:</p> <ul> <li>the qualifying-states option (which allows states that provided coverage to now CHIP-eligible children prior to CHIP's enactment to continue to provide such coverage), and </li> <li>the express-lane eligibility option (which allows states to use eligibility findings from other public benefit programs to determine children's eligibility for Medicaid and CHIP).</li> </ul> <p>Beginning in FY2020, the division allows state child-health plans to adopt more restrictive eligibility standards with respect to children in families whose income exceeds 300% of the poverty line.</p> <p>(Sec. 102) The division extends funding through FY2023 for the Childhood Obesity Demonstration Project and the Pediatric Quality Measures Program.</p> <p>(Sec. 103) The division: (1) extends funding through FY2023 for specified outreach and enrollment grants, and (2) makes eligible for such grants "parent-mentors" who are trained to assist families with children who have no health-insurance coverage. Any nominal amount received by an individual for participation as a parent-mentor shall be disregarded for purposes of determining the individual's income-based eligibility for Medicaid.</p> <p>(Sec. 104) Current law provides states with an enhanced Federal Matching Assistance Percentage (FMAP) for child-health assistance through FY2019. The division maintains the enhanced FMAP in FY2020, but halves the percentage-point increase.</p> <p>(Sec. 105) The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services shall make additional funding available to states for specified activities related to mechanized claims systems.</p> <p>DIVISION D--SUSPENSION OF CERTAIN HEALTH-RELATED TAXES </p> <p>(Sec. 4001) This section amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend for two years (2018 and 2019) the moratorium on the 2.3% excise tax on the sale of medical devices. (Under current law, the moratorium expired at the end of 2017.) </p> <p>(Sec. 4002) This section amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to delay for two years the implementation of the excise tax on high cost employer-sponsored health coverage (commonly referred to as the Cadillac tax). Under the bill, the tax will go into effect in 2022 instead of 2020, as required under current law. </p> <p>(Sec. 4003) This section suspends for 2019 the annual fee imposed on certain health insurance providers based on market share. </p> <p>DIVISION E--BUDGETARY EFFECTS </p> <p>(Sec. 5001) This division exempts the budgetary effects of division C and each succeeding division of this bill from Pay-As-You-Go (PAYGO) rules and certain budget scorekeeping guidelines. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr195v70" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-24">
<action-date>2018-01-22</action-date>
<action-desc>House agreed to Senate amendment without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Federal Register Printing Savings Act of 2017 </strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This division bars the Government Publishing Office from furnishing a printed copy of the Federal Register without charge to any Member of Congress or any other office of the United States during a year unless the Member or office requests: (1) a printed copy of a specific issue of the Federal Register, or (2) a subscription to printed copies of the Federal Register for that year. </p> <p>DIVISION B--EXTENSION OF CONTINUING APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2018 </p> <p><em>Extension of Continuing Appropriations Act, 2018 </em></p> <p>(Sec. 2001) This division amends the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2018 to provide continuing FY2018 appropriations to federal agencies through February 8, 2018 (January 19, 2018, under current law). </p> <p>It ends the government shutdown that began when the existing continuing resolution (CR) expired because none of the 12 FY2018 regular appropriations bills that fund the federal government have been enacted. </p> <p>This division also adds provisions to the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2018 that: </p> <ul> <li> permit funds appropriated by the Department of Defense Missile Defeat and Defense Enhancements Appropriations Act, 2018 to be obligated and expended notwithstanding a provision of the National Security Act of 1947 that requires a specific authorization of appropriations for intelligence activities; </li> <li> provide the Department of Agriculture with funding flexibility to ensure that certain demonstration projects for providing meals to low-income children during the summer will be fully operational by May 2018; </li> <li> provide the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) with funding flexibility to maintain the planned launch capability schedules for the Space Launch System launch vehicle, Exploration Ground Systems, and Orion Multi-Purpose Crew Vehicle programs; </li> <li> provide the Department of Energy with funding flexibility to maintain the June 30, 2017, staffing levels of the Office of Inspector General; </li> <li> provide the Small Business Administration with funding flexibility to accommodate increased demand for general business loans authorized under section 7(a) of the Small Business Act; and</li> <li>permit the Department of Housing and Urban Development to make certain adjustments to the Section 8 housing choice voucher annual renewal funding allocations and administrative fee eligibility determinations for public housing agencies in an area for which the President declared a disaster in 2017 or 2018 under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 2002) This section amends the Further Additional Continuing Appropriations Act, 2018 to strike a provision that extended certain authorities provided by the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) through the duration of the CR. (The FISA Amendments Reauthorization Act of 2017 was signed into law on January 19, 2018.) </p> <p>DIVISION C--HEALTHY KIDS ACT</p> <p><em>Helping Ensure Access for Little Ones, Toddlers, and Hopeful Youth by Keeping Insurance Delivery Stable Act or the HEALTHY KIDS Act</em></p> <p> (Sec. 101) This division extends funding through FY2023 for the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP) and the Child Enrollment Contingency Fund.</p> <p>In addition, the bill reauthorizes through FY2023:</p> <ul> <li>the qualifying-states option (which allows states that provided coverage to now CHIP-eligible children prior to CHIP's enactment to continue to provide such coverage), and </li> <li>the express-lane eligibility option (which allows states to use eligibility findings from other public benefit programs to determine children's eligibility for Medicaid and CHIP).</li> </ul> <p>Beginning in FY2020, the division allows state child-health plans to adopt more restrictive eligibility standards with respect to children in families whose income exceeds 300% of the poverty line.</p> <p>(Sec. 102) The division extends funding through FY2023 for the Childhood Obesity Demonstration Project and the Pediatric Quality Measures Program.</p> <p>(Sec. 103) The division: (1) extends funding through FY2023 for specified outreach and enrollment grants, and (2) makes eligible for such grants "parent-mentors" who are trained to assist families with children who have no health-insurance coverage. Any nominal amount received by an individual for participation as a parent-mentor shall be disregarded for purposes of determining the individual's income-based eligibility for Medicaid.</p> <p>(Sec. 104) Current law provides states with an enhanced Federal Matching Assistance Percentage (FMAP) for child-health assistance through FY2019. The division maintains the enhanced FMAP in FY2020, but halves the percentage-point increase.</p> <p>(Sec. 105) The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services shall make additional funding available to states for specified activities related to mechanized claims systems.</p> <p>DIVISION D--SUSPENSION OF CERTAIN HEALTH-RELATED TAXES </p> <p>(Sec. 4001) This section amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend for two years (2018 and 2019) the moratorium on the 2.3% excise tax on the sale of medical devices. (Under current law, the moratorium expired at the end of 2017.) </p> <p>(Sec. 4002) This section amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to delay for two years the implementation of the excise tax on high cost employer-sponsored health coverage (commonly referred to as the Cadillac tax). Under the bill, the tax will go into effect in 2022 instead of 2020, as required under current law. </p> <p>(Sec. 4003) This section suspends for 2019 the annual fee imposed on certain health insurance providers based on market share. </p> <p>DIVISION E--BUDGETARY EFFECTS </p> <p>(Sec. 5001) This division exempts the budgetary effects of division C and each succeeding division of this bill from Pay-As-You-Go (PAYGO) rules and certain budget scorekeeping guidelines. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr195v40" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2018-01-22">
<action-date>2018-01-18</action-date>
<action-desc>House agreed to Senate amendment with amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Federal Register Printing Savings Act of 2017 </b></p> <p>This bill bars the Government Publishing Office from furnishing a printed copy of the Federal Register without charge to any Member of Congress or any other office of the United States during a year unless the Member or office requests: (1) a printed copy of a specific issue of the Federal Register, or (2) a subscription to printed copies of the Federal Register for that year. </p> <p><i>Extension of Continuing Appropriations Act, 2018</i></p> <p>The bill also amends the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2018 to extend the expiration date of the FY2018 Continuing Resolution (CR) from January 19, 2018, to February 16, 2018. The bill provides continuing appropriations for federal agencies through the earlier of February 16, 2018, or the enactment of the applicable appropriations legislation. It prevents a government shutdown that would otherwise occur when the existing CR expires. </p> <p><i>Helping Ensure Access for Little Ones, Toddlers, and Hopeful Youth by Keeping Insurance Delivery Stable Act or the HEALTHY KIDS Act</i></p> <p>The bill amends title XXI (Children's Health insurance Program) (CHIP) of the Social Security Act to extend funding through FY2023 for CHIP. In addition, the bill: (1) extends through FY2023 funding for the Child Enrollment Contingency Fund, the Childhood Obesity Demonstration Project, the Pediatric Quality Measures Program, and specified outreach and enrollment grants; and (2) reauthorizes through FY2023 the qualifying-states option and the express-lane eligibility option. </p> <p>Current law provides states with an enhanced Federal Matching Assistance Percentage (FMAP) for child-health assistance through FY2019. The bill maintains the enhanced FMAP in FY2020, but halves the percentage-point increase. </p> <p>The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services shall make additional funding available to states for specified activities related to mechanized claims systems. </p> <p>The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code and the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to suspend specified health-related taxes and fees. </p> <p>Specified budgetary effects of bill shall be exempt from Pay-As-You-Go (PAYGO) rules and certain budget scorekeeping guidelines. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr195v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2018-01-18">
<action-date>2017-12-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Federal Register Printing Savings Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill bars the Government Publishing Office from furnishing a printed copy of the Federal Register without charge to any Member of Congress or any other office of the United States during a year unless:</p> <ul> <li>the Member or office requests a printed copy of a specific issue of the Federal Register; or </li> <li>during that year or the previous year, the Member or office requested a subscription to printed copies of the Federal Register for that year.</li></ul> <p>TITLE II--KEVIN AND AVONTE'S LAW OF 2017</p> <p><em>Kevin and Avonte's Law of 2017</em></p> <p>Subtitle A--Missing Alzheimer's Disease Patient Alert Program Reauthorization</p> <p><i>Missing Americans Alert Program Act of 2017</i></p> <p>(Sec. 212) This bill amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to revise and rename the Missing Alzheimer's Disease Patient Alert Program as the Missing Americans Alert Program and to reauthorize it through FY2022.</p> <p>It directs the Department of Justice's (DOJ's) Bureau of Justice Assistance (BJA) to award competitive grants to health care, law enforcement, or public safety agencies, and nonprofit organizations, to develop or operate locally based proactive programs to prevent wandering and locate missing individuals with dementia or children with developmental disabilities. The BJA must give preference to law enforcement or public safety agencies partnering with nonprofit organizations that use person-centered plans and are directly linked to individuals, and families of individuals, with dementia or developmental disabilities.</p> <p>Additionally, it directs the BJA to award grants to health care, law enforcement, or public safety agencies to develop tracking technology programs to locate missing individuals with dementia or children with developmental disabilities.</p> <p>The bill subjects grants under the Missing Americans Program to accountability provisions. DOJ's Office of Inspector General must conduct annual audits of selected grant recipients. The bill prohibits grants to nonprofit organizations that hold money in an offshore account to avoid tax liability. It also limits the use of grants under this bill for conferences that use more than $20,000 in DOJ funds.</p> <p>DOJ must identify and report on duplicative grant awards. DOJ must also report annually to Congress certain information regarding the Missing Americans Alert Program.</p> <p>Subtitle B--Education and Outreach</p> <p>(Sec. 231) The bill amends the Missing Children's Assistance Act to specify that, with respect to training and technical assistance provided by the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children, cases involving missing and exploited children include cases involving children with developmental disabilities such as autism.</p> <p>Subtitle C--Privacy Protections</p> <p>(Sec. 242) DOJ must establish and certain grant recipients must comply with standards and best practices related to the use of tracking technology to locate missing individuals with dementia or developmental disabilities.</p> <p>The bill prohibits the use of data from tracking devices to create a federal database. It also prohibits construing this bill to require a parent or guardian to use a tracking device.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr195v80" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2017-11-15">
<action-date>2017-11-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to Senate without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House passed version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Federal Register Printing Savings Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill bars the Government Publishing Office from furnishing a printed copy of the Federal Register without charge to any Member of Congress or any other office of the United States during a year unless:</p> <ul> <li>the Member or office requests a printed copy of a specific issue of the Federal Register; or </li> <li>during that year or the previous year, the Member or office requested a subscription to printed copies of the Federal Register for that year.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr195v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-25">
<action-date>2017-05-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Federal Register Printing Savings Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill bars the Government Publishing Office from furnishing a printed copy of the Federal Register without charge to any Member of Congress or any other office of the United States during a year unless:</p> <ul> <li>the Member or office requests a printed copy of a specific issue of the Federal Register; or </li> <li>during that year or the previous year, the Member or office requested a subscription to printed copies of the Federal Register for that year.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr195v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-30">
<action-date>2017-01-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Federal Register Printing Savings Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill bars the Government Publishing Office from furnishing a printed copy of the Federal Register without charge to any Member of Congress or any other office of the United States during a year unless:</p> <ul> <li>the Member or office requests a printed copy of a specific issue of the Federal Register; or </li> <li>during that year or the previous year, the Member or office requested a subscription to printed copies of the Federal Register for that year.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
