<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="576" measure-id="id115hr576" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-13" update-date="2018-01-17">
<title>Social Impact Partnerships to Pay for Results Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr576v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-17">
<action-date>2017-01-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Social Impact Partnerships to Pay for Results Act</b></p> <p>This bill allows the Department of the Treasury to enter into agreements with state and local governments&nbsp;for social-impact partnership projects&nbsp;for which federal funds&nbsp;shall be&nbsp;awarded only if a project achieves certain agreed-upon outcomes resulting in&nbsp;both social benefit&nbsp;and federal, state, or local savings. In carrying out&nbsp;these agreements, Treasury must consult with the Federal Interagency Council on Social Impact Partnerships and the&nbsp;Commission on Social Impact Partnerships (both newly established by&nbsp;the bill). Treasury may transfer to another federal agency the authority to administer&nbsp;the agreements.</p> <p>At least 50% of all federal payments made&nbsp;under such agreements must be used for initiatives that directly benefit children.</p> <p> The bill also extends funding through 2017 for the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) program and specified related grant programs.</p> <p>In addition, the&nbsp;bill provides for specified research and evaluation by&nbsp;the Department of Health and Human Services&nbsp;(HHS), the U.S. Census Bureau, and states&nbsp;with respect to&nbsp;TANF and related programs. HHS, in consultation with the Department of Labor, shall develop a database of projects that have used a proven or promising approach in moving TANF recipients to work.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
