<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2712" measure-id="id115hr2712" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-25" update-date="2017-12-04">
<title>Palestinian International Terrorism Support Prevention Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2712v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-04">
<action-date>2017-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Palestinian International Terrorism Support Prevention Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill states that it shall be U.S. policy to prevent Hamas, the Palestinian Islamic Jihad, or any affiliate or successor from accessing its international support networks.</p> <p>The President shall report to Congress for up to three years identifying foreign persons, agencies, or instrumentalities that knowingly and materially assist any such organization.</p> <p> The President shall impose two or more of the following sanctions on an identified person, agency, or instrumentality, including the denial of: (1) Export-Import guarantees, credit, or insurance; (2) defense article sales or services; (3) munitions export licenses; (4) exports of goods or technology controlled for national security reasons; and (5) loans or credit of more than $10 million.</p> <p>The President shall: (1) periodically report to Congress identifying each foreign government that provides support for acts of terrorism or material support to any such organization; (2) impose on an identified government a one-year suspension of U.S. assistance, international loans or technical assistance, and munitions exports; (3) prohibit such government's transactions in foreign exchanges that are subject to U.S. jurisdiction; and (4) prohibit credit or payment transfers between financial institutions that involve any interest of such a government and that are subject to U.S. jurisdiction. </p> <p>The President shall report to Congress regarding countries: (1) that support any such organization, or in which Hamas maintains important portions of its financial, fund raising, or money laundering networks; and (2) that are or are not taking adequate steps to counter such activities. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
