<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1352" measure-id="id115hr1352" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-02" update-date="2018-01-17">
<title>Preparing More Welfare Recipients for Work Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1352v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-17">
<action-date>2017-03-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Preparing More Welfare Recipients for Work Act</b></p> <p>This bill&nbsp;revises mandatory work requirements under the&nbsp;Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF)&nbsp;program. Specifically, for purposes of counting work activities toward the satisfaction of such requirements, the bill:</p> <ul> <li>eliminates the distinction between&nbsp;core work activities and other specified work activities&nbsp;related to training and education; </li> <li>in general, eliminates&nbsp;separate requirements for&nbsp;two-parent families and other families; </li> <li>allows partial credit with respect to families that participate in work activities for fewer hours than required; </li> <li>allows&nbsp;states to request approval for an alternative work-participation rate calculation; </li> <li>limits, after three months of participation,&nbsp;the extent to which job-search activities shall be counted as work activities; </li> <li>modifies requirements for counting secondary-school attendance as work participation; </li> <li>removes from the definition of "work activities" the provision of child-care services to an individual who is participating in a community service program; and </li> <li>increases, from 12 to 24 months, the maximum period for which vocational educational training counts a work activities. </li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
