<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1742" measure-id="id115hr1742" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-27" update-date="2017-05-04">
<title>Article V Records Transparency Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1742v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-04">
<action-date>2017-03-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Article V Records Transparency Act of</strong> <b>2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) to make and transmit to Congress an organized compilation of all applications and rescissions of applications ever made by states under article V of the Constitution to call a convention for proposing constitutional amendments. </p> <p>NARA must: (1) use NARA records and outside sources to obtain an official copy of any application or rescission that may not be in such records, (2) submit a report on the extent of suspected missing applications or rescissions not included in each compilation, and (3) catalog the applications and rescissions by year of submission and state. </p> <p>The committees on the judiciary in each chamber shall designate the applications and rescissions contained in such compilation for public availability on a website and update the compilation as specified.</p> <p>In order to simplify and make uniform the process by which state legislatures make such an application or rescission, Congress recommends that after adoption of an application or rescission by a state legislature, the secretary of state or other state official should submit at least two copies of the measure containing the application or rescission to Congress, one copy addressed to the President of the Senate and one copy to the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
