<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1815" measure-id="id115hr1815" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-30" update-date="2017-11-07">
<title>Protecting Sensitive Locations Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1815v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-07">
<action-date>2017-03-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protecting Sensitive Locations Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide that an immigration enforcement action by the Department of Homeland Security or an individual designated to perform immigration enforcement functions may not take place at a sensitive location, except: (1) under exigent circumstances, and (2) with prior approval. </p> <p>A &quot;sensitive location&quot; includes all of the physical space located within 1,000 feet of: </p> <ul> <li> medical treatment or health care facilities; </li> <li> public and private schools; </li> <li> scholastic or education-related activities; </li> <li> school bus or school bus stops during periods when school children are present; </li> <li> emergency shelter or food locations; </li> <li> any organization that assists children, pregnant women, victims of crime or abuse, or individuals with significant mental or physical disabilities or that provides disaster or emergency social services; </li> <li> places of worship; </li> <li> funerals, weddings, or other public religious ceremonies; </li> <li> public demonstrations; </li> <li> federal, state, or local courthouses; </li> <li> congressional district offices; </li> <li> public assistance or social security offices; or</li> <li> motor vehicles departments. </li> </ul> <p>The bill shall not apply to the transportation of an individual apprehended at or near a land or sea border to a hospital or health care provider for the purpose of providing such individual with medical care.</p> <p>If an enforcement action is carried out in violation of this bill: (1) no information resulting from the action may be entered into the record or received into evidence in a resulting removal proceeding, and (2) the affected alien may file a motion for such proceeding's immediate termination. </p> <p>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement and U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall provide training to officers and report to Congress on any enforcement activity occurring at sensitive locations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
