<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="990" measure-id="id115hr990" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-09" update-date="2017-07-31">
<title>To prohibit any hiring freeze from affecting Department of Defense civilian positions in facilities that perform depot maintenance or are designated as a center for industrial and technical excellence, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr990v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-31">
<action-date>2017-02-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill declares that any presidential action to prevent a federal agency from filling or creating federal civilian employee positions shall have no force or effect with respect to any Department of Defense civilian position at, or in support of, any facility: (1) at which depot-level maintenance and repair is carried out, or (2) designated as a center for industrial and technical excellence.</p> <ul> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
