<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2872" measure-id="id115hr2872" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-12" update-date="2018-02-07">
<title>Promoting Hydropower Development at Existing Nonpowered Dams Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2872v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-07">
<action-date>2017-12-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Promoting Hydropower Development at Existing Nonpowered Dams Act</b></p> <p>(Sec.2)This bill amends the Federal Power Act to authorize the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)to establish an expedited licensing process for issuing and amending licenses and preliminary permits for any qualifying facility as defined by this bill.</p> <p>In establishing the expedited process, FERC shall convene an interagency task force with appropriate federal and state agencies and Indian tribes to coordinate the regulatory process associated with the authorizations required to construct and operate a qualifying facility.</p> <p>FERC must assess the safety of existing non-federal dams and other non-federal structures related to the qualifying facility before issuing any license for a qualifying facility.</p> <p>FERC must coordinate with the Department of the Army, Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture to jointly develop a list of existing nonpowered federal dams that have the greatest potential for non-federal hydropower development.</p> <p>(Sec.3)Licensees of a qualifying facility are not required to pay an annual charge for administrative expenses until construction commences.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2872v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-10">
<action-date>2017-06-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Promoting Hydropower Development at Existing Nonpowered Dams Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Power Act (FPA)to authorize the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to exempt from FPA license requirements any qualifying facility (a facility that meets criteria specified in this bill). </p> <p>No federal authorization required for a qualifying facility may include any condition or other requirement that results in any material change to the storage, control, withdrawal, diversion, release, or flow operations of the associated qualifying nonpowered dam. </p> <p> Unless FERC determines that its obligations under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 for granting exemptions under this bill can be met through a categorical exclusion, its environmental review of a proposed exemption shall be only an environmental assessment. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
