<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1833" measure-id="id115hr1833" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-30" update-date="2017-07-25">
<title>Investing in America's Small Businesses Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1833v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-25">
<action-date>2017-03-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Investing in America's Small Businesses Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of 1994 to require the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund to make grants to community development financial institutions for: (1)&nbsp;the establishment of loan-loss reserve funds to defray the costs of small business lending, and (2) related technical assistance.</p> <p>A community development financial institution must provide nonfederal matching funds equal to 50% of the amount of any grant received.</p> <p>A grantee may not&nbsp;use grant funds to make direct loans to small businesses.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
