<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2812" measure-id="id115hr2812" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-07" update-date="2018-02-26">
<title>Enhance Partner Cyber Capabilities Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2812v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-26">
<action-date>2017-06-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Enhance Partner Cyber Capabilities Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the President to develop a strategy for the offensive use of cyber capabilities by federal agencies. The strategy shall include: (1) a description of enhancements needed to improve such capabilities of the United States and partner nations, including North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) members; and (2) a statement of principles for deployment of such capabilities.</p> <p>The bill authorizes the Department of Defense to furnish technical assistance to NATO members in developing and enhancing their capabilities. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
