<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="512" measure-id="id115hr512" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-12" update-date="2017-03-13">
<title>WINGMAN Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr512v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-03-13">
<action-date>2017-02-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Working to Integrate Networks Guaranteeing Member Access Now Act or the WINGMAN Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide each veteran who submits a claim for VA benefits with an opportunity to permit a covered congressional employee in the office of the veteran's Member of Congress to have read-only access to all of the veteran's records in the Veterans Benefits Administration databases. A Member may designate up to two such covered congressional employees.</p> <p>A covered congressional employee may not be recognized as an agent or attorney with respect to veterans' benefit claims.</p> <p>Funds under this bill may not be used to design or administer any training for covered congressional employees. </p> <p>The bill makes up to $10 million available for obligation or expenditure for FY2018 through FY2021 for such congressional employee access program.</p> <p> No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr512v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-02-15">
<action-date>2017-01-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Working to Integrate Networks Guaranteeing Member Access Now Act or the WINGMAN Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide each veteran who submits a claim for VA benefits with an opportunity to permit a covered congressional employee in the office of the veteran's Member of Congress to have read-only access to all of the veteran's records in the Veterans Benefits Administration databases. A Member may designate up to two such covered congressional employees.</p> <p>A covered congressional employee may not be recognized as an agent or attorney with respect to veterans' benefit claims.</p> <p>Funds under this bill may not be used to design or administer any training for covered congressional employees. </p> <p>The bill makes funds available for FY2018 through FY2021 for such congressional employee access program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
