<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3025" measure-id="id115hr3025" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-22" update-date="2018-02-16">
<title>Fostering Unity Against Russian Aggression Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3025v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-16">
<action-date>2017-06-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fostering Unity Against Russian Aggression Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the Russian Federation should return to verifiable compliance with the Treaty Between the United States of America and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics on the Elimination of Their Intermediate-Range and Shorter-Range Missiles (INF) Treaty, (2) concerns persist over the growing sophistication of unconventional and hybrid state-sponsored Russian threats, and (3) maritime capabilities should be enhanced.</p> <p>The Department of Defense (DOD) shall: (1) develop a strategy to counter Russian threats; (2) develop a strategy to increase conventional precision strike weapon stockpiles in the U.S. European Command's areas of responsibility, including increases to enhance deterrence and fighting capability of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization; (3) develop a plan to counter Russian military capabilities; (4) develop a plan to train the national security forces of U.S. allies and partners to counter Russian cyberspace and information operations; (5) report to Congress regarding DOD's strategy to expand the forward presence of U.S. military forces in Europe; (6) submit a plan to Congress that includes options to reduce the risk of miscalculation and unintended consequences that could precipitate a nuclear war; and (7) report to Congress regarding the location and capacities of training areas in the European Command's areas of responsibility.</p> <p>The President shall submit a plan to Congress to impose sanctions against Russia for non-compliance with the INF Treaty. Such sanctions should include expanding asset freezes and travel bans and prohibiting financial transactions and government-to-government contracts.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
