<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1443" measure-id="id115hr1443" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-09" update-date="2017-05-04">
<title>Energy Savings and Industrial Competitiveness Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1443v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-04">
<action-date>2017-03-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Energy Savings and Industrial Competitiveness Act</b></p> <p>This bill revises a variety of programs to encourage energy efficiency in buildings, industry, the federal government, and certain appliances, including by:</p> <ul> <li>requiring states and Indian tribes to measure their compliance with certain residential and commercial building energy codes;</li> <li>requiring the Department of Energy (DOE) to provide grants for establishing building training and assessment centers at institutions of higher education;</li> <li>requiring DOE to establish a process to recognize schools for implementing energy efficient and renewable energy projects;</li> <li>directing DOE to carry out an industry-government partnership program to research, develop, and demonstrate new sustainable manufacturing and industrial technologies and processes;</li> <li>establishing a Supply Star program within DOE to identify and promote practices, recognize companies, and recognize products that use highly efficient supply chains that conserve energy, water, and other resources;</li> <li>requiring DOE to establish rebate programs concerning energy efficient electric motors or transformers;</li> <li>revising requirements concerning the energy performance of federal buildings, certification under the Energy Star Program, certification of green buildings, and energy efficiency in federal real estate transactions and programs; and </li> <li>requiring the Department of Housing and Urban Development to establish a demonstration program for energy and water conservation improvements at multifamily residential units. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
