<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="972" measure-id="id115hr972" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-07" update-date="2017-06-07">
<title>Menstrual Equity For All Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr972v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-07">
<action-date>2017-02-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Menstrual Equity For All Act of 2017 </b></p> <p>This bill establishes a tax credit, a tax exclusion, and requirements that apply to the purchase or distribution of menstrual hygiene products.</p> <p>The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) expand the tax exclusion for reimbursements from a health flexible spending arrangement to include amounts paid or incurred for menstrual hygiene products, and (2) allow a refundable tax credit of $120 for certain individuals who use menstrual hygiene products, subject to adjustments for inflation and a limitation based on adjusted gross income. </p> <p>The bill amends the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to require the Emergency Food and Shelter Program National Board to establish written guidelines for the Emergency Food and Shelter Program to ensure that funds provided under the program to private nonprofit organizations and local governments may be used to provide menstrual hygiene products.</p> <p>Each state that receives a grant under the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program must annually certify to the Department of Justice (DOJ) that all female inmates and detainees in that state have access to menstrual hygiene products on demand and at no cost to the inmates and detainees. If a state does not submit the required certification, DOJ must reduce the state's grant funding under the program by 20% and reallocate the funding to states that submitted certifications. </p> <p>This bill also amends the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to require the Department of Labor to issue a rule requiring private employers with not less than 100 employees to provide free menstrual hygiene products for their employees. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
