<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2108" measure-id="id115hr2108" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-20" update-date="2017-08-22">
<title>GI Bill STEM Extension Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2108v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-22">
<action-date>2017-04-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>GI Bill STEM Extension Act of 2017</strong></p> <p> This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs to pay the lesser of nine months or $30,000 of additional Post-9/11 educational assistance to selected eligible veterans who have used all of the Post-9/11 educational assistance to which they were entitled and who: (1) are enrolled in a postsecondary education program that requires more than the standard 128 semester (or 192 quarter) credit hours for completion in a specified science, technology, engineering, or mathematics (STEM) field; or (2) have earned a postsecondary degree in one of those fields and are enrolled in a teaching certification program.</p> <p> In selecting eligible individuals, priority shall be given to individuals who: (1) require the most credit hours; or (2) served on active duty service for at least 36 months with an honorable discharge, continued active duty service after such 36-month period, or served at least 30 days of continuous active duty service with a service-connected discharge.</p> <p> Such additional assistance may not be transferred.</p> <p> The maximum amount of assistance paid to all eligible individuals in a fiscal year may not exceed $100 million.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
