<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4816" measure-id="id115hr4816" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2018-01-17" update-date="2018-01-26">
<title>Stop Civil Asset Forfeiture Funding for Marijuana Suppression Act of 2018</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4816v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-26">
<action-date>2018-01-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Stop Civil Asset Forfeiture Funding for Marijuana Suppression Act of 2018</b></p> <p>This bill prohibits the use of amounts in the Department of Justice Assets Forfeiture Fund for the Drug Enforcement Administration's (DEA's) Domestic Cannabis Suppression/Eradication Program.</p> <p>Additionally, the bill prohibits the transfer of property to a federal or state and local agency for a purpose pertaining to such a program.</p> <p>Finally, the bill expresses the sense of Congress that the DEA's marijuana prohibition policy is an inappropriate use of resources.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
