<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4877" measure-id="id115hr4877" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2018-01-25" update-date="2018-02-09">
<title>Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2018</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4877v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-09">
<action-date>2018-01-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 201</b><b>8</b></p> <p>Provides FY2018 appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for military activities. Excludes military construction, military family housing, civil works projects of the Army Corps of Engineers, and nuclear warheads, which are all considered in other appropriations bills. </p> <p>Provides appropriations to DOD for: </p> <ul> <li>Military Personnel; </li> <li>Operation and Maintenance; </li> <li> Procurement; </li> <li> Research, Development, Test and Evaluation; and </li> <li> Revolving and Management Funds. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Other Department of Defense Programs, including: </p> <ul> <li> the Defense Health Program, </li> <li>Chemical Agents and Munitions Destruction, </li> <li> Drug-Interdiction and Counter-Drug Activities, and </li> <li> the Office of the Inspector General. </li> </ul> <p>Provides appropriations for Related Agencies, including the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System Fund and the Intelligence Community Management Account. </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Overseas Contingency Operations/ Global War on Terrorism. </p> <p>Rescinds specified unobligated balances from prior appropriations to DOD. Sets forth permissible and prohibited uses for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
