<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2886" measure-id="id115hr2886" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-12" update-date="2018-01-31">
<title>CARE Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2886v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-31">
<action-date>2017-06-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Children's Act for Responsible Employment of 2017 or the CARE Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to redefine "oppressive child labor," for purposes of the Act's child labor prohibitions, as the employment of any employee who is: </p> <UL> <LI>16 or 17 years of age in any occupation found by the Department of Labor to be particularly hazardous or detrimental to such employee's health or well-being; <LI>14 or 15 years of age, unless the employment is confined to periods which do not interfere with the employee's schooling, health, and well-being; or <LI>under age 14. </LI> </UL> <p>The bill revises exemptions for child agricultural employment.</p>   <p>The bill increases civil penalties for child labor violations and imposes new criminal penalties for repeated or willful violations of child labor prohibitions that result in serious illness or injury of an employee under age 18.</p> <p>Labor shall revise regulations to prohibit the employment of children under age 18 in duties involving the handling of pesticides.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
