<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1814" measure-id="id115hr1814" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-30" update-date="2017-04-28">
<title>Rural Spectrum Accessibility Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1814v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-04-28">
<action-date>2017-03-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Rural Spectrum Accessibility Act of</strong> <b>2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Federal Communications Commission to establish a program under which a wireless carrier receiving a license under specified provisions of the Communications Act of 1934 may partition or disaggregate the license in order to make unused spectrum available to small carriers or carriers to serve certain rural areas.</p> <p>A "small carrier" is defined as a carrier with not more than 1,500 employees as calculated under regulatory standards used by the Small Business Administration to determine the number of individuals employed by a business concern on a full-time, part-time, or other basis.</p> <p>A three-year license extension is provided to any carrier that receives such a license and participates in the program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
