<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3436" measure-id="id115hr3436" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-26" update-date="2017-10-30">
<title>Southwest Border Security Threat Assessment Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3436v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-30">
<action-date>2017-07-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Southwest Border Security Threat Assessment Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to submit a southwest border threat analysis that includes an assessment of:</p> <ul> <li>terrorism and criminal threats posed by individuals and organized groups seeking to unlawfully enter the United States through the southwest border or seeking to exploit security vulnerabilities along such border; </li> <li>improvements needed at and between ports of entry to prevent terrorists and instruments of terror from entering the United States; </li> <li>gaps in law, policy, and coordination that hinder effective and efficient border security, counterterrorism, anti-human smuggling and trafficking efforts; </li> <li>the flow of legitimate trade along the southwest border; </li> <li>the current percentage of situational awareness and of operational control achieved by DHS along the southwest border; </li> <li>the impact of trusted traveler programs on border wait times and border security; and </li> <li>traveler crossing times and any potential security vulnerability associated with prolonged wait times. </li></ul> <p>The bill requires the Border Patrol, within 180 days after submission of the threat analysis and every five years thereafter, to issue a Border Patrol Strategic Plan that includes consideration of such analysis and other specified factors, including: </p> <ul> <li>efforts to increase situational awareness, to detect and prevent terrorists and instruments of terrorism from entering the United States, and to detect, interdict, and disrupt aliens and illicit drugs at the earliest possible point upon entry into the United States; </li> <li>staffing requirements; and </li> <li>assessments of training programs for detecting fraudulent documents and of how border security operations affect crossing times. </li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
