<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2732" measure-id="id115hr2732" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-25" update-date="2018-02-12">
<title>North Korea Travel Control Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2732v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-12">
<action-date>2017-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>North Korea Travel Control Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of the Treasury to issue regulations prohibiting transactions related to travel to, from, or within North Korea by any person subject to U.S. jurisdiction unless authorized either by a general or specific license issued by Treasury.</p> <p>Treasury may not not issue such a license for travel the primary purpose of which is tourist activities.</p> <p>Penalties are provided for violations of this bill.</p> <p>This bill shall cease to be effective five years after its enactment.</p> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
