<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3739" measure-id="id115hr3739" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-12" update-date="2017-11-21">
<title>Presidential Allowance Modernization Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3739v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-21">
<action-date>2017-11-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Presidential Allowance Modernization Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Former Presidents Act of 1958 to to revise provisions governing the compensation provided to a former President. Each former President shall receive from the United States an annuity of $200,000 per year. The General Services Administration (GSA) is authorized to provide each former President a monetary allowance of $500,000 per year for five years beginning six months after the expiration of his or her term, $350,000 per year for the next five years, and $250,000 per year thereafter. </p>  <p>Such annuity and allowance shall be increased each year by the same percentage as Social Security benefits.</p> <p>Such allowance shall be reduced by the amount the former President's earned income exceeds $400,000.</p> <p>The bill: (1) limits the office staff provided for each former President to not more than 13 individuals, and (2) requires that suitable office space for a former President be provided on a reimbursable basis.</p> <p>The increases from $20,000 per year to $100,000 per year, and provides for cost-of-living adjustments to, the monetary allowance amount for surviving spouses of former Presidents.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3739v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-22">
<action-date>2017-09-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Presidential Allowance Modernization Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Former Presidents Act of 1958 to revise provisions governing the compensation provided to a former President. Each former President shall receive from the United States: (1) an annuity of $200,000 per year; and (2) a monetary allowance of $500,000 per year for five years beginning six months after the expiration of his or her term, $350,000 per year for the next five years, and $250,000 per year thereafter. </p> <p>Such annuity and allowance shall be increased each year by the same percentage as Social Security benefits.</p> <p>Such allowance shall be reduced by the amount the former President's earned income exceeds $400,000.</p> <p>The bill: (1) limits the office staff provided for each former President to not more than 13 individuals, and (2) requires that suitable office space for a former President be provided on a reimbursable basis.</p> <p>The bill increases and provides for cost-of-living adjustments to the monetary allowance for surviving spouses of former Presidents.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
