<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1998" measure-id="id115hr1998" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2017-11-06">
<title>To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to notify the Committees on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives and certain Members of Congress before the expiration or termination of a HUD-VASH contract, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1998v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-06">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to notify the House and Senate Veterans' Affairs Committees and each Member of Congress from the jurisdiction covered by a HUD-VASH contract at least 90 days before the contract terminates or expires. </p> <p>&quot;HUD-VASH contract&quot; refers to a contract for low-income housing assistance, a rental voucher for VA-supported housing.</p> <p> The VA shall notify such committees and members within 60 days after such notification of the VA's plan to provide assistance to veterans served under such contract.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
