<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1774" measure-id="id115hr1774" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-29" update-date="2017-08-22">
<title>Developing the Next Generation of Small Businesses Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1774v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-22">
<action-date>2017-03-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Developing the Next Generation of Small Businesses Act of 2017</b></p> <p><i>Small Business Development Centers Improvement Act of 2017</i></p> <p> This bill amends the Small Business Act to revise the authority of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to use certain SBA programs, including the small business development center (SBDC) program, to provide grants, financial assistance, loans, export assistance, and subcontracting opportunities on federal contracts to specified small businesses, organizations, state governments, universities, companies, and other entities that assist smaller enterprises.</p> <p>The SBA shall:</p> <ul> <li>use such programs only to deliver entrepreneurial development services, entrepreneurial education, support for the development and maintenance of clusters, or business training (excepts services provided to assist small businesses owned by an Indian tribe);</li> <li>not prohibit SBDC grant recipients from marketing and advertising their services to individuals and small business concerns; and</li> <li>establish a Data Collection Working Group.</li> </ul> <p>The SBA may not award SBDC grants to entities other than those that received them before September 30, 2015, and that seek to renew them after that date, with an exception for not-for-profit institutions of higher education.</p> <p><i>Women's Business Centers Improvements Act of 2017</i></p> <p> The bill revises the duties of the Office of Women's Business Ownership and declares it is the Office's mission to assist women entrepreneurs to start, grow, and compete in global markets by providing quality support with access to capital, access to markets, job creation, growth, and counseling.</p> <p> The SBA shall establish standards for a program to accredit specified eligible entities receiving a grant to operate one or more women's business centers.</p> <p><i>SCORE for Small Business Act of 2017</i></p> <p> The bill reauthorizes the SCORE program (Service Corps of Retired Executives) for FY2018-FY2019. The program is renamed as simply the SCORE program.</p> <p> The SBA shall award a grant to the SCORE Association (or any successor group) to manage the program.</p> <p> The bill prescribes duties of volunteers participating in, and requirements of, the program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
