<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3453" measure-id="id115hr3453" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-27" update-date="2017-09-05">
<title>Tax Relief for Artists Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3453v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-05">
<action-date>2017-07-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Tax Relief for Artists Act of 2017 </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a standard deduction for the trade and business expenses of artists. The deduction is limited to the lesser of: (1) $2,500, or (2) the gross income of the taxpayer derived from one or more artistic trades or businesses carried on by the taxpayer (or, if less, taxable income). </p> <p>To be eligible for the deduction, a taxpayer must have: (1) household income for the taxable year that does not exceed 250% of the poverty line for a family of the size involved, and (2) gross income derived from one or more artistic trades or businesses carried on by the taxpayer. </p> <p>An &quot;artistic trade or business&quot; is any trade or business in the literary, graphic design, film, visual, media, musical, theatre, recording, or dance arts. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
