<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1092" measure-id="id115hr1092" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-15" update-date="2017-04-12">
<title>Chief Manufacturing Officer Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1092v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-04-12">
<action-date>2017-02-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Chief Manufacturing Officer Act</b></p> <p>This bill: (1) expresses the sense of Congress that a well-designed national manufacturing strategy would benefit the U.S. economy, and (2) directs the President to appoint a United States Chief Manufacturing Officer, which shall be a member of the National Economic Council. </p> <p>The Officer's duties shall include developing, by May 1, 2018, a national manufacturing strategy, which shall incorporate: (1) the national strategic plan for advanced manufacturing developed under the America COMPETES Reauthorization Act of 2010, and (2) the strategic plan developed for the Network for Manufacturing Innovation Program under the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act. The Officer shall provide annual updates on progress made toward achieving the objectives of such strategic plan for advanced manufacturing and carrying out the strategy developed under this bill. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
