<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2883" measure-id="id115hr2883" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-12" update-date="2018-03-08">
<title>Promoting Cross-Border Energy Infrastructure Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2883v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-08">
<action-date>2017-07-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Promoting Cross-Border Energy Infrastructure Act</b></p> <p>(Sec.2)This bill prohibits any person from constructing, connecting, operating, or maintaining a border-crossing facility for the import or export of oil, natural gas, or electricity across an international border of the United States without obtaining a certificate of crossing.</p> <p>The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC), with respect to oil or natural gas pipelines, or the Department of Energy (DOE), with respect to electric transmission facilities, must issue a certificate of crossing for the border-crossing facility within 120 days after final action is taken under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, unless it is not in the public interest.</p> <p>DOE, as a condition of issuing a certificate, must require that the border-crossing facility be constructed, connected, operated, or maintained consistent with specified policies and standards of: (1)the Electric Reliability Organization and applicable regional entity, and (2)the Regional Transmission Organization or Independent System Operator with operational or functional control over the border-crossing facility.</p> <p>The bill amends the Natural Gas Act to require FERC to approve within 30 days after receipt any application for the importation or exportation of natural gas to or from Canada or Mexico.</p> <p>No presidential permit as required under specified executive orders shall be necessary for the construction, connection, operation, or maintenance of an oil or natural gas pipeline or electric transmission facility, including any border-crossing facility.</p> <p>No certificate of crossing shall be required for a modification to an existing facility that is operating for the import or export of oil, natural gas, or electricity prior to the enactment of this bill.</p> <p>FERC and DOE must publish a final rule in the Federal Register within one year to carry out the requirements of this bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2883v18" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-09">
<action-date>2017-07-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended, Part I</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Promoting Cross-Border Energy Infrastructure Act</b></p> <p>(Sec.2)This bill prohibits any person from constructing, connecting, operating, or maintaining a border-crossing facility for the import or export of oil, natural gas, or electricity across an international border of the United States without obtaining a certificate of crossing.</p> <p>The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC), with respect to oil or natural gas pipelines, or the Department of Energy (DOE), with respect to electric transmission facilities, must issue a certificate of crossing for the border-crossing facility within 120 days after final action is taken under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, unless it is not in the public interest.</p> <p>DOE, as a condition of issuing a certificate, must require that the border-crossing facility be constructed, connected, operated, or maintained consistent with specified policies and standards of the: (1)Electric Reliability Organization and applicable regional entity, and (2)Regional Transmission Organization or Independent System Operator with operational or functional control over the border-crossing facility.</p> <p>The bill amends the Natural Gas Act to require FERC to approve within 30 days after receipt any application for the importation or exportation of natural gas to or from Canada or Mexico.</p> <p>No presidential permit as required under specified executive orders shall be necessary for the construction, connection, operation, or maintenance of an oil or natural gas pipeline or electric transmission facility, including any border-crossing facility.</p> <p>No certificate of crossing shall be required for a modification to an existing facility that is operating for the import or export of oil, natural gas, or electricity prior to the enactment of this bill.</p> <p>FERC and DOE must publish a final rule in the Federal Register within one year to carry out the requirements of this bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2883v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-19">
<action-date>2017-06-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Promoting Cross-Border Energy Infrastructure Act</b></p> <p>This bill prohibits any person from constructing, connecting, operating, or maintaining a border-crossing facility for the import or export of oil, natural gas, or electricity across an international border of the United States without obtaining a certificate of crossing.</p> <p>The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC), with respect to oil or natural gas pipelines, or the Department of Energy (DOE), with respect to electric transmission facilities, must issue a certificate of crossing for the border-crossing facility within 120 days after final action is taken under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, unless it is not in the public interest.</p> <p>DOE, as a condition of issuing a certificate, must require that the border-crossing facility be constructed, connected, operated, or maintained consistent with specified policies and standards.</p> <p>The bill amends the Natural Gas Act to require FERC to approve within 30 days after receipt any application for the importation or exportation of natural gas to or from Canada or Mexico.</p> <p>No presidential permit as required under specified executive orders shall be necessary for the construction, connection, operation, or maintenance of an oil or natural gas pipeline or electric transmission facility, including any border-crossing facility.</p> <p>No certificate of crossing shall be required for a modification to an existing facility that is operating for the import or export of oil, natural gas, or electricity prior to the enactment of this bill.</p> <p>FERC and DOE must publish a final rule in the Federal Register within one year to carry out the requirements of this bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
