<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2910" measure-id="id115hr2910" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-15" update-date="2018-03-12">
<title>Promoting Interagency Coordination for Review of Natural Gas Pipelines Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2910v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-12">
<action-date>2017-07-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Promoting Interagency Coordination for Review of Natural Gas Pipelines Act</b></p> <p>(Sec.2)This bill expands the authority of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)to act as the lead agency for the purpose of coordinating all applicable federal authorizations and environmental reviews under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) with respect to authorizing a natural gas pipeline project under the Natural Gas Act.</p> <p>Federal, state, and local agencies involved in the environmental review process must defer to FERC's approved scope for a NEPA review.</p> <p>FERC must invite and designate the other participating agencies involved in the authorization process. A federal, state, or local agency may not participate if it informs FERC that it does not have the necessary authority or expertise, or does not intend to submit comments.</p> <p>An agency that is not designated may not request or conduct an environmental review unless it is legally required to do so and the agency requires information that FERC could not obtain through its NEPA review.</p> <p>The bill establishes a 90-day deadline to complete an authorization application for other authorizing agencies and requires concurrent reviews when multiple agencies are involved in the authorization process.</p><p>If a federal or state agency considering an aspect of an application for authorization requires the person applying for such authorization to submit data, the agency must consider any such data gathered by aerial or other remote means that the person submits.</p> <p>FERC must track and publicly display on its website specific information related to the actions required to complete an authorization.The information shall include:(1)the review schedule established by FERC under the Natural Gas Act;(2)a list of all the actions required by each applicable agency to complete permitting, reviews, and other actions necessary to obtain a final decision on the application;(3)the expected completion date for each such action;(4)a point of contact at the agency responsible for each such action;and(5)in the event that an action is still pending as of the expected date of completion, a brief explanation of the reasons for the delay.</p> <p>(Sec.3)In considering an application for an authorization or a certificate of public convenience and necessity under the Natural Gas Act, FERC shall consult with the Transportation Security Administration regarding an applicant's compliance with security guidance and for best practice recommendations regarding pipeline infrastructure security, pipeline cybersecurity, pipeline personnel security, and other pipeline security measures. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2910v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-18">
<action-date>2017-06-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Promoting Interagency Coordination for Review of Natural Gas Pipelines Act</b></p> <p>This bill expands the authority of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)to act as the lead agency for the purpose of coordinating all applicable federal authorizations and environmental reviews under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA) with respect to authorizing a natural gas pipeline project under the Natural Gas Act.</p> <p>Federal, state, and local agencies involved in the environmental review process must defer to FERC's approved scope for a NEPA review.</p> <p>FERC must invite and designate the other participating agencies involved in the authorization process. A federal, state, or local agency may not participate if it informs FERC that it does not have the necessary authority or expertise, or does not intend to submit comments.</p> <p>An agency that is not designated may not conduct an environmental review unless it is legally required to do so and the agency requires information that FERC could not obtain through its NEPA review.</p> <p>The bill establishes a 90 day deadline to complete an authorization application for other authorizing agencies and requires concurrent reviews when multiple agencies are involved in the authorization process.</p><p>If a federal or state agency considering an aspect of an application for authorization requires the person applying for such authorization to submit data, the agency must consider any such data gathered by aerial or other remote means that the person submits.</p> <p>FERC must track and publicly display on its website specific information related to the actions required to complete an authorization.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
