<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2078" measure-id="id115hr2078" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2017-07-12">
<title>Jump Start America Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2078v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-12">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Jump Start America Act of 2017 </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to several corporate and individual income tax policies, to:</p> <ul> <li>revise individual income tax rates to establish a 20% rate on taxable income of $1 million or less and a 30% rate on taxable income over $1 million, with an adjustment for inflation after 2016;</li> <li> revise the income tax rates on corporations to impose a single 20% rate on corporate taxable income; </li> <li>modify the formula for calculating the tax on the net capital gains of individual taxpayers to provide for a maximum 15% rate on the adjusted net capital gain of such taxpayers; </li> <li> reduce the tax rate on current and accumulated foreign earnings of U.S. corporations reinvested in the United States and make the lower rate permanent;</li> <li> increase the additional depreciation allowance (bonus depreciation) from 50% to 100% of the adjusted basis of qualifying business property and to make such increased allowance permanent; </li> <li>reduce Social Security and Medicare payroll taxes for employers, employees, and the self-employed; and </li> <li> repeal the federal estate, gift, and generation-skipping transfer taxes. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
