<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3994" measure-id="id115hr3994" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-06" update-date="2017-11-03">
<title>ACCESS BROADBAND Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3994v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-03">
<action-date>2017-10-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Advancing Critical Connectivity Expands Service, Small Business Resources, Opportunities, Access, and Data Based on Assessed Need and Demand Act or the ACCESS BROADBAND Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Commerce to establish the Office of Internet Connectivity and Growth within the National Telecommunications and Information Administration.</p> <p>The office&nbsp;shall:</p> <ul> <li>connect with communities that need access to high-speed internet and improved digital inclusion efforts,</li> <li>hold regional workshops to share best practices and effective strategies for promoting broadband access and adoption, </li> <li>develop targeted broadband training and presentations for various demographic communities through media, </li> <li>develop and distribute publications providing guidance to communities for expanding broadband access and adoption, and </li> <li>track construction and use of any broadband infrastructure built using federal support.</li></ul> <p>The office must report annually: (1) a description of the office's work, (2) the number of U.S. residents who received broadband as result of federal broadband programs and the Universal Service Fund program, and (3) an estimate of the economic impact of such broadband deployment efforts on the local economy.</p> <p>The office shall consult with any agency offering a federal broadband support program in order to streamline the application process and create one application that may be submitted to apply for all federal broadband support programs.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
