<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5258" measure-id="id115hr5258" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2018-03-13" update-date="2018-03-22">
<title>Affordable Health Insurance for the Middle Class Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr5258v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-22">
<action-date>2018-03-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Affordable Health Insurance for the Middle Class Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to modify the eligibility requirements for the premium assistance tax credit, which is provided to eligible individuals and families to subsidize the purchase of health insurance plans on an exchange established under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act. </p> <p>The bill expands eligibility for the credit by defining an &quot;applicable taxpayer&quot; as a taxpayer whose household income for the taxable year equals or exceeds 100% of the federal poverty line. (Under current law, household income must equal or exceed 100%, but may not exceed 400% of the poverty line.) </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
