<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1172" measure-id="id115hr1172" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-16" update-date="2017-06-23">
<title>Presidential Trade Transparency Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1172v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-23">
<action-date>2017-02-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Presidential Trade Transparency Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill requires the President to submit to Congress a report containing a full and complete statement of the President's income earned, assets held, and liabilities owed in the preceding 12 months that are associated with a foreign country:</p> <ul> <li> with which the United States is negotiating a trade or investment agreement,</li> <li>that is subject to a presidential trade enforcement action determination modifying the tariff treatment of imported articles from such country, or</li> <li>that is designated as eligible for preferential trade treatment under a trade preference program.</li> </ul> <p>If the President fails to report such information to Congress:</p> <ul> <li> any instrument providing for the modification of such tariff treatment shall have no force or effect, and</li> <li> the bill implementing such a trade or investment agreement shall not be eligible for trade authorities (fast track) procedures under the Bipartisan Congressional Trade Priorities and Accountability Act of 2015.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
