<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2843" measure-id="id115hr2843" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-08" update-date="2017-09-19">
<title>Medicaid and CHIP Quality Improvement Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2843v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-19">
<action-date>2017-06-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Medicaid and Chip Quality Improvement Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends titles XI (General Provisions) and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to expand reporting requirements&nbsp;with respect to the quality of care provided&nbsp;under Medicaid and the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP).</p> <p>Current law requires a state that contracts with a Medicaid managed organization&nbsp;to develop and implement a quality assessment and improvement strategy. The bill extends this requirement to state contracts with providers of&nbsp;comparable primary care case management services&nbsp;and other&nbsp;health care services under Medicaid.</p> <p>With respect to adults eligible for Medicaid and children enrolled in Medicaid or&nbsp;CHIP, a state must report annually on quality measures identified by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS). Such reporting shall be stratified by service delivery system.</p> <p>CMS shall establish a Medicaid Quality Performance Bonus fund to award states for high attainment and improvement on&nbsp;a core set of quality measures. A state must designate at least 75% of any bonus funds for the development and operation of quality-related initiatives that will directly benefit providers or managed care entities participating in, or under a waiver of, the state plan for medical assistance. A state may use&nbsp;the remainder of such&nbsp;funds for activities related to the goals and purposes of the state plan.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
