<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="31" measure-id="id115hr31" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-03" update-date="2017-01-06">
<title>Federal Sunset Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr31v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-01-06">
<action-date>2017-01-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Federal Sunset Act of 2017</strong></p> <p> This bill establishes the Federal Agency Sunset Commission to: (1) submit to Congress a schedule for review by the Commission, at least once every 12 years, of the abolishment or reorganization of each federal executive agency, including advisory committees; (2) review and evaluate the efficiency and public need for each agency using specified criteria; (3) recommend whether each agency should be abolished or reorganized; and (4) report to Congress on all legislation introduced that would establish a new agency or a new program to be carried out by an existing agency. The bill requires the abolishment of any agency within one year of the Commission's review unless the agency is reauthorized by Congress. The deadline for abolishing an agency may be extended for an additional two years by legislation enacted by a super majority of the House of Representatives and the Senate. </p> <p> The Commission shall terminate on December 31, 2037.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office and the Congressional Budget Office, in cooperation with the Congressional Research Service, shall prepare an inventory of federal programs within each agency, including the budget authority for each such program,&nbsp;to assist Congress and the Commission in carrying out the requirements of this bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
