<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2852" measure-id="id115hr2852" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-08" update-date="2017-06-16">
<title>EPIC Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2852v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-16">
<action-date>2017-06-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Election Protection &amp; Integrity Certification Act or the EPIC Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to require an organization applying for tax-exempt status to certify that it will not: (1) use foreign funds to make certain expenditures in connection with an election, a political party, or an electioneering communication; or (2) solicit, accept, or receive a contribution or donation from a foreign national for an election or a political party. </p> <p>A tax-exempt organization must certify in its annual tax return that it has not violated the requirements described above. </p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must study the political activities of corporations to determine whether foreign money is being used in U.S elections. </p> <p>The bill amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require tax-exempt organizations filing certain reports regarding disbursements for independent expenditures or electioneering communications to certify that foreign funds were not used for the disbursements. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
