<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2775" measure-id="id115hr2775" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-06" update-date="2018-01-30">
<title>Employee Privacy Protection Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2775v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-30">
<action-date>2017-09-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Employee Privacy Protection Act </b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the National Labor Relations Act to require the National Labor Relations Board, not earlier than seven days after it makes a final determination of the appropriate bargaining unit in a proposed election for collective bargaining representation, to acquire from the employer a list of all employees eligible to vote in the election, which shall: (1) be made available to all parties; and (2) include the employees' names and not more than one additional form of personal contact information (e.g., telephone number, email address, or mailing address) chosen by the employees in writing.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2775v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-30">
<action-date>2017-06-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Employee Privacy Protection Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the National Labor Relations Act to require the National Labor Relations Board, not earlier than seven days after it makes a final determination of the appropriate bargaining unit in a proposed election for collective bargaining representation, to acquire from the employer a list of all employees eligible to vote in the election, which shall: (1) be made available to all parties; and (2) include the employees' names and not more than one additional form of personal contact information (e.g., telephone number, email address, or mailing address) chosen by the employees in writing.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
