<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1202" measure-id="id115hr1202" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-17" update-date="2017-09-13">
<title>Red Hill Oversight and Environmental Protection Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1202v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-13">
<action-date>2017-02-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Red Hill Oversight and Environmental Protection Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to ensure that: (1) its budget justification materials submitted to Congress include a description of how it will use funds to support any deliverables that the parties of the agreement between the Department of the Navy, the Defense Logistics Agency, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), Region 9, and the State of Hawaii Department of Health, entered into on September 28, 2015, have identified as necessary to mitigate and prevent fuel leaks at the Red Hill Bulk Fuel Storage Facility on Oahu, Hawaii; and (2) each future-years defense program describes how DOD will use funds to support deliverables that the parties to such agreement identified as necessary to mitigate and prevent such leaks. </p> <p>The EPA must ensure that its budget justification materials submitted to Congress include a description of how it will use funds to support such deliverables.</p> <p>DOD may obligate or expend specified amounts to carry out an unspecified minor military construction project for the sustainment and maintenance of the facility. DOD shall submit to the congressional defense committees written notice of any decision to carry out such project, including a justification for, and the estimated cost of, such project. The authority to carry out such project shall terminate on September 30, 2030.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
