<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2824" measure-id="id115hr2824" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-08" update-date="2018-02-09">
<title>Increasing Opportunity and Success for Children and Parents through Evidence-Based Home Visiting Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2824v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-09">
<action-date>2017-09-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>TITLE I--INCREASING OPPORTUNITY AND SUCCESS FOR CHILDREN AND PARENTS THROUGH EVIDENCE-BASED HOME VISITING ACT</p> <p><em> Increasing Opportunity&nbsp;and Success for Children and Parents&nbsp;through Evidence-Based Home Visiting Act</em></p> <p>(Sec. 102) This bill amends title V (Maternal and Child Health Services) of the Social Security Act (SSAct) to reauthorize&nbsp;through FY2022, and otherwise revise,&nbsp;the Maternal, Infant, and Early Childhood Home Visiting Program.</p> <p>(Sec. 103) Under current law,&nbsp;grantees were required,&nbsp;after&nbsp;three years&nbsp;of program implementation, to demonstrate improvement in specified benchmark areas. The bill requires&nbsp;grantees&nbsp;to continue&nbsp;to track and&nbsp;demonstrate, on a triennial basis,&nbsp;improvement in applicable benchmark areas. A&nbsp;grantee that fails to do so&nbsp;must develop and implement a corrective action plan, subject to approval by&nbsp;the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS). HHS&nbsp;shall terminate a&nbsp;program grant made to&nbsp;a grantee&nbsp;that implements such a plan but continues to fail to demonstrate improvement. </p> <p>(Sec. 104) As a condition&nbsp;for receiving grant funds under the program, a state must&nbsp;review and update its statewide needs assessment by&nbsp;October 1, 2020.</p> <p>(Sec. 107) A grantee may use&nbsp;program grant funds&nbsp;to support&nbsp;a "pay-for-outcomes initiative"&nbsp;(a performance-based grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, awarded by a public entity, in which a commitment is made to pay for improved outcomes that result in social&nbsp;benefit and&nbsp;public-sector cost savings). </p> <p>(Sec. 108) Grantees must provide matching funds under the program beginning in FY2020.</p> <p>(Sec. 109) HHS must designate data-exchange standards applicable to the program.</p> <p>(Sec. 110) To the extent that grant funds are allocated on the basis of relative population or poverty considerations, HHS shall use the most accurate federal data available.</p> <p> TITLE II--CONTROL UNLAWFUL FUGITIVE FELONS ACT</p> <p><em>Control Unlawful Fugitive Felons Act of 2017</em></p> <p>(Sec. 202) The bill amends title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) of the SSAct to prohibit the payment of SSI benefits to an individual who is the subject of an outstanding arrest warrant for: (1) committing, or attempting to commit, a felony; or (2) violating a condition of parole or probation.</p> <p>Current law prohibits the payment of such benefits to an individual who: (1)&nbsp;is fleeing to avoid prosecution or confinement for committing, or attempting commit, a felony; or (2) is violating a condition of parole or probation.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2824v18" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-18">
<action-date>2017-09-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended, Part I</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Increasing Opportunity&nbsp;and Success for Children and Parents&nbsp;through Evidence-Based Home Visiting Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill amends title V (Maternal and Child Health Services) of the Social Security Act to reauthorize&nbsp;through FY2022, and otherwise revise,&nbsp;the Maternal, Infant, and Early Childhood Home Visiting Program.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) Under current law,&nbsp;grantees were required,&nbsp;after&nbsp;three years&nbsp;of program implementation, to demonstrate improvement in specified benchmark areas. The bill requires&nbsp;grantees&nbsp;to continue&nbsp;to track and&nbsp;demonstrate, on a triennial basis,&nbsp;improvement in applicable benchmark areas. A&nbsp;grantee that fails to do so&nbsp;must develop and implement a corrective action plan, subject to approval by&nbsp;the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS). HHS&nbsp;shall terminate a&nbsp;program grant made to&nbsp;a grantee&nbsp;that implements such a plan but continues to fail to demonstrate improvement. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) As a condition&nbsp;for receiving grant funds under the program, a state must&nbsp;review and update its statewide needs assessment by&nbsp;October 1, 2020.</p> <p> (Sec. 8) A grantee may use&nbsp;program grant funds&nbsp;to support&nbsp;a "pay-for-outcomes initiative"&nbsp;(a performance-based grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, awarded by a public entity, in which a commitment is made to pay for improved outcomes that result in social&nbsp;benefit and&nbsp;public-sector cost savings). </p> <p>(Sec. 9) Grantees must provide matching funds under the program beginning in FY2020.</p> <p>(Sec. 10) HHS must designate data-exchange standards applicable to the program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2824v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-20">
<action-date>2017-06-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Increasing Opportunity through Evidence-Based Home Visiting Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends title V (Maternal and Child Health Services) of the Social Security Act (SSAct) to reauthorize&nbsp;through FY2022, and otherwise revise,&nbsp;the Maternal, Infant, and Early Childhood Home Visiting Program.</p> <p> Under current law,&nbsp;grantees were required,&nbsp;after&nbsp;three years&nbsp;of program implementation, to demonstrate improvement in specified benchmark areas. The bill requires&nbsp;grantees&nbsp;to continue, in subsequent years,&nbsp;to track and demonstrate improvement in applicable benchmark areas. A&nbsp;grantee that fails to do so&nbsp;must develop and implement a corrective action plan, subject to approval by&nbsp;the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS). HHS&nbsp;shall terminate a&nbsp;program grant made to&nbsp;a grantee&nbsp;that implements such a plan but continues to fail to demonstrate improvement. </p> <p>As a condition&nbsp;for receiving grant funds under the program, a state must conduct a statewide needs assessment by&nbsp;October 1, 2019, and at least once every five years thereafter.</p> <p>A grantee may use&nbsp;program grant funds&nbsp;to support&nbsp;a "pay-for-outcomes initiative"&nbsp;(a performance-based grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, awarded by a public entity, in which a commitment is made to pay for improved outcomes that result in social&nbsp;benefit and&nbsp;public-sector cost savings). </p> <p>Grantees must provide matching funds under the program beginning in FY2020.</p> <p>HHS must designate data-exchange standards applicable to the program.</p> <p>The bill also amends title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) under the SSAct to&nbsp;prohibit&nbsp;the payment of SSI&nbsp;benefits to an individual who is subject to an arrest warrant for: (1)&nbsp;committing, or attempting to commit, a felony; or (2) violating a condition of parole or probation.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
