<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="827" measure-id="id115hr827" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-02" update-date="2017-06-07">
<title>Imperial Valley Desert Conservation and Recreation Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr827v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-07">
<action-date>2017-02-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Imperial Valley Desert Conservation and Recreation Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of the Interior to convey to the state of California approximately 934 acres of specified public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) in San Diego County, upon termination of all mining claims to such lands, to be managed in accordance with the provisions of the California Wilderness Act.</p> <p>On the submission of an application by Imperial County, California, the Department of Transportation shall seek a conveyance from Interior of approximately 3,500 acres of BLM-administered land adjacent to the Imperial County Holtville Airport in Imperial County, California, for purposes of airport expansion. </p> <p>The bill establishes the Vinagre Wash Special Management Area in California to conserve, protect, and enhance its plant and wildlife values and nationally significant resources. The area shall consist of approximately 81,880 acres of certain public lands in Imperial County. Interior shall manage specified lands in the management area to preserve their character for eventual inclusion in the National Wilderness Preservation System. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
