<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1914" measure-id="id115hr1914" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-05" update-date="2017-05-04">
<title>PROMOTE Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1914v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-04">
<action-date>2017-04-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Performance Royalty Owners of Music Opportunity To Earn Act of 2017 or the PROMOTE Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends federal copyright law to provide copyright owners the exclusive right to prohibit performance of a sound recording publicly by a broadcast transmission of a terrestrial AM/FM radio station. Exceptions are provided that allow terrestrial AM/FM radio broadcasts of a sound recording without the copyright owner's permission if: (1) a terrestrial AM/FM radio station pays royalties identical to those paid under the statutory license rates determined by Copyright Royalty Judges for eligible nonsubscription transmission services that apply to digital Internet radio streaming and webcasts; (2) the broadcast is of a religious service, by an educational terrestrial radio station, or by a low-power FM radio station; or (3) the broadcast is an incidental use. (Under current law, the exclusive right for the public performance of sound recordings extends only to digital audio transmissions, such as Internet and satellite radio broadcasts.)</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
