<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="396" measure-id="id115hr396" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-10" update-date="2017-08-26">
<title>Tax Accountability Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr396v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-26">
<action-date>2017-01-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Tax Accountability Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill declares that no government contracts or grants should be awarded to individuals or companies with seriously delinquent federal tax debts.</p> <p>Agencies offering a grant or issuing a solicitation for bids or a request for proposals for a contract in an amount greater than the simplified acquisition threshold (currently $150,000) shall require each person that submits a grant application, bid, or proposal to: (1) certify whether such person has a seriously delinquent tax debt, and (2) authorize the Department of the Treasury to disclose to the agency whether the person has a seriously delinquent tax debt.</p> <p>Agencies shall consider a person who has a seriously delinquent tax debt not to be a responsible source and thus the person may not be awarded contracts. Agencies must consider a grant applicant who has a seriously delinquent tax debt high risk, shall decline the grant application, and must ensure that the applicant does not receive future grants offered by the agency.</p> <p>Subject to waiver, agencies shall initiate a suspension or debarment proceeding against a person making offers or applying for grants who has a seriously delinquent tax debt or who falsely certified whether the person has a seriously delinquent tax debt. </p> <p>Individuals with seriously delinquent tax debts are not eligible for federal employment. Agencies must provide for review of public records to determine if a tax lien has been filed on employees or applicants for employment. Agencies may take certain personnel action against employees who fail to file a tax return or understate their tax liability. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
