<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="831" measure-id="id115hr831" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-02" update-date="2017-03-01">
<title>BALE Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr831v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-03-01">
<action-date>2017-02-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Beginning Agriculturalist Lifetime Employment Act of 2017 or the BALE Act of 2017</b></p> <p> This bill amends the Agricultural Act of 1961 to revise the limits for the Department of Agriculture's (USDA's) conservation loan guarantee program. </p> <p>The bill replaces the existing 80% limit on the portion of a loan that USDA may guarantee with limits that range from 80%-90%, depending on the principal amount of the loan. For socially disadvantaged or beginning farmers or ranchers, the bill replaces the existing 90% limit with limits that range from 85%-95%, depending on the principal amount of the loan. USDA may not guarantee a loan under the program that exceeds $3.5 million. </p> <p>The bill also revises the limitations on the amount of farm ownership loans to prohibit USDA from making or insuring any loan that would cause the unpaid indebtedness of any one borrower to exceed the smaller of: (1) the value of the farm or other security; or (2) in the case of a loan other than a loan guaranteed by USDA, $600,000, with an adjustment for inflation beginning with FY2023. </p> <p> <p> <p> <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
