<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1457" measure-id="id115hr1457" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-09" update-date="2018-02-22">
<title>MOBILE Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1457v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-22">
<action-date>2018-01-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(Sec. 1) This bill authorizes a financial institution to record personal information from a scan, copy, or image of an individual's driver's license or personal identification card and store the information electronically when an individual initiates an online request to open an account or obtain a financial product. The financial institution may use the information for the purpose of verifying the authenticity of the driver's license or identification card, verifying the identity of the individual, or complying with legal requirements. </p> <p>The financial institution must delete any copy or image of an individual's driver's license or personal identification card after use. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1457v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-26">
<action-date>2018-01-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(Sec. 1) This bill authorizes a financial institution to record personal information from a scan, copy, or image of an individual's driver's license or personal identification card and store the information electronically when an individual initiates an online request to open an account or obtain a financial product. The financial institution may use the information for the purpose of verifying the authenticity of the driver's license or identification card, verifying the identity of the individual, or complying with legal requirements. </p> <p>The financial institution must delete any copy or image of an individual's driver's license or personal identification card after use.</p>  <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1457v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-06">
<action-date>2017-03-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Making Online Banking Initiation Legal and Easy Act of 2017 or the</b> <b>MOBILE Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes a financial institution, with an individual's consent, to record personal information from a swipe or copy of an individual's driver's license or personal identification card and store the information electronically for the purpose of verifying the authenticity of the driver's license or identification card, verifying the identity of the individual, or complying with legal requirements. </p> <p>Financial institutions must not sell, rent, transfer, or make such information available to another person, other than an affiliate.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
