<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2681" measure-id="id115hr2681" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-25" update-date="2017-09-13">
<title>Foster EITC Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2681v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-13">
<action-date>2017-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Foster EITC Act of 2017</b></p> <p> This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the earned income tax credit, to: (1) expand the age range at which individuals without qualifying children are eligible for the credit to include individuals who have attained age 21 but not 68 (25 but not 65 under current law), and (2) make qualified foster youth eligible for the credit.</p> <p>A &quot;qualified foster youth&quot; is an individual who: (1) has attained age 18 but not attained age 21 before the close of the taxable year, and (2) on or after attaining the age of 14 was placed in a foster family home by a state, a political subdivision of the state, or a qualified foster care placement agency. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
