<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="672" measure-id="id115hr672" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-24" update-date="2017-07-19">
<title>Combating European Anti-Semitism Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr672v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-19">
<action-date>2017-05-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Combating European Anti-Semitism Act</strong> <strong>of 2017</strong></p> <p> (Sec. 3) This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) it is in the U.S. national interest to combat anti-Semitism at home and abroad; (2) there is a need to ensure the security of European Jewish communities, including synagogues, schools, and cemeteries; (3) the United States should continue to emphasize the importance of combating anti-Semitism in multilateral bodies; and (4) the Department of State should continue to document acts of anti-Semitism and anti-Semitic incitement and encourage adoption by national government institutions and multilateral institutions of a working definition of anti-Semitism similar to the one adopted in the International Holocaust Remembrance Alliance context. </p> <p> (Sec. 4) The International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 is amended to require the State Department's Annual Report on International Religious Freedom to include, for each European country in which threats or attacks against Jewish persons, schools, and religious institutions are particularly significant, a description of: </p> <ul> <li>the security challenges and needs of European Jewish communities and European law enforcement agencies; </li> <li>U.S. efforts to partner with European law enforcement agencies and civil society groups to combat anti-Semitic incidents;</li> <li>educational programming and public awareness initiatives that impart values of pluralism and tolerance, showcase the positive contributions of Jews, and pay special attention to population segments that exhibit a high degree of anti-Semitic animus; and </li> <li>efforts by European governments to adopt and apply a working definition of anti-Semitism.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr672v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-02-16">
<action-date>2017-01-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Combating European Anti-Semitism Act</strong></p> <p>This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) it is in the U.S. national interest to combat anti-Semitism at home and abroad; (2) there is a need to ensure the security of European Jewish communities, including synagogues, schools, and cemeteries; and (3) the United States should continue to emphasize the importance of combating anti-Semitism in multilateral bodies.</p> <p>The International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 is amended to require the Department of State's Annual Report on International Religious Freedom to include, for each European country in which threats or attacks against Jewish persons, schools, and religious institutions are particularly significant, a description of: </p> <ul> <li>the security challenges and needs of European Jewish communities and European law enforcement agencies; </li> <li>U.S. efforts to partner with European law enforcement agencies and civil society groups to combat anti-Semitic incidents;</li> <li>educational programming and public awareness initiatives that impart values of pluralism and tolerance, showcase the positive contributions of Jews, and pay special attention to population segments that exhibit a high degree of anti-Semitic animus; and </li> <li>efforts by European governments to adopt and apply a working definition of anti-Semitism.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
