<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3647" measure-id="id115hr3647" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-08-08" update-date="2017-11-14">
<title>Save America Comprehensive Immigration Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3647v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-14">
<action-date>2017-08-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Save America Comprehensive Immigration Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide increased protections and eligibility for family-sponsored immigrants.</p> <p> The bill establishes: (1) the Board of Family-based Visa Appeals, and (2) the Task Force to Rescue Immigrant Victims of American Sex Offenders.</p> <p> The bill sets forth provisions regarding: (1) the Border Patrol and other law enforcement officers, including regarding personnel increases; (2) status adjustment, including an adjustment for Haitians; (3) sex offenders; (4) unfair immigration-related employment practices; (5) removal proceedings, including for removal based om criminal offenses; (6) asylee and refugee proceedings; and (7) naturalization.</p> <p> The Anti-Smuggling Unit within the Border Patrol is reestablished.</p> <p> The worldwide level of diversity immigrants is increased. </p> <p>Gender-based persecution is established as a grounds for refugee status.</p> <p>Adjustment to permanent resident is provided for certain temporary protected status persons.</p> <p> The bill authorizes S (witness or informant) nonimmigrant status for aliens in possession of critical reliable information concerning commercial alien smuggling or trafficking in immigration documents. </p> <p> The definition of &quot;law enforcement officer&quot; under provisions of the Federal Employees Retirement System and the Civil Service Retirement System is amended to include: (1) federal employees not otherwise covered by such term whose duties include the investigation or apprehension of suspected or convicted individuals and who are authorized to carry a firearm, and (2) Internal Revenue Service employees whose duties are primarily the collection of delinquent taxes and the securing of delinquent returns.</p> <p> The bill repeals: (1) provisions prohibiting government entities and officials from preventing communications with federal immigration authorities, and (2) authority permitting state personnel to carry out immigration officer functions.</p> <p> The fashion model H-1B visa is replaced with an O-visa.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
