<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="477" measure-id="id115hr477" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-12" update-date="2018-02-22">
<title>Small Business Mergers, Acquisitions, Sales, and Brokerage Simplification Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr477v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-22">
<action-date>2017-12-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Small Business Mergers, Acquisitions, Sales, and Brokerage Simplification Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to exempt from&nbsp;that Act's registration requirements merger-and-acquisition brokers that facilitate transfer of ownership in privately held companies with earnings or revenues under a specified threshold. This exemption shall not apply, however, to brokers that: </p> <ul> <li> receive, hold, transmit, or have custody of funds or securities to be exchanged by parties to an ownership&nbsp;transfer; </li> <li>engage on behalf of an issuer in a public offering of registered securities; </li> <li>engage on behalf of any party in a transaction involving specified shell companies;</li> <li>provide financing related to the transfer of ownership;</li> <li>assist any party to obtain financing from a third party in specified circumstances;</li> <li>represent both buyer and seller without disclosure and consent from both parties;</li> <li>facilitate a transaction with a group of buyers formed with the assistance of the broker;</li> <li>engage in transferring ownership to a passive buyer;</li> <li>bind a party to a transfer of ownership; or </li> <li>are subject to suspension or revocation of registration or to other specified disqualifications. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr477v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-22">
<action-date>2017-11-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Small Business Mergers, Acquisitions, Sales, and Brokerage Simplification Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to generally exempt certain merger-and-acquisition brokers from&nbsp;that Act's registration requirements. This exemption shall not apply, however, to brokers that: (1) receive, hold, transmit, or have custody of funds or securities to be exchanged by parties to an ownership&nbsp;transfer of a privately held company that meets specified conditions; (2) engage on behalf of an issuer in a public offering of registered securities; (3) engage on behalf of any party in a transaction involving a public shell company; or (4) are subject to suspension or revocation of registration or to other specified disqualifications.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr477v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-10">
<action-date>2017-01-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Small Business Mergers, Acquisitions, Sales, and Brokerage Simplification Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to generally exempt certain merger-and-acquisition brokers from&nbsp;that Act's registration requirements. This exemption shall not apply, however, to brokers that: (1) receive, hold, transmit, or have custody of funds or securities to be exchanged by parties to an ownership&nbsp;transfer of a privately held company that meets specified conditions; (2) engage on behalf of an issuer in a public offering of registered securities; (3) engage on behalf of any party in a transaction involving a public shell company; or (4) are subject to suspension or revocation of registration or to other specified disqualifications.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
