<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="882" measure-id="id115hr882" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-06" update-date="2017-04-26">
<title>North American Development Bank Improvement and General Capital Increase Authorization Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr882v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-04-26">
<action-date>2017-02-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>North American Development Bank Improvement and General Capital Increase Authorization Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of the Treasury to subscribe to 150,000 additional shares of the capital stock of the North American Development Bank.</p> <p>The U.S. government shall support the financing of projects related to:</p> <ul> <li>natural gas, including natural gas pipelines and combined cycle power plants, with major emphasis on cross-border energy distribution and consumption and the energy security of the United States and Mexico; and</li> <li>the expansion or new construction of international land border crossings to facilitate the the flow of goods and people across the U.S.-Mexico border while reducing wait times and improving air quality related to vehicular and commercial traffic pollution.</li> </ul> <p>The U.S. government shall also require the bank to develop and implement:</p> <ul> <li> efficiency improvements to streamline and accelerate the bank's project certification and financing process, and </li> <li>performance measures that demonstrate how the bank's approved projects and financing are meeting its mission and providing value to the U.S.- Mexico border region.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
