<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4893" measure-id="id115hr4893" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2018-01-29" update-date="2018-03-12">
<title>Improve Data on Sexual Violence Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4893v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-12">
<action-date>2018-01-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Improve Data on Sexual Violence Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Office of Management and Budget to establish an interagency working group to study federal efforts to collect data on sexual violence and to make recommendations on efforts to coordinate sexual violence data collection to produce complementary information, without compromising programmatic needs.</p> <p> The working group shall consider:</p> <ul> <li>what activity constitutes different acts of sexual violence,</li> <li>whether reports that use the same terms for acts of sexual violence are collecting the same data on these acts,</li> <li>whether the context which led to such an act should impact how that act is accounted for in reports,</li> <li>whether the data collected is presented in a way that allows the general public to understand what acts of sexual violence are included in each measurement, and</li> <li>steps that agencies that compile reports relating to sexual violence can take to avoid double counting incidents.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
