<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="856" measure-id="id115hr856" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-03" update-date="2017-06-07">
<title>Putting Our Veterans Back to Work Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr856v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-07">
<action-date>2017-02-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Putting Our Veterans Back to Work Act of 2017</strong></p> <p> This bill amends the: (1) VOW to Hire Heroes Act of 2011 to extend through 2020 the veterans retraining assistance program, and (2) Wounded Warrior Act to extend through 2020 the authority of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide the same rehabilitation and vocational benefits to members of the Armed Forces with severe injuries or illnesses as are provided to veterans.</p> <p> The bill extends through: (1) March 31, 2020, additional VA rehabilitation programs for certain disabled veterans who have completed a VA rehabilitation program and have exhausted their rights to state unemployment benefits; and (2) FY2021 the collaborative veterans' training, mentoring, and placement program.</p> <p> The VA shall develop a single, unified federal web-based employment portal for veterans to access information on federal programs and activities concerning veterans employment, unemployment, and training.</p> <p> The bill directs the: (1) Department of Homeland Security to award grants to hire veterans as firefighters, and (2) Department of Justice to award grants to hire veterans as law enforcement officers.</p> <p> The head of each executive and defense agency shall consider favorably, as an evaluation factor in federal solicitations for civilian or defense contracts and task or delivery orders valued at or above $25 million, the employment by a prospective contractor of veterans constituting at least 5% of the contractor's workforce.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
