<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2857" measure-id="id115hr2857" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-08" update-date="2018-03-07">
<title>Supporting Families in Substance Abuse Treatment Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2857v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-07">
<action-date>2017-06-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Supporting Families in Substance Abuse Treatment Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act to provide that the removal and foster care placement of a child shall meet the requirements for foster care maintenance payments on the child's behalf if the child has been placed with a parent residing in a licensed residential family-based treatment facility.</p> <p>Placement with such a parent shall meet these requirements only if:</p> <ul> <li>the placement recommendation is specified in the child's case plan before the placement;</li> <li>the treatment facility offers, as part of substance abuse treatment, parenting skills training, parent education, and individual and family counseling; and</li> <li>this training and counseling are delivered under an organizational structure and treatment framework that involves understanding, recognizing, and responding to the effects of all types of trauma, and in accordance with recognized principles of a trauma-informed approach and trauma-specific interventions, to address the consequences of trauma and facilitate healing. </li> </ul> <p>The bill specifies the amount the state may receive for a child placed with a parent who is in a licensed residential family-based treatment facility for substance abuse.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2857v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-22">
<action-date>2017-06-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Supporting Families in Substance Abuse Treatment Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act to provide that the removal and foster care placement of a child shall meet the requirements for foster care maintenance payments on the child's behalf if the child has been placed with a parent residing in a licensed residential family-based treatment facility.</p> <p>Placement with such a parent shall meet these requirements, however, only if:</p> <ul> <li>the placement recommendation is specified in the child's case plan before the placement; </li> <li>the treatment facility offers, as part of substance abuse treatment, parenting skills training, parent education, and individual and family counseling; and </li> <li>this training and counseling are delivered under an organizational structure and treatment framework that involves understanding, recognizing, and responding to the effects of all types of trauma, and in accordance with recognized principles of a trauma-informed approach and trauma-specific interventions, to address the consequences of trauma and facilitate healing. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
