<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3392" measure-id="id115hr3392" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-25" update-date="2017-08-24">
<title>Lake Bistineau Land Title Stability Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3392v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-24">
<action-date>2017-07-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Lake Bistineau Land Title Stability Act</b></p> <p>This bill declares that the document titled &quot;Dependent Re-Survey, Extension Survey and Survey of Two Islands, Sections 17, 29, and 30&quot; (published in the Federal Register on February 27, 1969) shall not be considered to be, or serve as, a gross error determination and shall have no legal force or effect on the ownership of certain land surrounding Lake Bistineau in northern Louisiana. </p> <p>The meander lines recorded in the original survey of such land approved by the Surveyor General on December 8, 1842, shall be definitive for purposes of determining title to such land and two adjacent islands. </p> <p>The Department of the Interior shall prepare a disclaimer of any U.S. right, title, or interest in and to any such land that is located outside such meander lines and any omitted land that was in place, but not included, in the original survey. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
