<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3308" measure-id="id115hr3308" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-19" update-date="2018-03-09">
<title>Veterans Caregiver Improvement and Expansion Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3308v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-09">
<action-date>2017-07-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Veterans Caregiver Improvement and Expansion Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to conduct an audit of two specified caregiver programs of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA). Such audit shall include: (1) a review of the budget formulations, execution, allocation, and use of funds; and (2) recommendations for streamlining and consolidation. </p> <p>Within three months of the completion of such audit, VA must submit a report to Congress on:</p> <ul> <li>recommendations the VA is able to implement without legislative changes;</li> <li>legislative changes recommended by the GAO;</li> <li>recommendations that VA determines are problematic, overly expensive, or impractical; and </li> <li> alternative approaches to address the problem. </li> </ul> <p>Within 24 months of submitting such report, VA shall:</p> <ul> <li>implement the recommendations the VA is able to implement without legislative changes,</li> <li>establish national policies that are designed to streamline and consolidate the programs, and </li> <li>establish a database to monitor all VA programs that provide assistance to caregivers and all caregivers who receive such assistance.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
