<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2350" measure-id="id115hr2350" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-04" update-date="2017-11-20">
<title>Small Business Know-Before-You-Bid Construction Transparency Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2350v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-20">
<action-date>2017-05-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Small Business Know-Before-You-Bid Construction Transparency Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Small Business Act to require the Small Business Administration to make available a secured electronic system through which each agency shall provide access to documents relating to each construction contract it awards to a small business concern, including:</p> <ul> <li>any payment bond provided for the contract and any bond modification required by the agency; and</li> <li>the date and amount of each payment made to the prime contractor, any amounts withheld, and a general explanation of why an amount was withheld.</li> </ul> <p>The bill requires that such documents be made available in such system within 15 days after they are included in the contract file.</p> <p>For solicitations for the award of a construction contract anticipated to be awarded to a small business concern, the agency shall provide a notice along with the solicitation about the agency's required policies or practices relating to the timely definitization of requests for an equitable adjustment.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
