<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1590" measure-id="id115hr1590" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-16" update-date="2017-05-31">
<title>CLEAR SBA Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1590v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-31">
<action-date>2017-03-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Communicating Lender Activity Reports from the Small Business Administration Act or the CLEAR SBA Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends <his> the Small Business Act to define &quot;covered loan&quot; as a loan made or debenture issued under the Act or the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 by a private individual or entity.</p> <p>The bill requires the Small Business Administration (SBA) to make publicly available on its website a Lender Activity Index (i.e., a user-friendly database of specified information relating to lenders making covered loans).</p> <p>The SBA shall: (1) include in the database information relating to covered loans made during FY2009-FY2016, and (2) incorporate information related to such loans on an ongoing basis.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
