<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3761" measure-id="id115hr3761" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-13" update-date="2018-04-03">
<title>Carbon Capture Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3761v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-04-03">
<action-date>2017-09-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Carbon Capture Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend and modify the tax credit for carbon dioxide (CO2) sequestration. The bill modifies the credit to: </p> <ul> <li>allow certain new industrial or direct air capture facilities to qualify for the credit if construction begins before 2024; </li> <li> allow qualified projects to claim the credit for 15 years, beginning on the date the equipment was originally placed in service; </li> <li> increase the credit amounts for certain projects placed in service upon or after the enactment of this bill; </li> <li>expand the purposes for which captured CO2 may be used;</li> <li>modify the requirements for the amount of CO2 that must be captured; </li> <li> specify that the 75 million metric ton cap on the CO2 that may qualify for the credit applies only to projects placed in service before the enactment of this bill; </li> <li> allow the credit to be transferred from the entity that owns and uses the capture equipment to the entity that disposes of or uses the CO2; and</li> <li>allow certain facilities that were placed in service after 2015 and have not previously claimed the credit to be treated as placed in service on the date of the enactment of this bill. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
