<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3478" measure-id="id115hr3478" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-27" update-date="2017-11-20">
<title>Local and Independent Television Protection Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3478v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-20">
<action-date>2017-07-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Local and Independent Television Protection Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Federal Communications Commission to&nbsp;amend the National Television Multiple Ownership Rule&nbsp;to eliminate the UHF discount by increasing from&nbsp;50% to 100% the number of attributed television households in&nbsp;an&nbsp;ultrahigh frequency (UHF) television station's&nbsp;designated market area. <br /><br />(The number of attributed television households in a UHF television station's designated area&nbsp;is used&nbsp;to calculate the total number of television households&nbsp;an entity with a cognizable interest in more than one&nbsp;television station reaches nationally. A broadcast license cannot be granted or&nbsp;transferred if such license would result in the total number of television households reached nationally by&nbsp;an entity exceeds 39%.) </p> <p>This change in the National Television Multiple Ownership Rule does not apply to&nbsp;an entity&nbsp;that had a national television audience exceeding 39% prior to September 26, 2013, if such an entity exceeds the limit only because of the increased number of television households attributed&nbsp;to the entity's&nbsp;UHF television stations.&nbsp;</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
