<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1608" measure-id="id115hr1608" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-17" update-date="2017-07-25">
<title>ICE and CBP Body Camera Accountability Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1608v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-25">
<action-date>2017-03-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>ICE and CBP Body Camera Accountability Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) and Customs and Border Protection (CBP) to ensure that ICE and CBP agents and officers wear body cameras when engaged in official operations. ICE and CBP must establish: (1) policies for the use of such cameras, and (2) procedures for carrying out adverse actions for noncompliance with such policies.</p> <p>Such cameras must be on for an agent's or officer's entire shift.</p> <p>Footage collected by such a body camera shall be made available to each party to any administrative proceeding, civil action, or criminal prosecution to which it pertains. If such footage is not made available, such a party may notify ICE or CBP in writing for purposes of instigating an adverse action for noncompliance.</p> <p>DHS shall commence a rulemaking regarding the use of body cameras and the provision of footage that is consistent with the "Civil Rights Principles for Body Worn Cameras" of the Leadership Conference on Civil and Human Rights, May 2015.</p> <p>An ICE or CBP agent or officer whose body camera does not record footage in violation of this bill shall be subject to furlough, reduction in pay or grade, or a suspension of up to 30 days. If a body camera does not record at a time when the camera is required to be active, DHS may not determine that the camera suffered a malfunction unless the agent or officer submits evidence sufficient to establish that a malfunction occurred.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
