<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2460" measure-id="id115hr2460" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-16" update-date="2017-06-27">
<title>To amend chapter 301 of title 49, United States Code, to improve access to motor vehicle information, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2460v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-27">
<action-date>2017-05-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill allows the Department of Transportation (DOT) to require that each motor vehicle manufacturer provide the following information, with regard to a specific vehicle identification number:</p> <ul> <li>each original equipment manufacturer (OEM) part name included within the vehicle, including a description, number (including any superceded and successor OEM part number), any other part identification number (such as a serial number) and distinguishing marking, and software of each part;</li> <li>build sheet information; and</li> <li>additional information as determined by DOT.</li> </ul> <p>Each motor vehicle manufacturer shall provide access to such information on a website to the motor vehicle owner and any potential purchaser of the motor vehicle.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
