<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2484" measure-id="id115hr2484" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-17" update-date="2017-08-21">
<title>Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2484v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-21">
<action-date>2017-06-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the United States should be a global leader in promoting the participation of women in conflict prevention, management, and resolution and post-conflict relief and recovery efforts; and (2) the political participation and leadership of women in fragile environments, particularly during democratic transitions, is critical to sustaining democratic institutions.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The bill declares that it shall be U.S. policy to promote the meaningful participation of women in all aspects of overseas conflict prevention, management, and resolution, and post-conflict relief and recovery efforts.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) The President, by one year after this bill's enactment and four years thereafter, shall submit to Congress and make public a Women, Peace, and Security Strategy, which shall: </p> <ul> <li> be aligned with other countries' plans to improve the participation of women in peace and security processes, conflict prevention, peace building, and decision-making institutions; </li> <li>include goals and evaluation plans to ensure strategy effectiveness; and</li> <li> include a specific implementation plan from each relevant federal agency. </li> </ul> <p>The President is urged to promote women's participation in conflict prevention, in coordination with international partners.</p> <p> (Sec. 6) The Department of State and the Department of Defense (DOD) shall ensure that specified personnel receive training in conflict prevention, mitigation, and resolution and on other related topics.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) The State Department and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) may establish guidelines for overseas U.S. personnel to consult with appropriate stakeholders regarding U.S. efforts to: (1) prevent, mitigate, or resolve violent conflict; and (2) enhance the success of mediation and negotiation processes by ensuring the meaningful participation of women. </p> <p> The State Department is urged to work with international, regional, national, and local organizations to increase the participation of women in international peacekeeping operations.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) The State Department, in conjunction with USAID and DOD and within a year of the first submission of the strategy, shall brief Congress on existing, enhanced, or newly established training carried out pursuant to this bill. The President, within two years of the submission of each strategy, shall report to Congress regarding its implementation.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2484v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-21">
<action-date>2017-05-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the United States should be a global leader in promoting the participation of women in conflict prevention, management, and resolution and post-conflict relief and recovery efforts; and (2) the political participation and leadership of women in fragile environments, particularly during democratic transitions, is critical to sustaining democratic institutions.</p> <p>The President, by one year after this bill's enactment and four years thereafter, shall submit to Congress and make public a Women, Peace, and Security Strategy, which shall: </p> <ul> <li> be aligned with other countries' plans to improve the participation of women in peace and security processes, conflict prevention, peace building, and decision-making institutions; </li> <li>include goals and evaluation plans to ensure strategy effectiveness; and</li> <li> include a specific implementation plan from each relevant federal agency. </li> </ul> <p>The President is urged to promote women's participation in conflict prevention. </p> <p> The Department of State and the Department of Defense shall ensure that specified personnel receive training in conflict prevention, mitigation, and resolution and on other related topics.</p> <p>The State Department and the U.S. Agency for International Development may establish guidelines for overseas U.S. personnel to consult with appropriate stakeholders regarding U.S. efforts to: (1) prevent, mitigate, or resolve violent conflict; and (2) enhance the success of mediation and negotiation processes by ensuring the meaningful participation of women. </p> <p> The State Department is urged to work with international, regional, national, and local organizations to increase the participation of women in international peacekeeping operations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
