<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1014" measure-id="id115hr1014" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-13" update-date="2017-06-07">
<title>Haiti Emergency Relief Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1014v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-07">
<action-date>2017-02-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Haiti Emergency Relief Act of 2017</strong></p> <p> This bill extends 18-month temporary protected status to a national of Haiti who: (1) has been continuously physically present in the United States since November 4, 2016, (2) is admissible as an immigrant and not ineligible for temporary protected status, and (3) registers for temporary protected status in a manner that the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) shall establish. </p> <p> Such an alien may travel abroad if the alien establishes to the satisfaction of DHS that emergency and extenuating circumstances beyond the alien's control require his or her departure for a brief, temporary trip abroad. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
