<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2188" measure-id="id115hr2188" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-27" update-date="2017-07-29">
<title>Community Counterterrorism Preparedness Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2188v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-29">
<action-date>2017-06-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Community Counterterrorism Preparedness Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to carry out a grant program for emergency response providers to prevent, prepare for, and respond to emerging terrorist attack scenarios in major metropolitan areas.</p> <p>DHS shall provide to eligible applicants: (1) unclassified information on such scenarios, and (2) information on training and exercises best practices. </p> <p>Jurisdictions that receive funding under the Urban Area Security Initiative may apply for such a grant. </p> <p>Eligible applicants receiving funding under the program may include in funded activities neighboring jurisdictions that would be likely to provide mutual aid in response in such scenarios.</p> <p>Recipients may use grants to:</p> <ul> <li>identify capability gaps related to preparing for, preventing, and responding to such scenarios;</li> <li>develop or update plans, annexes, and processes to address such gaps; </li> <li>conduct training and exercises to address such gaps; and</li> <li>conduct exercises, including at locations such as mass gathering venues, places of worship, or educational institutions, as appropriate, to validate capabilities.</li> </ul> <p>DHS shall aggregate, analyze, and share with relevant emergency response providers information on best practices and lessons learned from: (1) the planning, training, and exercises conducted using program grants; and (2) responses to actual terrorist attacks around the world.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2188v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-29">
<action-date>2017-04-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Community Counterterrorism Preparedness Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to carry out a grant program for emergency response providers to prevent, prepare for, and respond to emerging terrorist attack scenarios in major metropolitan areas.</p> <p>DHS shall provide to eligible applicants: (1) unclassified information on such scenarios, and (2) information on training and exercises best practices. </p> <p>Jurisdictions that receive funding under the Urban Area Security Initiative may apply for such a grant. </p> <p>Eligible applicants receiving funding under the program may include in funded activities neighboring jurisdictions that would be likely to provide mutual aid in response in such scenarios.</p> <p>Recipients may use grants to:</p> <ul> <li>identify capability gaps related to preparing for, preventing, and responding to such scenarios;</li> <li>develop or update plans, annexes, and processes to address such gaps; and</li> <li>conduct training and exercises to address such gaps and validate capabilities.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
