<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2950" measure-id="id115hr2950" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-20" update-date="2017-08-22">
<title>Making Public Lands Public Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2950v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-22">
<action-date>2017-06-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Making Public Lands Public Act</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to ensure that a specified portion of the Land and Water Conservation Fund is made available each fiscal year for projects to: (1) maintain or increase public access to existing federal public land for hunting, fishing, or recreational shooting through the acquisition of rights-of-way or the acquisition of land through equal value land exchanges from willing owners; or (2) enhance, maintain, or restore access on existing roads, trails, or rights-of-way. </p> <p>Interior and USDA must develop a priority list of such projects each year. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
