<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3168" measure-id="id115hr3168" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-06" update-date="2018-02-20">
<title>SNP Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3168v18" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-20">
<action-date>2017-12-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended, Part I</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Special Needs Plans Reauthorization Act of 2017 or the SNP Reauthorization Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill&nbsp;allows a Medicare Advantage (MA) plan, until 2024,&nbsp;to restrict plan enrollment to certain special-needs individuals, provided that the plan meets specified applicable requirements. Current law allows an MA plan to do so until 2019. </p> <p>The Federal Coordinated Health Care Office within the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) shall serve as a dedicated point of contact for states with regard to special-needs MA plans for individuals who are dually eligible for Medicaid and Medicare.&nbsp;The CMS&nbsp;shall establish a unified process for grievances and appeals for individuals enrolled in such plans.</p> <p>The CMS must, with respect to special-needs MA plans for individuals with chronic conditions, convene a panel of clinical advisors to establish and update the list of chronic conditions that make an individual eligible for participation in such a plan.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office (GAO) must study and report to Congress on health outcomes of individuals enrolled in specialized MA plans.</p> <p>The CMS shall, with respect to special-needs MA plans,&nbsp;consider applying certain quality measures at the plan level rather than at the contract level.</p> <p>The GAO must report to Congress on state-level integration between the Medicaid program and&nbsp;special-needs MA plans for individuals who are dually eligible for Medicaid and Medicare.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) Beginning in plan year 2020, an MA plan may provide certain supplemental benefits to chronically ill enrollees.</p> <p>The GAO must report to Congress on the provision of such supplemental benefits to MA enrollees. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3168v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-09">
<action-date>2017-07-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill&nbsp;allows a Medicare Advantage (MA) plan, until 2024,&nbsp;to restrict plan enrollment to certain special-needs individuals, provided that the plan meets specified applicable requirements. Current law allows an MA plan to do so until 2019. </p> <p>The Federal Coordinated Health Care Office within the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) shall serve as a dedicated point of contact for states with regard to special-needs MA plans for individuals who are dually eligible for Medicaid and Medicare.&nbsp;The CMS&nbsp;shall establish a unified process for grievances and appeals for individuals enrolled in such plans.</p> <p>The CMS must, with respect to special-needs MA plans for individuals with chronic conditions, convene a panel of clinical advisors to establish and update the list of chronic conditions that make an individual eligible for participation in such a plan.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office (GAO) must study and report to Congress on health outcomes of individuals enrolled in specialized MA plans.</p> <p>The CMS shall, with respect to special-needs MA plans,&nbsp;consider applying certain quality measures at the plan level rather than at the contract level.</p> <p>The GAO must report to Congress on state-level integration between the Medicaid program and&nbsp;special-needs MA plans for individuals who are dually eligible for Medicaid and Medicare.</p> <p>Beginning in plan year 2020, an MA plan may provide certain supplemental benefits to chronically ill enrollees.</p> <p>The GAO must report to Congress on the provision of such supplemental benefits to MA enrollees.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
