<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2356" measure-id="id115hr2356" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-04" update-date="2017-05-17">
<title>MY DATA Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2356v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-17">
<action-date>2017-05-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Managing Your Data Against Telecom Abuses Act of 2017 or the MY DATA Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill prohibits providers of Internet broadband services or of Internet content, applications, or devices from using unfair or deceptive acts or practices relating to privacy or data security.</p> <p>The Federal Trade Commission (FTC), after consulting with the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), may promulgate regulations to carry out such prohibition. </p> <p>The FTC may also enforce this bill against common carriers regulated by the FCC under the Communications Act of 1934 and nonprofit organizations. (Currently, common carriers regulated under the Communications Act are exempt from the FTC's enforcement authority and nonprofit organizations are subject to FTC enforcement only if they provide substantial economic benefit to their for-profit members.)</p> <p>A state may bring a civil action in federal court to enforce such prohibition.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
