<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1370" measure-id="id115hr1370" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-06" update-date="2018-01-22">
<title>An Act to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to issue Department of Homeland Security-wide guidance and develop training programs as part of the Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1370v71" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2018-01-22">
<action-date>2017-12-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Senate agreed to House amendment without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>DIVISION A--FURTHER ADDITIONAL CONTINUING APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2018 </p> <p><em>Further Additional Continuing Appropriations Act, 2018</em></p> <p> (Sec. 1001) Amends the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2018 to provide continuing FY2018 appropriations to federal agencies through January 19, 2018 (December 22, 2017, under current law). </p> <p>(This provision prevents a government shutdown that would otherwise occur when the existing continuing resolution expires because the FY2018 appropriations bills have not been enacted.) </p> <p>Adds provisions to the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2018 that:</p> <ul> <li>permit funds provided to the Coast Guard to be used to carry out Retired Pay Reform, including continuation pay;</li> <li>provide additional funding to the Indian Health Service for the costs of staffing and operating newly constructed facilities;</li> <li>permit funds provided to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to be apportioned up to the rate for operations necessary to maintain programs and activities related to: (1) the care of unaccompanied alien children, and (2) efforts to combat the trafficking of children;</li> <li>provide additional funding for HHS to prepare for or respond to an influenza pandemic; and</li> <li>exempt security spending from sequestration (automatic spending cuts) for FY2018 and delay the sequestration for nonsecurity spending. </li> </ul> <p>(Sec. 1002) Extends certain authorities provided by the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) through the duration of the continuing resolution. Specifies that this section is repealed if legislation amending the dates included in section 403(b) of the FISA Amendments Act of 2008 is enacted.</p> <p>DIVISION B--MISSILE DEFENSE </p> <p><em>Department of Defense Missile Defeat and Defense Enhancements Appropriations Act, 2018 </em></p> <p>Provides FY2018 emergency appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for missile defense programs. (Emergency spending is exempt from discretionary spending limits and other budget enforcement rules.) </p> <p>TITLE I--MISSILE DEFEAT AND DEFENSE ENHANCEMENTS </p> <p>Provides Operation and Maintenance funds to DOD for necessary costs to repair damage to the USS <em>John S. McCain</em> and the USS <em>Fitzgerald</em>. </p> <p>Provides Operation and Maintenance; Procurement; and Research, Development, Test and Evaluation funds to DOD for necessary costs to detect, defeat, and defend against the use of ballistic missiles. </p> <p>TITLE II--MISSILE CONSTRUCTION ENHANCEMENTS </p> <p>Provides appropriations for Defense-Wide Military Construction for construction of a missile field in Alaska.</p> <p> TITLE III--GENERAL PROVISIONS</p> <p> (Sec. 2001) Specifies that the funds provided by this division are in addition to funds appropriated or otherwise made available to DOD for FY2018. </p> <p>(Sec. 2002) Requires funds provided by title I of this division to be allocated in accordance with the detailed congressional budget justifications submitted by DOD with the FY2018 budget amendments requested by the President on November 6, 2017. Specifies that any changes to the allocation of funds are subject to reprogramming requirements. </p> <p>(Sec. 2003) Specifies that funds designated in this division as emergency requirements are available only if the President subsequently designates all of the amounts as emergency requirements and transmits the designations to Congress. </p> <p>DIVISION C--HEALTH PROVISIONS</p> <p>TITLE I--PUBLIC HEALTH EXTENDERS</p> <p><em>CHIP and Public Health Funding Extension Act</em></p> <p>(Sec. 3101) Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to extend and make appropriations through the second quarter of FY2018 for community health centers and the National Health Service Corps.</p> <p>Amends the Public Health Service Act to make appropriations through the second quarter of FY2018 for a program that pays teaching health centers to establish or expand graduate medical residency training programs.</p> <p>(Sec. 3102) Makes appropriations through the second quarter of FY2018 for type I diabetes programs and diabetes programs for Native Americans.</p> <p>(Sec. 3103) Reduces FY2019-FY2022 for the Prevention and Public Health Fund.</p> <p>TITLE II--CHILDREN'S HEALTH INSURANCE PROGRAM (CHIP)</p> <p>(Sec. 3201) Amends title XXI (Children's Health Insurance Program [CHIP]) of the Social Security Act to extend funding for CHIP through the first half of FY2018.</p> <p> Establishes a special rule, with respect to the first half of FY2018, for the redistribution of unused CHIP allotments to state child health plans experiencing emergency shortfalls. Requires the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), on a monthly basis, to redistribute unused allotments to each state in an amount that will eliminate the state's emergency shortfall before the CMS may distribute the allotments to any state that is experiencing a nonemergency shortfall. Requires the CMS to redistribute such allotments in the order in which states realize monthly emergency shortfalls, but only to the extent that amounts are available for redistribution.</p> <p> DIVISION D--OTHER MATTERS </p> <p>(Sec. 4001) Provides $2.1 billion in mandatory funding for the Veterans Choice Program, which allows veterans to receive health care from providers outside of the Department of Veterans Affairs facilities. </p> <p>DIVISION E--BUDGETARY EFFECTS </p> <p>(Sec. 5001) Exempts the budgetary effects of division C and each succeeding division of this bill from Pay-As-You-Go (PAYGO) rules and certain budget scorekeeping guidelines. </p> <p>(Sec. 5002) Exempts the budgetary effects of specified reconciliation legislation from PAYGO rules. (This provision applies to the tax legislation that was signed into law on December 22, 2017, and was considered pursuant to the reconciliation instructions included in the FY2018 congressional budget resolution.) </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1370v35" currentChamber="SENATE" update-date="2018-02-20">
<action-date>2017-11-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed Senate amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign Authorization Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize in the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) a program to be known as the Blue Campaign, the purpose of which shall be to unify and coordinate DHS efforts to address human trafficking.</p> <p>The campaign director shall issue DHS-wide guidance to and develop training programs for appropriate DHS personnel, coordinate departmental efforts, and provide guidance and training on trauma-informed practices to ensure that human trafficking victims are afforded prompt access to victim support service providers and government assistance to address their immediate and long-term needs.</p> <p>Such campaign shall provide guidance and training to DHS personnel and other federal, state, tribal, and law enforcement personnel regarding:</p> <ul> <li>programs to help identify instances of human trafficking;</li> <li>the types of information that should be collected and recorded in DHS information technology systems to identify individuals suspected or convicted of human trafficking; </li> <li>systematic and routine information sharing within DHS and among federal, state, tribal, and local law enforcement agencies regarding such individuals and patterns and practices of human trafficking; </li> <li>techniques to identify suspected victims of trafficking along the U.S. border and at airport security checkpoints; </li> <li>methods to be used by the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) and personnel from other appropriate agencies to train TSA employees to identify suspected trafficking victims and to serve as a liaison and resource regarding human trafficking prevention to appropriate state, local, and private sector aviation workers and the traveling public; </li> <li>utilizing resources to educate partners and stakeholders and increase public awareness of human trafficking; and </li> <li>leveraging partnerships with state and local governmental, non-governmental, and private sector organizations to raise public awareness of human trafficking. </li> </ul>  <p>(Sec. 3) DHS shall ensure the integration of DHS information technology systems used to record and track information regarding individuals suspected or convicted of human trafficking.</p> <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1370v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-20">
<action-date>2017-05-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign Authorization Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize in the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) a unified, anti-human trafficking campaign to be known as the Blue Campaign, under which the Secretary of DHS shall issue DHS-wide guidance to, and develop and coordinate training for, appropriate DHS personnel regarding:</p> <ul> <li>programs to help identify instances of human trafficking and potential connections to terrorist activities, including along the U.S. borders; </li> <li>systematic and routine information sharing among DHS components and the National Network of Fusion Centers regarding individuals suspected or convicted of human trafficking, patterns and practices of human trafficking, and potential connections to terrorist activities; </li> <li>techniques to identify suspected victims of trafficking along the U.S. borders; </li> <li>techniques specifically for Transportation Security Administration personnel to identify suspected trafficking victims at airport security and to serve as a liaison and resource to aviation workers and the traveling public; </li> <li>utilizing resources to educate partners and stakeholders and increase public awareness of human trafficking; and </li> <li>leveraging partnerships with governmental, non-governmental, and private sector organizations at the state and local levels to raise public awareness of human trafficking and potential connections to terrorist activities. </li></ul> <p>DHS shall: (1) ensure that information technology systems utilized within DHS to record and track information regarding individuals suspected or convicted of human trafficking are capable of systematic and routine information sharing, and (2) report to Congress on the status and effectiveness of the campaign.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1370v18" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-20">
<action-date>2017-05-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House amended, Part I</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign Authorization Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize in the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) a Blue Campaign, under which the Secretary of DHS shall issue DHS-wide guidance to, and develop and coordinate training for, appropriate DHS personnel regarding:</p> <ul> <li>programs to help identify instances of human trafficking and potential connections to terrorist activities, including along the U.S. borders; </li> <li>systematic and routine information sharing among DHS components and the National Network of Fusion Centers regarding individuals suspected or convicted of human trafficking, patterns and practices of human trafficking, and potential connections to terrorist activities; </li> <li>techniques to identify suspected victims of trafficking along the U.S. borders; </li> <li>techniques specifically for Transportation Security Administration personnel to identify suspected trafficking victims at airport security and to serve as a liaison and resource to aviation workers and the traveling public; </li> <li>utilizing resources to educate partners and stakeholders and increase public awareness of human trafficking; and </li> <li>leveraging partnerships with governmental, non-governmental, and private sector organizations at the state and local levels to raise public awareness of human trafficking and potential connections to terrorist activities. </li></ul> <p>DHS shall: (1) ensure the integration of information technology systems utilized within DHS to record and track information regarding individuals suspected or convicted of human trafficking, and (2) report to Congress on the status and effectiveness of the campaign.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1370v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-19">
<action-date>2017-03-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign Authorization Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), as part of DHS's Blue Campaign, to issue DHS-wide guidance to, and develop training programs for, appropriate DHS personnel regarding:</p> <ul> <li>types of information that should be collected and recorded in information technology systems utilized by DHS to help identify individuals suspected or convicted of human trafficking,</li> <li>systematic and routine information sharing regarding such individuals among DHS components,</li> <li>techniques to identify suspected victims of trafficking along the U.S. border,</li> <li>techniques specifically for Transportation Security Administration personnel to identify suspected trafficking victims at airport security and to serve as a liaison and resource to aviation workers and the traveling public, and</li> <li>utilizing resources to educate partners and stakeholders and increase public awareness of human trafficking.</li> </ul> <p>DHS shall: (1) ensure the integration of information technology systems utilized within DHS to record and track information regarding individuals suspected or convicted of human trafficking, and (2) report to Congress on the status and effectiveness of the Blue Campaign.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
