<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4176" measure-id="id115hr4176" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-31" update-date="2018-03-29">
<title>Air Cargo Security Improvement Act of 2018</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4176v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-29">
<action-date>2018-03-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<tr><td> <p><b>Air Cargo Security Improvement Act of 2018 </b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to: (1) establish an air cargo security division, (2) submit to Congress a feasibility study regarding the use of computed tomography technology for the screening of air cargo transported on passenger aircraft operated by air carrier or foreign air carrier in air transportation, interstate air transportation, or interstate air commerce; (3) initiate a two-year pilot program to achieve enhanced air cargo security screening outcomes through the use of new or emerging screening technologies, such as computed tomography technology; and (4) report to Congress on actions to improve the Certified Cargo Screening Program. </p> <p>(Sec. 5) The Government Accountability Office must review the TSA's screening processes and procedures for air cargo entering the United States and assess its risk-based strategy for examining such cargo.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) The TSA must request the Air Cargo Subcommittee of the Aviation Security Advisory Committee to conduct a comprehensive review and security assessment of the known shipper program and recommend whether the program should be modified or eliminated in light of the full implementation of required 100% screening of air cargo carried on passenger aircraft.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4176v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-19">
<action-date>2017-10-31</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Air Cargo Security&nbsp;Improvement Act of 2017</strong></p> <p><strong></strong>This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA)&nbsp;to: (1) establish an air cargo security office, (2) conduct a pilot program to test the use of screening equipment using computed tomography technology, (3) report to Congress on actions to improve the Certified Cargo Screening Program, (4) develop standards for the use of third-party explosives detection canines for the primary screening of air cargo, and&nbsp; (5) request a review and assessment of the known shipper program. </p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must review the TSA's screening processes and procedures for&nbsp;examining&nbsp;air cargo entering the United States and assess its risk-based strategy for examining such cargo. </p> <p>The bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide statutory authority for the air cargo advance screening program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
