<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4660" measure-id="id115hr4660" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-12-14" update-date="2018-02-27">
<title>Prenatal Nondiscrimination Act (PRENDA) of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4660v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-27">
<action-date>2017-12-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Prenatal Nondiscrimination Act (PRENDA) of</strong> <b>2017</b></p> <p>This bill imposes criminal penalties on anyone who knowingly or knowingly attempts to: (1) perform an abortion knowing that the abortion is sought based on the sex or gender of the child, (2) use force or the threat of force to coerce a sex-selection abortion, (3) solicit or accept funds for the performance of such an abortion, or (4) transport a woman into the United States or across a state line for the purpose of obtaining such an abortion.</p> The bill authorizes civil actions by: (1) fathers, or maternal grandparents if the mother is an unemancipated minor, of unborn children who are the subject of a prohibited sex-selection abortion; or (2) women upon whom an abortion has been performed or attempted with a knowing or attempted use of force or threat of force to coerce a sex-selection abortion. <p>The bill also authorizes injunctive relief to prevent an abortion provider from performing or attempting further such abortions.</p> <p>Violations of this bill are deemed to be prohibited discrimination under title VI (Federally Assisted Programs) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964.</p> <p>Medical and mental health professionals must report known or suspected violations to law enforcement authorities.</p> <p>A woman having such an abortion may not be prosecuted or held civilly liable.</p> <p>Courts must make such orders as necessary to protect the anonymity of any woman upon whom an abortion has been performed or attempted if she does not give her written consent to such disclosure. In the absence of such consent, any party, other than a public official, who brings an action must use a pseudonym.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
