<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="766" measure-id="id115hr766" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-31" update-date="2017-08-09">
<title>To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a pilot program to expand telehealth options under the Medicare program for individuals residing in public housing located in health professional shortage areas, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr766v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-09">
<action-date>2017-01-31</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to establish a five-year pilot program to expand Medicare coverage of telehealth services for enrollees who reside in public housing. Specifically, the program shall provide for Medicare coverage with respect to "store-and-forward technologies" (i.e., the electronic transmission of medical information, such as digital images), which are covered as telehealth services&nbsp;under current law only&nbsp;with respect to&nbsp;demonstration programs conducted in Alaska and Hawaii. In addition, the program shall provide for increased flexibility with respect to geographic and&nbsp;other requirements.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
