<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2594" measure-id="id115hr2594" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-23" update-date="2017-12-18">
<title>Small Business Payment for Performance Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2594v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-18">
<action-date>2017-05-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Small Business Payment for Performance Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Small Business Act to allow a small business performing a construction contract awarded by a federal agency to submit a request for an equitable adjustment to the agency's contracting officer if such officer directs a change in the terms of the contract performance without the agreement of the small business.</p> <p>The agency must provide to the small business an interim partial payment of at least 50% of the estimated amount required to cover additional costs resulting from such change. Such small business shall pay to a first tier subcontractor or supplier the portion of such payment that is attributable to the increased costs of performance incurred by such subcontractor or supplier due to such change.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
