<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3325" measure-id="id115hr3325" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-20" update-date="2018-02-09">
<title>ACE Kids Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3325v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-09">
<action-date>2017-07-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Advancing Care for Exceptional Kids Act or the ACE Kids Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to establish a state Medicaid option to provide for medical assistance with respect to coordinated care provided through a health home (i.e., a designated provider or team of health-care professionals) for children with&nbsp;medically complex&nbsp;conditions. A state shall make payments for such health-home services regardless of whether they are provided through a fee-for-service or managed-care system. For an initial period of&nbsp;eight fiscal-year quarters, the federal matching rate applicable to such payments shall be increased by 20 percentage points, not to exceed 90%. </p> <p>A state that exercises this option shall specify its methodology for determining payment and evaluating quality of care, in accordance with requirements established by the bill. In addition,&nbsp;the state must meet specified requirements regarding hospital referrals, out-of-state providers, education and outreach, data collection, and reporting.</p> <p>The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services&nbsp;must issue guidance on best practices for using out-of-state providers to provide care to children with medically complex conditions.</p> <p>The Medicaid and Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP) Payment and Access Commission must report to Congress and to the Department of Health and Human Services on specified matters related to children with medically complex conditions.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
