<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="5099" measure-id="id115hr5099" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2018-02-27" update-date="2018-04-05">
<title>Enhancing DHS' Fusion Center Technical Assistance Program Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr5099v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-04-05">
<action-date>2018-02-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Enhancing DHS' Fusion Center Technical Assistance Program Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish a fusion center technical assistance program.</p> <p>DHS, in carrying out the program, shall: (1) provide technical assistance to fusion centers regarding grants administered under the Urban Areas Security Initiative and the Homeland Security Grant Program, terrorism prevention activities, and intelligence and information sharing; (2) provide to fusion centers notice of any changes to such activities; and (3) make available best practices regarding fusion center operations, information sharing and analysis of homeland security threats, and protecting privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties.</p> <ul> </ul> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
