<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2689" measure-id="id115hr2689" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-25" update-date="2017-07-07">
<title>RESPECT Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2689v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-07">
<action-date>2017-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Requirements, Expectations, and Standard Procedures for Executive Consultation with Tribes Act or the RESPECT Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires federal agencies to have a process to ensure meaningful and timely input by Native American tribes before undertaking an activity that may have substantial direct impacts on the lands or interests of the tribes, on the relationship between the federal government and the tribes, or on the distribution of power and responsibilities between the government and the tribes. Agencies may temporarily waive these requirements in an emergency. </p> <p>Federal agencies must: (1) recognize and respect tribal self-government and sovereignty, honor tribal rights, and strive to meet the responsibilities that arise from the unique legal relationship between the federal government and tribal governments; (2) grant tribal governments maximum discretion in the administration of federal statutes and regulations; (3) streamline the processes under which tribes apply for waivers of statutory and regulatory requirements; and (4) consider waiver applications with a view toward increasing opportunities for flexible policy approaches.</p> <p>Tribes may seek judicial review of a determination of an agency under this bill if the tribe has exhausted all other administrative remedies.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
