<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2777" measure-id="id115hr2777" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-06" update-date="2018-02-26">
<title>Give Veterans Home Loan Choices Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2777v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-26">
<action-date>2017-06-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Give Veterans Home Loan Choices A</strong>ct <strong>of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the National Housing Act to require that a Federal Housing Administration mortgage notice for a prospective borrower who is a veteran include, in addition to comparative rate and fee information about conventional loans, similar comparative information about Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) home loans.</p> <p>The Federal Housing Finance Agency shall direct the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) to revise the uniform residential loan application by December 31, 2018, to include: (1) a check box to indicate that the applicant is a veteran; (2) the statement &quot;If you are a veteran, you may be eligible for a VA mortgage&quot;; and (3) a blank line for the borrower to initial and a statement that all applicants must initial the line to confirm that they have read the VA mortgage eligibility statement.</p> <p>The bill requires pre-separation counseling for a member of the Armed Forces who is separating from active duty to include: </p> <ul> <li>information on the availability of VA home loan services and housing assistance benefits, including the authority of a member to use an honorable discharge certificate as a certificate of eligibility for a VA guaranteed housing loan or to request a specific certificate of eligibility for such loan; and </li> <li>counseling on responsible borrowing practices.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
