<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4433" measure-id="id115hr4433" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-11-16" update-date="2018-01-09">
<title>Securing DHS Firearms Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4433v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-09">
<action-date>2017-11-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Securing Department of Homeland Security Firearms Act of 2017 or the Securing DHS Firearms Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill makes the Under Secretary for Management of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) responsible for the security of DHS firearms and other sensitive assets.</p> <p>The Under Secretary shall disseminate a directive for achieving adequate security over such assets across DHS, which shall include: (1) descriptions of what equipment is classified as a sensitive asset, (2) requirements for securing such assets, (3) a classification system for all categories of DHS-issued badges and corresponding requirements for safeguarding such assets, and (4) reporting and record keeping requirements for lost assets. The Under Secretary shall update such directive within one year, including by adding a requirement relating to recording in the inventory systems maintained by each DHS component the acceptance or transfer of a sensitive asset. </p> <p>The Under Secretary shall disseminate a revised version of the Personal Property Asset Management Program Manual that includes: (1) procedures to safeguard sensitive assets during on- and off-duty time, (2) training on safeguarding such assets, (3) instructions for recording lost sensitive assets, and (4) a requirement that a file on a lost asset contain the DHS report and the corresponding police report.</p> <p>DHS components must:</p> <ul> <li>comply with federal law, executive branch guidance, and DHS policy regarding the management and oversight of securing sensitive assets; </li> <li>review the need for non-law enforcement badges; </li> <li>require personnel to comply with requirements for safeguarding sensitive assets and reporting on lost assets; and </li> <li>require that lost assets are reported to local law enforcement, the National Crime Information Center, and DHS headquarters and recorded in inventory systems in the time frame established by such directive. </li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
