<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="919" measure-id="id115hr919" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-07" update-date="2017-03-28">
<title>Portable Fuel Container Safety Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr919v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-03-28">
<action-date>2017-02-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Portable Fuel Container Safety Act of</b> <b>2017</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to promulgate a final rule for flame mitigation devices in portable flammable liquid fuel containers that impede the propagation of flame into the container, unless the CPSC publishes a determination that a voluntary standard developed by a standard development organization meets the intent of this bill. </p> <p>Either the promulgated standard or the voluntary standard shall be treated as a consumer product safety rule. </p> <p>If a standard development organization subsequently revises a voluntary standard, the organization must notify the CPSC and the revision becomes enforceable unless, within 90 days after receiving notice, the CPSC determines that the revised standard does not meet this bill's requirements. </p> <p>The CPSC must undertake a campaign to educate consumers about dangers associated with portable fuel containers near an open flame or other source of ignition. </p> <p>The bill amends the Children's Gasoline Burn Prevention Act to extend child-resistance requirements for closures on portable gasoline containers to receptacles for gasoline, kerosene, or diesel fuel (including any spout, retrofit spout, cap, and other closure mechanism and component) produced or distributed for sale to, or use by, consumers for transport of, or for refueling of internal combustion engines with, gasoline, kerosene, or diesel fuel. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
