<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2296" measure-id="id115hr2296" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-02" update-date="2017-10-12">
<title>Advancing CCUS Technology Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2296v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-12">
<action-date>2017-05-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Advancing CCUS Technology Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to direct the Department of Energy (DOE)to carry out research and developtechnologyto improve the conversion, use, and storage of carbon dioxide from fossil fuels. It also revises the program of research and commercial application for coal and power systems to require DOE, during each fiscal year after FY2017, to identify cost and performance goals for technologies allowing large-scale demonstration and the continued cost-competitive commercial use of coal.</p> <p>DOEmust annually evaluateand make recommendations regarding any project it has entered into with a public or privateentityto developcarbon capture, utilization, and sequestration technologies.</p> <p>DOE must report to Congress, within two years and every three years thereafter, regarding theprojectevaluations it has conductedand the progress it has made in advancing carbon capture, utilization, and sequestration technologies.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
