<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1720" measure-id="id115hr1720" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-24" update-date="2017-06-26">
<title>LOSAP CAP Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1720v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-26">
<action-date>2017-03-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Length of Service Award Program Cap Adjustment Priority Act or the LOSAP CAP Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to deferred compensation plans, to increase the limit on accruals that is required for length of service award plans (LOSAPs) for bona fide volunteers to be exempt from treatment as a deferred compensation plan. </p> <p>(Under current law, plans paying solely length of service awards to bona fide volunteers or their beneficiaries on the account of firefighting and prevention services, emergency medical services, and ambulance services performed by the volunteers are not treated as deferred compensation plans if they meet certain requirements. One of the requirements is a limit on the aggregate amount of length of service awards that may accrue with respect to any year of service for any bona fide volunteer.) </p> <p>The bill modifies the limit on accruals to: (1) increase the limit from $3,000 to $6,000; (2) provide for a cost-of-living adjustment to the limit after 2017; and (3) specify that, in the case of LOSAPs that are defined benefit plans, the limit applies to the actuarial present value of the aggregate amount of length of service awards accruing with respect to any year of service. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
