<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1958" measure-id="id115hr1958" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-05" update-date="2018-02-08">
<title>PACE Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1958v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-08">
<action-date>2017-04-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Protecting Americans from Credit Entanglements Act of 2017 or the PACE Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Truth in Lending Act to extend that Act's requirements to real property retrofit loans. A "real property retrofit loan" is a loan that is: (1) secured by an interest in real property; (2) repayable in installment payments made concurrently with the payment of property taxes on the real property; and (3) used to finance real property retrofits, including energy-efficiency upgrades, renewable-energy installations, seismic retrofits, water-conservation upgrades, and other similar improvements.</p> <p>At the time of application for a real property retrofit loan, the creditor must disclose that the loan will result in a lien on the real property securing the loan.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
