<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="428" measure-id="id115hr428" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-10" update-date="2017-03-29">
<title>Red River Gradient Boundary Survey Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr428v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-03-29">
<action-date>2017-02-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Red River Gradient Boundary Survey Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill directs the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) to commission a survey to identify the South Bank boundary line with respect to land along a specified 116-mile stretch of the Red River in Oklahoma and Texas (the affected area). </p> <p>The survey shall:</p> <ul> <li>adhere to the gradient boundary survey method;</li> <li>span the length of the affected area;</li> <li>be conducted by surveyors who are licensed and qualified to conduct official gradient boundary surveys, and selected by and operating under the direction of the Texas General Land Office and the Oklahoma Commissioners of the Land Office (the offices); and</li> <li>be completed within two years of enactment of this bill. </li> </ul> <p>The BLM shall submit the survey to the offices for approval. The offices shall determine whether to approve the survey within 60 days after receiving it. </p> <p>Surveys of individual parcels in the affected area shall be conducted according to the requirements for the survey of the South Bank boundary line. A parcel survey also shall be approved or disapproved by the offices within 60 days of receipt.</p> <p>Neither the South Bank boundary survey nor any parcel survey shall be submitted to the BLM for approval. </p> <p>After a survey for an individual parcel has been approved, the offices shall submit to the BLM:</p> <ul> <li> a notice of the approval of such survey; and </li> <li>a copy of such survey and any field notes related to the parcel. </li> </ul> <p>After receiving a notice of the approval of a survey related to an individual parcel, the BLM shall provide to each landowner of land adjacent to that parcel:</p> <ul> <li> such notice; and</li> <li> a copy of such survey and any field notes related to the parcel. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr428v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-02-01">
<action-date>2017-01-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Red River Gradient Boundary Survey Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) to commission a survey to identify the South Bank boundary line with respect to land along a specified 116-mile stretch of the Red River in Oklahoma and Texas (the affected area). </p> <p>The survey shall:</p> <ul> <li>adhere to the gradient boundary survey method;</li> <li>span the length of the affected area;</li> <li>be conducted by surveyors who are licensed and qualified to conduct official gradient boundary surveys, and selected by and operating under the direction of the Texas General Land Office and the Oklahoma Commissioners of the Land Office (the offices); and</li> <li>be completed within two years of enactment of this bill. </li> </ul> <p>The BLM shall submit the survey to the offices for approval and, within 60 days of receiving it, they shall determine whether to approve it. </p> <p>Surveys of individual parcels in the affected area shall be conducted according to the requirements for the survey of the South Bank boundary line. A survey of such a parcel shall be approved or disapproved by the offices within 60 days of receipt.</p> <p>The survey for identifying the South Bank boundary line and any survey of an individual parcel shall not be submitted to the BLM for approval. </p> <p>After a survey for an individual parcel has been approved, the offices shall submit to the BLM:</p> <ul> <li> a notice of the approval of such survey, and </li> <li>a copy of such survey and any field notes related to the parcel. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
