<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2087" measure-id="id115hr2087" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-12" update-date="2017-11-06">
<title>DAIRY Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2087v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-06">
<action-date>2017-04-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Defending the Agricultural Industry's Requirements Year-round Act of 2017 or the DAIRY Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to include in the H-2A nonimmigrant visa category (temporary agricultural workers) an alien coming temporarily to the United States to perform agricultural labor or services as a dairy worker.</p> <p>The initial period of admission for such dairy workers shall be 18 months, which may be extended for additional 18-month periods. No period of absence from the United States shall be required for such extensions.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
