<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="612" measure-id="id115hr612" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-23" update-date="2017-03-15">
<title>United States-Israel Cybersecurity Cooperation Enhancement Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr612v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-03-15">
<action-date>2017-01-31</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>United States-Israel Cybersecurity Cooperation Enhancement Act of 2017&nbsp;</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish a grant program to support cybersecurity research and development, and the demonstration and commercialization of cybersecurity technology, in accordance with the Agreement between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the State of Israel on Cooperation in Science and Technology for Homeland Security Matters, dated May 29, 2008, or a successor agreement. </p> <p>Grants may be awarded for social science research and technology intended to identify, protect against, respond to, and recover from cybersecurity threats.</p> <p>To be eligible for a grant, a project must be a joint venture between: (1) for-profit, nonprofit, or academic entities (including U.S. national laboratories) in the United States and Israel; or (2) the governments of the United States and Israel. </p> <p>Grants shall be awarded only for projects considered unclassified by both the United States and Israel.</p> <p>DHS must require cost sharing of at least 50% from nonfederal sources for grant activities, but it may reduce the nonfederal percentage if necessary on a case-by-case basis. </p> <p>DHS must establish an advisory board to monitor the impartial scientific and technical merit method by which grants are awarded and provide periodic reviews of the actions taken to carry out the program.</p> <p>The grant program terminates seven years after this bill's enactment. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr612v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-02-02">
<action-date>2017-01-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>United States-Israel Cybersecurity Cooperation Enhancement Act of 2017&nbsp;</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish a grant program to support cybersecurity research and development, and the demonstration and commercialization of cybersecurity technology, in accordance with the Agreement between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the State of Israel on Cooperation in Science and Technology for Homeland Security Matters, dated May 29, 2008, or a successor agreement. </p> <p>Grants may be awarded for social science research and technology intended to identify, protect against, respond to, and recover from cybersecurity threats.</p> <p>To be eligible for a grant, a project must be a joint venture between: (1) for-profit, nonprofit, or academic entities (including U.S. national laboratories) in the United States and Israel; or (2) the governments of the United States and Israel. </p> <p>Grants shall be awarded only for projects considered unclassified by both the United States and Israel.</p> <p>DHS must require cost sharing of at least 50% from nonfederal sources for grant activities, but it may reduce the nonfederal percentage if necessary on a case-by-case basis. </p> <p>DHS must establish an advisory board to monitor the impartial scientific and technical merit method by which grants are awarded and provide periodic reviews of the actions taken to carry out the program.</p> <p>The grant program terminates seven years after this bill's enactment. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
