<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3326" measure-id="id115hr3326" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-20" update-date="2018-01-30">
<title>World Bank Accountability Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3326v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-30">
<action-date>2017-07-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>World Bank Accountability Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill provides that for each of FY2018-FY2023, 15% of appropriations for the World Bank's International Development Association shall be withheld and not disbursed until the Department of the Treasury reports to Congress that the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development: (1) is implementing institutional incentives that prioritize poverty reduction, development outcomes, and capable project management over the Bank's lending and grant making volume; (2) is taking, or has completed, steps to address the management failures from the Uganda Transport Sector Development Project; and (3) is strengthening its trust fund management in order to increase accountability for poverty reduction and development outcomes. </p> <p>An additional 15% of appropriations for such fiscal years shall be withheld and not disbursed until Treasury reports that the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development: (1) is emphasizing its support for secure property rights, due process of law, and economic freedom as essential to sustained poverty reduction in World Bank borrowing countries; (2) has not approved any loans or grants to a country designated by the U.S. as a state sponsor of terrorism and is strengthening the ability of Bank-funded projects to undermine violent extremism; (3) is taking steps to conduct randomized forensic audits of projects receiving Bank assistance; and (4) is working to detect and minimize corruption in projects involving development policy lending. </p> <p>Such conditions will be considered to have been satisfied for a fiscal year if they have been satisfied for the preceding three fiscal years.</p> <p>The bill amends the International Development Association Act to authorize the Governor of the International Development Association to contribute a specified amount on behalf of the United States to the 18th replenishment of the association's resources.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
