<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="649" measure-id="id115hr649" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-24" update-date="2017-02-02">
<title>Protection of Military Airfields from Wind Turbine Encroachment Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr649v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-02-02">
<action-date>2017-01-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protection of Military Airfields from Wind Turbine Encroachment Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to make new wind facilities located near certain military installations ineligible for the tax credits for: (1) electricity produced from renewable resources, and (2) investments in qualified small wind energy property. </p> <p>The bill applies to facilities that are originally placed in service after the enactment of this bill and are located within a 50-mile radius of: (1) an airfield or airbase that is under the jurisdiction of a military department and in active use; or (2) an air traffic control radar site, weather radar site, or aircraft navigation aid that is owned or operated by the Department of Defense and is a permanent land-based structure at a fixed location. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
