<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2898" measure-id="id115hr2898" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-13" update-date="2018-03-09">
<title>RAC Reform Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2898v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-09">
<action-date>2017-06-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>RAC Reform Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000 to change the official who shall establish, maintain, and appoint the members of resource advisory committees from: (1) the Secretary of Agriculture to the the applicable Regional Forester for land within the National Forest System; and (2) the Secretary of the Interior to the applicable Bureau of Land Management State Director for such portions of the revested Oregon and California Railroad and reconveyed Coos Bay Wagon Road grant land under the jurisdiction of the Department of the Interior classified as timberlands and power-site land valuable for timber that shall be managed for permanent forest production.</p> <p> Any year of a member's service on such a committee, the majority of which was served during a fiscal year in which the committee's budget was less than $1 million, shall not count as a year of such member's term for purposes of the four-year term limit. </p> <p>The bill reduces the number of members of each committee, as well as the number representing each specified community interest category. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
