<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2683" measure-id="id115hr2683" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-25" update-date="2017-10-18">
<title>Protecting Veterans Credit Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2683v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-18">
<action-date>2017-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protecting Veterans Credit Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to exclude from consumer report information: (1) a veteran's medical debt if the hospital care or medical services relating to the debt antedates the credit report by less than one year; and (2) a fully paid or settled veteran's medical debt that had been characterized as delinquent, charged off, or in collection.</p> <p>The bill defines a &quot;veteran's medical debt&quot; as debt from health care provided in a non-Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) facility under the laws administered by the VA, including medical debt that the VA has wrongfully charged a veteran.</p> <p>A dispute process for veterans medical debt is established whereby: </p> <ul> <li>a veteran may submit a notice along with proof of VA liability for the debt or documentation that the VA is in the process of paying for authorized medical services to a consumer reporting agency or a reseller in order to dispute such debt's inclusion in the consumer report; </li> <li>the VA shall submit to a veteran a notice it has assumed liability for part or all of the veteran's medical debt; and </li> <li>if such notice and proof of liability or documentation is received, the consumer reporting agency shall delete all information relating to the veteran's medical debt from the file of the consumer and notify the furnisher and the consumer of such deletion.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
