<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1653" measure-id="id115hr1653" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-21" update-date="2017-05-03">
<title>Drinking Water Affordability Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1653v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-03">
<action-date>2017-03-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Drinking Water Affordability Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to revise requirements concerning national primary drinking water regulations, including by:</p> <ul> <li>removing a requirement that the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) maintain, or provide greater, protection of human health when revising those regulations;</li> <li>extending the repayment schedule for loans from the drinking water state revolving funds (SRFs); </li> <li>authorizing states to protect public drinking water source areas;</li> <li>removing federal reporting requirements if state or local requirements are not less stringent than federal requirements; and </li> <li>requiring the EPA to conduct a review on best practices for streamlining the application process for public water systems to receive loans or loan guarantees from an SRF as well as best practices for administering SRFs efficiently.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
