<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3542" measure-id="id115hr3542" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-28" update-date="2017-09-21">
<title>Hamas Human Shields Prevention Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3542v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-21">
<action-date>2017-07-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Hamas Human Shields Prevention Act</b></p> <p>This bill states that it is U.S. policy to: (1) condemn the use of human shields by Hamas as an act of terrorism and a violation of human rights and international humanitarian law, and (2) act against those engaging in or supporting the use of human shields. </p> <p>The President is urged to direct the U.S. Permanent Representative to the United Nations (U.N.) to use U.S. influence at the U.N. Security Council to secure support for a resolution imposing multilateral sanctions against Hamas's use of human shields. </p> <p>The President shall prohibit property transactions and U.S. entry with respect to: (1) each foreign person or entity that is a member of or acting on behalf of Hamas and that is responsible for or complicit in Hamas' use of human shields; and (2) each foreign person or entity and each agency or instrumentality of a foreign state that has significantly facilitated any act with respect to such use of human shields, provided material support to a listed person or entity, or attempted to facilitate or support such acts or persons. </p> <p>The President may waive a sanction for 120 days with prior congressional certification that such waiver is vital to U.S. national security interests. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
