<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3986" measure-id="id115hr3986" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-05" update-date="2018-01-24">
<title>Stopping the Iron Pipeline Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3986v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-24">
<action-date>2017-10-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Stopping the Iron Pipeline Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Justice (DOJ) to establish and newly manufactured firearms to meet a national standard for incorporating passive identification capability into all firearms sold in the United States. Passive identification capability means technology that: (1) enables identification by a mobile or fixed reading device, and (2) does not transmit an electronic monitoring or tracking signal. </p> <p>In developing a national standard, DOJ must prioritize certain considerations, including a firearm owner's right to privacy and right to legally own firearms and the ability of law enforcement authorities to use passive identification capability to track lost and stolen guns. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
