<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2471" measure-id="id115hr2471" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-16" update-date="2017-12-13">
<title>Terrorist Release Announcements to Counter Extremist Recidivism Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2471v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-13">
<action-date>2017-09-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Terrorist Release Announcements to Counter Extremist Recidivism Act or the TRACER Act</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), in coordination with the Department of Justice, to share with state, local, and regional fusion centers through the DHS State, Local, and Regional Fusion Center Partnership Initiative, for homeland security purposes, as well as other relevant law enforcement entities, release information from a federal correctional facility, including the name, charging date, and expected place and date of release, of individuals convicted of a federal crime of terrorism.</p> <p>DHS, prior to sharing such information, shall receive input and advice from DHS's Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties, Officer for Privacy, and Chief Intelligence Officer.</p> <p>A fusion center serves as a focal point within the state and local environment for the receipt, analysis, gathering, and sharing of threat-related information between the federal government and state, local, tribal, territorial, and private sector partners.</p> <p> DHS shall coordinate with appropriate federal officials to provide state, local, and regional fusion centers with periodic assessments regarding the overall threat from known or suspected terrorists currently incarcerated in a federal correctional facility. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2471v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-23">
<action-date>2017-05-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Terrorist Release Announcements to Counter Extremist Recidivism Act or the TRACER Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to share with state, local, and regional fusion centers through the DHS State, Local, and Regional Fusion Center Initiative, for homeland security purposes, release information from a federal correctional facility, including the name, charging date, and expected place and date of release, of individuals convicted of a federal crime of terrorism.</p> <p>A fusion center serves as a focal point within the state and local environment for the receipt, analysis, gathering, and sharing of threat-related information between the federal government and state, local, tribal, territorial, and private sector partners.</p> <p> DHS shall coordinate with appropriate federal officials to provide state, local, and regional fusion centers with periodic assessments regarding the overall threat from known or suspected terrorists currently incarcerated in a federal correctional facility. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
