<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1895" measure-id="id115hr1895" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-04" update-date="2017-12-29">
<title>Protecting Life and Integrity in Research Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1895v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-29">
<action-date>2017-04-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Protecting Life and Integrity in Research Act of 2017</strong></p> <p><strong></strong>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to prohibit the use of tissue from an induced abortion for research conducted or supported by the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS).</p> <p>HHS may develop or support new high-efficiency cell lines so long as the cell lines are not derived from tissue from an induced abortion.</p> <p>Soliciting or acquiring a donation of fetal tissue from an induced abortion for a purpose other than autopsy or burial&nbsp;is prohibited.</p> <p>The bill applies requirements on the research of transplantation of fetal tissue for therapeutic purposes to research on fetal tissue.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
