<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2370" measure-id="id115hr2370" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-04" update-date="2017-09-14">
<title>Escambia County Land Conveyance Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2370v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-14">
<action-date>2017-07-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House reported version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Escambia County Land Conveyance Act</b></p> <p> (Sec. 3) This bill authorizes Escambia County, Florida, to convey its interest in any part of the former Santa Rosa Island National Monument land that was conveyed to it by the federal government in 1947 to any person or entity, without restriction. </p> <p>The bill prohibits any person or entity holding a leasehold interest in such land from being required to involuntarily accept a fee interest to such land in place of the leasehold interest. </p> <p> The bill states that all interest of Escambia County in any part of such land that is within the jurisdictional boundaries of Santa Rosa County, Florida, shall be conveyed by Escambia County to such county within two years of the enactment of this bill. </p> <p> Santa Rosa County or any other person to whom such county reconveys such land may reconvey any part of it. </p> <p>Any proceeds from the conveyance of such land by either county (other than the amounts that are paid for the direct and incidental costs associated with the conveyance) shall be considered to be windfall profits that shall revert to the United States. </p> <p> Escambia County must preserve in perpetuity those areas of the monument land conveyed under this bill that, as of this bill's enactment, are dedicated for conservation, preservation, public recreation access, and public parking. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2370v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-05">
<action-date>2017-07-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Escambia County Land Conveyance Act</b></p> <p> (Sec. 3) This bill authorizes Escambia County, Florida, to convey its interest in any part of the former Santa Rosa Island National Monument land that was conveyed to it by the federal government in 1947 to any person or entity, without restriction. </p> <p>The bill prohibits any person or entity holding a leasehold interest in such land from being required to involuntarily accept a fee interest to such land in place of the leasehold interest. </p> <p> The bill states that all interest of Escambia County in any part of such land that is within the jurisdictional boundaries of Santa Rosa County, Florida, shall be conveyed by Escambia County to such county within two years of the enactment of this bill. </p> <p> Santa Rosa County or any other person to whom such county reconveys such land may reconvey any part of it. </p> <p>Any proceeds from the conveyance of such land by either county (other than the amounts that are paid for the direct and incidental costs associated with the conveyance) shall be considered to be windfall profits that shall revert to the United States. </p> <p> Escambia County must preserve in perpetuity those areas of the monument land conveyed under this bill that, as of this bill's enactment, are dedicated for conservation, preservation, public recreation access, and public parking. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2370v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-21">
<action-date>2017-05-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Escambia County Land Conveyance Act</b></p> <p> This bill authorizes Escambia County, Florida, to convey its interest in any part of the former Santa Rosa Island National Monument land that was conveyed to it by the federal government in 1947 to any person or entity, without restriction. </p> <p>The bill prohibits any person or entity holding a leasehold interest in such land from being required to involuntarily accept a fee interest to such land in place of the leasehold interest. </p> <p> The bill conditions such conveyance on requirements that: (1) all interest of Escambia County in any part of such land that is within the jurisdictional boundaries of Santa Rosa County, Florida, must be conveyed to Santa Rosa County within two years of the enactment of this bill; and (2) Escambia County must preserve in perpetuity the areas of the conveyed monument land that, as of this bill's enactment, are dedicated for conservation, preservation, public recreation access, and public parking. Santa Rosa County shall assume ownership of the non-federal land conveyed to it free of such restrictions.</p> <p> Santa Rosa County or any other person to whom such county reconveys such land may reconvey any part of it. Any proceeds from the conveyance of such land by either county shall be considered to be windfall profits that shall revert to the United States. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
