<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1609" measure-id="id115hr1609" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-17" update-date="2017-05-03">
<title>Department of Defense Cyber Scholarship Program Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1609v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-03">
<action-date>2017-03-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Department of Defense Cyber Scholarship Program Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill designates the existing Department of Defense (DOD) information assurance scholarship and grant program as the Department of Defense Cyber Scholarship Program to provide financial assistance (with consideration given to whether the recipient is, or the pursuit of the degree is at, a Center of Academic Excellence in Information Assurance Education designated by the National Security Agency) to: (1) persons pursuing information assurance degrees or certifications at institutions of higher education in exchange for an agreement to serve on active duty in the armed forces or as a DOD employee for a designated period; and (2) institutions of higher education to support development of faculty, curriculum, laboratories, and research for information assurance disciplines.</p> <p>Not less than 5% of the amounts available for scholarship financial assistance must be available for the pursuit of associate degrees. </p> <p>DOD must submit a plan for reinvigorating the program. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
