<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2040" measure-id="id115hr2040" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2017-11-28">
<title>Defense Spending Accountability Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2040v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-28">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Defense Spending Accountability Act</b></p> <p>This bill imposes on the Deputy Secretary of Defense (Chief Management Officer of the Department of Defense [DOD]), the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller), and the Chief Management Officer of each of the military departments: (1) a 5% pay cut if certain financial statements are not validated as ready for audit by September 30, 2017, and (2) a 10% pay cut if such statements for FY2018 are not ready for audit by March 31, 2019.</p> <p>The bill prescribes the following due process protections for such officials: (1) notice and opportunity to respond, and (2) appeal rights.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
