<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3925" measure-id="id115hr3925" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-03" update-date="2018-03-13">
<title>Patriot Employer Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3925v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-13">
<action-date>2017-10-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Patriot Employer Act</strong> <b>of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a Patriot employer a business-related tax credit equal to 10% of up to $15,000 of wages paid to any employee in a taxable year. </p> <p>The bill sets forth criteria for designation as a Patriot employer, including requirements that such employer: (1) maintains its headquarters in the United States and does not expatriate to avoid payment of U.S. income taxes, (2) complies with the employer mandate to provide minimum essential health care coverage to its employees under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, (3) provides employees with paid sick leave or paid family and medical leave, (4) compensates at least 90% of its employees at an hourly rate that is at least 218% of the federal poverty level for an individual for the calendar year divided by 1,750 and provides at least 90% of its employees with a basic level of retirement benefits, (5) provides for differential wage payments to its employees who are members of the Uniformed Services, (6) has a written policy in place for the recruitment of employees who have served in the Uniformed Services or who are disabled, and (7) increases the number of its employees performing substantially all of their services inside the United States to offset the number of employees who work outside the United States. </p> <p>The bill also sets forth a rule for the deferral of the tax deduction for foreign-related interest expense.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
