<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1999" measure-id="id115hr1999" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2017-05-01">
<title>Federal Budget Accountability Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1999v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-01">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Federal Budget Accountability Act </b></p> <p>This bill requires the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to report annually to Congress on the effect of provisions of legislation for the previous congressional session that were enacted to offset or pay for the costs of carrying out the legislation, including provisions that increase revenue, rescind budget authority, or reduce direct spending. </p> <p>The OMB must also establish and report to Congress on a system to track the accuracy of the offsets and pay-fors. (Under the bill, an &quot;offset and pay-for&quot; is an estimate by the Congressional Budget Office for a provision of legislation that reduces spending, increases revenue, or reduces the deficit.) </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
