<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1486" measure-id="id115hr1486" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-09" update-date="2018-03-14">
<title>Securing American Non-Profit Organizations Against Terrorism Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1486v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-14">
<action-date>2018-01-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Securing American Non-Profit Organizations Against Terrorism Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish a Non-Profit Security Grant Program in the Department of Homeland Security, under which the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) shall make grants to tax-exempt, nonprofit organizations determined to be at risk of a terrorist attack, through the state in which such organizations are located, for target hardening and other security enhancements to protect against terrorist attacks.</p> <p>Recipients may use grants for:</p> <ul> <li>target hardening activities, including physical security enhancement equipment and inspection and screening systems; </li> <li>fees for security training relating to physical security and cyber security, target hardening, terrorism awareness, and employee awareness; and </li> <li>any other appropriate activity, including cyber security resilience activities. </li></ul> <p>FEMA shall: (1) make funds provided available for use by a recipient of a grant for a period of not less than 36 months, and (2) report to Congress annually for each of FY2018-FY2022 on the expenditure by each recipient of grant funds made under the Act. Appropriations are authorized for those years to carry out the program, with a specified amount designated for: (1) recipients located in jurisdictions that receive funding under the Urban Area Security Initiative, and (2) recipients located in other jurisdictions.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1486v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-17">
<action-date>2017-03-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Securing American Non-Profit Organizations Against Terrorism Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish a Non-Profit Security Grant Program in the Department of Homeland Security, under which the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) shall make grants to tax-exempt, nonprofit organizations determined to be at risk of a terrorist attack, through the state in which such organizations are located, for target hardening and other security enhancements.</p> <p>A nonprofit organization shall not be ineligible for such a grant solely because it is not located within a jurisdiction receiving funding under the Urban Area Security Initiative.</p> <p>Recipients may use grants for:</p> <ul> <li>the acquisition or installation of certain security equipment, including on their real property, specifically to prevent or protect against the risk of a terrorist attack; and </li> <li>fees for training relating to the protection of critical infrastructure key resources, including for physical security and cybersecurity, target hardening, terrorism awareness, and employee awareness.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
