<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="390" measure-id="id115hr390" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-10" update-date="2017-09-19">
<title>Iraq and Syria Genocide Emergency Relief and Accountability Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr390v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-19">
<action-date>2017-06-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Iraq and Syria Genocide Relief and Accountability Act of 2017</strong></p> <p> (Sec. 4) This bill states that is U.S. policy to ensure that humanitarian, stabilization, and recovery assistance for nationals and residents of Iraq or Syria, and of communities from those countries, is directed toward ethnic and minority individuals and communities with the greatest need, including those individuals and communities that are at risk of persecution or war crimes. </p> <p> (Sec. 5) The Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development may provide assistance, including financial and technical assistance, to support the efforts of entities, including nongovernmental organizations with expertise in international criminal investigations and law, to address crimes of genocide, crimes against humanity, or war crimes in Iraq since January 2014 by: </p> <ul> <li>conducting criminal investigations, </li> <li>developing indigenous investigative and judicial skills to adjudicate cases consistent with due process and respect for the rule of law, and </li> <li>collecting and preserving evidence for use in prosecutions. </li> </ul> <p>The State Department shall encourage foreign governments to identify and prosecute individuals who are suspected of committing such crimes, including members of foreign terrorist organizations operating in Iraq or Syria. </p> <p>(Sec. 6) The State Department shall identify: </p> <ul> <li>threats of persecution, genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes against members of Iraqi or Syrian religious or ethnic groups that are minorities in Iraq or in Syria with respect to whom the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS) has committed such crimes in Iraq or Syria since January 2014 or who are members of other persecuted religious or ethnic groups; </li> <li> persecuted religious and ethnic minority groups in Iraq or Syria that are at risk of forced migration and the primary reasons for such risk;</li> <li>humanitarian, stabilization, and recovery needs of these individuals; and </li> <li> entities, including faith-based entities, that are providing such assistance and the extent of U.S. assistance to or through such entities. </li> </ul> <p> (Sec. 7) The State Department shall provide Congress with: </p> <ul> <li>a description of the efforts taken and proposed to implement this bill; and </li> <li>an assessment of the feasibility and advisability of prosecuting individuals for acts of genocide, crimes against humanity, or war crimes in Iraq since January 2014 or in Syria since March 2011. <p> </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr390v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-09">
<action-date>2017-01-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Iraq and Syria Genocide Relief and Accountability Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of State <o > to provide assistance to entities taking specified criminal and judicial actions against individuals who are suspected of committing genocide, crimes against humanity, or war crimes in Iraq since January 2014 or in Syria since March 2011. </p> <p>The State Department shall encourage foreign governments to identify and prosecute individuals who are suspected of committing such crimes, including members of foreign terrorist organizations operating in Iraq or Syria. </p> <p>The Department of Justice shall review existing criminal statutes concerning genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes to determine: </p> <ul> <li>the extent to which U.S. courts have jurisdiction over such crimes where the perpetrators or victims are U.S. nationals, residents, or persons present in a U.S. territory; </li> <li> current statutes that would apply to such conduct and whether additional statutory authorities are necessary; and </li> <li>the extent to which the absence of criminal statutes defining the crimes or granting jurisdiction impede their prosecution in U.S. courts.</li> </ul> <p>The State Department shall identify: </p> <ul> <li>threats of persecution, genocide, crimes against humanity, and war crimes against members of Iraqi or Syrian religious or ethnic groups that are minorities in Iraq or in Syria with respect to whom the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS) has committed such crimes in Iraq or Syria since January 2014, or who are members of other persecuted religious or ethnic groups; </li> <li>humanitarian, stabilization, and recovery needs of these individuals; and </li> <li>assistance provided by the United States, the U.N., and other entities, including faith-based entities.</li> </ul> <p> Aliens who are, or were, a national and a resident of Iraq or Syria, and who share common characteristics that identify them as targets of persecution on account of membership in a religious or ethnic minority in that country: (1) are deemed to be of special humanitarian concern to the United States; and (2) shall be eligible for priority-2 processing under the refugee resettlement priority system. </p> <p> The Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1990 is amended to extend: (1) refugee set-asides for nationals of the former Soviet Union, Estonia, Latvia, or Lithuania; and (2) the period of eligibility for status adjustment from a parolee who was denied refugee status to a lawfully admitted permanent resident for certain aliens from the former Soviet Union, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Vietnam, Laos, or Cambodia.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
