<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2590" measure-id="id115hr2590" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-22" update-date="2017-06-01">
<title>Computer Science for All Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2590v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-01">
<action-date>2017-05-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Computer Science for All Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill establishes a program through which the Department of Education (ED) shall award grants to states, local educational agencies, and eligible tribal schools to serve as models for national replication of computer education expansion efforts. A grant application shall include specified plans that demonstrate the applicant's ability to carry out an ambitious expansion effort for all students, including traditionally underrepresented students.</p> <p>A grant recipient&nbsp;shall use the grant funds to:</p> <ul> <li>train teachers to teach computer science; </li> <li>expand access to high-quality learning materials and online learning options; </li> <li>create plans for expanding overall access to science, technology, engineering, arts, and mathematics (STEAM) classes; </li> <li>utilize computer science as a catalyst for increased interest in STEAM more broadly; </li> <li>reduce course equity gaps for all students; and </li> <li>ensure additional support and resources.</li></ul> <p>A grantee may also use grant funds to:</p> <ul> <li>build effective regional collaborations, </li> <li>recruit and hire instructional personnel, </li> <li>prepare for effectively sustaining project activities after the grant period ends, and </li> <li>disseminate information about effective practices.</li></ul> <p>At least semi-annually, a grantee must report to ED on specified data related to the number of&nbsp;students served through program activities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
