<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3999" measure-id="id115hr3999" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-10" update-date="2018-02-22">
<title>To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit the manufacture, possession, or transfer of any part or combination of parts that is designed and functions to increase the rate of fire of a semiautomatic rifle but does not convert the semiautomatic rifle into a machinegun, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3999v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-22">
<action-date>2017-10-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the federal criminal code to prohibit certain conduct with respect to any part or combination of parts that is designed and functions to increase the rate of fire of a semiautomatic rifle but does not convert the semiautomatic rifle into a machine gun. </p> <p>Specifically, it makes it a crime to manufacture, possess, or transfer such device: (1) in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce, or (2) that has been shipped or transported in interstate or foreign commerce.</p> <p>An individual who knowingly violates the prohibition is subject to criminal penalties&#8212;a fine, a prison term of up to five years, or both.</p> <p>Additionally, the U.S. Sentencing Commission must review and amend the sentencing guidelines and policy statements to provide an enhanced penalty if the device has been: (1) used, carried, or possessed during or in relation to a crime of violence or drug trafficking crime; or (2) unlawfully smuggled into or from the United States. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
