<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1244" measure-id="id115hr1244" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-28" update-date="2018-02-08">
<title>Capital Access for Small Businesses and Jobs Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1244v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-08">
<action-date>2017-02-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Capital Access for Small Businesses and Jobs Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Credit Union Act to allow a&nbsp;federal credit union, other than a low-income credit union,&nbsp;to receive payments on uninsured non-share accounts that:</p> <ul> <li>do not alter the cooperative nature of the credit union; </li> <li>are subordinate to all other claims against the credit union; </li> <li>are available to cover operating losses in excess of retained earnings and, to the extent so applied, will not be replenished; </li> <li>meet applicable requirements with respect to maturity; </li> <li>are subject to disclosure and consumer-protection requirements as determined by the&nbsp;National Credit Union Administration&nbsp;Board; </li> <li>are offered by a credit union that is sufficiently capitalized and well-managed; and </li> <li>are subject to such rules and regulations as the board may establish.<br /></li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
