<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="12" measure-id="id115hr12" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-23" update-date="2017-12-19">
<title>Voter Empowerment Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr12v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-19">
<action-date>2017-06-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Voter Empowerment Act of 2017</b></p> <p><i>Voter Registration Modernization Act of 2017</i></p> <p>This bill amends the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to require states to make available online voter registration.</p> <p>The federal criminal code is amended to prohibit hindering, interfering with, or preventing voter registration.</p> <p>The Help America Vote Act of 2002 is amended to require states to promote access to voter registration and voting for individuals with disabilities.</p> <p>The Election Assistance Commission (EAC) must support pilot programs enabling individuals with disabilities to register and vote at their residences.</p> <p>The bill reauthorizes support for state and local governments to ensure voting access for individuals with disabilities.</p> <p>States must notify individuals convicted of a criminal offense under state law, upon release or upon sentence to probation, of their right to vote in federal elections.</p> <p><i>Voter Confidence and Increased Accessibility Act of 2017</i></p> <p>This bill revises auditing requirements for voting systems.</p> <p>Voting systems must use individual, durable, voter-verified paper ballots. </p> <p>The National Science Foundation must support the study and development of accessible ballot voting and best practices to enhance the accessibility of voting for certain individuals.</p> <p>With exceptions, states must audit federal election results.</p> <p>The Servicemembers Civil Relief Act is amended to extend the guarantee of voting residency to family members of absent military personnel.</p> <p>The EAC must support poll-worker recruitment and training and develop materials for a model program.</p> <p>The Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 is amended to prohibit a chief state election administration official, unless the official or a family member is a candidate, from taking part in political management or in a political campaign for federal office over which the official has supervisory authority.</p> <p>The EAC is reauthorized and its exemption from certain contracting requirements is repealed. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
