<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2955" measure-id="id115hr2955" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-20" update-date="2018-01-19">
<title>Collision Avoidance Systems Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2955v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-19">
<action-date>2017-06-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Collision Avoidance Systems Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill allows a passenger car, multipurpose passenger vehicle, truck, or bus to be equipped with a pulsating light system for high mounted stop lamps.</p> <p>The term &quot;pulsating light system&quot; means a system for a high mounted stop lamp in which: (1) the lamp pulses rapidly no more than four times and for no more than two seconds when the vehicle brake is applied and then converts to a continuous light until the brake is released, and (2) the rapid pulsing may not be repeated upon a subsequent application of the brakes for a lock-out period of five seconds after the brake's release.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
