<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2967" measure-id="id115hr2967" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-20" update-date="2017-10-06">
<title>Nutrition Coordinators for Local Healthy Youth Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2967v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-06">
<action-date>2017-06-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Nutrition Coordinators for Local Healthy Youth Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to establish a Department of Agriculture program to award grants to local educational agencies to appoint nutrition coordinators with a background in nutrition education, dietetics, or nutrition program management. </p> <p>The responsibilities of the coordinators include: </p> <ul> <li> ensuring compliance with local school wellness policies under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act, </li> <li> coordinating nutrition education programs with school food service directors, </li> <li> conducting training and facilitating information sharing of best practices, </li> <li> working with programs that promote and motivate students to participate in school wellness activities, </li> <li> coordinating and collaborating with other nutrition education programs, </li> <li> providing community outreach to promote nutrient-rich foods and farm-to-school activities, </li> <li> promoting regular physical activity in students, </li> <li> ensuring students receive effective and consistent messages regarding healthy eating and active living, and </li> <li> promoting nutrition education and team network nutrition programs in the state by coordinating and collaborating with the team nutrition network coordinator and community partners. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
