<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="539" measure-id="id115hr539" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-13" update-date="2017-04-03">
<title>USPSTF Transparency and Accountability Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr539v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-04-03">
<action-date>2017-01-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>USPSTF Transparency and Accountability Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to expand the scope and responsibilities of the United States Preventive Services Task Force to require it to: (1) publish research plans to guide its review of scientific evidence relating to the effectiveness of preventive services; (2) make evidence reports and recommendations available for public comment; (3) establish a system for grading preventive care (Grades A, B, C, and D and a Grade I for insufficient information); and (4) convene a preventive services stakeholders board to provide feedback on task force activities and recommend preventive services and scientific evidence for the task force to review. Members of the task force and the preventive services stakeholders board must disclose conflicts of interest.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must report on: (1) current recommendations of the task force; (2) task force recommendations and recommendations of other federal health agencies, national medical professional societies, and patient and disease advocacy organizations; and (3) the impact of task force recommendations on insurance coverage, access, and outcomes, including the impact on morbidity and mortality.</p> <p>This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to revise HHS's authority to modify coverage of preventive services. HHS may modify such coverage only based on a task force grade or recommendation that was developed or updated in accordance with this bill.</p> Medicare quality measures related to a recommendation of the task force may only be applied if the recommendation was developed or updated in accordance with this bill.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
