<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="810" measure-id="id115hr810" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-01" update-date="2017-11-06">
<title>Hadiya Pendleton and Nyasia Pryear-Yard Stop Illegal Trafficking in Firearms Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr810v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-06">
<action-date>2017-02-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Hadiya Pendleton and Nyasia Pryear-Yard Stop Illegal Trafficking in Firearms Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the federal criminal code to establish stand-alone criminal offenses for trafficking in firearms and straw purchasing of firearms. <p>The bill expands the categories of prohibited persons (i.e., persons barred from receiving or possessing a firearm or ammunition) to include persons who intend: (1) to sell or transfer a firearm or ammunition to a prohibited person, (2) to sell or transfer a firearm to further a crime of violence or drug trafficking offense, or (3) to unlawfully export.</p> <p>It increases the maximum prison term for the sale or transfer of a firearm to or the receipt or possession of a firearm by a prohibited person.</p> <p>The bill revises the existing prohibition on transferring a firearm knowing that it will be used to commit a crime of violence or drug trafficking offense. It broadens the scope of the prohibition and increases the maximum prison term for a violator.</p> <p>The bill also revises the existing prohibition on smuggling a firearm into the United States with the intent to unlawfully import or to promote a crime of violence or drug trafficking offense. It broadens the scope of the prohibition and increases the maximum prison term for a violator.</p> <p>Finally, the bill makes it a crime to smuggle a firearm or ammunition out of the United States, or conspire or attempt to do so, with the intent to unlawfully export or to promote a crime of violence or drug trafficking offense.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
