<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2555" measure-id="id115hr2555" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-19" update-date="2017-11-08">
<title>Veterans' Health Care Integrity Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2555v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-08">
<action-date>2017-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Veterans' Health Care Integrity Act of 2017 </b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to ensure that the director of each VA medical facility annually certifies that: (1) the facility is in full compliance with all provisions of law and regulations relating to scheduling appointments for veterans hospital care and medical services, and (2) any official data on appointment wait times is accurate. </p> <p>The VA may not waive any applicable provision of such laws or regulations. </p> <p>If unable to make such certification, a director shall provide the VA with an explanation of any noncompliance and a description of compliance actions being taken. If a director does not make a certification for any year, each covered official may not receive specified awards or bonuses during the subsequent year. &quot;Covered officials&quot; are a facility's director, chief of staff, associate director, associate director for patient care, and deputy chief of staff. </p> <p>The VA shall ensure that its directives and policies apply to, and are implemented by, each VA office or facility in a uniform manner. </p> <p> The following VA positions shall be appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate: (1) Deputy Under Secretary for Health for Operations and Management, (2) Deputy Under Secretary for Health for Policy and Services, (3) Principal Deputy Under Secretary for Benefits, (4) Deputy Under Secretary for Disability Assistance, and (5) Deputy Under Secretary for Field Operations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
