<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4667" measure-id="id115hr4667" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-12-18" update-date="2017-12-27">
<title>Making further supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018, for disaster assistance for Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, and calendar year 2017 wildfires, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4667v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-27">
<action-date>2017-12-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>DIVISION A--DISASTER ASSISTANCE </p> <p><i>Further Additional Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements, 2017 </i></p> <p>This division provides $81 billion in FY2018 emergency appropriations to several federal agencies for disaster assistance related to Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria; and wildfires that occurred in 2017. (Emergency spending is exempt from discretionary spending limits and other budget enforcement rules.)</p> <p>DIVISION B--DISASTER RECOVERY REFORM ACT </p> <p>This division amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to modify the Federal Emergency Management Agency disaster response and recovery programs. </p> <p>DIVISION C--OTHER MATTERS </p> <p>This division amends the Agricultural Act of 2014 to designate cottonseed as a covered commodity beginning with the 2018 crop year. (Producers of covered commodities are eligible for Department of Agriculture [USDA] price and income support programs such as the Price Loss Coverage program.) </p> <p>It also amends the Federal Crop Insurance Act to remove the $20 million cap on annual expenditures for livestock producers under the federal crop insurance program. </p> <p>The bill requires all states to participate in USDA's National Accuracy Clearinghouse, which is a database for states to use to prevent Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP, formerly known as the food stamp program) participants from receiving duplicative benefits in multiple states. (The clearinghouse is currently a pilot program with five participating states.)</p> <p>DIVISION D--BUDGETARY EFFECTS </p> <p>This division exempts the budgetary effects of division B and each succeeding division of this bill from Pay-As-You-Go (PAYGO) and other budget enforcement rules. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
