<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1054" measure-id="id115hr1054" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-14" update-date="2017-06-21">
<title>Botanical Sciences and Native Plant Materials Research, Restoration, and Promotion Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1054v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-21">
<action-date>2017-02-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Botanical Sciences and Native Plant Materials Research, Restoration, and Promotion Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), the U.S. Geological Survey, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS), the National Park Service, and other appropriate entities to support a program of intramural and extramural botanical science research to support the land management responsibilities of the Department of the Interior. Interior may hire additional personnel to augment its expertise in the botanical sciences.</p>  <p>Interior's land management agencies, the Forest Service, and the Department of Defense shall give preference to using locally adapted native plant materials when undertaking land management activities on lands under their respective jurisdictions. </p> <p>A state shall maximize the use of such plant materials when carrying out environmental mitigation efforts and environmental restoration and pollution abatement activities authorized under the surface transportation block grant program.</p> <p>Sponsors of development or redevelopment projects involving certain federal facilities shall establish, maintain, or restore use of such plant materials on all natural spaces. </p> <p>Specified federal agencies shall collaborate regarding land use responsibility when undertaking specified activities related to native plant materials.</p> <p> The bill authorizes the BLM to undertake specified activities for the development and use of native plant materials. </p> <p>The National Fish and Wildlife Foundation shall ensure that a program of activities which is focused on conservation and protection of native plants is incorporated into its existing programs and activities. </p> <p>The USFWS shall support a program of collaborative grants to: (1) prevent rare plants from becoming endangered, and (2) encourage the recovery of endangered plants. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
