<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3095" measure-id="id115hr3095" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-28" update-date="2017-09-20">
<title>Veterans ACCESS Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3095v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-20">
<action-date>2017-06-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Veterans Acquiring Community Care Expect Safe Services Act of 2017 or the Veterans ACCESS Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to deny or revoke eligibility to provide non-VA health care services to veterans for any any health care provider that: (1) was removed from VA employment for violating VA policy relating to the delivery of safe and appropriate health care, (2) violated medical license requirements, (3) had a VA credential revoked on grounds that impact the provider's ability to deliver safe and appropriate health care, or (4) violated a law for which a prison term of more than one year may be imposed.</p> <p>The VA may deny, revoke, or suspend a health care provider's eligibility to provide non-VA health care services based on a reasonable belief that such action is necessary to immediately protect the health or safety of veterans if: (1) the provider is under investigation by a state's medical licensing board, (2) the provider has entered into a settlement agreement for a disciplinary charge relating to the practice of medicine, or (3) the VA otherwise determines that such action is appropriate.</p> <p>The VA shall suspend a health care provider's eligibility to provide non-VA health care services to veterans if such provider is suspended from serving as a VA medical provider. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
