<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3296" measure-id="id115hr3296" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-19" update-date="2017-12-18">
<title>Frank Adelmann Manufactured Housing Community Sustainability Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3296v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-18">
<action-date>2017-07-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Frank Adelmann Manufactured Housing Community Sustainability Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a business-related tax credit equal to 75% of the gain from the sale or exchange of real property to a qualified manufactured home community cooperative or corporation if: (1) the property is acquired for use as a manufactured home community, (2) the seller (or any related person) owned the property for at least two years before the sale or exchange, and (3) the property is transferred subject to a binding covenant that the property will be used as a manufactured home community for at least 50 years. </p> <p>A &quot;qualified manufactured home community cooperative or corporation&quot; is a cooperative or a nonprofit corporation established pursuant to the laws of the state in which the property is located. The bill specifies membership and governance requirements for the communities owned by the cooperative or nonprofit corporation.</p> <p>The bill also imposes a tax on buyers who violate the covenant to use the property for manufactured housing for at least 50 years. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
