<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="948" measure-id="id115hr948" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-07" update-date="2017-02-17">
<title>Common Sense Housing Investment Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr948v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-02-17">
<action-date>2017-02-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Common Sense Housing Investment Act of 201</strong><b>7</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the tax deduction for mortgage interest, to: (1) allow, in lieu of such deduction, a tax credit for 15% of mortgage interest paid in a taxable year for the taxpayer's principal residence and one other residence; (2) provide for a phaseout of the tax deduction for mortgage interest between 2017 and 2021; (3) allow a deduction for interest and taxes relating to land for dwelling purposes owned or leased by cooperative housing corporations; and (4) increase the state housing credit ceiling for the low-income housing tax credit. </p> <p>The bill directs the Department of the Treasury to<strong> </strong>apply the savings from the enactment of this bill to the Housing Trust Fund, rental assistance programs, and the Public Housing Capital Fund. </p> <p>The Department of Housing and Urban Development must revise regulations for the Housing Trust Fund to: (1) increase the limitation on funds that are available for operating assistance for housing, (2) allow public housing agencies and tribally designated housing entities to be the recipients of grants that are allocated to a state or a state designated entity, and (3) eliminate the applicability of rules for the fund that are based on the HOME Investment Partnerships Act. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
