<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2781" measure-id="id115hr2781" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-06" update-date="2018-01-25">
<title>Ensuring Veteran Enterprise Participation in Strategic Sourcing Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2781v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-25">
<action-date>2017-07-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Ensuring Veteran Enterprise Participation in Strategic Sourcing Act</strong></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to certify that sufficient numbers of small businesses owned and controlled by veterans, and of small business owned by veterans with service-connected disabilities, are represented within each category of supplies or services (except for domestic delivery services) for which a suite of contracts has been awarded under the Federal Strategic Sourcing Initiative. A "sufficient number" means between two and enough to maximize the percentage of orders entered into by the VA with such businesses, as determined by the VA.</p> <p>If such representation within a category is not sufficient, the VA shall: (1) consult with the General Services Administration to increase the number of such concerns awarded contracts under that category, or (2) stop awarding orders under that category of the initiative.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2781v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-26">
<action-date>2017-06-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Ensuring Veteran Enterprise Participation in Strategic Sourcing Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to certify that sufficient numbers of small businesses owned and controlled by veterans, and of small business owned by veterans with service-connected disabilities, are represented within each category of supplies or services for which a suite of contracts has been awarded under the Federal Strategic Sourcing Initiative. A "sufficient number" means between two and enough to maximize the percentage of orders entered into by the VA with such businesses, as determined by the VA.</p> <p>If such representation within a category is not sufficient, the VA shall: (1) consult with the General Services Administration to increase the number of such concerns awarded contracts under that category, or (2) stop awarding orders under that category of the initiative.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
