<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2316" measure-id="id115hr2316" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-03" update-date="2018-01-03">
<title>Cooperative Management of Mineral Rights Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2316v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-03">
<action-date>2017-10-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House reported version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Cooperative Management of Mineral Rights Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill repeals provisions of the Mineral Leasing Act and the Energy Policy Act of 1992 that require: (1) the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to provide 60 days' advance notice before commencing surface-disturbing activities related to the development of oil and gas deposits on certain land within the Allegheny National Forest in Pennsylvania; and (2) persons who propose to develop oil and gas deposits on such lands to either permit USDA to market merchantable timber owned by the United States on the land subject to such activities or arrange to purchase merchantable timber on that land from USDA, or otherwise arrange for the disposition of such timber, upon such terms as USDA may accept. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2316v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-03">
<action-date>2017-09-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Cooperative Management of Mineral Rights Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill repeals provisions of the Mineral Leasing Act and the Energy Policy Act of 1992 that require: (1) the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to provide 60 days' advance notice before commencing surface-disturbing activities related to the development of oil and gas deposits on certain land within the Allegheny National Forest in Pennsylvania; and (2) persons who propose to develop oil and gas deposits on such lands to either permit USDA to market merchantable timber owned by the United States on the land subject to such activities or arrange to purchase merchantable timber on that land from USDA, or otherwise arrange for the disposition of such timber, upon such terms as USDA may accept. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2316v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-20">
<action-date>2017-05-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Cooperative Management of Mineral Rights Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill repeals requirements of the Mineral Leasing Act and the Energy Policy Act of 1992 regarding the development of oil and gas deposits on certain lands within the Allegheny National Forest in Pennsylvania. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
