<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="550" measure-id="id115hr550" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-13" update-date="2017-05-17">
<title>Checkpoint Safety Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr550v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-17">
<action-date>2017-01-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Checkpoint Safety Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill revises minimum requirements for the deployment of armed law enforcement personnel at security screening locations at certain airports.</p> <p>The Transportation Security Administration (TSA), formerly the Under Secretary of Transportation for Security of the Department of Transportation, shall order the deployment of at least one armed law enforcement officer within 300 feet of the security screening location and within the terminal during operating hours of each airport having annual enplanements of 8 million or more or international enplanements of 1 million or more. The TSA shall order the deployment of additional armed law enforcement officers at such airports if deemed necessary to ensure airport security.</p> <p>The bill revises air transportation security program requirements to require that such programs ensure:</p> <ul> <li>law enforcement presence at each airport is adequate to ensure the safety of passengers, as under current law, and their property;</li> <li>close cooperation between all relevant parties in ensuring airport security;</li> <li>high training standards for all security and law enforcement personnel;</li> <li>prompt notification of, and law enforcement response to, any security incidents at airports, including detention of persons who attempt to evade transportation security screening; and </li> <li>multiple means for TSA Officers or members of the public to request prompt law enforcement assistance in the airport.</li> </ul> <p>The bill repeals TSA authority for allowing deputized state and local law enforcement officers to be stationed other than at airport security screening locations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
