<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1754" measure-id="id115hr1754" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-28" update-date="2017-05-03">
<title>To amend the Federal Trade Commission Act to clarify the scope of the exception for common carriers.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1754v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-03">
<action-date>2017-03-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to authorize the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to regulate activities of common carriers insofar as the activities are not regulated by the Federal Communications Commission under the Communications Act of 1934 or by the Surface Transportation Board or the Department of Transportation under interstate transportation laws.</p> <p>Under current law, these common carriers are exempt from the FTC's authority based merely on their status as common carriers. The bill continues to prohibit the FTC from regulating common carriers insofar as they are subject to communications and transportation laws, but allows the FTC to regulate other activities of common carriers under its authority to investigate and prevent unfair methods of competition and unfair or deceptive acts or practices. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
