<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2285" measure-id="id115hr2285" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-02" update-date="2018-01-17">
<title>School-Based Respiratory Health Management Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2285v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-17">
<action-date>2017-05-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>School-Based Respiratory Health Management Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to revise the conditions under which the Department of Health and Human Services, in making asthma-related grants, gives preference to a state. A preference is given to states that require elementary and secondary schools to have: (1) on the premises during operating hours at least one individual trained in the administration of rescue medications for allergies and reversible lower airway disorders, and (2) an allergies and reversible lower airway disorders management program. Currently, this preference is given to states that require schools to have on the premises an individual trained in the administration of epinephrine to a student having a severe allergic reaction.</p> To be eligible for this preference, a state must have civil liability protections for trained individuals who administer rescue medications for allergies and reversible lower airway disorders.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
