<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1341" measure-id="id115hr1341" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-02" update-date="2017-10-26">
<title>Stop Foreign Donations Affecting Our Elections Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1341v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-26">
<action-date>2017-03-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Stop Foreign Donations Affecting Our Elections Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit political committees from accepting any Internet credit card contribution unless:</p> <UL> <LI>the individual or entity making the contribution is required, at the time of the contribution, to disclose the credit card's verification value; and <LI>the billing address associated with the card is located in the United States or, if the contribution comes from an individual U.S. citizen living outside of the United States, the individual gives the committee the U.S. mailing address he or she uses for voter registration.</LI> </UL> <p>The person receiving an Internet credit card contribution shall forward it to the treasurer of the political committee within 10 days, together with the name and address of the contributor and the date of receipt. The treasurer shall keep an account of the contributor's name and address, together with the date and amount of the contribution.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
