<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3391" measure-id="id115hr3391" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-25" update-date="2018-02-16">
<title>Medical Marijuana Research Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3391v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-16">
<action-date>2017-07-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong></strong></p> <p><b>Medical Marijuana Research Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Controlled Substances Act to establish a new, separate registration process to facilitate research with marijuana for medical purposes. The Drug Enforcement Administration must register: (1) practitioners to conduct medical marijuana research, and (2) manufacturers and distributors to supply marijuana for such research.</p> <p>The Department of Health and Human Services must continue to produce marijuana through the National Institute on Drug Abuse Drug Supply Program and offer to sell immature plants and seeds to researchers until manufacturers and distributors can provide a sufficient supply of marijuana for medical research.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
