<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1218" measure-id="id115hr1218" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-24" update-date="2018-02-08">
<title>Social Security and Medicare Lock-Box Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1218v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-08">
<action-date>2017-02-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Social Security and Medicare Lock-Box Act</b></p> <p>This bill establishes: (1)&nbsp;in the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund, a Social Security Surplus Protection Account; and (2) in the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund, a Medicare Surplus Protection Account.</p> <p>The Managing Trustee of&nbsp;each trust fund (in both cases, the Secretary of the Treasury): (1) must transfer the annual surplus of&nbsp;the trust fund to its respective&nbsp;account; and (2) may not invest the balance in the account until a law takes effect that authorizes, for amounts in the trust fund, an investment vehicle other than U.S. obligations.</p> <p>The bill establishes in the executive branch a commission to study the most effective vehicles for investment of the trust funds, other than investments in the form of U.S. obligations. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
