<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2365" measure-id="id115hr2365" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-04" update-date="2018-02-06">
<title>Desert Community Lands Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2365v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-06">
<action-date>2017-05-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Desert Community Lands Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of the Interior to convey, without consideration, to the town of Apple Valley in California the surface estate of specified land, to be known and designated as the Apple Valley Off-Highway Vehicle Recreation Area. </p> <p>The conveyed land may be used by the town to provide: (1) a suitable location for the establishment of a centralized, off-road vehicle recreation park; (2) the public with opportunities for off-road vehicle recreation; and (3) a designated area and facilities that would discourage unauthorized use of off-highway vehicles in areas that have been identified by the federal government, the state of California, or San Bernardino County, California, to contain environmentally sensitive land. </p> <p>Such land may not be disposed of by the town without Interior's approval. </p> <p>Interior may develop a special management plan for the recreation area to enhance the safe use of off-highway vehicles for recreational purposes.</p> <p>Interior shall convey, without consideration, the surface estate of specified lands to the cities of Twentynine Palms, Barstow, and Victorville in California. </p> <p>All land conveyances under this bill are subject to valid existing rights and do not include the mineral estate in the lands conveyed.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
