<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1684" measure-id="id115hr1684" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-22" update-date="2017-09-11">
<title>Disaster Assistance Support for Communities and Homeowners Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1684v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-11">
<action-date>2017-06-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Disaster Assistance Support for Communities and Homeowners Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to provide technical assistance to a common interest community that provides essential services of a governmental nature on actions such community may take to be eligible to receive reimbursement from a grantee that receives FEMA funds for certain activities performed following a disaster declaration.</p> <p>FEMA shall provide to specified congressional committees a legislative proposal on how to provide eligibility for disaster assistance with respect to common areas of condominiums and housing cooperatives.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1684v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-24">
<action-date>2017-03-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Disaster Assistance Support for Communities and Homeowners Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to provide technical assistance to a common interest community that provides essential services of a governmental nature on actions such community may take to be eligible to receive reimbursement from a grantee that receives FEMA funds for certain activities performed following a disaster declaration.</p> <p>FEMA shall provide recommendations to Congress on how common areas of condominiums and housing cooperatives may be eligible for assistance.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
