<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1102" measure-id="id115hr1102" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-16" update-date="2017-12-18">
<title>Redistricting Reform Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1102v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-18">
<action-date>2017-02-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><STRONG>Redistricting Reform Act of 2017</STRONG></p> <p> This bill prohibits a state that has been redistricted after an apportionment of Members of the House of Representatives based on the results of the census from being redistricted again until after the next apportionment, unless the state is ordered by a court to conduct redistricting in order to comply with the Constitution or the Voting Rights Act of 1965.</p> <p> Redistricting must be conducted in accordance with a plan established by a state independent redistricting commission or, if such a plan is not established, in accordance with a redistricting plan established by a three-judge panel of the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia. </p> <p> This bill sets forth provisions relating to: (1) the establishment and procedures of state independent redistricting commissions, including requirements for commissions to hold their meetings in public and maintain a public website; (2) the development and publication of preliminary redistricting plans; (3) the establishment of a redistricting plan by a three-judge panel and redistricting conducted under a federal court order; and (4) Election Assistance Commission payments to states for carrying out redistricting.</p> <p> This bill authorizes the Department of Justice to bring a civil action to enforce this bill. The action must be given expedited consideration.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
