<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1351" measure-id="id115hr1351" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-02" update-date="2017-11-09">
<title>Strengthening Oversight of TSA Employee Misconduct Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1351v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-09">
<action-date>2017-07-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Strengthening Oversight of TSA Employee Misconduct Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to designate a senior official: </p> <ul> <li> implement a plan to oversee unannounced inspections at airports of agency actions taken to address TSA employee misconduct, including corrective actions by airport managers and employee removal from federal service;</li> <li>certify to the TSA, on a biannual basis until September 30, 2023, that such unannounced inspections were completed across a sufficient number of airports;</li> <li>review the results of such inspections to identify causes of any variances and overall trends in actions taken in response to employee misconduct and to develop corrective actions and recommendations; </li> <li>implement the corrective actions and any recommendations; and</li> <li>provide the results of such inspections to DHS.</li> </ul> <p>Unannounced inspections of certain locations may be consolidated and coordinated with other TSA offices. TSA may extend the time for completing such inspections for up to an additional fiscal year if exigent circumstances warrant.</p> <p>DHS may review such results to identify trends and make recommendations to the TSA to address employee misconduct. The TSA shall implement such recommendations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1351v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-06">
<action-date>2017-03-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Strengthening Oversight of TSA Employee Misconduct Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to designate a senior official: </p> <ul> <li> implement a plan to oversee unannounced inspections of actions taken in response to allegations of TSA employee misconduct, including corrective actions by airport managers and employee dismissal;</li> <li>certify to the TSA, on a quarterly basis until September 30, 2022, that such unannounced inspections were completed across a sufficient number of airports;</li> <li>review the results of such inspections to identify root causes of any variances in actions taken in response to employee misconduct allegations and to develop corrective actions; </li> <li>implement any recommendations; and</li> <li>provide the results of such inspections to DHS.</li> </ul> <p>DHS shall review such results to identify trends and make recommendations to the TSA to address employee misconduct. The TSA shall implement such recommendations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
