<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4926" measure-id="id115hr4926" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2018-02-05" update-date="2018-02-12">
<title>American Opportunity Carbon Fee Act of 2018</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4926v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-12">
<action-date>2018-02-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>American Opportunity Carbon Fee Act of 201</strong><b>8</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose fees on: (1) fossil fuel products producing carbon dioxide emissions, including coal, petroleum products, and natural gas; (2) fluorinated greenhouse gases; (3) emissions of any greenhouse gas from any greenhouse gas emissions source; and (4) associated emissions (attributable to venting, flaring, and leakage across the supply chain). </p> <p>The bill directs the Department of the Treasury to: </p> <ul> <li> establish, implement, and report on a program to identify all major source categories of associated emissions and collect data on associated emissions from the coal, petroleum products, and natural gas supply chains; </li> <li> make specified adjustments to the new fees for importers and exporters of energy-intensive manufactured goods; </li> <li> make a specified payment each calendar year to certain Social Security beneficiaries, veterans, and disabled individuals; </li> <li> make cost mitigation grants to states to assist low-income and rural households and provide job training and worker transition assistance; and </li> <li>establish a website to make regular disclosures concerning revenue, tax savings, and benefits attributable to this bill.</li> </ul> <p>The bill also allows a new carbon fee offset tax credit for the lesser of: 6.2% of earned income, or $800.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
