<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1415" measure-id="id115hr1415" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-07" update-date="2017-06-29">
<title>End Neglected Tropical Diseases Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1415v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-29">
<action-date>2017-03-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>End Neglected Tropical Diseases Act</b></p> <p>This bill expands programs to address neglected tropical diseases (NTDs), which are infections caused by pathogens, including viruses, microbes, and helminths (parasitic worms), that disproportionately impact individuals living in extreme poverty, especially in developing countries.</p> <p>The NTDs Program of the U.S. Agency for International Development must incorporate specified priorities, including: (1) conducting monitoring and evaluation of program investments, (2) including morbidity management in treatment plans, (3) addressing additional NTDs recognized as high-burden diseases, and (4) continuing investments in research and development.</p> <p>The President must direct the U.S. Executive Director at the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development to urge the World Bank Institute to take actions on NTDs, including deworming programs.</p> <p>The Department of Health and Human Services must: (1) continue to promote the need for NTDs programs and activities through interagency groups and international forums; (2) report to Congress on NTDs in the United States; and (3) establish a panel to evaluate issues relating to worm infections, including potential solutions such as deworming medicines.</p> <p>The bill authorizes the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to enter into agreements and make grants to support one or more centers of excellence for NTD research, training, and treatment.</p> <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
