<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2395" measure-id="id115hr2395" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-04" update-date="2017-06-14">
<title>Stop Predatory Bail Contracts Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2395v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-14">
<action-date>2017-05-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Stop Predatory Bail Contracts Act</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to limit the fee that bail bond agents or persons underwriting or insuring the provision of a bail bond may charge for an ankle monitor or homing device that they require an accused individual to wear as a condition on issuing a bond for his or her appearance in court. The fee may not exceed the cost of maintaining and operating such monitor or device.</p> <p>The bill provides the FTC with authority to enforce against violations, which shall be treated as unfair or deceptive acts or practices under Federal Trade Commission Act.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
