<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2996" measure-id="id115hr2996" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-22" update-date="2018-02-09">
<title>Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program Reform Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2996v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-09">
<action-date>2017-06-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program Reform Act of 2017 </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to modify the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP, formerly known as the food stamp program) work requirements that apply to able-bodied adults without dependents (ABAWDs). </p> <p>The bill modifies the work requirements to: </p> <ul> <li>terminate the authority of the Department of Agriculture to waive the requirements, upon the request of a state agency, for individuals residing in an area that has an unemployment rate of over 10% or does not have a sufficient number of jobs to provide employment for the individuals; </li> <li> shorten from three months to one month the time limit for receiving benefits in a three-year period without meeting the requirements; </li> <li> decrease from 15% to 5% the portion of ABAWDs that a state may exempt from the requirements; </li> <li> allow participation in a supervised job search to satisfy the requirements; </li> <li> require states receiving SNAP funds to provide ABAWDs with opportunities to participate in a work program, a workfare program, or a supervised job search; and </li> <li> reduce SNAP allotments for states that fail to comply with requirements regarding eligibility disqualifications.</li> </ul> <p>The bill also modifies the congressional declaration of policy to specify that the purpose of SNAP is to increase employment, to encourage healthy marriage, and to promote prosperous self-sufficiency (maintaining an income above the poverty level without services and benefits from the federal government). </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
