<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2479" measure-id="id115hr2479" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-17" update-date="2018-03-08">
<title>Leading Infrastructure for Tomorrow's America Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2479v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-08">
<action-date>2017-05-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Leading Infrastructure for Tomorrow's America Act</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes appropriations for the nation's infrastructure, including appropriations for:</p> <ul> <li>secure broadband internet access, with a prioritization on expanding broadband access in unserved areas;</li> <li>drinking water improvements, such as appropriations for the drinking water state revolving fund and programs for reducing lead in drinking water;</li> <li>the electric power grid, with a focus on grid modernization, security, resiliency, and efficiency;</li> <li>energy efficiency in buildings, including homes and schools;</li> <li>incentives for natural gas distribution companies to improve the public safety and environmental performance of the natural gas distribution system (e.g., pipeline replacements); </li> <li>the deployment of renewable energy systems;</li> <li>the incorporation of clean energy into community development and revitalization efforts;</li> <li> revitalization of brownfield sites (commercial properties that are hindered from reuse or redevelopment due to the presence of a hazardous substance, pollutant, or contaminant);</li> <li>hospital infrastructure, with a prioritization given to projects that include cybersecurity;</li> <li>outpatient health care facilities in the Indian Health Service; and</li> <li>the improvement, renovation, or modernization of the infrastructure at clinical laboratories, teaching health centers, or behavioral health care centers.</li> </ul> <p> In addition, the bill reauthorizes funding for: (1) a diesel emissions reduction program for certain diesel vehicles or fleets, (2) ensuring the Strategic Petroleum Reserve is operated and maintained in an environmentally sound manner; and (3) establishing a Southeast Refined Product Reserve to mitigate the impacts of a severe energy supply interruption in the Southeast.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
