<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3028" measure-id="id115hr3028" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-22" update-date="2018-03-28">
<title>BRAVE Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3028v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-28">
<action-date>2017-06-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Bolstering Returning American Veterans Education Act or the BRAVE Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide a standard training curriculum for school certifying officials regarding administrative responsibilities relating to VA educational assistance programs. Such curriculum shall be provided through an Internet website or taught at a VA-sponsored conference. </p> <p>The VA shall require as a condition of course approval that the school certifying official of the educational institution offering the course must: (1) complete the training curriculum within 30 days of after first being designated as a school certifying official, and (2) receive a minimum 75% score on a test of the official's knowledge of the covered subjects.</p> <p>A school certifying official is an educational institution official designated to: (1) sign or report enrollment certifications, or (2) sign the school portion of the application and enrollment certification for individualized tutorial assistance.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
