<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2422" measure-id="id115hr2422" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-15" update-date="2018-02-23">
<title>Action for Dental Health Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2422v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-23">
<action-date>2017-09-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Action for Dental Health Act 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize oral health promotion and disease prevention programs through FY2022. </p> <p>The Department of Health and Human Services&nbsp;may award grants or enter into contracts to collaborate with state, county, or local public officials and other stakeholders to develop and implement initiatives to: (1) improve oral health education and dental disease prevention; (2) reduce geographic barriers, language barriers, cultural barriers, and other similar barriers in the provision of dental services; (3) establish dental homes for children and adults; (4) reduce the use of emergency departments by individuals who seek dental services more appropriately delivered in a dental primary care setting; or (5) facilitate the provision of dental care to nursing home residents. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2422v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-13">
<action-date>2017-05-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Action for Dental Health Act 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize oral health promotion and disease prevention programs through FY2022. </p> <p>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) may award grants or enter into contracts to obtain portable or mobile dental equipment and pay operational costs for the provision of free dental services to underserved populations.</p> <p>The CDC may also award grants or enter into contracts to collaborate with state, county, or local public officials and other stakeholders to develop and implement initiatives to: (1) improve oral health education and dental disease prevention; (2) make the dental services delivery system more accessible and efficient through outreach programs that facilitate the establishment of dental homes; (3) reduce geographic barriers, language barriers, cultural barriers, and other similar barriers in the provision of dental services; (4) reduce the use of emergency departments by individuals who seek dental services more appropriately delivered in a dental primary care setting; or (5) facilitate the provision of dental care to nursing home residents who are disproportionately affected by lack of care.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
