<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3364" measure-id="id115hr3364" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-24" update-date="2017-07-27">
<title>Countering America's Adversaries Through Sanctions Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3364v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-27">
<action-date>2017-07-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Countering America's Adversaries Through Sanctions Act </b></p> <p><i>Countering Iran's Destabilizing Activities Act of 2017</i></p> <p>This bill directs the President to impose sanctions against: (1) Iran's ballistic missile or weapons of mass destruction programs, (2) the sale or transfer to Iran of military equipment or the provision of related technical or financial assistance, and (3) Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps and affiliated foreign persons. </p> <p>The President may impose sanctions against persons responsible for violations of internationally recognized human rights committed against individuals in Iran. </p> <p>The President may temporarily waive the imposition or continuation of sanctions under specified circumstances. </p> <p><i>Countering Russian Influence in Europe and Eurasia Act of 2017</i></p> <p>The President must submit for congressional review certain proposed actions to terminate or waive sanctions with respect to the Russian Federation.</p> <p>Specified executive order sanctions against Russia shall remain in effect.</p> <p>The President may waive specified cyber- and Ukraine-related sanctions. </p> <p>The bill provides sanctions for activities concerning: (1) cyber security, (2) crude oil projects, (3) financial institutions, (4) corruption, (5) human rights abuses, (6) evasion of sanctions, (7) transactions with Russian defense or intelligence sectors, (8) export pipelines, (9) privatization of state-owned assets by government officials, and (10) arms transfers to Syria.</p> <p>The Department of State shall work with the government of Ukraine to increase Ukraine's energy security. </p> <p>The bill: (1) directs the Department of the Treasury to develop a national strategy for combating the financing of terrorism, and (2) includes the Secretary of the Treasury on the National Security Council.</p> <p><i>Korean Interdiction and Modernization of Sanctions Act</i></p> <p>The bill modifies and increases the President's authority to impose sanctions on persons in violation of certain United Nations Security Council resolutions regarding North Korea.</p> <p> U.S. financial institutions shall not establish or maintain correspondent accounts used by foreign financial institutions to provide indirect financial services to North Korea. </p> <p>A foreign government that provides to or receives from North Korea a defense article or service is prohibited from receiving certain types of U.S. foreign assistance. </p> <p>The bill provides sanctions against: (1) North Korean cargo and shipping, (2) goods produced in whole or part by North Korean convict or forced labor, and (3) foreign persons that employ North Korean forced laborers.</p> <p>The State Department shall submit a determination regarding whether North Korea meets the criteria for designation as a state sponsor of terrorism. </p> </p> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
