<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1481" measure-id="id115hr1481" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-09" update-date="2017-05-02">
<title>Fire Sprinkler Incentive Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1481v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-02">
<action-date>2017-03-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Fire Sprinkler Incentive Act</strong> </p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow: (1) 100% expensing in a current taxable year of the cost of automated fire sprinkler system retrofit property, as defined by this bill; and (2) accelerated depreciation (i.e., a 15-year recovery period) of automated fire sprinkler system retrofit property that has a certain classification by the National Fire Protection Association and is installed in a building or structure that was placed in service before the sprinkler system and has an occupiable story that is greater than 75 feet above the lowest level of fire department vehicle access. </p> <p>&quot;Automated fire sprinkler system retrofit property&quot; does not include any sprinkler system required to be installed under state or local law due to the degree of additions or improvements made to a building or structure. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
