<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3371" measure-id="id115hr3371" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-24" update-date="2018-03-14">
<title>Modoc County Land Transfer and Economic Development Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3371v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-14">
<action-date>2017-07-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Modoc County Land Transfer and Economic Development Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Agriculture to convey, without consideration, to Modoc County, California, specified National Forest System land in Modoc National Forest which contains an obsolete Over-the-Horizon Backscatter Radar System receiving station. </p> <p>The purpose of such conveyance is to: (1) preserve and utilize the improvements constructed on such land, and (2) permit the county to use the conveyed property for economic development purposes.</p> <p> To expedite the conveyance, environmental remediation of such land by the Air Force shall be limited to the removal of the perimeter fence, which was treated with an arsenic-based weatherproof coating, and the treatment of the soil affected by the leaching of such chemical. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
