<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3717" measure-id="id115hr3717" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-08" update-date="2018-03-16">
<title>Small Business Owners' Tax Simplification Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3717v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-16">
<action-date>2017-09-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Small Business Owners' Tax Simplification Act of 2017</b></p> <p> This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to several requirements that affect small businesses and self-employed individuals, to: </p> <ul> <li> align the deadlines for quarterly estimated tax payments with the calendar year quarters;</li> <li> modify the dollar thresholds for various information reporting requirements;</li> <li> allow certain self-employed individuals to participate in cafeteria benefit plans; </li> <li> exclude from self-employment income net earnings that are less than the amount required under the Social Security Act for a quarter of coverage for the calendar year in which the tax year began; </li> <li> allow certain health insurance costs of self-employed individuals to be deducted for self-employment tax purposes; and</li> <li>specify that voluntary tax withholding agreements, training, or group discount programs have no effect on whether an individual is classified as an employee or an employer. </li> </ul> <p>The Department of the Treasury must: (1) establish uniform standards and procedures for the acceptance of digital or electronic signatures, and (2) use prenotification testing to verify recipient information before transferring a tax refund or credit through an electronic funds transfer. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
