<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4547" measure-id="id115hr4547" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-12-05" update-date="2018-02-20">
<title>Strengthening Protections for Social Security Beneficiaries Act of 2018</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4547v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-20">
<action-date>2018-02-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Strengthening Protections for Social Security Beneficiaries Act of 2018</strong></p> <p>TITLE I--STRENGTHENING OVERSIGHT AND BENEFICIARY PROTECTION</p> <p>(Sec. 101) This bill requires the Social Security Administration (SSA) to make annual grants to each state's protection and advocacy system for the purpose of conducting reviews of representative payees under the Supplemental Security Income (SSI) program and the Old Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance (OASDI) program. The SSA must also conduct periodic onsite reviews of individual and organizational payees.</p> <p>(Sec. 102) The bill lessens certain monitoring requirements with respect to specified&nbsp;family members&nbsp;who are serving as representative payees.</p> <p>(Sec. 103)&nbsp;The SSA must: (1) enter into agreements with each state for the purpose of sharing information to identify represented minor beneficiaries who are in foster care; and (2) determine the appropriate representative payee for any represented minor beneficiary who has entered foster care, exited foster care, or changed foster care placement in a given month.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must report to specified congressional committees on certain issues related to represented minor beneficiaries in foster care.</p> <p>(Sec. 104) The bill modifies provisions related to overpayment liability with respect to a represented minor beneficiary in foster care.</p> <p>(Sec. 105) The SSA must report to specified congressional committees on&nbsp;certain issues related to representative payment with respect to SSI and OASDI benefits.</p> <p>TITLE II--IMPROVING PAYEE SELECTION AND QUALITY</p> <p>(Sec. 201) The bill provides for advance designation of representative payees.</p> <p>(Sec. 202) In general, an individual who has been convicted of&nbsp;a felony, or of an attempt or a conspiracy to commit a felony, may not serve as a representative payee.</p> <p>(Sec. 203) An&nbsp;individual&nbsp;who has&nbsp;a representative payee may not also serve as a representative payee. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4547v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-09">
<action-date>2017-12-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Strengthening Protections for Social Security Beneficiaries Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Social Security Administration (SSA) to make annual grants to each state's protection and advocacy system for the purpose of conducting reviews of representative payees under the Supplemental Security Income (SSI) program and the Old Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance (OASDI) program. The SSA must also conduct periodic onsite reviews of individual and organizational payees.</p> <p>The bill lessens certain monitoring requirements with respect to specified&nbsp;family members&nbsp;who are serving as representative payees.</p> <p>The bill provides for advance designation of representative payees.</p> <p>In general, an individual who has been convicted of&nbsp;a felony, or of an attempt or a conspiracy to commit a felony, may not serve as a representative payee.</p> <p>An&nbsp;individual&nbsp;who has&nbsp;a representative payee may not also serve as a representative payee.</p> <p>The SSA must report to specified congressional committees on&nbsp;certain issues related to representative payment with respect to SSI and OASDI benefits.</p> <p>The SSA must: (1) enter into agreements with each state for the purpose of sharing information to identify represented minor beneficiaries who are in foster care; and (2) determine the appropriate representative payee for any represented minor beneficiary who has entered foster care, exited foster care, or changed foster care placement in a given month.</p> <p>The bill modifies provisions related to overpayment liability with respect to a represented minor beneficiary in foster care.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must report to specified congressional committees on certain issues related to represented minor beneficiaries in foster care.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
