<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3134" measure-id="id115hr3134" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-29" update-date="2017-09-19">
<title>Transforming Student Debt to Home Equity Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3134v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-19">
<action-date>2017-06-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Transforming Student Debt to Home Equity Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) and the Federal Housing Finance Agency&nbsp;to jointly establish and implement a pilot demonstration program to provide, to eligible applicants with federal student loan debt, assistance in purchasing eligible properties. Specifically, the program may provide for: (1) discounts on the appraised value of eligible properties, (2) flexibility in certain underwriting standards, (3) the development of new mortgage products specifically targeted to eligible applicants, (4) the development of a program that uses actuarial information to determine how the repayment of federal student loans may be integrated into a mortgage repayment schedule to allow eligible applicants to accumulate home equity, and (5) other appropriate assistance.</p> <p>An "eligible property" is a property: (1) that is designed as a dwelling&nbsp;for occupancy by one to four families; (2) that is safe and habitable; (3) the occupancy of which will promote community revitalization; and (4) that is owned by HUD, the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae), or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac).</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
