<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="530" measure-id="id115hr530" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-13" update-date="2017-03-13">
<title>SECURE Our Democracy Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr530v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-03-13">
<action-date>2017-01-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Safeguard our Elections and Combat Unlawful Interference in Our Democracy Act or the SECURE Our Democracy Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of State to submit within 120 days a list of each foreign person that: (1) was at any time since January 1, 2015, involved in actions to unlawfully access, disrupt, misappropriate, influence, or alter information related to U.S. political parties, federal election candidates, or the administration of federal elections; or (2) worked or acted as an agent or instrumentality of, or on behalf of, or that was otherwise associated with, such foreign person. </p> <p>The unclassified portion of such list shall be made available to the public and published in the Federal Register.</p> <p>A listed alien shall be ineligible to receive a U.S. entry visa, and any current visa shall be revoked. Such prohibitions shall also apply to an alien who is an official of, an agent or instrumentality of, or working or acting on behalf of, a listed foreign entity or government if such alien knowingly authorized, conspired to commit, was responsible for, engaged in, or otherwise assisted or facilitated such prohibited actions. </p> <p>The President, through the Department of the Treasury, shall: (1) freeze and prohibit a listed foreign person's transactions in property and property interests that are in the United States or controlled a U.S. person, and (2) require each financial institution that is a U.S. person and has within its possession or control such property or property interests to certify that it has frozen all such assets. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
