<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3933" measure-id="id115hr3933" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-03" update-date="2018-01-25">
<title>Veterans Health Nurse Recruitment and Retention Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3933v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-25">
<action-date>2017-10-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Veterans Health Nurse Recruitment and Retention Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to publish and submit to Congress an annual report regarding efforts to recruit, hire, and retain Veterans Health Administration nurses. </p> <p>Such report shall include details regarding: (1) efforts to recruit, hire, and retain nurses at each VA medical facility, (2) VA resources provided for such efforts, and (3) recommendations for appropriate legislation.</p> <p>The Federal Reports Elimination and Sunset Act of 1995 is amended to restore the annual Educational Assistance Program reporting requirement.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
