<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3250" measure-id="id115hr3250" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-14" update-date="2017-11-17">
<title>9/11 Immigrant Worker Freedom Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3250v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-17">
<action-date>2017-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>9/11 Immigrant Worker Freedom Act</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to adjust to permanent resident the status a qualifying alien who applies for adjustment not later than one year after enactment of this bill and who, after the September 11, 2011, terrorist attacks: </p> <ul> <li>worked or volunteered on site in rescue, recovery, debris cleanup, or related support services in lower Manhattan, the Staten Island Landfill, or the barge loading piers for a specified number of hours during certain periods between September 11, 2001, and July 31, 2002; </li> <li>was a vehicle-maintenance worker who was exposed to debris from the former World Trade Center while retrieving, driving, cleaning, repairing, and maintaining vehicles contaminated by airborne toxins for any time during such period; or</li> <li>was a member of a fire or police department, worked for a recovery or cleanup contractor, or was a volunteer and performed rescue, recovery, demolition, debris cleanup, or other related services at the Pentagon site during the period between September 11, 2001, and November 19, 2001, or at the Shanksville, Pennsylvania, site during the period between September 11, 2001-October 3, 2001. </li> </ul> <p>DHS may authorize an alien who has applied for adjustment of status under this bill to work during the pendency of his or her application. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
