<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2912" measure-id="id115hr2912" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-15" update-date="2017-12-21">
<title>Advancing America's Missile Defense Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2912v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-21">
<action-date>2017-06-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Advancing America's Missile Defense Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Missile Defense Agency (MDA) to use Department of Defense (DOD) policies to accelerate the development, testing, and fielding of the redesigned kill vehicle, the multi-object kill vehicle, the C3 booster, a space-based sensor layer, an airborne laser on unmanned aerial vehicles, and an additional missile defense site, including the completion of any outstanding environmental impact statements for an additional missile defense site on the east coast or in the midwest regions of the United States. </p> <p>DOD shall, subject to National Missile Defense funding, increase the number of U.S. ground-based interceptors by 28.</p> <p>The MDA shall report to Congress on: (1) infrastructure requirements to increase the number of ground-based interceptors at Missile Field 1 and Missile Field 2 at Fort Greely to 20 ground-based interceptors each, (2) increasing the capacity of the ground-based mid-course defense element of the ballistic missile defense system, (3) the status of the integrated layers of missile defense radars, and (4) a revised missile defense testing campaign plan that accelerates the development and deployment of new missile defense technologies.</p> <p>DOD, by December 31, 2021, shall: (1) execute any requisite construction to ensure that such missile fields or alternative fields at Fort Greely are capable of supporting and sustaining additional ground-based interceptors, (2) deploy 14 additional ground-based interceptors to field 1 or an alternative field at as soon as technically feasible, and (3) identify a ground-based interceptor stockpile storage site for a minimum of 14 ground-based interceptors.</p> <p>The MDA shall develop, test, and deploy a highly reliable space-based missile defense sensor architecture for the ground-based midcourse defense system that provides specified functions and capabilities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
