<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1071" measure-id="id115hr1071" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-15" update-date="2017-11-16">
<title>Assistance, Quality, and Affordability Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1071v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-16">
<action-date>2017-02-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Assistance, Quality, and Affordability Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to reauthorize for FY2018-FY2022 and revise the drinking water state revolving fund (SRF), including to require SRF-funded projects to use iron and steel produced in the United States. </p> <p> The bill revises requirements for state Intended Use Plans for SRF funds, including to require the plans to: (1) list systems that are not in compliance with national primary drinking water regulation, (2) reserve a specified amount of funding for assistance for disadvantaged communities, and (3) prioritize SRF funding for disadvantaged communities when steps to implement improvements to meet new drinking water standards are not affordable to those communities.</p> <p> The bill repeals: (1) requirements for regulations on variance technologies, and (2) state authority to exempt small public water systems from national primary drinking water regulations if the system installs certain treatment techniques.</p> <p> The Environmental Protection Agency must:</p> <ul> <li>prescribe follow up inspections after violations by public water systems,</li> <li>establish requirements for electronic submission of compliance monitoring data by public water systems,</li> <li>study the presence of pharmaceuticals and personal care products in drinking water sources,</li> <li>collect data on best practices for administration of SRF programs, </li> <li>implement a voluntary certification program for effective water loss and leak control technology, and </li> <li>submit a strategic plan for assessing and managing the risks of drought to drinking water provided by public water systems.</li> </ul> <p> The bill also reauthorizes for FY2018-FY2022 a grant program for certain lead reduction projects.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
