<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1723" measure-id="id115hr1723" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-24" update-date="2017-12-13">
<title>Let It Go Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1723v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-13">
<action-date>2017-03-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Let It Go Act</b></p> <p> This bill amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require individuals to use contributions or donations not later than six years following the most recent federal election in which the individual was a candidate and before the individual becomes a registered lobbyist.</p> <p> This bill requires remaining contributions or donations to be disposed of within 30 days, first by paying debts or obligations owed in connection with the campaign for that office. Additional remaining funds must be disposed of by: (1) returning those contributions or donations to the individuals, entities, or both, who made them; (2) making contributions to a charitable organization; or (3) making transfers to a national, state, or local committee of a political party.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
