<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1404" measure-id="id115hr1404" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-07" update-date="2017-09-21">
<title>Pascua Yaqui Tribe Land Conveyance Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1404v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-21">
<action-date>2017-07-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Pascua Yaqui Tribe Land Conveyance Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 3) This bill declares that 39.65 acres of land are to be held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Pascua Yaqui Tribe of Arizona, effective the day after the Tuscon Unified School District No. 1 relinquishes its interest in the land. <p>(Sec. 4) The United States must convey to the school district 13.24 acres of federal land in exchange for payment of the fair market value of the land and the cost of conveyance. <p>The school district may acquire the federal reversionary interest in 27.5 acres of district land by paying the appraised value, plus the costs of appraisal and conveyance, to the Department of the Interior. <p>(Sec. 5) Gaming is prohibited on the land taken into trust pursuant to this bill. <p>(Sec. 6) There are no federal reserved water rights for the land taken into trust. The tribe retains state water rights for this land. Water rights for this land may not be forfeited or abandoned.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1404v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-29">
<action-date>2017-03-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Pascua Yaqui Tribe Land Conveyance Act</b></p> <p>This bill declares that 39.65 acres of land are to be held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Pascua Yaqui Tribe of Arizona, effective the day after the Tuscon Unified School District No. 1 relinquishes its interest in the land. <p>The United States must convey to the school district 13.24 acres of federal land in exchange for payment of the fair market value of the land and the cost of conveyance. <p>The school district may acquire the federal reversionary interest in 27.5 acres of district land by paying the appraised value, plus the costs of appraisal and conveyance, to the Department of the Interior. <p>Gaming is prohibited on the land taken into trust pursuant to this bill. <p>There are no federal reserved water rights for the land taken into trust. The tribe retains state water rights for this land. Water rights for this land may not be forfeited or abandoned.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
