<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1119" measure-id="id115hr1119" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-16" update-date="2018-03-14">
<title>SENSE Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1119v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-14">
<action-date>2018-03-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on January 12, 2018. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Satisfying Energy Needs and Saving the Environment Act or the SENSE Act</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill eases emission limits for hazardous air pollutants from electric utility steam generating units (electric power plants) that convert coal refuse into energy. The Environmental Protection Agency must allow utilities to select a standard for either hydrogen chloride or sulfur dioxide with which to comply from a list of specified standards.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1119v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-01">
<action-date>2018-01-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Satisfying Energy Needs and Saving the Environment Act or the SENSE Act</b></p> <p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill eases emission limits for hazardous air pollutants from electric utility steam generating units (electric power plants) that convert coal refuse into energy. The Environmental Protection Agency must allow utilities to select a standard for either hydrogen chloride or sulfur dioxide with which to comply from a list of specified standards.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1119v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-25">
<action-date>2017-02-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Satisfying Energy Needs and Saving the Environment Act or the SENSE Act</b></p> <p>This bill modifies the Cross-State Air Pollution Rule as it applies to certain electric utility steam generating units (electric power plants) that convert coal refuse into energy. The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) must maintain the existing limits for sulfur dioxide emissions from coal refuse utilities under the cap-and-trade system, instead of applying the more restrictive limits that are scheduled to go into effect in 2017. (Under the current system, a cap sets a limit on emissions. The cap is lowered over time to reduce the amount of pollutants released. Utilities may only emit as much carbon as permitted under their allowances, which may be traded with others.) Thus, EPA must allocate to coal refuse utilities in 2017 and subsequent years the same number of emissions allowances for sulfur dioxide that have been previously allocated to coal refuse utilities, instead of reducing allowances. </p> <p>After January 1, 2017, a coal refuse utility may not trade any unused sulfur dioxide allowances. Those allowances may be saved by the coal refuse utilities for use in future compliance periods.</p> <p>The EPA may not increase the total number of allowances for sulfur dioxide emissions from all sources that are allocated to each state. </p> <p>The bill eases emission limits for hazardous air pollutants from coal refuse utilities. The EPA must allow the utilities to meet compliance requirements by meeting the maximum achievable control technology standards for either hydrogen chloride or sulfur dioxide. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
