<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2699" measure-id="id115hr2699" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-25" update-date="2017-09-28">
<title>To direct the Secretary of Defense to more effectively provide mental health resources for members of the Armed Forces at high risk of suicide, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2699v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-28">
<action-date>2017-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill directs the Department of Defense (DOD) to develop a methodology to: </p> <ul> <li> identify units of the Armed Forces that have a disproportionately high rate of suicide and suicide attempts;</li> <li> provide additional mental health resources for members of the Armed Forces deployed with such units;</li> <li> identify the circumstances of deployments associated with increased vulnerability to suicide, including the length and area of deployment and the nature and extent of contact with enemy forces; and</li> <li> provide additional preventative mental health care to units deployed under similar circumstances.</li> </ul> <p> DOD shall: (1) develop a methodology to assess the rate of suicide and suicide attempts of members of the Armed Forces of units that have been deployed in support of a contingency operation after September 11, 2001, and (2) provide outreach regarding the available mental health resources for veterans enrolled in the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) health care system who were deployed with such units.</p> <p>Information obtained pursuant to this bill may be used by DOD and VA officers, employees, and contractors only for the purposes of carrying it out.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
