<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3731" measure-id="id115hr3731" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-11" update-date="2018-03-12">
<title>Secret Service Recruitment and Retention Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3731v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-12">
<action-date>2017-12-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Secret Service Recruitment and Retention Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Overtime Pay for Protective Services Act of 2016 to extend through 2018 the exemption of U.S. Secret Service officers, employees, and agents who perform protective services from the limitation on premium pay otherwise applicable to federal employees. </p> <p>The bill provides that such amendment shall take effect as if it had been enacted on December 31, 2016. </p> <p>The Secret Service must report to Congress by January 30, 2018, and January 30, 2019, on the amounts of premium pay above the limitation paid to Secret Service personnel in the previous year. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) The Government Accountability Office shall study and report to specified congressional committees on the extent of the progress made by the Secret Service in implementing the recommendations of the U.S. Secret Service Protective Mission Panel, including those items which pertain to training and personnel enumerated in the Executive Summary to Report from the panel to the Secretary of Homeland Security, dated December 15, 2014. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) A specified amount is permanently rescinded from the unobligated balances available under the Department of Justice Assets Forfeiture Fund. </p> <p>The bill authorizes specified amounts to be rescinded in FY2018-FY2019 from such balances. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3731v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-13">
<action-date>2017-09-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Secret Service Recruitment and Retention Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Overtime Pay for Protective Services Act of 2016 to extend through 2018 the exemption of U.S. Secret Service officers, employees, and agents who perform protective services from the limitation on premium pay otherwise applicable to federal employees. </p> <p>The Secret Service must report to Congress by January 30, 2018, and January 30, 2019, on the amounts of premium pay above the limitation paid to Secret Service personnel in the previous year. </p> <p>The Secret Service must conduct and provide to Congress updated threat assessments, including protection costs, on all of the individuals who are protected by the Secret Service. No such assessments will be conducted for the President, the Vice-President, their spouses or children, or former Presidents or Vice-Presidents. </p> <p>The Secret Service must submit to Congress: (1) a report on its recruitment and retention efforts; (2) a notice whenever it, at the direction of the Department of Homeland Security or the President, extends the protection of an individual beyond the length of time such protection would otherwise be provided; and (3) a list of all of the questions asked in 2016 on any polygraph exam it issued to applicants for employment. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
