<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="924" measure-id="id115hr924" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-07" update-date="2017-07-14">
<title>Financial Institutions Due Process Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr924v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-14">
<action-date>2017-02-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Financial Institutions Due Process Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1978 to establish&nbsp;an Independent Examination Review Panel. The panel shall have exclusive jurisdiction of an appeal of a final material supervisory determination of a federal financial institutions regulatory agency.</p> <p>A financial institution may request from a federal financial institutions regulatory agency a written determination of the agency's: (1)&nbsp;permission to take an action, and (2) interpretation of a law or regulation. An agency must respond to such a request within a specified timeframe.</p> <p>The bill also establishes timeframes within which a&nbsp;federal financial institutions regulatory agency must: (1) conduct an exit interview with respect to the examination of a financial institution, and (2)&nbsp;provide a final examination report.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
