<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1576" measure-id="id115hr1576" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-16" update-date="2017-11-21">
<title>Innovation Corps Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1576v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-21">
<action-date>2017-03-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Innovation Corps Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Commerce to establish a competitive program to make grants to institutions of higher education to establish or enhance education programs that retrain workers displaced from their jobs by automation to provide such workers with skills needed for jobs in science, technology, engineering, or mathematics (STEM) fields.</p> <p>Commerce shall establish an Innovation Corps whereby recent college graduates may volunteer, in an education program for which an institution of higher education receives (or is eligible to receive) such a grant, to help retrain displaced workers.</p> <p>The Higher Education Act of 1965 is amended to: (1) allow federal student loan deferment for graduate volunteers who serve in the corps, and (2) require Commerce to repay up to $100,000 of such a student loan for a borrower who completes two years of corps service.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
