<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2213" measure-id="id115hr2213" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-27" update-date="2017-12-28">
<title>Anti-Border Corruption Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2213v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-28">
<action-date>2017-06-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Anti-Border Corruption Reauthorization Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends the Anti-Border Corruption Act of 2010 to expand the authority of the U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) to waive the administration of polygraph examinations to civilian and military applicants for law enforcement positions in the CBP. This expanded waiver authority terminates five years after the enactment of this bill.</p>  <p>(Sec. 3) An individual who receives such a waiver is not exempt from other hiring requirements relating to suitability for employment and eligibility to hold a national security designated position.</p> <p>Any individual who receives a waiver and holds a current Tier 4 (High Risk Public Trust) background investigation shall be subject to a Tier 5 (Critical Sensitive and Special Sensitive National Security) background investigation.</p> <p>The CBP may administer a polygraph examination to an applicant or employee who receives a waiver if information is discovered prior to the completion of a background investigation that results in a determination that a polygraph examination is necessary to make a final determination regarding suitability for employment or continued employment.</p> <p>The CBP shall provide Congress information on the number of waivers requested, granted, and denied, and the reasons for any such denial, and the final outcome of the application for employment at issue. Such information shall also include the number of instances a polygraph examination was administered, the result of any such examination, and the final outcome of the application for employment at issue.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2213v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-26">
<action-date>2017-04-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Anti-Border Corruption Reauthorization Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Anti-Border Corruption Act of 2010 to revise the waiver authority of the U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP)&nbsp;for polygraph examinations of applicants for law enforcement positions in CBP. Such waiver authority terminates five years after the enactment of this bill.</p>  <p>Any individual who is granted a waiver and holds a current Tier 4 background investigation (High Risk Public Trust)&nbsp;shall be subject to a Tier 5 (Critical Sensitive and Special Sensitive National Security)&nbsp;background investigation.</p> <p>The CBP may administer a polygraph examination to an applicant for employment or employee who is eligible for a waiver if information is discovered prior to the completion of a background investigation that results in a determination that an examination is necessary to make a final determination regarding suitability for employment or continued employment.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
