<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3563" measure-id="id115hr3563" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-28" update-date="2018-02-09">
<title>Veterans' Pathway to Citizenship Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3563v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-09">
<action-date>2017-07-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Veterans' Pathway to Citizenship Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide that a current or former member of the Armed Forces who would be eligible for naturalization but is not because of failure to complete a specified period of residence or physical presence within the United States or failure to maintain lawful permanent resident status shall be deemed to be a lawful permanent resident and to have fulfilled any residency and physical presence requirements solely for naturalization purposes. </p> <p> With respect to any such individual seeking naturalization: (1) a prior removal may be not taken into account for purposes of any immigration benefit or in determining deportability or inadmissibility, and (2) an offense for which a pardon was received may not be taken into account for naturalization purposes unless the offense was the same offense that caused the individual's separation from the Armed Forces in any manner other than honorable.</p> <p>A military recruiter or officer overseeing an enlistment shall inform every recruit of, and the Department of Homeland Security shall provide every separating member of the Armed Forces with notice of, naturalization options and available naturalization assistance services.</p> <p>In the case of a current or former member of the Armed Forces who would be eligible for naturalization but is not because of failure to timely file an application for naturalization, a subsequently filed naturalization application shall be reviewed as if it were timely filed. This provision is repealed one year after the date of enactment of the bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
