<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="567" measure-id="id115hr567" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-13" update-date="2017-09-11">
<title>RIGGED Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr567v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-11">
<action-date>2017-01-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Relatives in Government Getting Employment Dishonorably Act or the RIGGED Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends federal civil service law to revise the restrictions on the employment of relatives to: (1) make such restrictions applicable to the White House Office and the Executive Office of the President; and (2) include as a civilian position whose appointment, employment, promotion, or advancement is prohibited one acting in a professional or official capacity as a consultant or advisor, regardless of whether the position is voluntary, gratuitous, or authorized by law to be compensated.</p> <p>An individual appointed, employed, promoted, or advanced in violation of such restrictions shall be removed immediately.</p> <p>The bill makes provisions concerning prohibited personnel practices applicable to the White House Office. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
