<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1310" measure-id="id115hr1310" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-02" update-date="2017-08-07">
<title>SMASH Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1310v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-07">
<action-date>2017-03-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Strengthening Mosquito Abatement for Safety and Health Act or the SMASH Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to revise and extend through FY2023 Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) grants for mosquito control programs. The grant program is expanded so that grants may be used to address emerging, infectious mosquito-borne diseases and to improve existing control programs. The CDC must give preference to applicants that have: (1) a public health emergency due to a mosquito-borne disease, or (2) a control program that is consistent with existing state preparedness plans. The requirement for matching funds may be waived if the area covered by a grant applicant has an extreme need due to the size or density of the human population, the size or density of the mosquito population, or the severity of the mosquito-borne disease. </p> <p>CDC grants to help public health agencies improve surveillance and response activities are extended through FY2023.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must report on the surveillance and control of mosquito-borne infectious diseases in the United States and territories.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
