<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3507" measure-id="id115hr3507" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-27" update-date="2017-09-05">
<title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make permanent and modify the energy efficient commercial buildings deduction, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3507v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-05">
<action-date>2017-07-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the deduction for energy efficient commercial buildings, to: (1) make the deduction permanent, (2) permit 501(c)(3) tax-exempt organizations and Indian tribal governments to allocate the deduction to the person primarily responsible for designing the property in lieu of the owner of the property, (3) allow partnerships and S corporations to receive the full benefit of a deduction allocated at the partner or shareholder level, and (4) exempt property placed in service in a qualified low-income building from the requirement to reduce the basis of the property by the amount of the deduction. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
