<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="910" measure-id="id115hr910" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-07" update-date="2017-07-14">
<title>Fair Access to Investment Research Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr910v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-14">
<action-date>2017-05-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fair Access to Investment Research Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to establish and implement a "safe harbor" for certain investment fund research reports published by brokers and dealers. Such reports shall be deemed not to be "offers" under specified provisions of securities law, even if the broker or dealer participates in the registered offering of the investment fund's securities.</p> <p>In implementing the safe harbor, the SEC must prohibit a self-regulatory organization from maintaining or enforcing a rule that would prevent a member from: (1) publishing or distributing a covered investment fund research report solely because the member is also participating in a registered offering of the fund,&nbsp;or (2) participating in a registered offering of a covered investment fund solely because the member has published a research report about the fund.<strike></strike></p> <p>The bill restricts the SEC from conditioning the safe harbor upon specified requirements. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr910v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-03">
<action-date>2017-02-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fair Access to Investment Research Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to establish and implement a "safe harbor" for certain investment fund research reports published by brokers and dealers. Such reports shall be deemed not to be "offers" under specified provisions of securities law, even if the broker or dealer participates in the registered offering of the investment fund's securities.</p> <p>In implementing the safe harbor, the SEC must prohibit a self-regulatory organization from maintaining or enforcing a rule that would prevent a member from: (1) publishing or distributing a covered investment fund research report solely because the member is also participating in a registered offering of the fund,&nbsp;or (2) participating in a registered offering of a covered investment fund solely because the member has published a research report about the fund.<strike></strike></p> <p>The bill restricts the SEC from conditioning the safe harbor upon specified requirements. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
