<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2786" measure-id="id115hr2786" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-06" update-date="2017-10-17">
<title>To amend the Federal Power Act with respect to the criteria and process to qualify as a qualifying conduit hydropower facility.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2786v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-17">
<action-date>2017-07-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on July 12, 2017. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p>(Sec.1)This bill amends the Federal Power Act to revise the criteria for a facility to qualify as a qualifying conduit hydropower facility.</p> <p>Under current law, a hydropower facility must have a capacity that does not exceed five megawatts.This bill eliminates such requirement.</p> <p>Additionally, the bill revises the time frame from 45 days to 30 days for an entity to contest whether its hydroelectric facility meets the qualifying criteria.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2786v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-17">
<action-date>2017-07-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(Sec.1)This bill amends the Federal Power Act to revise the criteria for a facility to qualify as a qualifying conduit hydropower facility.</p> <p>Under current law, a hydropower facility must have a capacity that does not exceed five megawatts.This bill eliminates such requirement.</p> <p>Additionally, the bill revises the time frame from 45 days to 30 days for an entity to contest whether its hydroelectric facility meets the qualifying criteria.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2786v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-19">
<action-date>2017-06-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Federal Power Act to revise the criteria for a facility to qualify as a qualifying conduit hydropower facility.</p> <p>Under current law, a hydropower facility must have a capacity that does not exceed five megawatts.This bill eliminates such requirement.</p> <p>Additionally, the bill revises the timeframe for an entity to contest whether its hydroelectric facility meets the qualifying criteria.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
