<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4173" measure-id="id115hr4173" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-31" update-date="2017-11-15">
<title>Veterans Crisis Line Study Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4173v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-15">
<action-date>2017-11-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Veterans Crisis Line Study Act of 2017</strong></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to: (1) conduct a study on the outcomes and the efficacy of the toll-free Veterans Crisis Line during the five-year period beginning January 1, 2014, based on an analysis of national suicide data and data collected from the line, and (2) submit such study to Congress by May 31, 2019.</p> <p>Such study shall address: (1) the efficacy of the line in leading veterans to sustained mental health regimens and suicide prevention; (2) the line's visibility; (3) the role of the line as part of the VA's mental health care services; (4) whether receiving sustained mental health care affects suicidality and whether veterans previously receiving VA mental health care use the line in times of crisis; (5) the line's effectiveness in assisting veterans at risk for suicide when it is contacted by a non-veteran; (6) the line's overall efficacy in preventing suicides and whether the number of contacts affects such efficacy; (7) the line's long-term efficacy in preventing repeated suicide attempts and whether such efficacy is temporary; (8) whether referral to mental health care affects the risk of suicide; and (9) the line's efficacy in promoting continued mental health care for those veterans who are at high risk for suicide whose suicide was prevented. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4173v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-15">
<action-date>2017-11-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Veterans Crisis Line Study Act of 2017</strong></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to: (1) conduct a study on the outcomes and the efficacy of the toll-free Veterans Crisis Line during the five-year period beginning January 1, 2014, based on an analysis of national suicide data and data collected from the line, and (2) submit such study to Congress by March 1, 2020.</p> <p>Such study shall address: (1) the efficacy of the line in leading veterans to sustained mental health regimens and suicide prevention; (2) the line's visibility; (3) the role of the line as part of the VA's mental health care services; (4) whether receiving sustained mental health care affects suicidality and whether veterans previously receiving VA mental health care use the line in times of crisis; (5) the line's effectiveness in assisting veterans at risk for suicide when it is contacted by a non-veteran; (6) the line's overall efficacy in preventing suicides and whether the number of contacts affects such efficacy; (7) the line's long-term efficacy in preventing repeated suicide attempts and whether such efficacy is temporary; (8) whether referral to mental health care affects the risk of suicide; and (9) the line's efficacy in promoting continued mental health care for those veterans who are at high risk for suicide whose suicide was prevented. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4173v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-07">
<action-date>2017-10-31</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Veterans Crisis Line Study Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to conduct a study on the outcomes and the efficacy of the Veterans Crisis Line during the five-year period beginning January 1, 2014, based on an analysis of national suicide data and data collected from the line. </p> <p>Such study shall address: (1) the efficacy of the line in leading veterans to sustained mental health regimens and suicide prevention; (2) the line's visibility; (3) the role of the line as part of the VA's mental health care services; and (4) whether receiving sustained mental health care affects suicidality, including among veterans who are at high risk for suicide.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
