<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1075" measure-id="id115hr1075" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-15" update-date="2017-08-16">
<title>Freedom for Refugees Escaping Enmity (FREE) Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1075v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-16">
<action-date>2017-02-15</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Freedom for Refugees Escaping Enmity (FREE) Act</strong></p> <p>This bill nullifies Executive Order 13769, entitled &quot;Protecting the Nation from Foreign Terrorist Entry into the United States.&quot; No federal funds may be used to implement or enforce any of the policy changes set forth in such order. </p> <p>Among the order's major provisions are restrictions on the entry of immigrants and nonimmigrants from seven countries (Iran, Iraq, Libya, Somalia, Sudan, Syria, and Yemen) and additional limitations on refugee admissions to the United States. </p> <p>The Department of Homeland Security shall release any alien in custody under authority of such order. Visas or documentation that were revoked or refused under authority of such order shall be reissued or reconsidered as appropriate unless a consular officer knows, or has reason to believe, that the alien is ineligible to receive the visa or documentation under any provision of the immigration laws.</p> <p>The Immigration and Nationality Act is amended to prohibit an alien from being given immigration visa preference, being discriminated against, or being denied U.S. entry or admission based upon religion or lack of religious beliefs.</p> <p>The President may may not exercise his or her authority to suspend or restrict the U.S. entry of aliens or classes of aliens so as to modify the entry, reentry, or admission requirements of an alien having a valid and unexpired: (1) immigrant or nonimmigrant visa, or (2) refugee or legal permanent resident status. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
