<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3388" measure-id="id115hr3388" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-25" update-date="2017-09-06">
<title>To amend title 49, United States Code, regarding the authority of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration over highly automated vehicles, to provide safety measures for such vehicles, and for other purposes</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3388v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-06">
<action-date>2017-07-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Designating Each Car's Automation Level Act or the DECAL Act</b> </p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Transportation (DOT) to:</p> <ul> <li> complete research to determine the most cost effective method and terminology for informing consumers about the capabilities and limitations of each highly automated vehicle or each vehicle that performs partial driving automation; and</li> <li>determine whether such information includes terminology as defined by SAE International in Recommended Practice Report J3016 (published September 2016) or alternative terminology.</li> </ul> <p>After completion of such research, DOT shall initiate a rulemaking proceeding to require manufacturers to inform consumers about such information.</p> <p>The bill defines: (1) a &quot;highly automated vehicle&quot; as a motor vehicle, other than a commercial motor vehicle, that is equipped with an automated driving system; and (2) an &quot;automated driving system&quot; as the hardware and software of a vehicle that are collectively capable of performing the entire dynamic driving task on a sustained basis, regardless of whether such system is limited to a specific operational design domain.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
