<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2798" measure-id="id115hr2798" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-07" update-date="2018-02-26">
<title>No Russian DACHA Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2798v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-26">
<action-date>2017-06-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>No Russian Diplomatic Access to Compounds Here in America Act or No Russian DACHA Act</b></p> <p>This bill prohibits the President from allowing access by the government of the Russian Federation or its personnel to Russian-owned diplomatic facilities and properties at Pioneer Point in Centreville, Maryland, and in Upper Brookville, New York. </p> <p>Before taking any action to waive or otherwise limit the application of such prohibition, the President must submit to specified congressional committees and the majority and minority leaders of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report that describes the proposed action and certifies that the Russian government: (1) did not use such facilities and properties for intelligence-related purposes, and (2) has ceased the harassment of U.S. government diplomatic personnel in Russia. </p> <p>The bill provides for a period of congressional review of such report and certification and prohibits the President from taking any such action if Congress passes a joint resolution disapproving it. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
