<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1411" measure-id="id115hr1411" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-07" update-date="2017-09-14">
<title>Transparent Summer Flounder Quotas Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1411v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-14">
<action-date>2017-03-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Transparent Summer Flounder Quotas Act</b></p> <p>This bill addresses rules governing summer flounder fisheries.</p> <p>As applicable to summer flounder, the rule submitted by the National Marine Fisheries Service (NMFS) titled &quot;Fisheries of the Northeastern United States; Summer Flounder, Scup, and Black Sea Bass Fisheries; 2017-2018 Summer Flounder Specifications and Announcement of 2017 Summer Flounder and Black Sea Bass Commercial Accountability Measures&quot; isnullified.The rule published in the Federal Register on December 22, 2016, establishes summer flounder quotas for the 2017-2018 recreational and commercial fishing seasons.</p> <p>The prior regulations governing summer flounder shall apply until the NMFS completes a new summer flounder stock assessment and establishes a new rule based on the stock assessment. (The prior regulations titled &quot;Fisheries of the Northeastern United States; Summer Flounder, Scup, and Black Sea Bass Fisheries; 2016-2018 Summer Flounder, Scup, and Black Sea Bass Specifications&quot; were published in the Federal Register on December 28, 2015, and effective as of January 1, 2016.)</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
