<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2655" measure-id="id115hr2655" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-25" update-date="2018-02-09">
<title>Small Business Innovation Protection Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2655v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-09">
<action-date>2017-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Small Business Innovation Protection Act of 2017</b> </p> <p>This bill directs the Small Business Administration (SBA) and the Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) to enter into a partnership agreement to: </p> <ul> <li>develop high-quality training for small business concerns related to domestic and international protection of intellectual property and how such protections should be considered in small business concerns' business plans and growth strategies, and</li> <li>leverage existing training materials already developed to educate inventors and small business concerns. </li> </ul> <p>Such training may be provided by the SBA, the USPTO, or SBA development centers (SBDCs): (1) through electronic resources, including Internet-based webinars, and (2) at physical locations, including an SBDC or the headquarters or regional office of the USPTO.</p> <p>The bill amends the Small Business Act to require services at an SBDC to include training, developed by the SBA and the USPTO, in person or through a website relating to: (1) domestic and international intellectual property protections, and (2) how such protections should be considered in the business plans and growth strategies of small business concerns.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
