<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2255" measure-id="id115hr2255" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-28" update-date="2018-02-20">
<title>HOME Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2255v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-20">
<action-date>2018-01-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong></strong></p> <p>TITLE I--HOUSING OPPORTUNITIES MADE EASIER </p> <p>(Sec. 101) This bill amends the Truth in Lending Act to deem mortgage appraisal services donated by a fee appraiser to an organization that is eligible to receive tax-deductible charitable contributions to be customary and reasonable.</p> <p>TITLE II--EXPANDING ACCESS TO CAPITAL FOR RURAL JOB CREATORS </p> <p>(Sec. 201) The bill amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation within the Securities and Exchange Commission to report on issues encountered by rural-area small businesses.</p> <p>TITLE III--SENIOR SAFE <p>(Sec. 301) The bill extends immunity from liability to certain individuals who, in good faith and with reasonable care,&nbsp;disclose the suspected exploitation of a senior citizen to a regulatory or law-enforcement agency. Specifically, this immunity shall&nbsp;apply to certain credit-union, depository-institution, investment-adviser, broker-dealer,&nbsp;transfer-agency, insurance-company,&nbsp;and insurance-agency employees who&nbsp;have&nbsp;received specified training related&nbsp;to identifying&nbsp;and reporting&nbsp;the suspected exploitation of a senior citizen. Similarly,&nbsp;the employing&nbsp;financial institution shall not be liable with respect to&nbsp;disclosures made by such employees. </p> <p>(Sec. 302) The bill allows financial institutions and third-party entities to offer training related to the suspected financial exploitation of a senior citizen to specified employees. The bill provides guidance regarding the content, timing, and record-maintenance requirements of such training.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2255v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-07">
<action-date>2017-04-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Housing Opportunities Made Easier Act or the HOME Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Truth in Lending Act to deem mortgage appraisal services donated by a fee appraiser to an organization that is eligible to receive tax-deductible charitable contributions to be customary and reasonable. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
