<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2839" measure-id="id115hr2839" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-08" update-date="2017-06-26">
<title>Acupuncture for Heroes and Seniors Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2839v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-26">
<action-date>2017-06-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Acupuncture for Heroes and Seniors Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill provides access to qualified acupuncturist services for: (1) military members and their dependents under the TRICARE program, and (2) veterans enrolled in the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) health care system.</p> <p>The position of certified, trained acupuncturist for civilian employees in the Department of Defense shall be the grade of GS-12 or higher under the General Schedule. </p> <p>The VA shall carry out such program at in at least one VA facility in each Veterans Integrated Service Network in both urban and rural areas.</p> <p>The VA shall establish the Advisory Committee on Acupuncturist Services. </p> <p>Title XVIII of the Social Security Act is amended to provide Medicare coverage for acupuncturist services.</p> <p>The Public Health Act is amended to make acupuncturists eligible for appointment as officers in the commissioned Regular Corps and the Ready Reserve Corps of the Public Health Service.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
