<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1388" measure-id="id115hr1388" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-07" update-date="2017-07-31">
<title>CLEAN Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1388v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-31">
<action-date>2017-03-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Clean Legislating and Ethical Accountability Now Act or the CLEAN Act</b></p> <p>This bill enacts H.Res. 895, 110th Congress (establishing the Office of Congressional Ethics [OCE]) into permanent law, except that:</p> <ul> <li>the OCE shall be treated as a standing House committee for purposes of procuring the temporary or intermittent services of individual consultants or organizations to study or advise the OCE on matters within its jurisdiction or on its administration of affairs,</li> <li>references to the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct shall be construed to be references to the House Committee on Ethics,</li> <li>the prohibition on members of the OCE board serving more than four consecutive Congresses shall not apply,</li> <li>individuals appointed for the remainder of a Congress may be reappointed for a second additional term of two Congresses,</li> <li>individuals who are subjects of a preliminary review or second-phase review by the board shall be informed of the right to be represented by counsel, and invoking that right should not be held negatively against them,</li> <li> the OCE may not take actions that would deny persons rights or protection provided under the Constitution; and </li> <li> the OCE shall have the same subpoena power as a House standing committee.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
