<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1271" measure-id="id115hr1271" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-01" update-date="2018-02-01">
<title>DXM Abuse Prevention Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1271v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-01">
<action-date>2017-03-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>DXM Abuse Prevention Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to: (1)&nbsp;require a retailer that sells&nbsp;certain drugs containing dextromethorphan (DXM) to have a verification system that is&nbsp;intended to ensure that no one under 18 years of age purchases such drugs from the retailer, (2)&nbsp;establish other restrictions on&nbsp;the sale of over-the-counter drugs containing DXM, and (3)&nbsp;establish restrictions on the distribution of bulk DXM.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
