<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1433" measure-id="id115hr1433" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-08" update-date="2017-10-05">
<title>Strengthening Preventive Health Care for Service Members Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1433v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-05">
<action-date>2017-03-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Strengthening Preventive Health Care for Service Members Act</strong></p> <p>This bill expands preventive health care services under the Department of Defense's (DOD) TRICARE program to include services comparable to coverage provided by a group health plan and a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage under the Public Health Service Act, including certain: (1) evidence-based items or services; (2) immunizations; (3) evidence-informed preventive care and screenings for infants, children, and adolescents; and (4) additional preventive care and screenings for women. </p> <p>Persons entitled to such medical care shall also be entitled to other evidence-based preventive health care services and screenings, as DOD may prescribe.</p> <p>DOD shall prescribe regulations to: (1) waive certain copayments for preventive services for beneficiaries, and (2) ensure that a beneficiary pays nothing for such preventive services without regard to whether the beneficiary has reached his or her annual deductible.</p> <p>The bill makes immunizations and health promotion and disease prevention visits available to all dependents. (Currently, different health care provisions apply to dependents based upon whether they are under, or at least, six years old.)</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
