<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1749" measure-id="id115hr1749" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-28" update-date="2017-12-04">
<title>VET CARE Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1749v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-04">
<action-date>2017-03-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Veterans Early Treatment for Chronic Ailment Resurgence through Examinations Act of 2017 or the VET CARE Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to: (1) carry out a four-year pilot program in five Veterans Health Administration facilities to provide outpatient dental services and treatment, and related dental appliances, to eligible veterans at no cost; and (2) determine whether there is a correlation between veterans receiving such services and their suffering fewer complications of chronic ailments, thereby yielding a lower cost of care.</p> <p>&quot;Eligible veterans&quot; means veterans who are:</p> <ul> <li> enrolled in, but not eligible for dental care under, the VA's health care program; </li> <li> between 40 and 70 years of age; and</li> <li> diagnosed with type 2 diabetes. </li> </ul> <p> Applicants shall receive an initial periodontal evaluation. Those diagnosed with periodontal disease that requires surgery shall be disqualified.</p> <p>The VA shall enroll at least 1,500 eligible veterans, one-third of whom shall have been diagnosed with no or mild periodontitis and two-thirds of whom shall have been diagnosed with moderate to severe periodontitis.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
