<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2651" measure-id="id115hr2651" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-25" update-date="2018-02-24">
<title>Horseracing Integrity Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2651v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-24">
<action-date>2017-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Horseracing Integrity Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill establishes the Horseracing Anti-Doping and Medication Control Authority as an independent non-profit corporation with responsibility for developing and administering an anti-doping and medication control program for: (1) Thoroughbred, Quarter, and Standardbred horses that participate in horse races that have a substantial relation to interstate commerce, (2) such horse races, and (3) the personnel engaged in the care, training, or racing of such horses.</p> <p>The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) shall have exclusive jurisdiction over all horse racing anti-doping and medication control matters. The Authority and such FTC jurisdiction shall terminate if an interstate compact providing for services consistent with such program is established within five years after the program takes effect. </p> <p>The Authority may enter into agreements with state racing commissions to implement the program within their jurisdictions.</p> <p>Program elements shall include:</p> <ul> <li>anti-doping and medication control rules, </li> <li>lists of permitted and prohibited substances and methods, </li> <li>a prohibition on the administration of any such substance within 24 hours of a horse's next racing start, and </li> <li>testing and laboratory standards.</li> </ul> <p>The Authority shall:</p> <ul> <li> develop, maintain, and publish such lists; </li> <li> establish a list of anti-doping and medication control rule violations applicable to either covered horses or persons;</li> <li> establish standards and the process for laboratory accreditation and sample testing; and</li> <li> promulgate rules for anti-doping and medication control results management, for the disciplinary process for violation results management, and for imposing sanctions for violations.</li> </ul> <p>The bill sets forth civil enforcement provisions. </p> <p>Activities under this bill are funded by an assessment placed on state racing commissions based on the calculation of cost per racing starter.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
