<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="595" measure-id="id115hr595" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-20" update-date="2017-12-19">
<title>Bailout Prevention Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr595v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-19">
<action-date>2017-01-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Bailout Prevention Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Reserve Act to declare a borrower ineligible to borrow from any emergency lending program or facility unless the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (the Board) and all federal banking regulators with jurisdiction over the borrower certify that, at the time the borrower initially borrows under the program or facility, the borrower is not insolvent. Solvency shall be assessed by examining the last four months of relevant financial data and determining whether the fair value of the borrower's assets exceeds its liabilities, with appropriate adjustment for temporary illiquidity in the relevant markets.</p> <p>A borrower shall be deemed insolvent for such purposes if it is in bankruptcy, resolution under title II of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, or any other federal or state insolvency proceedings, or is a bridge financial company or a bridge depository institution.</p> <p>A program shall be considered one with &quot;broad-based eligibility&quot; only if at least five companies are eligible to participate in the program in a significant manner.</p> <p>The annual interest rate for emergency lending must be at least 500 basis points greater than the cost of borrowing for the Treasury for a commensurate loan term. </p> <p>The Board may create an emergency lending program or facility that does not meet the broad-based eligibility requirement or the interest rate requirement, but only if Congress enacts into law a joint resolution of approval within 30 days.</p> <p>The bill reduces the timing of various reporting requirements of the Government Accountability Office and the Board from 1-2 years to 60 days.</p> <p> <p> <p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
