<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="794" measure-id="id115hr794" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-01" update-date="2017-10-05">
<title>EAC Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr794v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-05">
<action-date>2017-02-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>EAC Reauthorization Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to: (1) reauthorize the Election Assistance Commission through FY2022, (2) authorize funding to states for FY2018 for security upgrades to voter registration lists and processes and waive the 5% match requirement for these funds, (3) require each state to furnish to the commission such information as the commission may request for the purposes of conducting any post-election surveys of the states with respect to the administration of a regularly scheduled general election, and (4) require the National Institute of Standards and Technology to report on its use of funds transferred from the commission.</p> <p>The commission shall carry out an assessment: (1) of whether the voting systems available for use in the elections for federal office to be held in 2018 are adequate to meet the demands of such elections, and (2) of the security and effectiveness of the commission's information technology systems.</p> <p>The commission shall carry out a review of the effectiveness and efficiency of the state-based administrative complaint procedures established and maintained under such Act for the investigation and resolution of allegations of violations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
