<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4527" measure-id="id115hr4527" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-12-01" update-date="2018-02-05">
<title>Stop HATE Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4527v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-05">
<action-date>2017-12-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Stop Harmful and Abusive Telecommunications Expression Act of 2017 or the Stop HATE Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Commerce and the Department of Justice to report about the role of telecommunications in violent acts and the commission of crimes of hate against individuals or groups of individuals on the basis of race, gender and gender identity, religion, disability, sexual orientation, ethnicity, color, or national origin.</p> <p>The report must analyze information about the use of telecommunications to advocate and encourage violent acts and the commission of crimes of hate, including: (1)&nbsp;the role that such telecommunications are playing in giving groups that advocate and commit such crimes a platform to spread their messages and to organize; (2)&nbsp;how such use and the role of telecommunications have changed with new forms of communication on the Internet and other electronic media; and (3) any recommendations, consistent with the First Amendment, necessary to address such use and such role of telecommunications.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
