<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3140" measure-id="id115hr3140" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-29" update-date="2017-09-19">
<title>ACTION for National Service Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3140v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-19">
<action-date>2017-06-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>America's Call To Improve Opportunities Now for National Service Act or the ACTION for National Service Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the National and Community Service Act of 1990 and the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 to reestablish the Corporation for National and Community Service&nbsp;as an independent executive agency called the National and Community Service Administration.</p> <p>An individual who successfully completes a term of full-time national service shall be entitled to a national service educational award equal to twice the amount of tuition for the institution of higher education where the individual is enrolled, not to exceed twice the average in-state tuition. Current law limits the award's value to the maximum amount of a Federal Pell Grant that&nbsp;an individual is eligible to receive in the aggregate.</p> <p>Within the administration, the bill establishes an interagency working group to evaluate specified issues related to: (1) eligibility for tuition and student loan repayment assistance with regard to participation in certain national or volunteer service programs, (2) the advisability of granting federal hiring preference to certain volunteer program participants, and (3) methods for increasing the participation of seniors in national service programs.</p> <p>The National Service Foundation,&nbsp;a nonprofit corporation established by the bill, shall accept and administer gifts&nbsp;made in connection with&nbsp;the administration.</p> <p>The bill expresses support for the authorization of appropriations sufficient to provide, within 10 years,&nbsp;volunteer service opportunities for at least 1 million volunteers in full-time national service annually.</p> <p>The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude AmeriCorps educational awards from gross income.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
