<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3342" measure-id="id115hr3342" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-20" update-date="2017-11-09">
<title>Sanctioning Hizballah's Illicit Use of Civilians as Defenseless Shields Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3342v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-09">
<action-date>2017-10-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House reported version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Sanctioning Hizballah's Illicit Use of Civilians as Defenseless Shields Act</b></p> <p> (Sec. 3) This bill states that it shall be U.S. policy to condemn Hizballah's use of human shields as a gross violation of internationally recognized human rights and act against those that engage in such practice.</p> <p> (Sec. 4) The President is urged to use U.S. influence at the United Nations Security Council to secure support for a resolution imposing multilateral sanctions against Hizballah for its use of human shields.</p> <p> (Sec. 5) The President shall: </p> <ul> <li> transmit to Congress and update a list of each foreign person or entity that is a member of, or acting on behalf of, Hizballah and that is responsible for, or complicit in, the use of human shields and each foreign person, entity, or instrumentality of a foreign state that has supported or facilitated such person or entity; and </li> <li>impose U.S.-based property blocking and visa sanctions, including revocation of existing visas, against such person, entity, or instrumentality.</li> </ul> <p>The President may waive the application of sanctions for up to 120 days if the President reports to Congress that such waiver is vital to national security interests.</p> <p> (Sec. 6) The President shall report to Congress on whether the following persons or instrumentalities meet sanctions criteria: (1) the Secretary General of Hizballah; (2) members of the Hizballah Politburo; (3) other senior members of Hizballah or other associated entities as the President determines appropriate; and (4) any person, agency, or instrumentality of a foreign state that provides material support to Hizballah's use of civilian human shields.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3342v28" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-09">
<action-date>2017-10-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment, Part I</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Sanctioning Hizballah's Illicit Use of Civilians as Defenseless Shields Act</b></p> <p> (Sec. 3) This bill states that it shall be U.S. policy to condemn Hizballah's use of human shields as a gross violation of internationally recognized human rights and act against those that engage in such practice.</p> <p> (Sec. 4) The President is urged to use U.S. influence at the United Nations Security Council to secure support for a resolution imposing multilateral sanctions against Hizballah for its use of human shields.</p> <p> (Sec. 5) The President shall: </p> <ul> <li> transmit to Congress and update a list of each foreign person or entity that is a member of, or acting on behalf of, Hizballah and that is responsible for, or complicit in, the use of human shields and each foreign person, entity, or instrumentality of a foreign state that has supported or facilitated such person or entity; and </li> <li>impose U.S.-based property blocking and visa sanctions, including revocation of existing visas, against such person, entity, or instrumentality.</li> </ul> <p>The President may waive the application of sanctions for up to 120 days if the President reports to Congress that such waiver is vital to national security interests.</p> <p> (Sec. 6) The President shall report to Congress on whether the following persons or instrumentalities meet sanctions criteria: (1) the Secretary General of Hizballah; (2) members of the Hizballah Politburo; (3) other senior members of Hizballah or other associated entities that the President determines appropriate; and (4) any person, agency, or instrumentality of a foreign state that provides material support to Hizballah's use of civilian human shields. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3342v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-31">
<action-date>2017-07-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Sanctioning Hizballah's Illicit Use of Civilians as Defenseless Shields Act</b></p> <p>This bill states that it shall be U.S. policy to condemn Hizballah's use of human shields as a gross violation of internationally recognized human rights. </p> <p>The President is urged to use U.S. influence at the United Nations Security Council to secure support for a resolution imposing multilateral sanctions against Hizballah for its use of human shields.</p> <p>The President shall: </p> <ul> <li> transmit to Congress and update a list of each foreign person or entity that is a member of, or acting on behalf of, Hizballah and that is responsible for, or complicit in, the use of human shields and each foreign person, entity, or instrumentality of a foreign state that has supported or facilitated such person or entity; </li> <li>impose asset blocking and U.S. exclusion sanctions against such person, entity, or instrumentality; and </li> <li>report to Congress on whether specified persons or instrumentalities meet such sanctions criteria. </li> </ul> <p>The President may waive the application of such sanctions for up to 120 days if the President reports that such waiver is vital to national security interests.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
