<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2664" measure-id="id115hr2664" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-25" update-date="2017-09-21">
<title>Enhancing Detection of Human Trafficking Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2664v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-21">
<action-date>2017-07-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>Enhancing Detection of Human Trafficking Act</strong></p> <p> (Sec. 3) This bill directs the Department of Labor to implement a program to: (1) train and periodically retrain relevant Labor personnel to detect and assist law enforcement in preventing human trafficking during the course of their primary roles and responsibilities, and (2) ensure that such personnel regularly receive current information on matters related to the detection of human trafficking.</p> <p> Such training may be conducted through in-class or virtual learning capabilities and shall include: (1) methods for identifying suspected victims and perpetrators of human trafficking, (2) location- or environment-specifiic training, (3) other topics that reflect current trends and best practices for particular locations or professional environments, (4) a course of action for referring human trafficking cases to the Department of Justice and other appropriate authorities, and (5) post-training evaluation. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) Labor shall report to Congress annually regarding: (1) the effectiveness of the training, (2) the number of Labor employees who have completed such training, (3) the number of of human trafficking cases referred to Labor personnel, and (4) the metrics used to measure and track responses.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2664v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-22">
<action-date>2017-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhancing Detection of Human Trafficking Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Labor to implement a program to: (1) train and periodically retrain relevant Labor personnel to detect and assist law enforcement in preventing human trafficking during the course of their primary roles and responsibilities, and (2) ensure that such personnel regularly receive current information on matters related to the detection of human trafficking.</p> <p>Labor shall report annually to Congress regarding the effectiveness of the training, the number of Labor employees who have completed such training, and the number of of human trafficking cases referred to Labor personnel.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
