<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2931" measure-id="id115hr2931" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-16" update-date="2017-06-26">
<title>Community Economic Assistance Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2931v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-26">
<action-date>2017-06-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Community Economic Assistance Act of 2017 </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for the establishment of community economic assistance zones that are eligible for certain tax deductions and credits.</p> <p>A zone must be nominated by the governor of the state where it is located and designated by the Department of the Treasury. A nominated area must:</p> <ul> <li>have received a Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act notice after December 31, 2014, and met other criteria related to loss of employment;</li> <li>have been (or will be) seriously impacted by changes in trade through loss of employment; or</li> <li>satisfy at least two specified conditions, including status as an energy-transitioning or low-income community and other factors related to employment and economic activity. </li> </ul> <p>For businesses or individuals located in or investing in a zone, the bill allows: </p> <ul> <li> an employment tax credit, </li> <li> increased expensing, </li> <li> nonrecognition of gain from certain investments, </li> <li> a 3-year carryback of net operating losses, </li> <li> a tax credit for bonds issued for a community economic development plan, </li> <li> a 15-year depreciation period for certain rebuilt and retrofitted property, </li> <li>an increased deduction for start-up expenditures, and </li> <li> an increased new markets tax credit. </li> </ul> <p>Treasury must approve community economic development plans using specified criteria and may award grants for assessments to develop the plans. </p> <p>The Department of Commerce must deploy teams to provide support and assistance to a region if: (1) it is requested by the governor, and (2) the region is experiencing or threatened with an abrupt rise of unemployment or other specified economic hardships. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
