<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4338" measure-id="id115hr4338" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-11-09" update-date="2018-01-24">
<title>Chuck Osier Burial Benefits Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4338v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-24">
<action-date>2017-11-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Chuck Osier Burial Benefits Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs, upon request and at U.S. expense, to furnish to a deceased individual in lieu a headstone or marker: (1) an urn to signify the individual's veteran status, in which such individual's remains may be placed at private expense; or (2) a commemorative plaque signifying the individual's veteran status. </p> <p> A &quot;deceased individual&quot; is an individual: (1) who served in the Armed Forces on or after April 6, 1917; (2) who is eligible for a headstone or marker or would be so eligible but for the date of the individual's death; and (3) whose remains were cremated and placed in a site of interment or inurnment other than a national cemetery, a state veterans' cemetery, a tribal cemetery, or a private cemetery.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
