<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2544" measure-id="id115hr2544" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-18" update-date="2018-01-29">
<title>Teacher Health and Wellness Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2544v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-29">
<action-date>2017-05-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Teacher Health and Wellness Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the National Institutes of Health to carry out a five-year study on reducing teacher stress and increasing teacher retention and well-being by implementing and analyzing the results of any of several types of innovative approaches that include:</p> <ul> <li>workplace wellness programs;</li> <li>social emotional learning programs;</li> <li>teacher stress management programs;</li> <li>mentoring and induction programs during the school year and teacher pre-service;</li> <li>organizational interventions such as principal training programs;</li> <li>teacher residency programs;</li> <li>complementary health approaches, such as mindfulness meditation; and</li> <li>school reorganization. </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
