<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1431" measure-id="id115hr1431" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-08" update-date="2017-04-14">
<title>EPA Science Advisory Board Reform Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1431v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-04-14">
<action-date>2017-03-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on March 27, 2017. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>EPA Science Advisory Board Reform Act of 2017</b></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill amends the Environmental Research, Development, and Demonstration Authorization Act of 1978 to revise the process of selecting members of the Science Advisory Board, guidelines for participation in board advisory activities, and terms of office. The board provides scientific advice to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). This bill requires the board to independently provide that advice.</p> <p>Among the revisions to requirements concerning the board's membership are the following:</p> <ul> <li>a requirement to balance scientific and technical points of view;</li> <li>a set minimum level of representation from state, local, or tribal governments;</li> <li>allowance of affiliation with, or representation of, entities that may have a potential interest in the board's advisory activities;</li> <li>conflict of interest restrictions;</li> <li>restrictions on participation in advisory activities involving review of a member's work; </li> <li>a prohibition on appointment of registered lobbyists; and</li> <li>prohibitions on member receipt of current EPA grants or contracts. </ul> <p>The EPA must make public a list of nominees to the board and accept public comments on the nominees. Reports filed upon the provisional nomination of a member disclosing financial relationships and interests must also be made public.</p> <p>The EPA must provide draft risk or hazard assessments in its regulatory proposals and documents to the board. The board's advice and comments must be included in the record regarding any such proposal and published in the Federal Register.</p> <p>The board's member committees and investigative panels must operate in accordance with the membership, participation, and policy requirements contained in this bill, including new requirements for public participation in advisory activities of the board. The member committees and investigative panels do not have the authority to make decisions on behalf of the board and may not report directly to the EPA. <p>The bill imposes additional public participation requirements, including: <ul> <li>The EPA and the board must make public all reports and relevant scientific information at the same time they are received by the board; </li> <li>The board must hold public information-gathering sessions to discuss the state of the science related to a major advisory activity; </li> <li>Prior to convening a member committee or investigative panel, the EPA must accept and address public comments on questions asked of the board, and </li> <li>The board, member committees, and investigative panels may not accept a question that unduly narrows the scope of an advisory activity. </li> </ul> <p>In carrying out its advisory activities, the board must: (1) strive to avoid making policy determinations or recommendations, (2) communicate uncertainties associated with the scientific advice provided to the EPA or Congress, (3) encourage dissenting members to make their views known, (4) conduct periodic reviews to ensure that its activities address the most important scientific issues affecting the EPA, and (5) respond to Congress fully and in a timely manner. <p>(Sec. 3) This bill shall not be construed as supplanting the requirements of the Federal Advisory Committee Act or the Ethics in Government Act of 1978.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1431v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-04-10">
<action-date>2017-03-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>EPA Science Advisory Board Reform Act of 2017</b></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill amends the Environmental Research, Development, and Demonstration Authorization Act of 1978 to revise the process of selecting members of the Science Advisory Board, guidelines for participation in board advisory activities, and terms of office. The board provides scientific advice to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). This bill requires the board to independently provide that advice.</p> <p>Among the revisions to requirements concerning the board's membership are the following:</p> <ul> <li>a requirement to balance scientific and technical points of view;</li> <li>a set minimum level of representation from state, local, or tribal governments;</li> <li>allowance of affiliation with, or representation of, entities that may have a potential interest in the board's advisory activities;</li> <li>conflict of interest restrictions;</li> <li>restrictions on participation in advisory activities involving review of a member's work; </li> <li>a prohibition on appointment of registered lobbyists; and</li> <li>prohibitions on member receipt of current EPA grants or contracts. </ul> <p>The EPA must make public a list of nominees to the board and accept public comments on the nominees. Reports filed upon the provisional nomination of a member disclosing financial relationships and interests must also be made public.</p> <p>The EPA must provide draft risk or hazard assessments in its regulatory proposals and documents to the board. The board's advice and comments must be included in the record regarding any such proposal and published in the Federal Register.</p> <p>The board's member committees and investigative panels must operate in accordance with the membership, participation, and policy requirements contained in this bill, including new requirements for public participation in advisory activities of the board. The member committees and investigative panels do not have the authority to make decisions on behalf of the board and may not report directly to the EPA. <p>The bill imposes additional public participation requirements, including: <ul> <li>The EPA and the board must make public all reports and relevant scientific information at the same time they are received by the board; </li> <li>The board must hold public information-gathering sessions to discuss the state of the science related to a major advisory activity; </li> <li>Prior to convening a member committee or investigative panel, the EPA must accept and address public comments on questions asked of the board, and </li> <li>The board, member committees, and investigative panels may not accept a question that unduly narrows the scope of an advisory activity. </li> </ul> <p>In carrying out its advisory activities, the board must: (1) strive to avoid making policy determinations or recommendations, (2) communicate uncertainties associated with the scientific advice provided to the EPA or Congress, (3) encourage dissenting members to make their views known, (4) conduct periodic reviews to ensure that its activities address the most important scientific issues affecting the EPA, and (5) respond to Congress fully and in a timely manner. <p>(Sec. 3) This bill shall not be construed as supplanting the requirements of the Federal Advisory Committee Act or the Ethics in Government Act of 1978.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1431v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-03-29">
<action-date>2017-03-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>EPA Science Advisory Board Reform Act of 2017</b></p> <p> This bill amends the Environmental Research, Development, and Demonstration Authorization Act of 1978 to revise the process of selecting members of the Science Advisory Board, guidelines for participation in board advisory activities, and terms of office. The board provides scientific advice to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA). This bill requires the board to independently provide that advice. Registered lobbyists may not be appointed to the board. Board members may not have current grants or contracts from the EPA and may not apply for them for three years following the end of their board term. </p> <p>The EPA must provide draft risk or hazard assessments in its regulatory proposals and documents to the board. The board's advice and comments must be included in the record regarding those proposals and published in the Federal Register.</p> <p>The board's member committees and investigative panels must operate in accordance with the membership, participation, and policy requirements contained in this bill, including new requirements for public participation in advisory activities of the board. <p>The board must: (1) strive to avoid making policy determinations or recommendations, (2) communicate uncertainties, (3) encourage dissenting members to make their views known, (4) conduct periodic reviews to ensure that its activities address the most important scientific issues affecting the EPA, and (5) respond to Congress fully and in a timely manner. <p> This bill may not be construed as supplanting the requirements of the Federal Advisory Committee Act or the Ethics in Government Act of 1978.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
