<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3998" measure-id="id115hr3998" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-10" update-date="2018-04-05">
<title>Protect America Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3998v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-04-05">
<action-date>2017-10-10</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Protect America Act of </b><b>2017</b></p> <p><i>Preventing Terrorists From Obtaining Firearms Act of 2017</i></p> <p>This bill amends the federal criminal code to authorize the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives (ATF) or a U.S. Attorney's Office to delay for up to 72 hours and file an emergency petition to prohibit a firearm transfer to a person who is being investigated, or who during the past five years has been investigated, as a known or suspected terrorist. <p><i>Preventing Terrorists From Obtaining Explosives Act of </i><i>2017</i></p> <p>Additionally, the bill authorizes the ATF or a U.S. Attorney's Office to delay for up to 90 days and file an emergency petition to prohibit the approval of an application for an explosives permit or license from a person who is being investigated, or who during the past five years has been investigated, as a known or suspected terrorist.</p> <p>The bill requires the Department of Justice to review the terrorist watch and no-fly lists and remove the name of any person whose name was erroneously placed on such lists.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
