<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2690" measure-id="id115hr2690" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-25" update-date="2017-09-18">
<title>Agricultural Worker Program Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2690v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-18">
<action-date>2017-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Agricultural Worker Program Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to confer blue card status upon an alien who: (1) has performed specified periods of U.S. agricultural employment or is a qualifying alien's spouse or child, (2) has been physically present in the United States for a qualifying period, (3) applied for such status during the application period, (4) is not ineligible under specified grounds for such status, (5) has passed security and law enforcement clearances, and (6) has paid the required fees and penalties.</p> <p>Blue card status is limited to eight years.</p> <p>A blue card alien (individual) may: (1) work in the United States, and (2) travel from and return to the United States, including commuting to the United States from a foreign residence.</p> <p>DHS shall adjust an individual's blue card status to lawful permanent resident status if the individual: (1) performs a specified period of qualifying agricultural employment, (2) applies before the expiration of his or her blue card status, and (3) pays a required fine and satisfies any federal tax liability. The bill also provides for status adjustment of such an individual's qualifying spouse and child.</p> <p>The bill enumerates: (1) grounds for revocation of blue card status or denial of permanent resident status, (2) protections for aliens apprehended before or during the application period or in removal proceedings, and (3) employer protections.</p> <p> Such an individual: (1) is ineligible for any federal means-tested benefit, and (2) may correct certain social security records.</p> <p>DHS shall report to Congress, after six months and annually for the next eight years, on the blue card program.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
