<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2067" measure-id="id115hr2067" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2018-02-08">
<title>Cents and Sensibility Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2067v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-08">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Cents and Sensibility Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires that the one-cent, five-cent, ten-cent, and quarter-dollar coins be: (1) produced primarily of steel, and (2) treated to impart a color so that their appearance is similar to coins produced previously.</p> <p>In minting these coins, Treasury shall use steel produced only in the United States unless: (1) doing so would be inconsistent with the public interest, or (2) an adequate supply of the appropriate grade of steel is not produced in the United States in sufficient and reasonably available quantities.</p> <p>In setting specifications for these coins, Treasury may not: (1) require more than one change to coin-accepting and coin-handling equipment to accommodate new coins produced; (2) facilitate or allow the use of a coin with a lesser value produced by another country, or the use of any token or other easily or regularly produced metal device of minimal value, in the place of a circulating coin produced by Treasury; or (3) require non-trivial changes to coin-accepting or coin-handling equipment to easily accommodate continued co-circulation of both old and new coins. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
