<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2565" measure-id="id115hr2565" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-19" update-date="2017-12-18">
<title>To require the use of replacement cost value in determining the premium rates for flood insurance coverage under the National Flood Insurance Act, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2565v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-18">
<action-date>2017-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(Sec. 1) This bill directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to incorporate the replacement cost value of a structure insured under the National Flood Insurance Program of 1968 in its consideration of chargeable premium rates.</p> <p>FEMA must conduct a study regarding risk rating redesign utilizing replacement cost and report the findings to Congress.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2565v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-04">
<action-date>2017-05-19</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to direct the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to incorporate the replacement cost value of a structure insured under the National Flood Insurance Program of 1968 in its consideration of chargeable premium rates.</p> <p>FEMA must conduct a study regarding risk rating redesign utilizing replacement cost and report the findings to Congress.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
