<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="796" measure-id="id115hr796" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-01" update-date="2017-11-16">
<title>Drain the Swamp Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr796v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-16">
<action-date>2017-02-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Drain the Swamp Act of 2017 </b></p> <p>This bill increases the ban on certain former executive branch officials, Members of Congress, and legislative staff within five years of termination of employment to knowingly make, with the intent to influence, any communication or appearance before an officer or employee of the executive branch, a Member of Congress or their staff, or any other legislative office on behalf of any other person (except the United States). The bill establishes penalties for such violations. The bill eliminates a similar two-year ban on certain senior executive branch officials.</p> <p>The bill creates a lifetime ban on certain senior personnel of the executive branch (including independent agencies) from representing, aiding, or advising foreign entities.</p> <p>The bill broadens the definition of lobbying activities in the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to also include consulting and advising. The bill amends the definition of lobbyist in the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to include individuals who spend at least 10% of their time engaged in lobbying services to one client in a 3-month period. </p> <p>The scope of prohibitions on foreign nationals is expanded to include soliciting a contribution or donation in connection with a federal, state, or local election; to a political party; or for an electioneering communication.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
