<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="802" measure-id="id115hr802" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-01" update-date="2017-05-16">
<title>Aid to Allies Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr802v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-16">
<action-date>2017-02-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Aid to Allies Act</strong></p> <p>This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: </p> <ul> <li>in periods of constrained resources all budget items deserve scrutiny, especially foreign aid dollars; </li> <li>rather than assisting governments that undermine our allies, such dollars would be better spent in countries that support the shared interests of the American people; and </li> <li>the Board of the Millennium Challenge Corporation should not enter into any compact with Senegal until the board reports to Congress regarding Senegal's eligibility to meet specified democratic and economic criteria that consider the impact of Senegal's co-sponsorship of U.N. Security Council Resolution 2334 and other governance issues with respect to Senegal. </li> </ul> <p>Such resolution characterizes Israeli settlements in the West Bank and East Jerusalem as illegal and demands cessation of settlement activities. </p> <p>The bill prohibits Senegal from receiving certain development assistance under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 for two years and makes such assistance available to Rwanda and Uganda.</p> <p>The President's Malaria Initiative, the Feed the Future program, and the President's Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief are exempted from such prohibition.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
