<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="851" measure-id="id115hr851" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-03" update-date="2018-02-05">
<title>Housing Financial Literacy Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr851v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-05">
<action-date>2017-02-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Housing Financial Literacy Act of 2017 </b></p> <p>This bill amends the National Housing Act to&nbsp;modify the&nbsp;discount&nbsp;given by&nbsp;the Federal Housing Administration (FHA) on single-family mortgage-insurance premium payments for first-time homebuyers who complete a financial-management counseling program. Under current law, the maximum premium amount for such homebuyers is 2.75% of the original insured principal obligation of the mortgage (compared to 3% for other homebuyers). The bill instead&nbsp;requires that the maximum premium amount for such homebuyers be 25 basis points (0.25% of the original insured principal obligation of mortgage) lower than the amount otherwise established by the FHA.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
