<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1915" measure-id="id115hr1915" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-05" update-date="2017-08-23">
<title>To amend the Small Business Act to provide the Administrator of the Small Business Administration authority to increase amount for general business loans, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1915v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-23">
<action-date>2017-04-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Small Business Act to provide that if the amount of Small Business Administration (SBA) commitments for authorized general business loans for a fiscal year exceeds the limit on the total amount of commitments the SBA may make for such loans under such Act, the SBA may make such commitments for such loans for such fiscal year in a total amount equal to up to 120% of that limit. </p> <p>The SBA may not exercise this authority without prior approval of specified congressional committees. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
