<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="4749" measure-id="id115hr4749" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2018-01-09" update-date="2018-03-22">
<title>Truth in Certification for Foreign Food Ingredients Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr4749v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-22">
<action-date>2018-01-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Truth in Certification for Foreign Food Ingredients Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 to require the Foreign Agricultural Service (FAS) to carry out a program to enhance transparency and traceability of food products and ingredients that are exported to the United States in order to protect consumers and food manufacturers against mislabeling, adulteration, and fraud. </p> <p>Under the program, the FAS must provide foreign government officials, agricultural producers, and exporters of food products and ingredients to the United States with technical assistance and best practices to improve: (1) transparency, traceability and fraud prevention; and (2) cooperation with private certification and verification bodies to ensure the accuracy and integrity of their food product and ingredient certification and verification. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
