<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="742" measure-id="id115hr742" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-30" update-date="2017-10-04">
<title>To prohibit any hiring freeze from affecting any Department of Defense position at, or in support of, a public shipyard.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr742v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-04">
<action-date>2017-01-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill declares that the memorandum titled &quot;Presidential Memorandum Regarding the Hiring Freeze&quot; published on January 23, 2017, or any other action by the President to prevent a department or agency from filling vacant civilian employee positions or creating new such positions, shall have no force or effect with respect to any Department of Defense (DOD) civilian position under which an employee performs a DOD function at a public shipyard or a DOD function that directly supports a public shipyard.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
