<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3242" measure-id="id115hr3242" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-14" update-date="2017-12-18">
<title>To expand access to the Rural Community Facilities Program of the Department of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3242v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-18">
<action-date>2017-07-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to modify the requirements for the Department of Agriculture (USDA) Rural Community Facilities Program, which provides funding to develop essential community facilities in rural areas. </p> <p>For the purposes of the program, a &quot;rural area&quot; may not have a population of more than 20,000 inhabitants. The bill increases the limit to 35,000 inhabitants for determinations made under the program on or after April 1 of any fiscal year. In making a grant or loan on or after April 1, USDA must give priority to applications with respect to community facilities at which public safety, health care, and job training are to be provided. </p> <p>In awarding grants for essential community facilities technical assistance and training, USDA must allow applications for grants from qualified organizations for the sole purpose of providing on-site training and technical assistance on a national or multi-state regional basis. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
