<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1859" measure-id="id115hr1859" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-03" update-date="2017-12-05">
<title>To amend the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 to designate a portion of United States Route 15 in Pennsylvania as part of the Interstate System, and for other purposes.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1859v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-05">
<action-date>2017-04-03</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 to designate U.S. Route 15 in Pennsylvania from its intersection with Interstate Route 180 to the New York border as part of a high priority corridor on the National Highway System. Pennsylvania shall erect signs identifying such corridor as Interstate Route 99. </p> <p>The Department of Transportation is authorized to make grants to Pennsylvania for projects to:</p> <ul> <li>erect signs identifying the segment designated by this bill as part of the Interstate System (IS), and </li> <li>make improvements as necessary for such segment to conform with applicable IS standards. </li> </ul> <p>The bill permits vehicles that could operate legally on such segment before its designation as part of the IS to continue to operate on such segment without regard to IS vehicle weight limitations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
