<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3844" measure-id="id115hr3844" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-26" update-date="2017-10-03">
<title>End For-Profit Prisons Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3844v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-10-03">
<action-date>2017-09-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>End For-Profit Prisons Act of </b><b>2017</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Justice (DOJ) to phase out existing contracts with private prison companies and private community confinement facilities.</p> <p>It amends the federal criminal code to require federal employees to perform the core correctional services&#8212;housing, safeguarding, protecting, and disciplining of offenders&#8212;at correctional facilities used by the Bureau of Prisons (BOP) or the U.S. Marshals Service.</p> <p>The bill also prohibits the BOP from entering into or maintaining contracts with private companies to manage community confinement facilities (e.g., halfway houses).</p> <p>DOJ must evaluate the effectiveness of and develop guidelines for programs to improve community reintegration at community confinement facilities.</p> <p>The Marshals Service must annually inspect each correctional facility it uses for confinement. </p> <p>The BOP must provide to prisoners, as part of prerelease procedures, information and counseling about: criminal record expungement; educational, employment, and treatment programs; and applications for public assistance programs. The BOP must also provide prisoners with post-release information about fines, assessments, surcharges, restitution, and other penalties.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
