<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="341" measure-id="id115hr341" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-05" update-date="2017-03-01">
<title>Support Our Startups Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr341v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-03-01">
<action-date>2017-01-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Support Our Startups Act of 201</strong><b>7</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the amount of the tax deduction for business start-up expenses for taxable years beginning in 2017 or 2018. </p> <p>Under current law, start-up expenses are paid or incurred in connection with: (1) investigating the creation or acquisition of an active trade or business; (2) creating an active trade or business; or (3) any activity engaged in for profit and for the production of income before the day on which the active trade or business begins, in anticipation of the activity becoming an active trade or business. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
