<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1907" measure-id="id115hr1907" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-05" update-date="2017-08-09">
<title>Election Infrastructure and Security Promotion Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1907v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-09">
<action-date>2017-04-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Election Infrastructure and Security Promotion Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security to: (1) designate voting systems used in the United States as critical infrastructure; (2) include threats of compromise, disruption, or destruction of voting systems in national planning scenarios; and (3) conduct a campaign to proactively educate local election officials about the designation of voting systems as critical infrastructure and election officials at all levels of government of voting system threats.</p> <p>The National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) shall develop standards for ensuring the operational security of the voting systems used in elections for federal office.</p> <p>This bill amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require a state, in operating the voting system, to comply with applicable standards developed by NIST for ensuring the operational security of voting systems.</p> <p>The testing and certification of voting systems hardware and software shall test whether voting systems are in compliance with applicable NIST standards for ensuring the operational security of voting systems.</p> <p>NIST shall develop standards for ensuring that the process by which ballots are counted in elections for federal office is transparent and permits voters to verify that votes in such elections are counted correctly.</p> <p>States shall comply with applicable NIST standards, in operating the voting system, for ensuring that the process by which ballots are counted in elections for federal office is transparent and permits voters to verify that votes in such elections are counted correctly.</p> <p>The National Science Foundation shall establish an election technology innovation research and development program. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
