<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1715" measure-id="id115hr1715" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-23" update-date="2017-05-31">
<title>Medgar Evers House Study Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1715v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-31">
<action-date>2017-05-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Medgar Evers House Study Act</b></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of the Interior to conduct a special resource study of the home of the late civil rights activist Medgar Evers, located at 2332 Margaret Walker Alexander Drive in Jackson, Mississippi. </p> <p> Interior shall: (1) evaluate the national significance of the site; (2) determine the suitability and feasibility of designating the site as a unit of the National Park System (NPS); (3) determine the effect of the site's designation on existing commercial and recreational uses and on state and local government management of those activities; and (4) identify any authorities, including condemnation, that will compel or permit Interior to influence or participate in local land use decisions or place restrictions on nonfederal land if the site is designated as an NPS unit. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1715v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-03-29">
<action-date>2017-03-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Medgar Evers House Study Act</b></p> <p> This bill directs the Department of the Interior to conduct a special resource study of the home of the late civil rights activist Medgar Evers, which is located at 2332 Margaret Walker Alexander Drive in Jackson, Mississippi. </p> <p> Interior shall: (1) evaluate the national significance of the site, and (2) determine the suitability and feasibility of designating it as a unit of the National Park System. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
