<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2585" measure-id="id115hr2585" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-22" update-date="2018-02-09">
<title>21st Century Glass-Steagall Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2585v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-09">
<action-date>2017-05-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>21st Century Glass-Steagall Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956, the&nbsp;Home Owner's&nbsp;Loan Act, the&nbsp;International Banking Act of 1978, the federal bankruptcy code, and other laws&nbsp;to:</p> <ul> <li>limit affiliations between an insured depository institution and&nbsp;any insurance company, securities entity, or swaps entity</s />; </li> <li>restrict the authority of a national banking association to purchase&nbsp;or sell investment securities&nbsp;or stock, invest in certain structured or synthetic products, control or hold an interest in financial subsidiaries, or otherwise engage in nonbanking activities; </li> <li>restrict the authority of a&nbsp;federal savings association to invest in, redeem, or hold shares or certificates issued by an open-end management investment company;&nbsp; </li> <li>limit the authority of a financial holding company to engage in nonfinancial activities; </li> <li>disallow certain foreign banks from engaging in nonbanking activities in the United States; </li> <li>repeal bankruptcy code provisions related to the contractual right to liquidate, terminate, or accelerate certain types of financial instruments; and </li> <li>establish various enforcement and penalty provisions.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
