<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="750" measure-id="id115hr750" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-30" update-date="2017-09-14">
<title>Ensuring Access to Quality Complex Rehabilitation Technology Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr750v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-14">
<action-date>2017-01-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Ensuring Access to Quality Complex Rehabilitation Technology Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to establish a separate Medicare benefit category for complex rehabilitation technology (CRT) items&nbsp;that: (1) are designed or configured to meet an individual's unique needs and capacities; (2) are primarily used to serve a medical or functional purpose; and (3) require certain services to ensure appropriate design, configuration, and use. The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS)&nbsp;shall designate CRT items&nbsp;and establish eligibility criteria with respect to such&nbsp;items, in accordance with specified exclusions and other requirements.&nbsp;</p> <p>The CMS must also establish: (1)&nbsp;a payment system applicable to CRT items, subject to clinical conditions and other specified requirements; (2) quality standards for suppliers of CRT items; and (3) a formal process for the&nbsp;submission of certain CRT code-set modification requests by stakeholder groups.</p> <p>If specified requirements are met, Medicare payment must be made for the replacement of a CRT item (or item part), without regard to certain continuous-use or useful-lifetime restrictions applicable to&nbsp;items of durable medical equipment.</p> <p>In addition, Medicare payment may be made for the temporary rental of a CRT item if&nbsp;such an&nbsp;item owned by&nbsp;a qualified enrollee is undergoing&nbsp;necessary repairs.&nbsp;</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
