<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2095" measure-id="id115hr2095" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-14" update-date="2018-03-06">
<title>Fair Pay Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2095v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-06">
<action-date>2017-04-14</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Fair Pay Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to prohibit discrimination in the payment of wages on account of sex, race, or national origin. (Payment of different wages is allowed under seniority systems, merit systems, systems that measure earnings by quantity or quality of production, or differentials based on bona fide factors that the employer demonstrates are job-related or further legitimate business interests.) The bill allows compensatory or punitive damages for violations of such prohibition. </p> <p>The bill prohibits an employer from discriminating against any individual who opposes any act or practice made illegal by this bill or for assisting in an investigation, or discharging or discriminating against any employee who inquires about or discusses another employee's wages.</p> <p> <p>The Equal Employment Opportunity Commission shall: (1) undertake studies and provide information and technical assistance to employers, labor organizations, and the general public for implementing this bill's wage discrimination prohibitions; and (2) carry on a continuing program of research, education, and technical assistance to correct wage disparities.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
