<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1695" measure-id="id115hr1695" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-23" update-date="2017-04-28">
<title>Register of Copyrights Selection and Accountability Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1695v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-04-28">
<action-date>2017-04-26</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Register of Copyrights Selection and Accountability Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends federal copyright law to require the President, with the advice and consent of the Senate, to appoint a Register of Copyrights from a list of at least three individuals recommended by a panel composed of:</p> <ul> <li>the Speaker of the House of Representatives;</li> <li> the President pro tempore of the Senate;</li> <li>the majority and minority leaders of the House and the Senate; and </li> <li>the Librarian of Congress.</li> </ul> <p>(Currently, the Register of Copyrights is appointed by the Librarian of Congress.)</p> <p>To be eligible for appointment, the individual must be a citizen of the United States with a professional background and experience in copyright law and must be capable of identifying and supervising a chief information officer responsible for managing modern information technology systems.</p> <p>The bill limits the term of office for the Register of Copyrights to 10 years, but the individual may be reappointed subject to the same requirements established in this bill.</p> <p>The President may remove the Register of Copyrights from office and must notify both chambers of Congress of any such removal. </p> <p>(Sec. 3) Nothing in this bill may be construed to impact the mandatory deposit requirements under which owners of a copyright or of an exclusive right of publication must deposit in the U.S. Copyright Office two copies or phonorecords of works published in the United States for the use or disposition of the Library of Congress.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1695v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-04-27">
<action-date>2017-04-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Register of Copyrights Selection and Accountability Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill amends federal copyright law to require the Register of Copyrights to be a U.S. citizen with a professional background and experience in copyright law who is appointed by the President, with the advice and consent of the Senate, from a list of three individuals recommended by a panel composed of:</p> <ul> <li>the Speaker of the House of Representatives;</li> <li> the President pro tempore of the Senate;</li> <li>the majority and minority leaders of the House and the Senate; and </li> <li>the Librarian of Congress.</li> </ul> <p>(Currently, the Register of Copyrights is appointed by the Librarian of Congress.)</p> <p>The term of office for the Register of Copyrights is limited to 10 years, but the individual may be reappointed subject to the same requirements established in this bill.</p> <p>The President may remove the Register of Copyrights from office and must notify both chambers of Congress of any such removal. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1695v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-04-27">
<action-date>2017-03-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Register of Copyrights Selection and Accountability Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends federal copyright law to require the Register of Copyrights to be a U.S. citizen with a professional background and experience in copyright law who is appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate. (Currently, the Register of Copyrights is appointed by the Librarian of Congress.)</p> <p>The term of office for the Register of Copyrights is limited to 10 years, but the individual may be reappointed subject to the same Senate advice and consent requirement.</p> <p>The President may remove the Register of Copyrights from office and must notify both chambers of Congress of any such removal. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
