<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="920" measure-id="id115hr920" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-07" update-date="2017-02-21">
<title>Protecting Our Border Communities Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr920v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-02-21">
<action-date>2017-02-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Protecting Our Border Communities Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill states that: (1) beginning on January 25, 2017, Executive Order 13767, entitled &quot;Border Security and Immigration Enforcement Improvements,&quot; is null and void, shall have no force and effect, and may not be implemented or enforced; and (2) no federal funds may be used to implement or enforce any of the policy changes set forth in such order. Among the order's provisions concerning border security and immigration enforcement along the southern border of the United States are directives concerning physical barriers, detention facilities, additional Border Patrol agents, requirements for reporting on foreign aid to Mexico, and parole and asylum procedures.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
