<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2969" measure-id="id115hr2969" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-20" update-date="2018-02-27">
<title>MORE Makerspaces Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2969v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-27">
<action-date>2017-06-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Move Ownership and Responsibility to Encourage Makerspaces Act of 2017 or the MORE Makerspaces Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Assets Sale and Transfer Act of 2016 to require federal agencies to submit recommendations to the General Services Administration and the Office of Management and Budget on federal civilian real properties that have sufficient square footage, technological capabilities, and community accessibility for use as makerspaces.</p> <p>The bill defines &quot;makerspace&quot; as a community space that: (1) provides access to tools, technology, and knowledge for learners and entrepreneurs; (2) results in the prototyping or creation of physical goods; and (3) supports the development of educational opportunities for personal growth, workforce training, and early stage business ventures. </p> <p>The Public Buildings Reform Board shall: (1) establish a review process through which federal agencies may lease or sell an abandoned or unused federal civilian real property for use as a makerspace; (2) establish an online public campaign to inform local municipalities of such process; and (3) when such a property is identified through such process, notify the Member of Congress in whose district such property is located so that such Member can inform the local municipality and community of the opportunity to use such property as a makerspace. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
