<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1588" measure-id="id115hr1588" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-16" update-date="2017-07-31">
<title>Servicemember Intimate Privacy Protection Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1588v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-31">
<action-date>2017-03-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Servicemember Intimate Privacy Protection Act</strong></p> <p>This bill amends the Uniform Code of Military Justice to prohibit the nonconsensual distribution of private sexual images.</p> <p>To be guilty of such offense, a person must have:</p> <ul> <li> knowingly broadcast or distributed a visual image of another person who is at least 18 years of age, who is identifiable from the image itself or from information displayed in connection with the image, and who is engaged in a sexual act or exposes a private area; </li> <li>obtained the image under circumstances in which a reasonable person would know or understand that the image was to remain private; and </li> <li>known, or reasonably should have known, that the person depicted in the image has not consented to its broadcast or distribution.</li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
