<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="491" measure-id="id115hr491" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-12" update-date="2018-01-17">
<title>Let the GSEs Pay Us Back Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr491v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-17">
<action-date>2017-01-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Let the GSEs Pay Us Back Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill&nbsp;provides for the repayment of amounts previously borrowed by government-sponsored enterprises (GSEs) from the Department of the Treasury.&nbsp;GSEs are financial services corporations created by Congress and include the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac).</p> <p>Under an existing Preferred Stock Purchase Agreement, net income from the GSEs is directed to Treasury&nbsp;as a dividend but is not counted toward repayment of the GSEs' debt. The bill requires this agreement to be modified such that: (1) the amounts previously borrowed by the GSEs from Treasury shall be treated as a loan,&nbsp;in accordance with specified terms;&nbsp;and (2) payments&nbsp;made&nbsp;under the agreement by&nbsp;the GSEs to Treasury, including&nbsp;payments made prior to the agreement's modification,&nbsp;shall&nbsp;be treated as payments of principal and interest under&nbsp;such loan.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
