<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3223" measure-id="id115hr3223" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-13" update-date="2017-12-06">
<title>Refund Rights for Taxpayers Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3223v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-06">
<action-date>2017-07-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Refund Rights for Taxpayers Act </b></p> <p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) extend the statute of limitations for making a claim for a credit or refund for the overpayment of any tax, and (2) shorten the statute of limitations for a collection after the assessment of any tax. </p> <p>(Under current law, the statute of limitations for making a claim for a credit or refund is three years from the time the return was filed or two years from the time the tax was paid, whichever period expires later. If no return was filed by the taxpayer, the limit is two years from the time the tax was paid.) The bill extends this limit to seven years from the later of the time the return was filed or the tax was paid or, if no return was filed, seven years from the time the tax was paid. </p> <p>With respect to the statute of limitations for a collection after the assessment of any tax, the bill decreases the limit from 10 years to 7 years after the assessment of the tax. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
