<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1660" measure-id="id115hr1660" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-21" update-date="2018-02-28">
<title>Global Health Innovation Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1660v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-28">
<action-date>2018-01-18</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><strong>Global Health Innovation Act of 2017</strong></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill directs the Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to report to Congress, annually for four years, on the development and use of global health innovations in USAID programs, projects, and activities.</p> <p> Such reports shall include descriptions of: (1) goals and progress towards their achievement; (2) how innovation has advanced USAID's commitments to achieving an HIV/AIDS-free generation, ending preventable child and maternal deaths, and protecting communities from infectious diseases; (3) how USAID, alone and in partnerships, is leveraging U.S. investments to achieve greater health innovation; and (4) coordination with other federal departments.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1660v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-03-25">
<action-date>2017-03-21</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Global Health Innovation Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to report to Congress, annually for four years, on the development and use of global health innovations in USAID programs, projects, and activities.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
