<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2615" measure-id="id115hr2615" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-23" update-date="2017-12-15">
<title>Gulf Islands National Seashore Land Exchange Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2615v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-15">
<action-date>2017-11-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Gulf Islands National Seashore Land Exchange Act of 2017</b></p> <p> (Sec. 2) This bill authorizes the National Park Service (NPS) to convey specified federal lands located within the Gulf Islands National Seashore in Jackson County, Mississippi, to the Veterans of Foreign Wars Post 5699 in exchange for certain land located in such county. </p> <p>The values of the parcels to be exchanged shall be determined by an independent appraiser in accordance with nationally recognized appraisal standards. If the values of such parcels are not equal, their values shall be equalized through a cash payment or adjustments to their acreage. </p> <p>The NPS shall require the Post to pay or reimburse the costs incurred by the NPS to carry out such exchange.</p> <p>The bill subjects the exchange to valid existing rights.</p> <p>Land acquired by the United States under this bill shall be administered as part of the Gulf Islands National Seashore. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2615v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-16">
<action-date>2017-05-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Gulf Islands National Seashore Land Exchange Act of 2017</b></p> <p> This bill authorizes the National Park Service (NPS) to convey to the Veterans of Foreign Wars Post 5699 approximately 1.542 acres of real property located within the Gulf Islands National Seashore in Jackson County, Mississippi, in exchange for a parcel of 2.161 acres. </p> <p>The NPS shall require the Post to pay the costs incurred by the NPS to carry out such exchange.</p> <p>Land and interests acquired by the United States under this bill shall be administered as part of the Gulf Islands National Seashore. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
