<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1803" measure-id="id115hr1803" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-30" update-date="2017-12-05">
<title>10th Amendment Restoration Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1803v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-05">
<action-date>2017-03-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>10th Amendment Restoration Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill establishes the Constitutional Government Review Commission, which shall review the authorizing statute and statutory authority of each agency to determine if they should be repealed to eliminate federal powers not definitively delegated by the Constitution. </p> <p>The commission, after completing any such review, shall: (1) recommend whether immediate repeal action is appropriate, (2) prepare an estimate of federal spending or revenue changes resulting from adoption of a repeal recommendation, and (3) prepare a recommendation for distributing any federal budget savings among the states for the administration of powers returned to the states as a result of adoption of a repeal recommendation. </p> <p>Such a review may be initiated by the President, a Member of Congress, any federal, state, local, tribal, or regional government officer or employee, or any member of the public.</p> <p>The bill requires the commission to report to Congress detailing its activities and recommendations for the repeal of statutes and the distribution of savings among the states. </p> <p>The bill establishes procedures for the expedited congressional consideration of commission recommendations. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
