<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1613" measure-id="id115hr1613" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-17" update-date="2017-04-24">
<title>HELP for Coal Miners Health Care Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1613v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-04-24">
<action-date>2017-03-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Helping Ensure Long-Term Protection for Coal Miners Health Care Act of 2017 or the HELP for Coal Miners Health Care Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (SMCRA) to transfer certain funds to the Multiemployer Health Benefit Plan to provide health benefits to retired coal miners and their families. </p> <p>The bill expands the group whose retiree health benefits are taken into account in determining the amount that the Department of the Treasury must transfer from the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund and the General Fund of the Treasury to the Multiemployer Health Benefit Plan.</p> <p>The Government Accountability Office must study the Multiemployer Health Benefit Plan and submit to Congress reports analyzing whether federal funds are being spent appropriately by the plan. </p> <p>The bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to repeal requirements for current and former signatories to labor agreements with the United Mineworkers of America to pay unassigned beneficiaries premiums or backstop premiums if transfers under SMCRA are less than the amount required to be transferred.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
