<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="271" measure-id="id115hr271" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-04" update-date="2017-07-25">
<title>Stephanie Tubbs Jones Assets for Independence Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr271v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-25">
<action-date>2017-01-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Stephanie Tubbs Jones Assets for Independence Reauthorization Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill reauthorizes through FY2022 and otherwise amends the Assets for Independence Act, which provides for demonstration projects to fund individual development accounts (IDAs). (IDAs are matched savings accounts through which low-income individuals may save targeted amounts for qualifying purposes such as first-time home ownership or post-secondary education.) </p> <p>With respect to IDAs, the bill expands: (1) qualifying educational expenses; and (2) qualifying expenses for home replacement, repair, or improvement. </p> <p>In addition, with respect to demonstration projects, the bill: (1) requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to give special consideration to applications from victims of domestic violence, individuals who are or have been in foster care, and certain other categories of individuals; (2) revises income-eligibility requirements; (3) modifies procedures related to terminated projects; and (4) revises other specified requirements and limitations. </p> <p>An individual who is a recent or current victim of domestic violence shall not, for purposes of project participation, fail to qualify as a first-time homebuyer by reason of having a co-ownership interest in a principal residence with a person who committed domestic violence against the individual. </p> <p>HHS may use funds appropriated under the Act to cover certain necessary training costs. </p> <p>HHS is authorized to waive certain project requirements and limitations. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
