<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3049" measure-id="id115hr3049" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-23" update-date="2018-02-24">
<title>Evan's Law</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3049v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-24">
<action-date>2017-06-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Evan's Law</b></p> <p>This bill requires the military department concerned to ensure that any window of a military family housing unit the bottom sill of which is within 36 inches of the floor is equipped with fall prevention devices that protect against unintentional falls by young children and that comply with applicable International Building Code (IBC) standards. </p> <p>Each department must brief the House Committee on Armed Services on the implementation of such requirement and include in the briefing: (1) a plan to retrofit existing military family housing units to meet such requirement; (2) the feasibility and cost-effectiveness of expanding such requirement to apply to windows with higher sills, modifying such requirement to require windows to be equipped with additional fall prevention devices that meet specified criteria, or extending such requirement to private housing leased or otherwise used by military families; and (3) the feasibility and cost-effectiveness of other potential methods to protect against unintentional window falls by young children in military family housing units. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
