<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1595" measure-id="id115hr1595" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-17" update-date="2018-02-08">
<title>Mutual Bank Capital Opportunity Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1595v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-08">
<action-date>2017-03-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Mutual Bank Capital Opportunity Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to allow mutual capital certificates issued by&nbsp;a mutual depository&nbsp;(i.e., a federally insured depository institution operating in a non-stock form)&nbsp;to qualify as common-equity Tier 1 capital for purposes of&nbsp;satisfying federal&nbsp;capital requirements. A&nbsp;"mutual capital certificate" is&nbsp;a financial instrument that: (1) is subordinate to all claims against, and unsecured by the assets of,&nbsp;the issuing mutual depository; (2) does not permit preemptive rights; (3) in general, does not provide voting or member rights; (4) is not eligible for use as collateral for any loan made&nbsp;by the issuing mutual depository; (5)&nbsp;entitles the holder to a payment of fixed, variable, or participating dividends (if the depository's board so declares); and (6)&nbsp;is generally not redeemable until five years after issuance.</p> <p>The appropriate federal banking agencies must jointly issue regulations to implement these provisions and to identify other financial instruments issued by mutual depositories that shall qualify as additional Tier 1 capital for purposes of federal capital requirements. The agencies must submit to Congress a series of reports on their progress in promulgating such regulations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
