<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3008" measure-id="id115hr3008" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-22" update-date="2017-07-05">
<title>George W. Bush Childhood Home Study Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3008v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-05">
<action-date>2017-06-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>George W. Bush Childhood Home Study Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of the Interior to conduct a special resource study of the childhood home of former President George W. Bush, which is located at 1412 West Ohio Avenue in Midland, Texas.</p> <p>Interior shall: (1) evaluate the national significance of the site, (2) determine the suitability and feasibility of designating the site as a unit of the National Park System (NPS), and (3) determine the effect of the site's designation as an NPS unit on existing commercial and recreational uses and the effect on state and local governments to manage those activities. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
