<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3681" measure-id="id115hr3681" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-06" update-date="2018-01-24">
<title>ARPA-E Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3681v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-24">
<action-date>2017-09-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>ARPA-E Reauthorization Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill amends the AMERICA Competes Act to declare that the following categories of information collected by the Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy (ARPA-E) from recipients of ARPA-E financial assistance awards are considered privileged and confidential and not subject to disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act: </p> <ul> <li>plans for the commercialization of technologies that have been developed under the award,</li> <li>investments provided to an awardee from third parties,</li> <li>additional financial support that the awardee plans to invest or has invested into the technology developed under the award or that the awardee is seeking from third parties, and </li> <li>revenue from the licensing or sale of new products or services resulting from the research that was conducted under the award. </li> </ul> <p>The bill reauthorizes the ARPA-E through FY2022. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
