<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3328" measure-id="id115hr3328" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-20" update-date="2017-11-28">
<title>Cuban Airport Security Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3328v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-28">
<action-date>2017-10-23</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p><b>Cuban Airport Security Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to brief Congress and the Government Accountability Office on specified aspects of security measures at each of Cuba's 10 international airports</p> <p>No U.S. air carrier that has entered into a covered agreement may employ a Cuban national beginning 30 days after enactment of this bill unless such carrier has publicly disclosed the full text of the agreement, and such nationals shall not have been recruited, hired, or trained by entities that are owned, operated, or controlled by Cuba's Council of State, Council of Ministers, Communist Party, Ministry of the Revolutionary Armed Forces, Ministry of Foreign Affairs, or Ministry of the Interior.</p> <p>A &quot;covered agreement&quot; means a formal agreement between a U.S. air carrier with passenger air service between any location in Cuba and any location in the United States and the Empresa Cubana de Aeropuertos y Servicios Aeronauticos or any other entity associated with the Cuban government.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) TSA shall develop a standard working document for all negotiations and agreements between the United States and foreign governments or partners regarding Federal Air Marshal coverage of flights to and from the United States. All such agreements shall be written and signed by the DHS Secretary. DHS shall notify Congress of any such agreement within 30 days of it being signed.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The U.S. Ambassador or the Charge d'Affaires to the U.S. Mission to the International Civil Aviation Organization shall pursue improvements to airport security, including introducing a resolution to raise minimum airport security standards.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3328v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-28">
<action-date>2017-07-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Cuban Airport Security Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to brief Congress and the Government Accountability Office on specified aspects of security measures at each of Cuba's 10 international airports.</p> <p>No U.S. air carrier that has entered into a covered agreement may employ a Cuban national beginning 30 days after enactment of this bill unless such carrier has publicly disclosed the full text of the agreement, and such nationals shall not have been recruited, hired, or trained by entities that are owned, operated, or controlled by Cuba's Council of State, Council of Ministers, Communist Party, Ministry of the Revolutionary Armed Forces, Ministry of Foreign Affairs, or Ministry of the Interior.</p> <p>A &quot;covered agreement&quot; means a formal agreement between a U.S. air carrier with passenger air service between any location in Cuba and any location in the United States and the Empresa Cubana de Aeropuertos y Servicios Aeronauticos or any other entity associated with the Cuban government.</p> <p>TSA shall develop a standard working document for all negotiations and agreements between the United States and foreign governments or partners regarding Federal Air Marshal coverage of flights to and from the United States. All such agreements shall be written and signed by the DHS Secretary. DHS shall notify Congress of any such agreement within 30 days of it being signed.</p> <p>The U.S. Ambassador or the Charge d'Affaires to the U.S. Mission to the International Civil Aviation Organization shall pursue improvements to airport security, including introducing a resolution to raise minimum airport security standards.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
