<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3017" measure-id="id115hr3017" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-22" update-date="2018-03-23">
<title>Brownfields Enhancement, Economic Redevelopment, and Reauthorization Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3017v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-23">
<action-date>2017-11-30</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p> <p><b>Brownfields Enhancement, Economic Redevelopment, and Reauthorization Act of 2017</b> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill modifies the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) to specify if a state or local government takes title to a brownfield site as a result of law enforcement activity, that government is not an owner or operator for the purposes of CERCLA. (Brownfields are certain commercial properties that are hindered from reuse or redevelopment due to the presence of a hazardous substance, pollutant, or contaminant.) <p>(Sec. 3) The bill modifies brownfield program eligibility with respect to petroleum sites where no viable responsible party exists. Specifically, it eliminates the requirement that sites be of relatively low risk. <p>(Sec. 4) The bill revises leaseholder status regarding bona fide prospective purchasers. <p>(Sec. 5) The bill expands CERCLA eligibility for nonprofit organizations and qualified community development entities. <p>(Sec. 6) The brownfield site characterization and assessment grant program and the brownfield remediation grant and loan program are revised by authorizing eligible governmental entities to receive grants and loans for property that was acquired before January 11, 2002, even if the entities do not qualify as bona fide prospective purchasers. <p>(Sec. 7) The bill increases the cap on the amount that may be given in grants and loans for each site to be remediated. <p>(Sec. 8) The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) must establish a program to provide multipurpose grants to carry out inventory, characterization, assessment, planning, or remediation activities at brownfield sites. <p>(Sec. 9) The bill allows grant recipients to use up to 5% of funds for administrative costs. <p>(Sec. 10) The EPA must consider the production of renewable energy on brownfield sites as part of the grant application ranking process. <p>(Sec. 11) The EPA is allowed to provide grants to assist small communities, Indian tribes, rural areas, or disadvantaged areas for the purpose of establishing a brownfields program. <p>(Sec. 12) The bill reauthorizes brownfields revitalization funding through FY2022. <p>(Sec. 13) The bill reauthorizes state response programs through FY2022.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3017v28" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-16">
<action-date>2017-09-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment, Part I</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Brownfields Enhancement, Economic Redevelopment, and Reauthorization Act of 2017</b></p> This bill amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) to: (1) revise and reauthorize brownfields revitalization funding through FY2021, and (2) reauthorize state response programs through FY2021. (Brownfields are certain commercial properties that are hindered from reuse or redevelopment due to the presence of a hazardous substance, pollutant, or contaminant.) <p>Certain nonprofit organizations and community development entities are made eligible for brownfields revitalization funding.</p> <p>The Environmental Protection Agency must establish a program to provide multipurpose grants to carry out inventory, characterization, assessment, planning, technical assistance, or remediation activities at brownfield sites.</p> <p>The brownfield site characterization and assessment grant program and the brownfield remediation grant and loan program are revised by authorizing eligible governmental entities to receive grants and loans for property that was acquired before January 11, 2002, even if the entities do not qualify as bona fide prospective purchasers.</p> <p>The bill increases the cap on the amount that may be given in grants and loans for each site to be remediated.</p> <p>If a state or local government takes title to a brownfield site as a result of law enforcement activity, that government is not an owner or operator for the purposes of CERCLA.</p> <p>The bill modifies brownfield program eligibility with respect to petroleum sites where no viable responsible party exists.</p> <p>The bill revises leaseholder status regarding bona fide prospective purchasers.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3017v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-15">
<action-date>2017-06-22</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Brownfields Enhancement, Economic Redevelopment, and Reauthorization Act of 2017</b></p> This bill amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (CERCLA) to: (1) revise and reauthorize brownfields revitalization funding through FY2021, and (2) reauthorize state response programs through FY2021. (Brownfields are certain commercial properties that are hindered from reuse or redevelopment due to the presence of a hazardous substance, pollutant, or contaminant.) <p>Certain nonprofit organizations and community development entities are made eligible for brownfields revitalization funding.</p> <p>The Environmental Protection Agency must establish a program to provide multipurpose grants to carry out inventory, characterization, assessment, planning, technical assistance, or remediation activities at brownfield sites.</p> <p>The brownfield site characterization and assessment grant program and the brownfield remediation grant and loan program are revised by authorizing eligible governmental entities to receive grants and loans for property that was acquired before January 11, 2002, even if the entities do not qualify as bona fide prospective purchasers.</p> <p>The bill increases the cap on the amount that may be given in grants and loans for each site to be remediated.</p> <p>If a state or local government takes title to a brownfield site as a result of law enforcement activity, that government is not an owner or operator for the purposes of CERCLA.</p> <p>The bill modifies brownfield program eligibility with respect to petroleum sites where no viable responsible party exists.</p> <p>The bill revises leaseholder status regarding bona fide prospective purchasers.]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
