<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3611" measure-id="id115hr3611" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-28" update-date="2018-02-09">
<title>Healthcare Outcomes Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3611v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-09">
<action-date>2017-07-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Healthcare Outcomes Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to replace the existing methodology for calculating Medicare payment adjustments for subsection (d) hospitals&nbsp;based on&nbsp;outcomes in readmissions and complications with&nbsp;a new methodology&nbsp;based on value-based outcomes in those and other areas.&nbsp;(In general, a&nbsp;"subsection (d) hospital" is an acute care hospital that receives payments under Medicare's inpatient prospective payment system.)</p> <p>Specifically, the bill: (1)&nbsp;establishes a methodology for determining a hospital's financial impact attributable to complications, readmissions, return emergency room visits, and post-acute care episode expenditures;&nbsp;and (2) requires the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) to select methodologies for identifying potentially avoidable outcomes in those categories.&nbsp;Subject to both a ceiling and a&nbsp;floor,&nbsp;among&nbsp;other specified refinements, a hospital's&nbsp;payment adjustment factor for an applicable prospective period&nbsp;shall be&nbsp;based on&nbsp;the ratio of that financial impact to the aggregate amount of standardized payments made to the hospital with respect to that period. </p> <p>The CMS must ensure budget neutrality with respect to application of the payment adjustment factor across all subsection (d) hospitals.</p> <p>The CMS&nbsp;shall regularly report to hospitals and to the public on each hospital's performance with regard to potentially avoidable outcomes.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
