<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3960" measure-id="id115hr3960" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-04" update-date="2017-12-06">
<title>Preserving Liu Xiaobo Legacy of Freedom &amp; Gold Medal Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3960v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-06">
<action-date>2017-10-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Preserving Liu Xiaobo Legacy of Freedom &amp; Gold Medal Act</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate to award a Congressional Gold Medal to Liu Xiaobo and collectively to all those who have peacefully advocated for democracy and human rights in China in recognition of their achievements and contributions to freedom, human rights, and peace in China and globally. </p> <p> The bill expresses the sense of Congress that the Smithsonian Institution should make the medal available for display, particularly at locations: (1) associated with the research of the Tiananmen Protests of 1989 and their violent suppression, and (2) dedicated to preserving the history of the Chinese pro-democracy movement. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
