<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2454" measure-id="id115hr2454" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-16" update-date="2017-12-13">
<title>Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2454v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-13">
<action-date>2017-09-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) develop a data framework to integrate existing DHS datasets and systems for access by authorized personnel in a manner consistent with relevant legal authorities and privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties policies and protections; (2) ensure that all information of a DHS office or component that falls within the scope of the information sharing environment, and any information or intelligence relevant to priority mission needs and capability requirements of the homeland security enterprise, is included; and (3) ensure that the framework is accessible to DHS employees who have an appropriate security clearance, who are assigned to perform a function that requires access, and who are trained in applicable standards for safeguarding and using such information.</p> <p>DHS shall: (1) issue guidance for DHS employees authorized to access and contribute to the framework that enforces a duty to share between DHS offices and components for mission needs; and (2) promulgate data standards and instruct DHS components to make available information through the framework in a machine-readable format.</p> <p>DHS may exclude information that could:</p> <ul> <li> jeopardize the protection of sources, methods, or activities; </li> <li> compromise a criminal or national security investigation; </li> <li> be inconsistent with the other federal laws or regulations; or </li> <li> be duplicative or not serve an operational purpose.</li> </ul> <p>DHS shall incorporate into such framework systems capabilities for auditing and ensuring the security of information. Such capabilities shall include: (1) mechanisms for identifying insider threats and security risks; and (2) safeguards for privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties.</p> <p>DHS shall ensure that, by two years after this bill's enactment, the framework has the ability to include appropriate information in existence within the department to meet its critical mission operations.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2454v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-11">
<action-date>2017-05-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Department of Homeland Security Data Framework Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) develop a data framework to integrate existing DHS datasets and systems for access by authorized personnel in a manner consistent with relevant legal authorities and privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties policies and protections; (2) ensure that all information of a DHS office or component that falls within the scope of the information sharing environment, and any information or intelligence relevant to priority mission needs and capability requirements of the homeland security enterprise, is included; and (3) ensure that the framework is accessible to DHS employees who have an appropriate security clearance, who are assigned to perform a function that requires access, and who are trained in applicable standards for safeguarding and using such information.</p> <p>DHS shall issue guidance for DHS employees authorized to access and contribute to the framework that enforces a duty to share between DHS offices and components for mission needs.</p> <p>DHS may exclude information that could:</p> <ul> <li> jeopardize the protection of sources, methods, or activities; </li> <li> compromise a criminal or national security investigation; </li> <li> be inconsistent with the other federal laws or regulations; or </li> <li> be duplicative or not serve an operational purpose.</li> </ul> <p>DHS shall incorporate into such framework systems capabilities for auditing and ensuring the security of information.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
