<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2674" measure-id="id115hr2674" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-25" update-date="2017-09-19">
<title>Young Americans Financial Literacy Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2674v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-19">
<action-date>2017-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Young Americans Financial Literacy Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau to award competitive grants to eligible&nbsp;institutions for the establishment of centers of excellence to support research, development, implementation, and evaluation of effective financial-literacy education programs for young people and families. An &quot;eligible institution" is a partnership among two or more of the following:</p> <ul> <li>an institution of higher education;</li> <li>a local educational agency;</li> <li>a nonprofit agency, organization, or association; or</li> <li>a financial institution.</li></ul> <p>Authorized grant-funded activities shall include:</p> <ul> <li>developing and implementing comprehensive, research-based, financial-literacy education programs for young people;</li> <li>designing instructional materials;</li> <li>developing and supporting the delivery of professional-development programs in financial-literacy education;</li> <li>improving access to, and dissemination of, financial-literacy information for young people and families;</li> <li>developing educational programs to reduce student-loan default rates;</li> <li>conducting ongoing research and evaluation of financial-literacy education programs; and</li> <li>measuring the effectiveness of authorized activities.</li></ul> <p>The&nbsp;grant program&nbsp;shall terminate&nbsp;after FY2019.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
