<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2431" measure-id="id115hr2431" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-16" update-date="2017-09-27">
<title>Michael Davis, Jr. and Danny Oliver in Honor of State and Local Law Enforcement Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2431v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-09-27">
<action-date>2017-05-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Michael Davis, Jr. and Danny Oliver in Honor of State and Local Law Enforcement Act</b></p> <p> This bill amends the Immigration and Nationality Act and related federal law with respect to immigration law enforcement within the United States.</p> <p> The bill authorizes: (1) states and localities to enact and enforce criminal penalties for immigration violations; and (2) state and local law enforcement personnel to investigate, arrest, and transfer aliens to federal custody. </p> <p>The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) shall: (1) make grants to states and localities for equipment, technology, and facilities; (2) construct or acquire additional domestic detention facilities for aliens pending removal; and (3) expand to all states a program that provides for the identification and removal of detained criminal aliens. </p> <p>The bill provides for: (1) federal custody of inadmissible or deportable aliens upon state or local request, and (2) personal liability immunity for state or local personnel enforcing immigration laws. </p> <p>States and localities shall: (1) notify the federal government of inadmissible or removable aliens encountered by law enforcement personnel, and (2) comply with federal law enforcement information requests. </p> <p>Specified federal assistance is denied to a state or locality that prohibits cooperation with federal immigration enforcement.</p> <p> The bill: (1) revises certain terrorism-related requirements and prohibitions with respect to benefits, naturalization and denaturalization, asylum, voluntary departure, and removal; (2) adds new grounds of inadmissibility and deportability; (3) establishes probable cause standards for Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) detainers; (4) provides for increases in immigration enforcement personnel; (5) prescribes visa security provisions; (6) authorizes DHS to designate groups as criminal gangs and makes alien gang members inadmissible or deportable; (7) establishes an ICE Advisory Council; and (8) prescribes criminal alien removal provisions.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
