<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2440" measure-id="id115hr2440" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-16" update-date="2017-08-23">
<title>Presidential Disclosure of Foreign Business Transactions Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2440v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-08-23">
<action-date>2017-05-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Presidential Disclosure of Foreign Business Transactions Act</strong></p> <p>This bill directs the President: (1) within 90 days after first assuming office, to submit to the Department of the Treasury an initial report detailing any private business transaction with a foreign government conducted by the President during the previous 10 years; and (2) each month thereafter, to submit a report detailing any private business transaction between businesses affiliated with the President and foreign governments during that month. </p> <p>A &quot;business transaction&quot; is defined as any transaction of more than $10,000 in relation to any private businesses or investments listed in the President's financial disclosure reports, including any report submitted pursuant to the Ethics in Government Act of 1978.</p>  <p>Such reports shall be made available on Treasury's public website. </p> <p>A violation of this bill shall constitute a high crime and misdemeanor for purposes of the Constitution's impeachment provision.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
