<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="513" measure-id="id115hr513" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-12" update-date="2017-06-21">
<title>Alaska Mental Health Trust Land Exchange Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr513v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-21">
<action-date>2017-01-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Alaska Mental Health Trust Land Exchange Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to convey certain federal land in two phases to the Alaska Mental Health Trust Authority in exchange for certain nonfederal land.</p>  <p>Before completing each phase of the land exchange, USDA shall complete any necessary land surveys and required pre-exchange clearances, mitigation activities, and approvals related to:</p> <ul> <li>threatened and endangered species,</li> <li>cultural and historic resources,</li> <li>wetland and floodplains, and </li> <li>hazardous materials. </li> </ul>   <p>Upon acquisition by USDA, the nonfederal land shall become part of Tongass National Forest, and shall be withdrawn from:</p> <ul> <li>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</li> <li>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and </li> <li>disposition under the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws. </li> </ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
