<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3907" measure-id="id115hr3907" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-10-02" update-date="2017-12-26">
<title>Wildland Firefighter Recognition Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3907v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-26">
<action-date>2017-10-02</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Wildland Firefighter Recognition Act</strong></p> <p>This bill requires the Office of Personnel Management to develop a distinct wildland firefighter occupational series. The series&nbsp;must&nbsp;apply to the following positions:&nbsp;</p> <ul> <li>forestry technician; </li> <li>range technician; </li> <li>other positions related to significant prevention, preparedness, control, suppression, or management activities for wildland firefighters; and </li> <li>other positions conducting activities necessary to meet any other emergency incident.</li></ul> <p>The Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture must use the series in the advertising and hiring of a wildland firefighter. </p> <p>The bill requires an employee in a wildland firefighter occupational series to receive a pay differential based on the unusual physical hardship or hazardous nature of the position.</p> <p>An individual employed as a wildland firefighter on the date on which the occupational series takes effect may: (1) remain in the occupational series in which the individual is working, or (2) be included in the wildland firefighter occupational series.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
