<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2668" measure-id="id115hr2668" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-25" update-date="2017-12-20">
<title>Smarter Approach to Nuclear Expenditures Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2668v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-12-20">
<action-date>2017-05-25</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Smarter Approach to Nuclear Expenditures Act</strong></p> <p>This bill prohibits the obligation or expenditure of Department of Defense (DOD) funds: (1) for procuring more than eight Columbia-class submarines; (2) to maintain more than 150 deployed intercontinental ballistic missiles; or (3) through FY2024, for the research, development, test, and evaluation (RDT&amp;E) or the procurement of the B-21 long-range penetrating bomber aircraft.</p> <p>The bill prohibits the obligation or expenditure of DOD or Department of Energy (DOE) funds: </p> <ul> <li>to maintain more than 1,000 deployed strategic warheads, as counted under the New START Treaty; </li> <li> to make the F-35 Joint Strike Fighter aircraft capable of carrying nuclear weapons;</li> <li> for extending the life of tactical versions of the B61 gravity bomb;</li> <li> for the RDT&amp;E or procurement of a new air-launched cruise missile or for the W80 warhead life extension program;</li> <li> for the RDT&amp;E or procurement of the ground-based strategic deterrent or any new intercontinental ballistic missile;</li> <li> for the IW-1 life extension program;</li> <li> for the Mixed Oxide Fuel Fabrication Facility project at the Savannah River Site, Aiken, South Carolina; or</li> <li> for the Uranium Processing Facility located at the Y-12 National Security Complex, Oak Ridge, Tennessee.</li> </ul> <p>DOD and DOE must report to Congress on the plans for, and the estimated cost savings from, carrying out this bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
