<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3584" measure-id="id115hr3584" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-07-28" update-date="2018-01-03">
<title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to extend certain credits against tax related to empowerment zones.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3584v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-03">
<action-date>2017-07-28</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to empowerment zones, to: (1) extend the termination date for empowerment zone designations to December 31, 2020, and (2) allow nominations for existing zones to be amended to provide for the new termination date. </p> <p>(Empowerment zones are federally designated geographic areas where certain federal tax incentives and grants are allowed to increase investment and employment.) </p> <p>The bill also extends the $400 million annual limitation for qualified zone academy bonds to 2018, 2019, and 2020. (Under current law, the limit is zero after 2016 unless provisions permitting the carryover of unused limitation apply.)</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
