<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2115" measure-id="id115hr2115" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-24" update-date="2018-02-13">
<title>Wakiesha's Law</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2115v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-13">
<action-date>2017-04-24</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Family Notification of Death in Custody or Life-Threatening Emergency Act of 2017 or Wakiesha's Law</b></p> <p>This bill requires federal, state, and local law enforcement agencies to obtain identifying information about an individual in custody and contact information for the individual's next of kin or designated emergency contact. It establishes minimum standards with respect to notifying the next of kin or designated emergency contact following an individual's death or life-threatening emergency while in custody.</p> <p>The Department of Justice must reduce by 10% the allocation of funds under the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant program for a state or local government that fails to comply. </p> <p>The bill also amends the Death in Custody Reporting Act of 2013 to require a state or federal law enforcement agency to include, in its quarterly report on deaths in custody, additional information such as the date and time that death notification was provided and the date and time of each unsuccessful notification attempt.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
