<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1776" measure-id="id115hr1776" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-29" update-date="2018-01-18">
<title>Improving Access To Affordable Prescription Drugs Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1776v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-18">
<action-date>2017-03-29</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends provisions of various laws relating to prescription-drug pricing and affordability.&nbsp;Specifically, the bill:</p> <ul> <li>expands reporting requirements for drug manufacturers&nbsp;and establishes corresponding civil penalties for noncompliance; </li> <li>adds reporting requirements for certain nonprofit patient-assistance programs; </li> <li>requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to report to Congress on the impact of patient-assistance programs on prescription-drug pricing and expenditures; </li> <li>requires the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) to negotiate prices for certain prescription drugs under the Medicare program; </li> <li>requires the GAO to report to Congress on such negotiations conducted by the CMS; </li> <li>requires the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation within the CMS to test specified models for negotiating drug prices; </li> <li>establishes reporting requirements, and corresponding civil penalties for noncompliance,&nbsp;for pharmaceutical companies with respect to spikes in prescription-drug prices; </li> <li>establishes an excise tax on prescription drugs subject to price spikes; </li> <li>lessens prescription-drug cost-sharing requirements under qualified health plans, group health plans, and the Medicare program; </li> <li>modifies provisions related to the importation of prescription drugs; </li> <li>requires drug manufacturers to provide drug rebates for drugs dispensed to certain low-income individuals under the Medicare program; </li> <li>establishes a prize fund for new and more effective treatments of bacterial infections; </li> <li>establishes a Center for Clinical Research within the National Institutes of Health; </li> <li>modifies provisions related to drug exclusivity; </li> <li>allows the Federal Trade Commission to initiate enforcement proceedings against parties to an agreement resolving or settling a patent-infringement claim in connection with the sale of a drug product; </li> <li>requires the Food and Drug Administration to establish a database of generic drugs; and </li> <li>modifies other provisions related to generic drugs, prescription-drug advertising, and product hopping.</li></ul>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
