<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1134" measure-id="id115hr1134" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-16" update-date="2018-02-13">
<title>DISCLOSE 2017 Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1134v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-13">
<action-date>2017-02-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Disclosure of Information on Spending on Campaigns Leads to Open and Secure Elections Act of 2017 or the DISCLOSE 2017 Act</b></p> <p>This bill amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to:</p> <ul> <li> revise the definition of "independent expenditure;"</li> <li> expand the period during which certain communications are treated as electioneering communications;</li> <li>require certain organizations making campaign-related disbursements to file a statement with the Federal Election Commission;</li> <li> require campaign-related radio or television communications that are not authorized by a candidate or candidate's political committee to include an individual or organizational disclosure statement, together with other information;</li> <li> repeal the prohibition against political contributions by individuals age 17 or younger; and</li> <li> require certain organizations that submit regular, periodic reports to shareholders, members, or donors to include in each report information regarding campaign-related disbursements</s>.</li> </ul> <p> The bill amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to require the semiannual reports on certain election campaign contributions filed with the Senate or the House of Representatives by registered lobbyists (or persons or organizations required to register as lobbyists) to contain: (1) the amount of any independent expenditure of $1,000 or more made by each such person or organization, along with the name of each candidate being supported or opposed and the amount spent supporting or opposing that candidate; and (2) the amount of any electioneering communication of $1,000 or more made by such person or organization, along with the name of the candidate referred to in the communication and whether the communication was in support of or in opposition to the candidate. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
