<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3669" measure-id="id115hr3669" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-01" update-date="2018-04-04">
<title>Securing General Aviation and Commercial Charter Air Carrier Service Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3669v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-04-04">
<action-date>2017-12-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Securing General Aviation and Commercial Charter Air Carrier Service Act of 2017</b> </p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to study the cost and feasibility of establishing web-based access to the Secure Flight passenger screening program for commercial charter air carriers.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The TSA is authorized to provide screening services to a commercial charter air carrier in areas other than primary passenger terminals of airports upon such carrier's request. TSA shall enter into an agreement for compensation from such carrier for the cost of providing such services.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The TSA shall submit to Congress an implementation plan for the recommendations adopted by the Aviation Security Advisory Committee and concurred to by the TSA: </p> <ul> <li>on February 17, 2015, regarding general aviation access to Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport, </li> <li>on July 28, 2016, regarding the vetting of persons seeking flight training in the United States, and </li> <li>prior to enactment of this bill regarding general aviation security. </li></ul> <p>(Sec. 5) The TSA is authorized to designate at least one full-time TSA employee to be responsible for engagement with general aviation stakeholders and to manage issues related to general aviation.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) The TSA shall report on the feasibility of requiring security threat assessments for all candidates seeking flight school training in operating aircraft weighing more than 12,500 pounds to enhance the vetting of persons seeking such training in the United States. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3669v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-03-30">
<action-date>2017-10-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Securing General Aviation and Commercial Charter Air Carrier Service Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to study the cost and feasibility of establishing web-based access to Secure Flight for commercial charter air carriers.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) The TSA is authorized to provide screening services to a commercial charter air carrier in areas other than primary passenger terminals of airports upon such carrier's request. TSA shall enter into an agreement for compensation from such carrier for the cost of providing such services.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) The TSA shall submit to Congress an implementation plan for the recommendations adopted by the Aviation Security Advisory Committee and concurred to by the TSA: </p> <ul> <li>on February 17, 2015, regarding general aviation access to Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport, </li> <li>on July 28, 2016, regarding the vetting of persons seeking flight training in the United States, and </li> <li>prior to enactment of this bill regarding general aviation security. </li></ul> <p>(Sec. 5) The TSA is authorized to designate at least one full-time TSA employee to be responsible for engagement with general aviation stakeholders and to manage issues related to general aviation.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) The TSA shall report on the feasibility of requiring security threat assessments for all candidates seeking flight school training in operating aircraft weighing more than 12,500 pounds to enhance the vetting of persons seeking such training in the United States. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3669v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-09">
<action-date>2017-09-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Securing General Aviation and Commercial Charter Air Carrier Service Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to study the cost and feasibility of establishing web-based access to Secure Flight for commercial charter air carriers.</p> <p>The TSA is authorized to provide screening services to a commercial charter air carrier in areas other than primary passenger terminals of airports upon such carrier's request. TSA shall enter into an agreement for compensation from such carrier for the cost or providing such services.</p> <p>The TSA shall submit to Congress an implementation plan for the recommendations adopted by the Aviation Security Advisory Committee: </p> <ul> <li>on February 17, 2015, regarding general aviation access to Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport,</li> <li>on July 28, 2016, regarding the vetting of persons seeking flight training in the United States, and </li> <li>prior to enactment of this bill regarding general aviation security.</li> </ul> <p>The TSA is authorized to designate at least one full-time TSA employee to be responsible for engagement with general aviation stakeholders and manage issues related to general aviation.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
