<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="482" measure-id="id115hr482" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-12" update-date="2017-04-10">
<title>Local Zoning Decisions Protection Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr482v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-04-10">
<action-date>2017-01-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Local Zoning Decisions Protection Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill nullifies:</p> <ul> <li>the final Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) rule entitled &quot;Affirmatively Furthering Fair Housing&quot; and any successor rule substantially similar to it, and</li> <li>the notice relating to the Affirmatively Furthering Fair Housing Assessment Tool and any successor notice or rule substantially similar to it.</li> </ul> <p>No federal funds may be used to design, build, maintain, utilize, or provide access to a federal database of geospatial information on community racial disparities or disparities in access to affordable housing.</p> <p>HUD is required to: (1) consult with state, local government, and public housing agency officials to develop recommendations, consistent with applicable rulings of the U.S. Supreme Court, to further the Fair Housing Act's purposes and policies; and (2) make a final report publicly available online within 12 months after enactment of this bill.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
