<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2264" measure-id="id115hr2264" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-05-01" update-date="2017-11-21">
<title>Make It In America Manufacturing Communities Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2264v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-21">
<action-date>2017-05-01</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Make It In America Manufacturing Communities Act</b></p> <p>This bill requires the Department of Commerce to establish a Manufacturing Community Support Program to improve the competitiveness of U.S. manufacturing by: (1) designating consortiums as manufacturing communities, and (2) authorizing federal agencies electing to participate in the program to provide such communities preferential consideration in awarding financial and technical assistance.</p> <p>A consortium, to be eligible for such designation and assistance, must: </p> <ul> <li> represent a region that is large enough to contain critical elements of the key technologies or supply chain prioritized by the consortium and small enough to enable close collaboration among the consortium's members; </li> <li> include at least one institution of higher education, a private sector entity, and a government entity; and </li> <li> have a lead applicant that is a district organization, an Indian tribe, a state or political subdivision of a state, an institution of higher education, a nonprofit organization or association with an application supported by a state, a political subdivision of a state, or a native community. </li> </ul> <p>Commerce shall make such designations for a two-year period, and may renew a designation for additional two-year periods, based on specified criteria.</p> <p> Recipients may use such financial or technical assistance to support investments in ecosystems that will improve the competitiveness of U.S. manufacturing, including infrastructure, access to capital, promotion of exports and foreign direct investment, equipment upgrades, workforce training and recruitment, energy or process efficiency, business incubators, site preparation, advanced research, supply chain development, and small business assistance. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
