<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1511" measure-id="id115hr1511" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-13" update-date="2018-01-30">
<title>Homeless Children and Youth Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1511v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-30">
<action-date>2017-03-13</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Homeless Children and Youth Act of 2017</b></p> <p> This bill amends the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to modify definitions relating to homeless individuals and homeless children or youth as used by the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to verify eligibility for HUD homeless assistance programs to align them with the definitions of &quot;homeless&quot; used to verify eligibility for other federal assistance programs. (The amended definitions would increase access to federal homeless programs by homeless children, youth, and families.)</p>  <p>The community-wide homeless management information system shall be made publicly available on HUD's website.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
