<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1598" measure-id="id115hr1598" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-17" update-date="2017-05-03">
<title>Ninth Circuit Court Modernization and Twelfth Circuit Court Creation Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1598v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-05-03">
<action-date>2017-03-17</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Ninth Circuit Court Modernization and Twelfth Circuit Court Creation Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill divides the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit into: (1) a new Ninth Circuit that consists of only California; and (2) a newly established Twelfth Circuit to be composed of Alaska, Arizona, Idaho, Montana, Nevada, Oregon, Washington, Guam, and Hawaii.</p> <p>The Twelfth Circuit must hold regular sessions in Las Vegas, Phoenix, Anchorage, Missoula, Portland, and Seattle. </p> <p>Each circuit judge of the former Ninth Circuit who is in regular active service and whose official duty station is currently in Alaska, Arizona, Idaho, Montana, Oregon, Washington, Guam, Hawaii, the Northern Mariana Islands, or Nevada shall be a circuit judge of the new Ninth Circuit.</p> <p>The President shall appoint, with the advice of the Senate, 17 circuit judges for the new Twelfth Circuit, selected from the states assigned to that circuit.</p> <p>Senior circuit judges of the former Ninth Circuit currently stationed in Alaska, Arizona, Idaho, Montana, Oregon, Washington, Guam, Hawaii, Nevada, or the Northern Mariana Islands may elect their circuit assignment. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
