<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="378" measure-id="id115hr378" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-09" update-date="2017-07-12">
<title>Bonuses for Cost-Cutters Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr378v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-07-12">
<action-date>2017-01-09</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Bonuses for Cost-Cutters Act of 2017</b></p> <p>The bill authorizes the head of a federal agency to pay a cash award to any agency employee whose identification of unnecessary expenses has resulted in cost savings for the agency. The maximum dollar amount of such award is increased from $10,000 to $20,000. </p>   <p>If the Chief Financial Officer of the agency determines that potential unnecessary expenses identified by the employee meet applicable requirements, the head of the agency shall transfer the amount of the unnecessary expenses or unnecessary budget authority from the applicable appropriations account to the general fund of the Treasury. Any amount so transferred shall be deposited in the Treasury and used for deficit reduction or to reduce the federal debt, if there is no current budget deficit.</p> <p>An agency head may retain not more than 10% of amounts transferred to the general fund of the Treasury.</p> <p>The bill expands the list of federal officers and employees ineligible to receive a cash award. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
