<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2028" measure-id="id115hr2028" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-06" update-date="2018-01-04">
<title>Healthy Relationships Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2028v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-01-04">
<action-date>2017-04-06</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Healthy Relationships Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill authorizes the Administration for Children &amp; Families of the Department of Health and Human Services to award grants to public and private entities for the exclusive purpose of providing qualified sexual risk avoidance education to youth and their parents. </p> <p>Such education must address specified topics, including:</p> <UL> <LI>benefits associated with personal responsibility and healthy decisionmaking; <LI>the advantage of reserving sexual activity for marriage; <li>the skills needed to resist the harms associated with pornography and pervasive, sex-saturated culture; </li> <LI>the foundational components of healthy relationships; and <LI>how to resist and avoid sexual coercion and dating violence.</LI> </UL> <p>Priority in awarding grants must be given to applicants who propose sexual risk avoidance education programs that will regularly reinforce the sexual risk avoidance message in both the middle and high school grades and will promote parent-child communication on the benefits of avoiding all sexual risk.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
