<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="2940" measure-id="id115hr2940" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-06-20" update-date="2017-11-06">
<title>Congressional Self-Defense Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr2940v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-06">
<action-date>2017-06-20</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<b>Congressional Self-Defense Act</b> <p>This bill amends the federal criminal code to allow a Member of Congress who is carrying a valid Member identification document and who is not otherwise prohibited from transporting, shipping, or receiving a firearm to carry a concealed firearm for any lawful purpose: (1) in the U.S. Capitol only as authorized by regulations issued by the Capitol Police Board; and (2) anywhere else in the United States, except where the U.S. Secret Service is protecting the President or Vice President and prohibiting the possession of a firearm.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
