<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1934" measure-id="id115hr1934" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-04-05" update-date="2017-11-02">
<title>To establish a 5-year ban on individuals appointed to Executive Schedule positions and Members of Congress engaging in lobbying activities at the Federal level.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1934v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-02">
<action-date>2017-04-05</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill amends the federal criminal code to increase to five years the ban on individuals appointed to executive schedule positions (except special government employees who serve less than 60 days in a 1-year period) from engaging in lobbying activities in the executive branch. </p> <p>The Office of Government Ethics may waive lobbying restriction for certain executive schedule employees if it determines that the restrictions would create an undue hardship in obtaining qualified personnel for agency positions and granting such waiver would not create the potential for use of undue influence or unfair advantage.</p> <p>The bill increases to five years the ban on lobbying activities by Senators or Members of the House of Representatives.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
