<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1196" measure-id="id115hr1196" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-02-16" update-date="2017-06-19">
<title>Counterterrorism Screening and Assistance Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1196v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-19">
<action-date>2017-02-16</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Counterterrorism Screening and Assistance Act of 2017</strong></p> <p>This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the U.S. government must ensure that capacity-building assistance to combat terrorist travel is coordinated among departments and agencies as well as with foreign implementing partners, and (2) such assistance should be prioritized for the highest-risk countries for travel by terrorists and foreign fighters. </p> <p>The Department of State shall submit to Congress biennially a foreign partner engagement plan that catalogues existing capacity-building initiatives abroad to combat travel by terrorists and foreign fighters and identifies areas for adjustment to align efforts with risk-based priorities. </p> <p>The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and the State Department shall accelerate the provision of appropriate versions of the following systems to foreign governments: </p> <ul> <li>U.S. Customs and Border Protection's global travel targeting and analysis systems; and </li> <li>the State Department's watchlisting, identification, and screening systems. </li> </ul> <p>DHS may provide, with specified exceptions, excess DHS nonlethal equipment and supplies (as well as related training) to a foreign government if that would: </p> <ul> <li>further U.S. homeland security interests; and</li> <li>enhance the recipient government's capacity to mitigate the threat of terrorism, infectious disease or natural disaster, protect lawful trade and travel, or enforce intellectual property rights.</li> </ul> <p>DHS shall: </p> <ul> <li>notify Congress before providing such systems, equipment, or supplies; and </li> <li>report to Congress annually through 2022 regarding foreign government efforts to combat terrorist and foreign fighter travel.</li> </ul> <p>The State Department may suspend non-humanitarian, non-trade-related foreign assistance to a foreign country identified in such a report as a country to which the minimum standards for serious and sustained efforts to combat terrorist and foreign fighter travel are applicable but whose government is not fully complying with such standards and is not making significant efforts to bring itself into compliance. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
