<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="3705" measure-id="id115hr3705" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-09-07" update-date="2017-11-16">
<title>Veterans Fair Debt Notice Act of 2017</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3705v36" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-16">
<action-date>2017-11-08</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House amended</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on November 7, 2017. The summary of that version is repeated here.)</p> <p><b>Veterans Fair Debt Notice Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to collaborate with veterans service organizations to write a standard letter to be provided to individuals who owe debts to the VA. Such letter shall be written in plain language and shall include a notice of the debt and a clear explanation of: (1) why the individual owes such money, and (2) available options.</p> <p>The VA shall develop a method by which individuals may elect to receive debt notification letters by electronic means and shall ensure that the letter is delivered: (1) by both standard mail and electronic means to individuals who have made such election, and (2) only by standard mail to individuals who have not made such election.</p> <p>The VA shall: (1) notify Congress regarding the completion of such letter, and (2) study and report to Congress on the process by which it notifies veterans of debt collection efforts. </p> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3705v17" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-16">
<action-date>2017-11-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Veterans Fair Debt Notice Act of 2017</b></p> <p>(Sec. 2) This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to collaborate with veterans service organizations to write a standard letter to be provided to individuals who owe debts to the VA. Such letter shall be written in plain language and shall include a notice of the debt and a clear explanation of: (1) why the individual owes such money, and (2) available options.</p> <p>The VA shall develop a method by which individuals may elect to receive debt notification letters by electronic means and shall ensure that the letter is delivered: (1) by both standard mail and electronic means to individuals who have made such election, and (2) only by standard mail to individuals who have not made such election.</p> <p>The VA shall: (1) notify Congress regarding the completion of such letter, and (2) study and report to Congress on the process by which it notifies veterans of debt collection efforts. </p> </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr3705v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-11-07">
<action-date>2017-09-07</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><b>Veterans Fair Debt Notice Act of 2017</b></p> <p>This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to require that certified mail be used: (1) to send a veteran any debt demand or debt information notification concerning collection of debts resulting from the veteran's participation in a VA benefit or home loan program, and (2) by a veteran to request a collection waiver from the VA. </p> <p>A VA debt demand shall explain in plain language why the debtor owes money to the VA, and a VA debt notification shall include in plain language options available to the debtor.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
