<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="257" measure-id="id115hr257" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-01-04" update-date="2017-06-23">
<title>Recognition of Jerusalem as the Capital of the State of Israel Act</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr257v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-06-23">
<action-date>2017-01-04</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p><strong>Recognition of Jerusalem as the Capital of the State of Israel Act</strong></p> <p>This bill states that it is U.S. policy to recognize Jerusalem as the undivided capital of Israel. </p> <p>The bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the United States should recognize the sovereign status of an undivided Jerusalem as Israel's capital, (2) recognizing Jerusalem as Israel's capital and transferring the U.S. Embassy to Jerusalem from Tel Aviv will signal U.S. commitment to Israel, (3) the President and the Department of State should affirm as a matter of U.S. policy that Jerusalem must remain Israel's undivided capital, (4) the President should implement the provisions of the Jerusalem Embassy Act of 1995 and begin the process of relocating the U.S. Embassy in Israel to Jerusalem, and (5) U.S. officials should refrain from actions that contradict U.S. law on this subject.</p> <p> The bill states that any official U.S. government document that lists countries and their capital cities should identify Jerusalem as Israel's capital. </p> <p> The President shall relocate the U.S. Embassy in Israel to Jerusalem by January 1, 2019.</p> <p>The Jerusalem Embassy Act of 1995 is amended to eliminate the President's authority, effective January, 1, 2018, to waive certain funding limitations for State Department acquisition and maintenance of buildings abroad until the U.S. Embassy in Jerusalem has officially opened. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
