<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><BillSummaries>
<item congress="115" measure-type="hr" measure-number="1733" measure-id="id115hr1733" originChamber="HOUSE" orig-publish-date="2017-03-27" update-date="2018-02-23">
<title>To direct the Secretary of Energy to review and update a report on the energy and environmental benefits of the re-refining of used lubricating oil.</title>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1733v81" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-23">
<action-date>2017-12-12</action-date>
<action-desc>Passed House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House reported version is repeated here.) </p> <p>(Sec.1)This bill directs the Department of Energy to update its report on the energy and environmental benefits of re-refining used lubricating oil and submit to Congress a strategic plan to increase the beneficial reuse of lubricating oil. </p> <p>The strategic plan shall address measures needed to: (1)increase the responsible collection of used oil; (2)disseminate public information concerning sustainable reuse options for used oil; and (3)promote sustainable reuse of used oil by federal agencies, recipients of federal grant funds, entities contracting with the federal government, and the general public.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1733v79" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2018-02-02">
<action-date>2017-12-11</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported to House without amendment</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</p> <p>(Sec.1)This bill directs the Department of Energy to update its report on the energy and environmental benefits of re-refining used lubricating oil and submit to Congress a strategic plan to increase the beneficial reuse of lubricating oil. </p> <p>The strategic plan shall address measures needed to: (1)increase the responsible collection of used oil; (2)disseminate public information concerning sustainable reuse options for used oil; and (3)promote sustainable reuse of used oil by federal agencies, recipients of federal grant funds, entities contracting with the federal government, and the general public.</p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
<summary summary-id="id115hr1733v00" currentChamber="HOUSE" update-date="2017-04-19">
<action-date>2017-03-27</action-date>
<action-desc>Introduced in House</action-desc>
<summary-text><![CDATA[<p>This bill directs the Department of Energy to update its report on the energy and environmental benefits of re-refining used lubricating oil and submit to Congress a strategic plan to increase the beneficial reuse of lubricating oil. </p>]]></summary-text>
</summary>
</item>
<dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
<dc:description>This file contains bill summaries for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
</dublinCore>
</BillSummaries>
