<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCCD6E641A17F481ABEC6D736B79BB984" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2223 IH: Community Protection and Preparedness Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2223</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170428">April 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000791">Mr. Walden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to provide for a rail spill preparedness fund, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1CAAD60CC5204C7AABCB7BCD94C1BDEC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H62F5A22CF0CB40758C0945B420628C52" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Protection and Preparedness Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB3E4F9EAF0174D768CD1717F96CB93BA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rail spill preparedness fund</header> <subsection id="H449FA993F69B49A4BAF605C7602D0BBE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/51">Chapter 51</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/5110">section 5110</external-xref> the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71BCDD2D19E64575A85E01A3F20BEC54" style="USC"> 
<section id="HB36F95580D084B93A5F1D063226E640A"><enum>5111.</enum><header>Rail spill preparedness fund</header> 
<subsection id="HBBDEAB583E5A4BBBA6166E924DC153D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of Rail Account</header><text>There is established in the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund a separate account to be known as the <quote>Rail Account</quote> consisting of such amounts as may be appropriated, credited, deposited, or transferred to such account as provided in this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H55688611BFB34AC9B8E0EDF4DF98DE63"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fee for certain railroad tank cars transporting Class 3 flammable liquids</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than October 1, 2017, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall impose a fee of $1,500 for each DOT–111 specification railroad tank car, including each CPC–1232 tank car, used to transport Class 3 flammable liquids during the previous fiscal year that, at the time such tank car was used, did not meet the DOT–117, DOT–117P, or DOT–117R specifications in part 179 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations. Such fee shall be—</text> 
<paragraph id="H13A2F2CBB2C3461588F613E2AA7B3C70"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">paid by each person who causes such liquids to be transported by such a tank car in commerce; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1905B0299B1A44BDB5D4B27CF4846A4A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>imposed regardless of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBBA18628C88444EEA128AE952AED9F4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>train composition; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H42512B174D204D899EFB3CFEBD58DDAD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the phase-out schedule under section 7304(b) of the FAST Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/20155">49 U.S.C. 20155</external-xref> note).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H91F3C8F276034EC2B63164735380AD7D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A fee imposed pursuant to subsection (b) may not be imposed on a railroad carrier that transports Class 3 flammable liquids.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0C4E68994AD1494DA7931C4CF8CBA8D5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Means of collection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prescribe procedures to collect the fees described in subsection (b). The Secretary may use a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government or of a State or local government to collect the fee and may reimburse the department, agency, or instrumentality a reasonable amount for its services.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H01ACEF83A9634BF693A2A20DCB3D969A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Deposits</header><text>Amounts equivalent to the fees collected pursuant to subsection (b) shall be deposited into the Rail Account.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDA5988DA65A8436C80893ED4152819DF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Expenditures</header><text>Amounts deposited pursuant to subsection (e) shall be available to the Secretary, without need of further appropriation, only for the following purposes:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6B00CC5CD1074F388A40F88347560A12"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The payment of removal and remediation costs and other costs, expenses, claims, and damages related to an accident or incident involving the transportation of Class 3 flammable liquids by rail.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D99A895565A4BFB9F4A7990F1F3E531"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For the Secretary to make grants to States and Indian tribes to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H609B2F08232B41A09DB4FA4B98A9DD6B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop, improve, and carry out emergency plans under the Emergency Planning and Community Right-To-Know Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11001">42 U.S.C. 11001</external-xref> et seq.) related to an accident or incident involving the transportation of Class 3 flammable liquids by rail, including ascertaining flow patterns of Class 3 flammable liquids on lands under the jurisdiction of a State or Indian tribe and lands of another State or Indian tribe;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBFB35E8246914AFC88FB47D9E5E3066E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to develop and train regional hazardous material emergency response teams to prepare for an accident or incident involving the transportation of Class 3 flammable liquids by rail;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB2C51B14864A49DFA05784994F9A10D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to train public sector employees to respond to accidents and incidents involving the transportation of Class 3 flammable liquids by rail consistent with the requirements of section 5116; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H733448FB24E844FFAD52EB268F37354E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>for any other measures that the Secretary, in consultation with States and Indian tribes, determines necessary to assist such States and Indian tribes in preparing for accidents and incidents involving the transportation of Class 3 flammable liquids by rail.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEE775EC7C1344CCF9D345BCF00E29A48"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Public sector training standards</header><text>To the extent that a grant under subsection (f) is used to train emergency responders, the State or Indian tribe shall ensure that the emergency responders who receive training under the grant have the ability to protect nearby persons, property, and the environment from the effects of accidents or incidents involving the transportation of hazardous material in accordance with existing regulations or National Fire Protection Association standards for competence of responders to accidents and incidents involving hazardous materials, including the transportation of Class 3 flammable liquids by rail.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA946DE9ACBFB4FF1A3FCA38D59333C1F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>No effect on compliance or liability under Federal or State law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to affect or limit the application of, obligation to comply with, or liability under any Federal or State law.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4B5E1C52462A461D93E2E2D718746105"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header> 
<paragraph id="HB4C166E0728049FEA6888A7EBAB6A4DF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Class 3 flammable liquid</header><text>The term <quote>Class 3 flammable liquid</quote> has the meaning given the term flammable liquid in section 173.120(a) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEADF1EB8F4B14D5DB0E04752AE386A79"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Railroad carrier</header><text>The term <quote>railroad carrier</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 20102.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7670B996289F4EC48AB0A31952E135C1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/5110">section 5110</external-xref> the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93939395F4CA4FAF8578DA2073A76496" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">5111. Rail spill preparedness fund.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="HE5A36217E32E4DEEBA23361E1C258B39"><enum>3.</enum><header>Final rule on oil spill response plans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration shall issue a final rule relating to the notice of proposed rulemaking issued on July 29, 2016, entitled <quote>Hazardous Materials: Oil Spill Response Plans and Information Sharing for High-Hazard Flammable Trains</quote> (81 Fed. Reg. 50067).</text></section> 
<section id="HBC8F12C87BD145CB989A0F571241789E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Track safety specialists</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration to hire a minimum of 2 additional track safety specialists per region.</text></section> <section id="H2B088ED3C3F14E98B0D32ECC07D8C772"><enum>5.</enum><header>Study on the adequacy of certain track inspections and regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall transmit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate—</text> 
<paragraph id="H042DC219430F404386ACB467C33BACEE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of the adequacy of—</text> <subparagraph id="H1ED60AE904D642398B44B4236E32505A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>railroad track inspections, including the frequency of inspections; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H11033D88360E460CB0BFCD10A240EA05"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">training provided to railroad track inspectors and related railroad personnel;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3516C234427A4BD69B41BE47E02E6DAA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>railroad compliance with Federal track safety regulations; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAD5073A130C941A18A61D3A76581D570"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Federal oversight of railroads with respect to track safety; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA25DBA47C57A46DA9439672DBEC5BC21"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an evaluation on the leading causes of track defects, particularly along routes where passenger trains, high-hazardous flammable trains, or trains carrying poisonous or toxic-by-inhalation materials, explosives, or radioactive material traverse.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

