<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFB83797784AB42CE84774C0380B6DFF8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2495 IH: Stop Online Booking Scams Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2495</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170517">May 17, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect consumers from deceptive practices with respect to online booking of hotel reservations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H805890A78595406091879989B705A513" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC7038164B5404218AA4DB747AF31BB61" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Online Booking Scams Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H586DDA3CE9904FCB92E3239F4D0CA4D5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="HF40AA9B772D14DA6B1D6AAA0DA4BFC46"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HAF979BD05A0A41C4B40A1951342D3140"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Internet has become an important channel of commerce in the United States, accounting for billions of dollars in retail sales every year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE239E27B50AA4FA983E786E907CF43D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Hotel reservation transactions can be easily made online and online commerce has created a marketplace where consumers can shop for hotels, flights, car rentals, and other travel-related services and products across thousands of brands on a single platform.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2CD37678A20649B9830EE16A39B02D99"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consumers should be able to clearly identify the company with which they are transacting business online.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9CD9FE91F0544EEA1A83ADFB0572A18"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Actions by third-party sellers that misappropriate brand identity, trademark, or other marketing content are harmful to consumers.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB918B05B50FA4F6DBE13B80D4DA65F49"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Platforms offered by online travel agencies provide consumers with a valuable tool for comparative shopping for hotels and should not be mistaken for the unlawful third-party actors that commit such misappropriation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA01A78B7D9BB42279F807D3A0DFDCEF5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The misleading and deceptive sales tactics companies use against consumers booking hotel rooms online have resulted in the loss of sensitive financial and personal information, financial harm, and other damages for consumers.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HFBBC679293BE48D29F09C41379EFF358"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HF379E9F1F8A846B6A027E898EE2D976F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consumers benefit from the ability to shop for travel-related services and products on the innovative platforms offered by online travel agencies;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDCF24544479F48B1AC2E6C64F7BAF931"><enum>(2)</enum><text>sellers on the Internet should—</text> <subparagraph id="H66E8FC3075F643899A564B4210E24BAB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide consumers with clear, accurate information; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA4A59842FFB448F986BF5EEACBB6A743"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have an opportunity to compete fairly with one another; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H296D7767F79B4C6E8CF837EBBE81A412"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Federal Trade Commission should revise the Commission’s Internet site to make it easier for consumers and businesses to report complaints of deceptive practices with respect to online booking of hotel reservations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section commented="no" id="H11960191B59840DEB242D612BCBA0337"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HC5C1E0CDB41A47E7B7913A24E67F8258"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affiliation contract</header><text>The term <term>affiliation contract</term> means, with respect to a hotel, a contract with the owner of the hotel, the entity that manages the hotel, or the franchisor of the hotel to provide online hotel reservation services for the hotel.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD71FDBC88C6A4BF894EAD696F615A525"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H46B02053059448829B941AA5B82798EF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exhibition organizer or meeting planner</header><text>The term <term>exhibition organizer or meeting planner</term> means the person responsible for all aspects of planning, promoting, and producing a meeting, conference, event, or exhibition, including overseeing and arranging all hotel reservation plans and contracts for the meeting, conference, event, or exhibition.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC7F30A6A2FD433BA0AFCAEDCE8DACEC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Official housing bureau</header><text>The term <term>official housing bureau</term> means the organization designated by an exhibition organizer or meeting planner to provide hotel reservation services for meetings, conferences, events, or exhibitions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H75E0CAC9910F4286BEAFC67D90A60BA9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Party directly affiliated</header><text>The term <term>party directly affiliated</term> means, with respect to a hotel, a person who has entered into an affiliation contract with the hotel.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFCDE22575562426A95B5585D017B7F20"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Third party online hotel reservation seller</header><text>The term <term>third party online hotel reservation seller</term> means any person that—</text> <subparagraph id="HE38713047F0B495BAC0036B400AA084A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sells any good or service with respect to a hotel in a transaction effected on the Internet; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD6892DAC0A5A41088DE86BDE62B19686"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not—</text> <clause id="HA878FD2596EC4056B4F4DD372365E59C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a party directly affiliated with the hotel; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H92C1EAA22F084168AFB891C570FF0D97"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an exhibition organizer or meeting planner or the official housing bureau for a meeting, conference, event, or exhibition held at the hotel.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HE9A7FE548EA44AFD92207C27704ED869"><enum>4.</enum><header>Requirements for third party online hotel reservation sellers</header> <subsection id="H8B38892251DC4ECBBFB3ABB559A8CE6C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a third party online hotel reservation seller to charge or attempt to charge any consumer’s credit card, debit card, bank account, or other financial account for any good or service sold in a transaction effected on the Internet with respect to a hotel unless the third party online hotel reservation seller—</text>
<paragraph id="H220F17994B7F4AD68FDA9DE01ABDB8D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>clearly and conspicuously discloses to the consumer all material terms of the transaction, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H43434EA0BB0740939308806DB759B29C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>before the conclusion of the transaction—</text>
<clause id="HB4F7848469F84D89899AAD3CD2C6E8CB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the good or service being offered; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA639FA77D42447BCB29D3A716E016528"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost of such good or service; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEB20FDC43A8E4507A2706A596B19DD17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a manner that is continuously visible to the consumer throughout the transaction process, that the person—</text> <clause id="H232CEDEC66A346A38B9A8DFABF069F62"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a third party online hotel reservation seller; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H76BB3F66AE674B31858D55E8D1E74450"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not—</text> <subclause id="H2985888043FD45AB90592780844A0ECB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>affiliated with the owner of the hotel or the entity that provides the hotel services or accommodations; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H43ACAADB044D402DABA980B267E3F620"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an exhibition organizer or meeting planner or the official housing bureau for a meeting, conference, event, or exhibition held at the hotel; or</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA52A02FE5704239BDAE6B6B58D9CB53"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes prominent and continuous disclosure of the brand identity of the third party online hotel reservation seller throughout the transaction process, whether online or over the phone.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H3A0B9B53211E43E0A3A98D6B0EB08ABC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by Commission</header>
<paragraph id="HEBF3BDF9580E4A4ABB3F5BEDA0C5B36B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of subsection (a) by a person subject to such subsection shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B39AEB6EFFA45F0A4001707A614F3BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header> <subparagraph id="H570E277C73F844E3924CB8B20C142197"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41</external-xref> et seq.) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0431F3D3679547A6A202D74FBF79C512"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any person who violates this section shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41</external-xref> et seq.).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE240A013DC724A6F9D6A8BF58D9A7358"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header> <clause id="H06EAA24812F540698282A31187BEABC4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission may promulgate such rules as the Commission considers appropriate to enforce this section.</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2016997B3DB74806B437CD7D0D0BBA58"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>The Commission shall carry out any rulemaking under clause (i) in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H66DDFC371224470894D024B1B895757B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement by States</header> <paragraph id="H1D1AF7FA744D459297ACAB79B8F23AAB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any case in which the attorney general of a State has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of the State has been or is being threatened or adversely affected by the engagement of any person subject to subsection (a) in a practice that violates such subsection, the attorney general of the State may, as parens patriae, bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate district court of the United States to obtain appropriate relief.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8164608255214D33A72032C61EB81D36"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rights of federal trade commission</header>
<subparagraph id="HD638228D6D224C0EAEFFAE44689D3CBA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notice to federal trade commission</header>
<clause id="HEEEFD25B1D3C4831BDCBE766474B8186"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (iii), the attorney general of a State shall notify the Commission in writing that the attorney general intends to bring a civil action under paragraph (1) before initiating any civil action against a person subject to subsection (a).</text></clause> <clause id="H8C11525FE3AC4E98B193C8F3B0EE69E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The notification required under clause (i) with respect to a civil action shall include a copy of the complaint to be filed to initiate the civil action.</text></clause>
<clause id="HDBB5861BEB7241B288F83FD5049F13CF"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If it is not feasible for the attorney general of a State to provide the notification required by clause (i) before initiating a civil action under paragraph (1), the attorney general shall notify the Commission immediately upon instituting the civil action.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H457944E976E4447CB6AC527EFE711123"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Intervention by federal trade commission</header><text>The Commission may—</text>
<clause id="HA98672FF5DFE46519E4DE7CA3CF66F14"><enum>(i)</enum><text>intervene in any civil action brought by the attorney general of a State under paragraph (1); and</text></clause> <clause id="H9345EF9CD5C44339B438592855378BC4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>upon intervening—</text>
<subclause id="H120AC5B3CCB84B4389A879C7CCCA40B4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>be heard on all matters arising in the civil action; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H599A32786F7246A6B7FA0CB5F9D89596"><enum>(II)</enum><text>file petitions for appeal of a decision in the civil action.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H87C9291EA50149728C6F5CD95ACE08F5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Investigatory powers</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prevent the attorney general of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general by the laws of the State—</text> <subparagraph id="H5D38C451F1154A3FAFBA5BF47514B672"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to conduct investigations;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0DDCC6A541EC4A4C8DC9A868685119E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to administer oaths or affirmations; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E518A6961FF4F2D8307356709969D01"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary or other evidence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H772EDE9B4A4342F88D4D0F4FBC98CFF6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State coordination with federal trade commission</header><text>If the Commission institutes a civil action or an administrative action with respect to a violation of subsection (a), the attorney general of a State shall coordinate with the Commission before bringing a civil action under paragraph (1) against any defendant named in the complaint of the Commission for the violation with respect to which the Commission instituted such action.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H135467AEA7F649A4AB79FCA049653ABF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Venue; service of process</header> <subparagraph id="HC83E845B19184694AD0D353EDD8CA0C0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Venue</header><text>Any action brought under paragraph (1) may be brought in—</text>
<clause id="HFCF504B663D3459FA912F328AD88FC1E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the district court of the United States that meets applicable requirements relating to venue under section 1391 of title 28, United States Code; or</text></clause> <clause id="H0FAB230B1F5E454F9EF0FDA6C0594EA1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>another court of competent jurisdiction.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7D0A278BF6F04CD3AE3C62749ADC5D75"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Service of process</header><text>In an action brought under paragraph (1), process may be served in any district in which the defendant—</text> <clause id="H488F3EA32EE14A008B15F5403678799B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is an inhabitant; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H42C7BA0580704F08973B5E7D5C96E7DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may be found.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2607DEB27CF247D9BB3696CC347890A2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Actions by other state officials</header> <subparagraph id="H9D6A52B501E94E25A2B6418702C10882"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to civil actions brought by attorneys general under paragraph (1), any other officer of a State who is authorized by the State to do so may bring a civil action under paragraph (1), subject to the same requirements and limitations that apply under this subsection to civil actions brought by attorneys general.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C05F352384D42B89D4B307994949BB1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prohibit an authorized official of a State from initiating or continuing any proceeding in a court of the State for a violation of any civil or criminal law of the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

