<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9DCC0594E8074B50AA95DD92F38085FE" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1928 IH: Families of Fallen Servicemembers First Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1928</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170405">April 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Thomas J. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide a permanent appropriation of funds for the payment of death gratuities and related
			 benefits for survivors of deceased members of the uniformed services in
			 event of any period of lapsed appropriations.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HFFAE0D96CE8B4578AAD9CE21E4E79F8E" style="OLC">
 <section id="H639DD34E1467406BBFB9FE5B887B0A72" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Families of Fallen Servicemembers First Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA8F0AD0071694E108F787C24CF2DD400"><enum>2.</enum><header>Permanent appropriation of funds for payment of death gratuities and related benefits for survivors of deceased military servicemembers in event of a period of lapsed appropriations</header> <subsection id="HA44B41DDE92B4D87ADA052C18080C3DC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds are hereby appropriated during any period of lapsed appropriations during a fiscal year, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for <quote>Operation and Maintenance</quote> and <quote>Military Personnel</quote> accounts related to members of the uniformed services (as defined in section 101(5) of title 37, United States Code) for the payment of death gratuities and the provision of related benefits described in subsection (c) to survivors of deceased members of the uniformed services during the period of lapsed appropriations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9647B39994934412B7C47CD3C269D104"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rate of appropriation</header><text>Funds appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) are appropriated at a rate for operations as provided for the most recent fiscal year for which an Act making appropriations for the uniformed services has been enacted and under the authority and conditions provided in such Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H97EDCA1781674612A418FACAC0614479"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) are available for the following purposes during the period of lapsed appropriations:</text>
 <paragraph id="H42F0E2A8920341E3A41AE0B57EDC3B22"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The payment of a death gratuity under sections 1475–1477 and 1489 of title 10, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE0D75F4CADD42059BD133962E22C6C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The payment or reimbursement for funeral and burial expenses authorized under sections 1481 and 1482 of title 10, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE8CFDBC13A44BBC852CC4E09E6B6B7F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The payment or reimbursement of authorized funeral travel and travel related to the dignified transfer of remains and unit memorial services under section 481f of title 37, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4C6979A9AC74F5EB3AE2CF50DC0C646"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The temporary continuation of a basic allowance of housing for dependents of members dying on active duty, as authorized by section 403(l) of title 37, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6A6CC15A96F400896CB0339D0EAD638"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) and authority granted pursuant to this Act shall be available whenever there is a period of lapsed appropriations for the duration of the period of lapsed appropriations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA217836CFDCF46A3AEF5CDAE4D185B9B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Treatment of expenditures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expenditures made pursuant to this Act shall be charged to the applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization whenever a bill in which such applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization is contained is enacted into law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA6E364B9FCE0472F93034D3B58036803"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of implementation</header><text>This Act shall be implemented so that only the most limited funding action of that permitted in this Act shall be taken in order to provide for continuation of the benefits described in subsection (c).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBBA6DB6ABB62415B8C4A976FC1B70B66"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Period of lapsed appropriations defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>period of lapsed appropriations</term> means any period during which appropriations are not available due to the absence of the timely enactment of any Act or joint resolution (including any Act or joint resolution making continuing appropriations) appropriating funds for the payment of the benefits described in subsection (c).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


