<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3F2238B659154321836631B0162C88B2" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2148 : Clarifying Commercial Real Estate Loans</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2148</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20171108">November 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to clarify capital requirements for certain acquisition,
			 development, or construction loans.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H1693A484D08C4D2E8BD3BEC413F4AFCA" style="OLC">
 <section id="id7455EF749F6E47D6A2C754D7EA87E469" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>Clarifying Commercial Real Estate Loans</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3B12D7D538F54F43AA3DFAF5B303A9A9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Capital requirements for certain acquisition, development, or construction loans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Deposit Insurance Act is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF61149528C8C41B69FE79AECF42A53E8" style="OLC">
				<section id="H7B018AD6C6624AE49C023B5FE7A8E49E"><enum>51.</enum><header>Capital requirements for certain acquisition, development, or construction loans</header>
 <subsection id="HDF1417053E6C4969A65B9663244C22AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appropriate Federal banking agencies may only subject a depository institution to higher capital standards with respect to a high volatility commercial real estate (HVCRE) exposure (as such term is defined under section 324.2 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, as of October 11, 2017, or if a successor regulation is in effect as of the date of the enactment of this section, such term or any successor term contained in such successor regulation) if such exposure is an HVCRE ADC loan.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H669C6216F8CF4DF59AC8ECE672DC5D4E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>HVCRE ADC loan defined</header><text>For purposes of this section and with respect to a depository institution, the term <quote>HVCRE ADC loan</quote>—</text> <paragraph id="H63E8E1F92BA049FC8010397C862EAC8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>means a credit facility secured by land or improved real property that, prior to being reclassified by the depository institution as a Non-HVCRE ADC loan pursuant to subsection (d)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4FEB624EF86F40D5A29E2C8D62ECEE13"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">primarily finances, has financed, or refinances the acquisition, development, or construction of real property;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC161F41971D24484AEE2B8B22D2F76BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has the purpose of providing financing to acquire, develop, or improve such real property into income-producing real property; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE087A4A3A71D419FB30C517918A19B15"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is dependent upon future income or sales proceeds from, or refinancing of, such real property for the repayment of such credit facility;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA224D99B6DA548DB80668F838B9A538F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include a credit facility financing—</text> <subparagraph id="H6EEE8E5BB91849B3BFA1A6B3F526AD53"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the acquisition, development, or construction of properties that are—</text>
 <clause id="HCF5B3DE987C342669FFB2C23BD2F6870"><enum>(i)</enum><text>one- to four-family residential properties;</text> </clause><clause id="HB2FBA21A26D744F986BFA72C5CAF2CEA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>real property that would qualify as an investment in community development; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H28CA983B9D0D41139E8662FDC744689F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>agricultural land;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H682B01C2098C439B95E16EE494A3BF9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the acquisition or refinance of existing income-producing real property secured by a mortgage on such property, if the cash flow being generated by the real property is sufficient to support the debt service and expenses of the real property, as determined by the depository institution, in accordance with the institution’s applicable loan underwriting criteria for permanent financings;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE35B97EDDBB45D8AF4215F26E69A50E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improvements to existing income-producing improved real property secured by a mortgage on such property, if the cash flow being generated by the real property is sufficient to support the debt service and expenses of the real property, as determined by the depository institution, in accordance with the institution’s applicable loan underwriting criteria for permanent financings; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8600FB44E3DB4F12997E6B0321D74A4B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>commercial real property projects in which—</text> <clause id="H757876AE57224DD7AD1BB851C3643648"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the loan-to-value ratio is less than or equal to the applicable maximum supervisory loan-to-value ratio as determined by the appropriate Federal banking agency; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HACE382CCB5F64A83822FE62310AAB67B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the borrower has contributed capital of at least 15 percent of the real property’s appraised, <quote>as completed</quote> value to the project in the form of—</text> <subclause id="H3DF6D72A7B374DF1A61605701357599C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>cash;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8C8861539C8C4C13BE98EA431E819FAB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>unencumbered readily marketable assets;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H672C09CE6BCC4D6E8C77738FE8E3288A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>paid development expenses out-of-pocket; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H97F23593E2A44E92AEB24C9C9D919A92"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>contributed real property or improvements; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H14D9C4ABD6564C78BE2C0DB255B8EDE7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the borrower contributed the minimum amount of capital described under clause (ii) before the depository institution advances funds under the credit facility, and such minimum amount of capital contributed by the borrower is contractually required to remain in the project until the credit facility has been reclassified by the depository institution as a Non-HVCRE ADC loan under subsection (d);</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H38CF97A2F96D429CB5845CF2B71AFEAB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>does not include any loan made prior to January 1, 2015; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B312739D3C14BE28F6EB10EB6AE7740"><enum>(4)</enum><text>does not include a credit facility reclassified as a Non-HVCRE ADC loan under subsection (d).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5762A266003E4797A0D38DB205B64082"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Value of contributed real property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the value of any real property contributed by a borrower as a capital contribution shall be the appraised value of the property as determined under standards prescribed pursuant to section 1110 of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/3339">12 U.S.C. 3339</external-xref>), in connection with the extension of the credit facility or loan to such borrower.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC5D729761CCA4D8CAF9B15B00EBB04C6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reclassification as a Non-HVCRE ADC loan</header><text>For purposes of this section and with respect to a credit facility and a depository institution, upon—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD4EFE78C779C4473A4F261CBCC101747"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the completion of the development or construction of the real property being financed by the credit facility; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H14694455FE374BD7ACB6B2E127F18749"><enum>(2)</enum><text>cash flow being generated by the real property being sufficient to support the debt service and expenses of the real property,</text>
						</paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">in either case to the satisfaction of the depository institution, in accordance with the
			 institution’s applicable loan underwriting criteria for permanent
			 financings, the credit facility may be reclassified by the depository
			 institution as a Non-HVCRE ADC loan.</continuation-text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20171107">Passed the House of Representatives November 7, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


