<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H729E27BA8DEC4BC591DE01BDE5CC8DDD" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1848 RH: Veterans Affairs Medical Scribe Pilot Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 99</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1848</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–151]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170403">April 3, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000791">Mr. Walden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action><action-date>May 23, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="Y000066">Mr. Young of Iowa</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action>
			<action-date>May 23, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed<pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program on the use of medical
			 scribes in Department of Veterans Affairs medical centers.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H81CF05F4D7434C7B8FF34FF1D236FDE8" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0F39F7276A754CCA934F2DB2E153EDA1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Affairs Medical Scribe Pilot Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDFC5D2ECCDB0461E9950E46C3FAE14CE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs medical scribe pilot program</header> <subsection id="H80F3ECF7C9174E09ACCB3E4AC83226A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a two-year pilot program under which the Secretary shall increase the use of medical scribes at Department of Veterans Affairs medical centers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1C15489B199C4526A1F07BA79A946D5C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Locations</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program at the 10 medical centers of the Department as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H21213692080D466C868F305C267AD159"><enum>(1)</enum><text>At least four such medical centers located in rural areas.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H22082E4ACFD64705980C399AC73AA512"><enum>(2)</enum><text>At least four such medical centers located in urban areas.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEBF1B254EFEC4233A3E4AA54C569EBB4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two such medical centers located in areas with need for increased access or increased efficiency, as determine by the Secretary.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7FDE635CFE6D4A2A81100F1EAAC55A8A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Medical scribes</header>
 <paragraph id="HB9BBF0C4CD9E4A0FA1B36B05C5D530C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hiring</header><text>Under the pilot program the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H307B29899A70423DA1BA8A291AB01D35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hire 20 new Department of Veterans Affairs term employees as medical scribes; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B3FCB776DBB411DAF5F5345F084ED04"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seek to enter into contracts with appropriate entities for the employment of 20 additional medical scribes.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H204044104E9C4336A89F62F8E43D4083"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>The Secretary shall assign four medical scribes to each of the 10 medical centers of the Department where the Secretary carries out the pilot program as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE5309EFCB5D34D35AF10CE93ED6CF5BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Two scribes shall be assigned to each of two physicians.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAE27950A48B4EDAA15A65246A4A7437"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Thirty percent of the scribes shall be employed in the provision of emergency care.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H545EC1173D114F17AD01BE6842D74CB7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Seventy percent of the scribes shall be employed in the provision of speciality care in specialties with the longest patient wait times or lowest efficiency ratings, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5D2913278434599820D29B7DABC2A1D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <paragraph id="HA20F4FFDCDC7414CB9876FC92DF74E0D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the commencement of the pilot program required under this section, and every 180 days thereafter for the duration of the pilot program, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress a report on the pilot program. Each such report shall include each of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7185F4C777254F6B809ECE444AEAF47F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A separate analysis of each the following with respect to medical scribes employed by the Department of Veterans Affairs and medical scribes performing Department of Veterans Affairs functions under a contract:</text>
 <clause id="H4C58D399FC814EC9BE185E679DA68300"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Provider efficiency.</text> </clause><clause id="HE1107E6DA8794131B910C3924456FC67"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Patient satisfaction.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCF4517BC6F904A3480C24CB571ADFBC0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Average wait time.</text> </clause><clause id="H24D1FD50FA4C439FB67DD13ADEC99374"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The number of patients seen per day by each physician or practitioner.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCCAC55F40D86496689228D07D235905D"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of time required to hire and train an employee to perform medical scribe functions under the pilot program.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DCB4B43682A4E0A9B1F3A3E5FD488BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Metrics and data for analyzing the effects of the pilot program, including an evaluation of the each of the elements under clauses (i) through (iv) of subparagraph (A) at medical centers who employed scribes under the pilot program for an appropriate period preceding the hiring of such scribes.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H989C08483DBD41E39296BDF737322B59"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comptroller General report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the termination of the pilot program under this section, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the pilot program. Such report shall include a comparison of the pilot program with similar programs carried out in the private sector.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEADD8222E174415FA22C77CAAFE6032A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H299F7C916B2E484AB62659EC5F136DA2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>medical scribe</quote> means an unlicensed individual hired to enter information into the electronic health record or chart at the direction of a physician or licensed independent practitioner whose responsibilities include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF05372DA08504A6981DE0754F3CD0A6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Assisting the physician or practitioner in navigating the electronic health record.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3605870358B84AF8B94051B6C9D00952"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Responding to various messages as directed by the physician or practitioner.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA1A5C82C7FC43F9A008FC6D94B727E8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Entering information into the electronic health record, as directed by the physician or practitioner.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAF2DECBAF634E2ABE2B34A12E92232E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>urban</quote> and <quote>rural</quote> have the meanings given such terms under the rural-urban commuting codes developed by the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H62B8528C20A04F4AA6178D0B7E88142B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The pilot program under this section shall be carried out using amounts otherwise authorized to be appropriated for the Department of Veterans Affairs. No additional amounts are authorized to be appropriated to carry out such program.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>May 23, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


