<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBC8CFB65635B4884BCA6587741B7CB95" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 38 IH: Concealed Carry Reciprocity Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 38</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170103">January 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000374">Mr. Abraham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000578">Mr. Gaetz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001065">Mr. Holding</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000362">Mr. King of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Thomas J. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000819">Mr. Walker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000560">Mr. Graves of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001036">Mr. Hensarling</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000297">Mr. Jenkins of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000017">Mr. Zeldin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000051">Mr. Sanford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001290">Mr. Brat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000614">Mr. Duffy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000063">Mr. Yoder</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000601">Mr. Ratcliffe</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001045">Mr. Harper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001297">Mr. Buck</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide a means by which nonresidents of a State whose
			 residents may carry concealed firearms may also do so in the State.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4EF0923253E6416D972711260F08CEA9" style="OLC">
 <section id="HDA69A816207B46CCB6E1374B38065B1D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Concealed Carry Reciprocity Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1EA8C2A212644519B5651146A024B4E3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reciprocity for the carrying of certain concealed firearms</header> <subsection id="H87BAAD975D5240D7968EA4C68442DF11"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">Chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/926C">section 926C</external-xref> the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H7317AEC5AF6F4107BD323DFC72E04F59" style="USC">
					<section id="H7059B98C2A7246949130B489951813FB"><enum>926D.</enum><header>Reciprocity for the carrying of certain concealed firearms</header>
 <subsection id="H762BF3ADFEBD45948FACF4FC21B1E3B8"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision of the law of any State or political subdivision thereof (except as provided in subsection (b)) and subject only to the requirements of this section, a person who is not prohibited by Federal law from possessing, transporting, shipping, or receiving a firearm, who is carrying a valid identification document containing a photograph of the person, and who is carrying a valid license or permit which is issued pursuant to the law of a State and which permits the person to carry a concealed firearm or is entitled to carry a concealed firearm in the State in which the person resides, may possess or carry a concealed handgun (other than a machinegun or destructive device) that has been shipped or transported in interstate or foreign commerce, in any State that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0A2B39BA5CF84CAEAC93D85FDCCA7E4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has a statute under which residents of the State may apply for a license or permit to carry a concealed firearm; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4281097324CD4D54A3C53141BDA2997D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not prohibit the carrying of concealed firearms by residents of the State for lawful purposes.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2239C87832E840C09E679AA092E6B90B"><enum>(b)</enum><text>This section shall not be construed to supersede or limit the laws of any State that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC13818457C8C4ACA9B607C9E93B77ECE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>permit private persons or entities to prohibit or restrict the possession of concealed firearms on their property; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5EE7209C3AE7446E8FEDBC3841C2399D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibit or restrict the possession of firearms on any State or local government property, installation, building, base, or park.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4F662F16EFFD44389EFD6D1F2B9D0CBB"><enum>(c)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H951DD163B8AC4ABEA710D887B5134A37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A person who carries or possesses a concealed handgun in accordance with subsections (a) and (b) may not be arrested or otherwise detained for violation of any law or any rule or regulation of a State or any political subdivision thereof related to the possession, transportation, or carrying of firearms unless there is probable cause to believe that the person is doing so in a manner not provided for by this section. Presentation of facially valid documents as specified in subsection (a) is prima facie evidence that the individual has a license or permit as required by this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H39363F4173584A97AE870549E791AD66" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>When a person asserts this section as a defense in a criminal proceeding, the prosecution shall bear the burden of proving, beyond a reasonable doubt, that the conduct of the person did not satisfy the conditions set forth in subsections (a) and (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B7FA4E4A2694E9AA8DF25AA1134D605" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>When a person successfully asserts this section as a defense in a criminal proceeding, the court shall award the prevailing defendant a reasonable attorney’s fee.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE727569B5F4F455CB967196A456D32A2"><enum>(d)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H69B218D0A1304197A7F39DBBBCF609F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A person who is deprived of any right, privilege, or immunity secured by this section, under color of any statute, ordinance, regulation, custom, or usage of any State or any political subdivision thereof, may bring an action in any appropriate court against any other person, including a State or political subdivision thereof, who causes the person to be subject to the deprivation, for damages or other appropriate relief.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3CCB252D47124306B6C07C51EADC925F" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The court shall award a plaintiff prevailing in an action brought under paragraph (1) damages and such other relief as the court deems appropriate, including a reasonable attorney’s fee.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H622548ABCEA0459FB0CD2BC1504B4EA3"><enum>(e)</enum><text>In subsection (a):</text> <paragraph id="HED002D7319474F9EBAF03D9DCBCA064E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>identification document</term> means a document made or issued by or under the authority of the United States Government, a State, or a political subdivision of a State which, when completed with information concerning a particular individual, is of a type intended or commonly accepted for the purpose of identification of individuals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70DC27BB08584AFAA49871CE2D759084"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>handgun</term> includes any magazine for use in a handgun and any ammunition loaded into the handgun or its magazine.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5E5AF01C24B4B598A533D9D0DF8EA31"><enum>(f)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFAFFB241950E4EDD915D0F5AF9341E9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A person who possesses or carries a concealed handgun under subsection (a) shall not be subject to the prohibitions of section 922(q) with respect to that handgun.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC21F0BC08534AEDAFB2776867CC62A8" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A person possessing or carrying a concealed handgun in a State under subsection (a) may do so in any of the following areas in the State that are open to the public:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE14BCE3B6B9A4F7780B3CAF16DC9F70E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A unit of the National Park System.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD68DF9D05777426381A81DFDBF8A36F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A unit of the National Wildlife Refuge System.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA04EDA8004424A8090D186E45AD33525"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Public land under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20B4ED29E4FD4DB7B5DC4D2693AE7129"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Land administered and managed by the Army Corps of Engineers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8892B05EE74E4307A5FB4A2C88A4DDEB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Land administered and managed by the Bureau of Reclamation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H721BA9A58D3D4FFAA84831220B26622D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 926C the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H415F0CA5FE4941959C7B8EDCE3C1F489" style="USC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H7317AEC5AF6F4107BD323DFC72E04F59" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="H7059B98C2A7246949130B489951813FB" level="section">926D. Reciprocity for the carrying of certain concealed firearms.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H71CC4D590AFB4582AE10D468C2CB0E17"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, if any provision of this section, or any amendment made by this section, or the application of such provision or amendment to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, this section and amendments made by this section and the application of such provision or amendment to other persons or circumstances shall not be affected thereby.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE84DCB40CD944E588CC1DC8893020BDD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


