<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HEEDD31B8CD304DEAA4D4E78D34A695E5" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3171 IH: To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide that certain orthotist’s and prosthetist’s clinical notes under Medicare be treated as part of the patient’s medical record.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3171</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170710">July 10, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001293">Mr. Bishop of Michigan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide that certain orthotist’s and
			 prosthetist’s clinical notes under Medicare be treated as part of the
			 patient’s medical record.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1A603F3B4A114B9FB7E9E142F977DE89" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7667A62D9E0A41F68725D995EC099A07" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Orthotist’s and prosthetist’s clinical notes as part of the patient’s medical record</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834(h) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(h)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1EBBCA6DB81C4C8CBEE30A7F5D5D63E3" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H79189ABD6FEF48CA8E75760024A60526"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Documentation created by orthotists and prosthetists</header><text>For purposes of determining the reasonableness and medical necessity of orthotics and prosthetics, documentation created by an orthotist or prosthetist shall be considered part of the patient’s medical record to support documentation created by eligible professionals described in section 1848(k)(3)(B).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


