<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCFACEEAD22AF42D7A0E9382CD2E5D574" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4291 IH: Precision Farming Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4291</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171107">November 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To utilize loans and loan guarantees under the rural broadband access program to provide broadband
			 service for agricultural producers and to provide universal service
			 support for installation charges for broadband service for agricultural
			 producers in order to improve precision farming and ranching, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H31D64EBE3BB2478A9E5F183071D35348" style="OLC">
 <section id="H55DE2AA65A04407CA328F219EBE1D7DB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Precision Farming Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC27BB5D1AEF84EB3B14A1AC88D714430"><enum>2.</enum><header>Loan priorities in providing access to broadband telecommunications services in rural areas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 601(c)(2) of the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/950bb">7 U.S.C. 950bb(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7E7E1F01E4334D79A2A34ADF78383665"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (C);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H54C006C8D6F8438FA1F13AE2C166F59D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (E) and, in such subparagraph, by striking <quote>in the applications of the applicants</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5379762C61E84507936AB6F619C8A4EB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following new subparagraph (D):</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H538C5CCD68204D97BB39C475CE326995" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H965AA509FD7E457DAADA9F7E7050B39E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">give priority to applicants that offer to provide broadband service, at better than the minimum acceptable level of broadband service established under subsection (e), to agricultural producers in the proposed service territory to improve their ability to conduct precision farming or ranching, as determined by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H130A60A8EF7849DBA8DD8883B28FB393"><enum>3.</enum><header>Universal service support for broadband service installation charges for agricultural producers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 254 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/254">47 U.S.C. 254</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73D29E61794844E9B6DD3FC84F20E4CD" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H565F2FC138F24772BA553D90C14269B2"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Support for broadband service installation charges for agricultural producers</header>
 <paragraph id="H7CDBB835250A42C7BCEEC5D70BA752A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A provider of broadband service serving a geographic area shall, upon a bona fide request from an agricultural producer for connection to such service to improve the ability of the producer to conduct precision farming or ranching, install any line or other facility or equipment necessary to enable such connection at a discount from the amount that the provider would charge other parties for a similar installation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5652C9CC92ED4F3B8D48D11E02CC30DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of discount</header><text>The amount of the discount provided under paragraph (1) shall be the lesser of—</text> <subparagraph id="HA4CAB7D183FA4FE0B20CA0341FE68C91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount that the provider would charge other parties for a similar installation; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2F1E9BBE6FC45968BBD550CBECD95FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$15,000.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H77D23019CC9D4531B3E89C7F283A94F5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limit of one discount per agricultural producer</header><text>An agricultural producer may not receive more than one discount under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAE784945C7D452AAEEB7695D96C6D6D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Offset or reimbursement</header><text>A provider of broadband service that makes an installation under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HBC43815362DC4221AB7D57AB3B4853CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have an amount equal to the amount of the discount provided under such paragraph treated as an offset to its obligation to contribute to the mechanisms to preserve and advance universal service; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7D9DCB9A165403F83FED40672AFAD47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (e), receive reimbursement utilizing the support mechanisms to preserve and advance universal service.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F51CE4E909142EDAFC766FC3C98BC8E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consistency with rural broadband access program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, promulgate such regulations as are necessary to ensure that this subsection is carried out in a manner that is consistent with the manner in which the Secretary of Agriculture carries out subparagraph (D) of section 601(c)(2) of the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/950bb">7 U.S.C. 950bb(c)(2)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


