<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBF24A38B24DD4BB8AF39344F37A97E44" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1986 IH: Transportation Security Administration Ombudsman Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1986</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to establish an Ombudsman Office within the Transportation
			 Security Administration for the purpose of enhancing transportation
			 security by providing confidential, informal, and neutral assistance to
			 address work-place related problems of Transportation Security
			 Administration employees, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3F584655BD56445791DB68B503E1B692" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3A9179E676E7498C8CC8F62EFA249F61" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transportation Security Administration Ombudsman Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H691062400F294EF29AD1EE2AB02AEE93"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transportation Security Administration ombudsman office</header> <subsection id="H529E1709FA034E1AA48B1F20078438E6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/449">chapter 449</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H7FF35D666DE4412EB96F14F3208EBF02" style="USC">
					<section id="HEFF0F8EBAA91492FB2F0CEDFB900734F"><enum>44947.</enum><header>Ombudsman</header>
						<subsection id="HD086C4BA0DE047A7BE8177AF69A6BBB4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="HF774F2843A894B2AB0A16FF4548CA99C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established an Office of the Ombudsman in the Transportation Security Administration.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H75C0FD5B07CA4453A2AF8A4B8334C098"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ombudsman</header> <subparagraph id="HD2158AA4893345ECAF74B260F87AC1FB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office shall be under the direction of the Ombudsman of the Transportation Security Administration, who shall be appointed by the Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security on behalf of the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9580FD0ABC4482F898B57546EEF3C93"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>An individual appointed as the Ombudsman must have expertise in—</text> <clause id="HCC91CD997D404D6DABA5B7395733511C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>labor and employment relations with Federal agencies; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3FDF953FE4F44FC582EDB304CCAA23D5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>dispute resolution.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E7CA687397E416AA4D1F46AF40A1670"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notification of Appointment and removal</header><text>The Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security shall notify the appropriate congressional committees within 30 days after the effective date of any of the following actions:</text>
 <clause id="H5B942480C7E54D30BC68BCB52CF6CBA8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The appointment of an individual as Ombudsman.</text> </clause><clause id="H18D6A0073D404F18856D3A6B9ED2A73D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The reappointment as Ombudsman of an individual who is serving as Ombudsman.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF573FAC6CFA34AB68701D773023C8B24"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The removal of an individual from the position of Ombudsman.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H908EB49C2DC0455194869D31DC10F801"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ensuring independence of Ombudsman</header> <subparagraph id="HD53C2CFA33104BDEB04A920066A8D696"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Ombudsman shall report—</text>
 <clause id="H33C699B0187343CC88FF765A204B2F69"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration; and</text> </clause><clause id="H93334AA89E4F4B57B24F9E551E78FB88"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to the Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security with respect to any dispute between the Ombudsman and the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration over matters involving the execution of the Ombudsman’s duties as set forth in subsection (b).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H168AD861F78741659B3C196146703C7C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inspector general’s authority to conduct investigations not affected</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall prohibit the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security from initiating, carrying out, or completing any investigation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4924CF7DB9E64E3E90F47537F2299AE5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Ombudsman shall—</text> <paragraph id="H5077D7CEE11D41A8B78D99CE9BF55E0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct outreach to Transportation Security Administration employees, including publicizing a toll-free telephone number to report complaints;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8398DC567A8416BACDCC01D815A28E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluate each complainant’s claim objectively;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H517D4A6E84664923915A11F38F034C10"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide information, advice, and assistance to complainants and, as appropriate, initiate informal, impartial fact-finding and inquiries, on complaints or on the Ombudsman’s own initiative;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE4FA2184BE5B4CABA9AEAED5B46AE08E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>inform each complainant—</text> <subparagraph id="HD71F9809AB1445D28FCD5A5B711BB18F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>when the Ombudsman decides against conducting a fact-finding inquiry into the complaint;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05DA1428EDB940908A3F6A3DC841E0FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on the status of the Ombudsman’s fact-finding inquiry to the complainant, on a regular basis if requested by the complainant; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H232991D4CFEA49CEA15716FD6F25F0D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>of the Ombudsman’s recommendations and information, as appropriate, for the complainant to formally complain to the appropriate authority;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H985B332ED6384B3585E599BC75403D14"><enum>(5)</enum><text>work with the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration to address issues identified through fact-finding and inquiries;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C123A3C04AF4E80AF19AD7CE042B593"><enum>(6)</enum><text>maintain confidential any matter related to complaints and inquiries, including the identities of the complainants and witnesses; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA83FD01B8F14C6CAD06C43E85FFAAE2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>submit an annual report to the appropriate congressional committees in accordance with subsection (c).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14D9F1AB463343CDAFC6A919E76F7156"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual report</header>
 <paragraph id="H640D3896357D4A349ECBB65CFA3B1C8B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Ombudsman shall report no later than September 30 each year to the appropriate congressional committees on the actions taken by the Office of the Ombudsman over the preceding year and the objectives of those actions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5AD17F29FD1A4AA6B63C664B96F62B36"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each such report shall, for the period covered by the report, include—</text> <subparagraph id="HC4595EA7F38447B58EFB3BD94C663B40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>statistical information, by region, on the volume of complaints received, general nature of complaints, general information on complainants, and the percentage of complaints that resulted in a fact-finding inquiry;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF77EAD5338C4584932A6621C062DD8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of problems encountered by complainants, including information on the most pervasive or serious types of problems encountered by complainants;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC882FD46BEB346A9B465DB064E8F92CD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>policy recommendations that the Office of the Ombudsman made to the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B3F0E26514D4D3284E2190BCD64CC65"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an inventory of the items described in subparagraphs (B) and (C) for which action has been taken, and the result of such action;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56A0EB0FB2E5429F8347CA0C55E3EF4B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an inventory of the items described in subparagraphs (B) and (C) for which action remains to be completed; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H587BBE1308E149128E29818F61343A80"><enum>(F)</enum><text>such other information as the Ombudsman considers relevant.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D6BB7F847084EFFB93E6311F4F52D24"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report to be submitted directly</header><text>Each report under this subsection shall be provided directly to the committees described in paragraph (1) without any prior comment or amendment by the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration. However, the Ombudsman shall seek comment from the Administrator to be submitted by the Ombudsman together with the annual report.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE451D79CE8F0429092566F0CB9473379"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Other reports</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to preclude the Ombudsman from issuing other reports on the activities of the Office of the Ombudsman.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8B68932FA639469B8AAA79F0D2185251"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Contact information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall make publically available on the Internet site of the Administration information about the Office of the Ombudsman, including regarding how to contact the Office.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4698AB7F1B384501AAE2969B70C78B26"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committee defined</header><text>In this section the term <quote>appropriate congressional committee</quote> means the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and any committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate having legislative jurisdiction under the rules of the House of Representatives or Senate, respectively, over the matter concerned.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF877FC04742248A8A5E5F7B50DC956BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis at the beginning of such chapter is amended by adding at the end of the items relating to subchapter II the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE19509004C0F4127AD7AF6A4AF8AD9C7" style="USC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H7FF35D666DE4412EB96F14F3208EBF02" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="HEFF0F8EBAA91492FB2F0CEDFB900734F" level="section">44947. Ombudsman.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFEA842D331E74846A37BB744C1F9D6C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated for each of fiscal years 2017, 2018, and 2019, $575,000 for implementing section 44946 of title 49, United States Code, as amended by this section.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


