<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD0562BE22E964EF79A47CC414FDAB01A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1711 IH: MAR-A-LAGO Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1711</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170323">March 23, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the disclosure of certain visitor access records.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H63DD3411FEBB4140A04F4550BAB397E5" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5450011C2B0A47C3B7806EA096A17D61" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Making Access Records Available to Lead American Government Openness Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>MAR-A-LAGO Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC9CD6257872C41F89235E36078CE67F7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H31EC8159C35B4EEF81A93E48D9F15CD9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Beginning in 2009, the Obama administration instituted a policy to release the visitor access records for the White House complex.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58722E2449DB4752A9B6E136FCE7DB8E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>This policy was responsible for making public the names of nearly 6,000,000 visitors to the White House in the 8 years of the Obama administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83CA50B2E75E4198A29ED19F6149F288"><enum>(3)</enum><text>This policy provided the people of the United States with insight into who influences the White House and transparency regarding efforts by lobbyists to effect policies, legislation, and Presidential actions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C69EB1882714A5BB255CD00D2D8E84D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To date, the Trump administration has not indicated whether it will continue the policy of publicly releasing White House visitor access records.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83C19982C9BE48CE95D6C75990BC1183"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Since taking office on January 20, 2017, President Trump has conducted official business not only in the White House, but also at several of his privately owned clubs and resorts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD06BDCD78544428489D75D47611AD924"><enum>(6)</enum><text>President Trump’s Mar-a-Lago Club in Palm Beach, Florida, has been dubbed the <quote>Winter White House</quote> and the <quote>Southern White House</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H947BC23B996447D79B712467A0EB4A12"><enum>(7)</enum><text>President Trump has spent 5 of his first 9 weekends in office at Mar-a-Lago.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H171BFC34DB0B4EDDB6B09C55708650A5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Mar-a-Lago is a private membership facility open to members, their guests, and others who have been invited as guests for special events.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1ECCE5806FDB462BA2FEF1A4B2EA329C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Visitors to Mar-a-Lago do not undergo the same background checks as White House visitors and visitor access records to the club have not been released to the public.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3AA4135F14974D90968F7B05688F2977"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The President has conducted official business and hosted international leaders at Mar-a-Lago.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F88AF71BC05472E869D6F59E31D9A49"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Media reports have shown President Trump and members of his Cabinet at Mar-a-Lago and nearby Trump International Golf Club interacting with members and guests, providing access unavailable to the general public.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF592AE090DD4D579E651E24ED402C3E"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">President Trump owns many other properties that offer similar amenities and membership-only access where he is likely to conduct official business during his term in office.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H384B5854DDE44D36A9E64898B75ABA87"><enum>(13)</enum><text>On March 11, 2017, President Trump hosted several members of his Cabinet at his Trump National Golf Club in Potomac Falls, Virginia, to discuss homeland security, health care, and the economy according to media reports.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAA3641E595B4D50B4FDDCCDC0F00D23"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Media reports have indicated that the President may use his Bedminster, New Jersey, resort as a <quote>Summer White House</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52B94A8B5FAF4B9FA17F7B72670ADF2C"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The people of the United States expect and deserve transparency in government. The policy to release visitor access records instituted by the previous administration appropriately balanced transparency with the need for confidentiality in government actions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45F06E32AFBA498EB702234C4F10B718"><enum>(16)</enum><text>To the extent Mar-a-Lago and any other private facilities become locations where the President conducts business and interacts with individuals who are not government officials, the same disclosures should apply.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H1561B869116D40D7B701DB36E346851A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improving access to influential visitor access records</header>
 <subsection id="H123AAEF69A854067BBC21E6B5785234A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H64255A60559943F6B4DBB56B3D5363A1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered location</header><text>The term <quote>covered location</quote> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDB9794AB7C38438184419FF069769A1E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the White House;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EA7DFCF2790412898EBCA6597AF57CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the residence of the Vice President; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2328A03A6864F93A3B12A78464AF083"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other location at which the President or the Vice President regularly conducts official business.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H12E6C70E601342459A0D29B10A95E7CA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered records</header><text>The term <quote>covered records</quote> means information relating to a visit at a covered location, which shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HA76B13EAC75A473A86ECB9ADA828C83F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name of each visitor at the covered location;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H681DA94B74A04255BC5AF76F8463178C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the name of each individual with whom each visitor described in subparagraph (A) met at the covered location; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96878D6E0F97409B89BAE59BEB35B295"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the purpose of the visit.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5686394D1B8D4E9CBF84E01993357BE2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (c), not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the President shall establish and update, every 90 days, a publicly available database that contains covered records for the preceding 30-day period.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H6687EC9D00074D6BBA576B001FD0C822"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
 <paragraph id="H059F78B942B142B88BC8924CFB4865E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall not include in the database established under subsection (b) any covered record—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2ACF0F98AEE04CCFB0ACADF0EB93D0BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the posting of which would implicate personal privacy or law enforcement concerns or threaten national security; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H219E71A1C5DF44A89BA19AF6C12161B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>relating to a purely personal guest at a covered location.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4088FFE494264D02B9DEF02498D0C6D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sensitive meetings</header><text>With respect to a particularly sensitive meeting at a covered location, the President shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H292AF110ABEE4556A74085754ED8E6AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include the number of visitors at the covered location in the database established under subsection (b); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15962092BC4D4B0C8DEC35B176BB3350"><enum>(B)</enum><text>post the applicable covered records in the database established under subsection (b) when the President determines that release of the covered records is no longer sensitive.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


