<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0A74A6AA914B44A4892059F628D2FCCD" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2131 IH: DHS FIRM Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2131</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170425">April 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Chief Human Capital Officer of the
			 Department of Homeland Security to improve consistency regarding
			 discipline and adverse actions in the Department’s workforce, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HDBD3439784D7492D9BE1A1BAD2B22346" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4CF3724C4F9242C49D8C8DA7A3BCF9A3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fixing Internal Response to Misconduct Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>DHS FIRM Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7F2E7C3FF65F4249B3B572120FC61743"><enum>2.</enum><header>DHS policy on discipline and adverse actions</header> <subsection id="HEB3C40909DB240BC9C2B59505706B4F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 704 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/344">6 U.S.C. 344</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H39533963491B4C1094D708A550FA69AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="HC57392242B9F4454980DC35A49503C24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38D95875002B4875B7D3E05AEDE7C4B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40F0792C37134888966AD69A3E47BAB9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8B16EE22E6234AB1A4C0B33F8B0560DC" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HC8E5AF38CB714C1BB7CD25EF51DF8EB3"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implement a Department-wide policy related to discipline and adverse actions described in subsection (e).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H77CD3A57ACD34A2F9C13D8A019257D17"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (f); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7AD12CF91D164EE493B65C26DF9703E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB7E1732642345329E7223922922482B" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="HFC5368AE7E9845918B34F5F0989FE828"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Policy on discipline and adverse actions</header>
 <paragraph id="H6B81C613897341EBA85CF4528CB88BE0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Chief Human Capital Officer, in accordance with any established Department-wide policy that deals with discipline and adverse actions, shall provide—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBD772DC254244165AE1B534EA0F678AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">guidance to the senior human resources official overseeing discipline and adverse actions for headquarters personnel and non-component entities, as identified by the Chief Human Capital Officer, and relevant component heads regarding informing the public about how to report employee misconduct;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC5F5B91757D47AFB7EC8ED28CF19ED4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>guidance on how Department employees should report employee misconduct; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA40DD89D3F94B1E901B728D739D7A23"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">guidance on the type, quantity, and frequency of data regarding discipline and adverse actions to be submitted to the Chief Human Capital Officer by the senior human resources official overseeing discipline and adverse actions for headquarters personnel and non-component entities, as identified by the Chief Human Capital Officer and component heads for the purposes of paragraph (3)(C).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H01A88F04CF144EFB86B455FCE3663529"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of offenses and penalties</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA89A412EBDCF41EDB803BC9545A3B519"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Pre-existing tables</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a table of offenses and penalties exists for a component of the Department as of the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Chief Human Capital Officer shall review and, if appropriate, approve such table and any changes to such table made after such date of enactment. In cases in which such tables do not comply with Department policy, the Chief Human Capital Officer shall instruct component heads on corrective measures to be taken in order to achieve such compliance.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC31F606143B94D2DB9BD923CC6F1917B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>New component tables</header><text>If a table of offenses and penalties does not exist for a component of the Department as of the date of enactment of this subsection, a component head may, in coordination with the Chief Human Capital Officer, develop a table of offenses and penalties to be used by such component. The Chief Human Capital Officer shall review and, if appropriate, approve such table and any changes to such table made after such date of enactment. In cases in which such tables or changes do not comply with Department policy, the Chief Human Capital Officer shall instruct the component head on corrective measures to be taken in order to achieve such compliance.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC63EF6176FF4AF5A0A1D3A0AFBFF59C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Component responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Component heads shall comply with Department-wide policy (including guidance relating to such) regarding discipline and adverse actions for the Department’s workforce, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H64A6527743094F658300444CA2C28149"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing any current table of offenses and penalties or future changes to a component’s table to the Chief Human Capital Officer for review in accordance with paragraph (2)(A);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8EC47D458BAE4783BFEA027D59631F6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing any new table of offenses and penalties or future changes to a component’s table to the Chief Human Capital Officer for review in accordance with paragraph (2)(B); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D8557CDD3D942F084EAC16572F3F663"><enum>(C)</enum><text>providing to the Chief Human Capital Officer any data regarding discipline and adverse actions in accordance with paragraph (1)(C).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF79BEAB446B430BBE1BE25582A347DD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Oversight</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0BEF6671812C4841B2F0B882AB2EE866"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Chief Human Capital Officer shall implement a process to oversee component compliance with any established Department-wide policy regarding discipline and adverse actions referred to in paragraph (1), including—</text>
 <clause id="H43FA9417E30D480AB73BF2BCD7475E2A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the degree to which components are complying with such policy; and</text> </clause><clause id="H99E4DF31EAAD45499986C68D11484B3D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at a minimum, each fiscal year, a review of component adjudication of misconduct data to—</text>
 <subclause id="HC97FAA4D6A044092A56517497C95E6DF"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure consistent adherence to such policy and any Department-wide table of offenses and penalties or any component-specific table of offenses and penalties approved by the Chief Human Capital Officer pursuant to paragraph (2); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H15A410435DFA4E03904F7D9628939092"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether employee training regarding such misconduct policy or adjustment in such misconduct policy is necessary.</text>
										</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE2B7E7D5B824EA082B7DD8320103A9F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Working groups</header>
 <clause id="HE2E94DEEF3FB47A59775A2DB67BC04C8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief Human Capital Officer may establish working groups, as necessary, to improve employee relations within the Department. If the Chief Human Capital Officer establishes such a working group, the Chief Human Capital Officer shall specify a timeframe for the completion of such group’s work.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3CA085181CC44A7DAC9826E88877483B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Function</header><text>A working group established pursuant to clause (i) shall identify the causes in persistent misconduct referred to in such subparagraph, review component processes for addressing misconduct, and develop alternate strategies to address such misconduct.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2FBF1D32F5934B6D980818B03D4F226D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Participation</header><text>If a working group is established pursuant to clause (i), the relevant component head shall participate in such working group and implement any recommendations issued by such working group.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H437877F95982476384A7C1C81EDB9D09"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Follow-up reviews</header><text>The Chief Human Capital Officer shall conduct annual, or on a more frequent basis as determined by the Chief Human Capital Officer, follow-up reviews of components with respect to which misconduct has been identified under this paragraph. In consultation with the Chief Human Capital Officer, the Secretary may request the Inspector General of the Department to investigate any concerns identified through the oversight process under this subsection that components have not addressed.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2F908CED014D4016A172A94CE636D086"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Inspector General functions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General of the Department may, as the Inspector General determines appropriate, issue management alerts regarding misconduct to the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2B4387FB66546E09F6A575299338835"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Misconduct defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>misconduct</quote> means the failure of a Department employee to comply with a performance plan, rule, regulation, or law within the scope of such employee’s duties, responsibilities, or functions.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC14AEF756D64462381ECE8A52284A630"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the development of the oversight process required under subsection (e) of section 704 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/344">6 U.S.C. 344</external-xref>) (as added by subsection (a) of this section), the Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security shall provide to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate information on such oversight process, including component compliance with any policy regarding discipline and adverse actions, data collection efforts, and information on the development of any working groups under such subsection (e).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA687FBB9944B4347A02E95AEAFB3DD2E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on new funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds are authorized to carry out this section and the amendments made by this section. This section and such amendments shall be carried out using amounts otherwise made available.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


