<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD27C9ACDC6CA4CD2B79AAE4A4FB3E4EE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1882 IH: Stop AIDS in Prison Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1882</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170404">April 4, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Guti&#233;rrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for an effective HIV/AIDS program in Federal prisons.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFAD328CDF6054FF4B686D2D337FA9232" style="OLC"> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H31F445AA5DD14B7EB22D7DDA7785CAB2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop AIDS in Prison Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0A32376F34C640ECB4EB83CA45C87750"><enum>2.</enum><header>Comprehensive HIV/AIDS Policy</header> <subsection id="H70802EA608404CECAC80ED09D8EE8096"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau of Prisons (hereinafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Bureau</quote>) shall develop a comprehensive policy to provide HIV testing, treatment, and prevention for inmates within the correctional setting and upon reentry.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H0174A10549BF499599AF036134069BDC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of this policy shall be as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H4A2F741B14054713954E2E52FBEF0041"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To stop the spread of HIV/AIDS among inmates.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H89A5199C71414ED7ACE6F2AAE952434E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To protect prison guards and other personnel from HIV/AIDS infection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HABE2931ADF3148319AD34368AFB33E99"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To provide comprehensive medical treatment to inmates who are living with HIV/AIDS.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD34348CE2776401794F152AB6917C111"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To promote HIV/AIDS awareness and prevention among inmates.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H801678DC85794ED69B44ABCB7326BDC2"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To encourage inmates to take personal responsibility for their health.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H04D25DDBBC1F452296D2E9F8FFF8BC18"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To reduce the risk that inmates will transmit HIV/AIDS to other persons in the community following their release from prison.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFB425885B89B4A0D8D805DFD094592EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau shall consult with appropriate officials of the Department of Health and Human Services, the Office of National Drug Control Policy, the Office of National AIDS Policy, and the Centers for Disease Control regarding the development of this policy.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE2FBCC2B502645F0899374DAB8AEBB51"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Time limit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau shall draft appropriate regulations to implement this policy not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H1841BA2915FD4F649701E841764CCDF0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requirements for policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The policy created under section 2 shall do the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HC91EFCB53CA645CC9FEFBE24331B34A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Testing and counseling upon intake</header>
<subparagraph id="HE150A00DA0114B5B85AE02D7D0BC2BF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Health care personnel shall provide routine HIV testing to all inmates as a part of a comprehensive medical examination immediately following admission to a facility. (Health care personnel need not provide routine HIV testing to an inmate who is transferred to a facility from another facility if the inmate’s medical records are transferred with the inmate and indicate that the inmate has been tested previously.)</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0F58214AF36E4A84A4783B7B0912CB17"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To all inmates admitted to a facility prior to the effective date of this policy, health care personnel shall provide routine HIV testing within no more than 6 months. HIV testing for these inmates may be performed in conjunction with other health services provided to these inmates by health care personnel.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H70A6FE544CB64FA2966708B0546A90B5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>All HIV tests under this paragraph shall comply with the opt-out provision.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA52F57824D3B4A349E3D53483311B8EF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pre-Test and Post-Test Counseling</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Health care personnel shall provide confidential pre-test and post-test counseling to all inmates who are tested for HIV. Counseling may be included with other general health counseling provided to inmates by health care personnel.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H189DD2BD10A24CE4B0AE09172818B940"><enum>(3)</enum><header>HIV/AIDS Prevention Education</header>
<subparagraph id="HACF4C4F7DFD34E9AA71AB0D6B2EA5882"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Health care personnel shall improve HIV/AIDS awareness through frequent educational programs for all inmates. HIV/AIDS educational programs may be provided by community based organizations, local health departments, and inmate peer educators.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB5664557B52846ADA3706B5691EF0FB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">HIV/AIDS educational materials shall be made available to all inmates at orientation, at health care clinics, at regular educational programs, and prior to release. Both written and audio-visual materials shall be made available to all inmates.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDFCD78EBFF76423B99B165630DED78AE"><enum>(C)</enum>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCBD5350946A54FDF803815C53E012C72"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The HIV/AIDS educational programs and materials under this paragraph shall include information on—</text> <subclause id="HA8A7806B5E7E42F594E68F03A5E653C2" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>modes of transmission, including transmission through tattooing, sexual contact, and intravenous drug use;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H472091E60F694904BC0F52C1FC37734F" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>prevention methods;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H7073A9D446424D53850824F97E9A4F17" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>treatment; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H25B933B892164645A141CC43ED8F1E42" indent="up1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>disease progression.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H348E9440C6844D1E86A24BD26711BAC3" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The programs and materials shall be culturally sensitive, written or designed for low literacy levels, available in a variety of languages, and present scientifically accurate information in a clear and understandable manner.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4272A7718B824E99B6E44E1DB9DE7A4E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>HIV Testing upon request</header>
<subparagraph id="H773C3096E554466C99CE1E20E0D2DA83"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Health care personnel shall allow inmates to obtain HIV tests upon request once per year or whenever an inmate has a reason to believe the inmate may have been exposed to HIV. Health care personnel shall, both orally and in writing, inform inmates, during orientation and periodically throughout incarceration, of their right to obtain HIV tests.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9BD742DABBC74060A1B768D491443144"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Health care personnel shall encourage inmates to request HIV tests if the inmate is sexually active, has been raped, uses intravenous drugs, receives a tattoo, or if the inmate is concerned that the inmate may have been exposed to HIV/AIDS.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9BC53C1EFC4141C5A8FF072EF75A8FB0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An inmate’s request for an HIV test shall not be considered an indication that the inmate has put him/herself at risk of infection and/or committed a violation of prison rules.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84B0A3DF4B164265BB258C340E1608FC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>HIV Testing of Pregnant Women</header> <subparagraph id="H784243D8CA0D432381E0B48D18D28281"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Health care personnel shall provide routine HIV testing to all inmates who become pregnant.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE848167480E44F59B7B0FC5F52DB7F0D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>All HIV tests under this paragraph shall comply with the opt-out provision.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H46C2FAB9BE6D47B2B069C68760185C85"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Comprehensive treatment</header> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1CD6BA63D4334ADAA30FC07E2C646FF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Health care personnel shall provide all inmates who test positive for HIV—</text>
<clause id="HF0666DDBF0AF4C6F8D16EBE496B52930"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">timely, comprehensive medical treatment;</text></clause> <clause id="HDD91983950114D829447D93D41C5E3A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">confidential counseling on managing their medical condition and preventing its transmission to other persons; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H25B60CCED3484E71A2F44B96FA7F2AC0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>voluntary partner notification services.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6682475FCA8B4AE485452ADC85C6C47F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Health care provided under this paragraph shall be consistent with current Department of Health and Human Services guidelines and standard medical practice. Health care personnel shall discuss treatment options, the importance of adherence to antiretroviral therapy, and the side effects of medications with inmates receiving treatment.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H028C151DED4643CBAE983CB232D78D0B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Health care personnel and pharmacy personnel shall ensure that the facility formulary contains all Food and Drug Administration-approved medications necessary to provide comprehensive treatment for inmates living with HIV/AIDS, and that the facility maintains adequate supplies of such medications to meet inmates’ medical needs. Health care personnel and pharmacy personnel shall also develop and implement automatic renewal systems for these medications to prevent interruptions in care.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5F265C3D83124E8D823960BE16746DA2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Correctional staff, health care personnel, and pharmacy personnel shall develop and implement distribution procedures to ensure timely and confidential access to medications.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF90E63485F464D0BA71C168B4FA46ABA"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Protection of Confidentiality</header>
<subparagraph id="HF321F71474F34FF4BA07D3A53371FBDA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Health care personnel shall develop and implement procedures to ensure the confidentiality of inmate tests, diagnoses, and treatment. Health care personnel and correctional staff shall receive regular training on the implementation of these procedures. Penalties for violations of inmate confidentiality by health care personnel or correctional staff shall be specified and strictly enforced.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H027E0AC3971845DC998EBEAF8A1728DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>HIV testing, counseling, and treatment shall be provided in a confidential setting where other routine health services are provided and in a manner that allows the inmate to request and obtain these services as routine medical services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC341421CCCB3405698D6AC6F525BE828"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Testing, counseling, and referral prior to reentry</header>
<subparagraph id="HC19ED42A9BED4A039437659214CAA645"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Health care personnel shall provide routine HIV testing to all inmates no more than 3 months prior to their release and reentry into the community. (Inmates who are already known to be infected need not be tested again.) This requirement may be waived if an inmate’s release occurs without sufficient notice to the Bureau to allow health care personnel to perform a routine HIV test and notify the inmate of the results.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9C32737F9C3B45F998507FFC130C8417"><enum>(B)</enum><text>All HIV tests under this paragraph shall comply with the opt-out provision.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H76A7E29EF7B54C80995593648FCCD72E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To all inmates who test positive for HIV and all inmates who already are known to have HIV/AIDS, health care personnel shall provide—</text> <clause id="HD54237B7C0874A55A3ECF2AA17A8A94E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">confidential prerelease counseling on managing their medical condition in the community, accessing appropriate treatment and services in the community, and preventing the transmission of their condition to family members and other persons in the community;</text></clause>
<clause id="H9BB8E5EEF6D445F98A58E5F610290DAE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">referrals to appropriate health care providers and social service agencies in the community that meet the inmate’s individual needs, including voluntary partner notification services and prevention counseling services for people living with HIV/AIDS; and</text></clause> <clause id="H69797B8F9DC9406C805E278855DE5CE6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a 30-day supply of any medically necessary medications the inmate is currently receiving.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0AAF0197EAEB416B8F77C567ADA2BC2A"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Opt-Out Provision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Inmates shall have the right to refuse routine HIV testing. Inmates shall be informed both orally and in writing of this right. Oral and written disclosure of this right may be included with other general health information and counseling provided to inmates by health care personnel. If an inmate refuses a routine test for HIV, health care personnel shall make a note of the inmate’s refusal in the inmate’s confidential medical records. However, the inmate’s refusal shall not be considered a violation of prison rules or result in disciplinary action. Any reference in this section to the <quote>opt-out provision</quote> shall be deemed a reference to the requirement of this paragraph.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87B6CC5F5FC84F5CAD76D1234BF2D3CF"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Exclusion of Tests Performed Under Section <enum-in-header>4014(b)</enum-in-header> from the Definition of Routine HIV Testing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">HIV testing of an inmate under section 4014(b) of title 18, United States Code, is not routine HIV testing for the purposes of the opt-out provision. Health care personnel shall document the reason for testing under section 4014(b) of title 18, United States Code, in the inmate’s confidential medical records.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H271B723EAD5E4EFBB975204B020EF149"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Timely notification of test results</header><text>Health care personnel shall provide timely notification to inmates of the results of HIV tests.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HC73E4D860CF640B4AE078F2FAE22BDF3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Changes in existing law</header> <subsection id="H2DBFE4D23BF143C19D1768BE757D87EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Screening in general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4014(a) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H4D79050A6D854D13A97F83C9029B69DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>for a period of 6 months or more</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5FF81DC2414406F8DB09D1CCB8B115D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, as appropriate,</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDCEC66BF7E1E4303853CB2EF63904243"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>if such individual is determined to be at risk for infection with such virus in accordance with the guidelines issued by the Bureau of Prisons relating to infectious disease management</quote> and inserting <quote>unless the individual declines. The Attorney General shall also cause such individual to be so tested before release unless the individual declines.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3B3A733A20D34EFC880E90935523EE84"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inadmissibility of HIV Test Results in civil and criminal proceedings</header><text>Section 4014(d) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>or under the <short-title>Stop AIDS in Prison Act of 2017</short-title></quote> after <quote>under this section</quote>.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HC87E6E327FF04CAA83123115DBE542C7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Screening as part of routine screening</header><text>Section 4014(e) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>Such rules shall also provide that the initial test under this section be performed as part of the routine health screening conducted at intake.</quote>.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H1DF3E23318A14116830D6FC1E1D0944B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header> <subsection id="H0FAAE8375ABB4FEEA4D6ABD52793FC64"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report on hepatitis and other diseases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Bureau shall provide a report to the Congress on Bureau policies and procedures to provide testing, treatment, and prevention education programs for hepatitis and other diseases transmitted through sexual activity and intravenous drug use. The Bureau shall consult with appropriate officials of the Department of Health and Human Services, the Office of National Drug Control Policy, the Office of National AIDS Policy, and the Centers for Disease Control regarding the development of this report.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HC1B76844EC114F268E5A9055CD64E816"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual reports</header>
<paragraph id="H4D0DEF5521214B0682ECBD7EC11E42C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Generally</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and then annually thereafter, the Bureau shall report to Congress on the incidence among inmates of diseases transmitted through sexual activity and intravenous drug use.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H47044F26487E4D858E318D912A6C94A0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters pertaining to various diseases</header><text>Reports under paragraph (1) shall discuss—</text>
<subparagraph id="H2844160ABB85438C9A0F9C892FB0286E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the incidence among inmates of HIV/AIDS, hepatitis, and other diseases transmitted through sexual activity and intravenous drug use; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD88634AF410A46C38A21B81836F7F66A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>updates on Bureau testing, treatment, and prevention education programs for these diseases.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H681E0BA3D5D9440097546363FC15BBBC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Matters pertaining to HIV/AIDS only</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reports under paragraph (1) shall also include—</text> <subparagraph id="HA68A3F2081624DF9BE970471A3995688"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of inmates who tested positive for HIV upon intake;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H60ACF0C7A37F490AA2C0A7CA8B29A3F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of inmates who tested positive prior to reentry;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0699A25E267446B1A7E70C53CF1347E5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of inmates who were not tested prior to reentry because they were released without sufficient notice;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE16FDFC05E5044939AD89774D1CC0DF4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of inmates who opted-out of taking the test;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0BE05F48E8094944A9F770980E7243C0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the number of inmates who were tested under section 4014(b) of title 18, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3A735ED532C940F3A0B7D63AEBC166DF"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the number of inmates under treatment for HIV/AIDS.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF60617DD8AE740989B22A96DFC726F2D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau shall consult with appropriate officials of the Department of Health and Human Services, the Office of National Drug Control Policy, the Office of National AIDS Policy, and the Centers for Disease Control regarding the development of reports under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

