<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1B43F701DBB5490F8205B560557798E5" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2215 IH: Secure And Fair Enforcement Banking Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2215</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170427">April 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001077">Mr. Coffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000390">Mr. Kihuen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000587">Mr. Lewis of Minnesota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000409">Mr. Rohrabacher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To create protections for depository institutions that provide financial services to
			 cannabis-related legitimate businesses, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA04F565BC6FF44DAA30E3E4E43F56CD2" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7CEABFBCE44D43AA926A5AA343E1911E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Secure And Fair Enforcement Banking Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFE Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4E087A12095F483CBBFEA07D7718976F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Safe harbor for depository institutions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A Federal banking regulator may not—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD9361F3D9A0640DB900AF688B19C72C7" indent="down1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">terminate or limit the deposit insurance or share insurance of a depository institution under the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1811">12 U.S.C. 1811</external-xref> et seq.) or the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1751">12 U.S.C. 1751</external-xref> et seq.) solely because the depository institution provides or has provided financial services to a cannabis-related legitimate business;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAABF86CD56345D2A8D38BF02D8C2434" indent="down1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibit, penalize, or otherwise discourage a depository institution from providing financial services to a cannabis-related legitimate business or to a State or political subdivision of a State that exercises jurisdiction over cannabis-related legitimate businesses;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF68352D61E054E17B8926062C338B4E0" indent="down1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommend, incentivize, or encourage a depository institution not to offer financial services to an account holder, or to downgrade or cancel the financial services offered to an account holder solely because—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDA702E7975194E38BA6CD817FB4D13BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the account holder is a manufacturer or producer, or is the owner, operator, or employee of a cannabis-related legitimate business;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC41FA48232740A48B8B1D9E20A6BEBE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the account holder later becomes an owner or operator of a cannabis-related legitimate business; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0CC165731FF4E0C95ED11A603ACB811"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the depository institution was not aware that the account holder is the owner or operator of a cannabis-related legitimate business; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8220681B56DE4CC18517B97F46F0D2AB" indent="down1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">take any adverse or corrective supervisory action on a loan made to an owner or operator of—</text> <subparagraph id="HDB8654B6D4354391B92975EAB7E52794"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a cannabis-related legitimate business, solely because the owner or operator owns or operates a cannabis-related legitimate business; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF12714B07D1943DF8F0C8E8CF0310290"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">real estate or equipment that is leased to a cannabis-related legitimate business, solely because the owner or operator of the real estate or equipment leased the equipment or real estate to a cannabis-related legitimate business.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H3C4FE16C783F406CA55A22F5BDA607E3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Protections under Federal law</header>
 <subsection id="HC09D719C6CBD4D4E8BCAB5FA2B30B701"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a State or a political subdivision of a State that allows the cultivation, production, manufacture, sale, transportation, display, dispensing, distribution, or purchase of cannabis pursuant to a law or regulation of such State or political subdivision a depository institution that provides financial services to a cannabis-related legitimate business, and the officers, directors, and employees of that depository institution may not be held liable pursuant to any Federal law or regulation—</text>
 <paragraph id="H535F9ABDDDE040299774734426A7C6A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solely for providing such financial services pursuant to the law or regulation of such State or political subdivision; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3F19DC41CFE447F28D24EE103E0DDF62"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for further investing any income derived from such financial services.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD9C2027346C2429CB70B603E8BC38893"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Forfeiture</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A depository institution that has a legal interest in the collateral for a loan or another financial service provided to an owner or operator of a cannabis-related legitimate business, or to an owner or operator of real estate or equipment that is leased or sold to a cannabis-related legitimate business, shall not be subject to criminal, civil, or administrative forfeiture of that legal interest pursuant to any Federal law for providing such loan or other financial service.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H7B7B666D2D5648C5B5178B19AD76944F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall require a depository institution to provide financial services to a cannabis-related legitimate business.</text>
 </section><section commented="no" id="HED724C69594F4588B016763B00758FF8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Requirements for filing suspicious activity reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5318(g) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H1F5A7F351DA547D1BF6D03102460A201" style="OLC"> <paragraph commented="no" id="HDE9E47D6CF914901908CE9C59EA5B24A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Requirements for cannabis-related businesses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A financial institution or any director, officer, employee, or agent of a financial institution that reports a suspicious transaction pursuant to this subsection and the reason for the report relates to a cannabis-related legitimate business (as defined in section 6 of the Secure and Fair Enforcement Banking Act of 2017), the report shall comply with appropriate guidance issued by the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network. The Secretary shall ensure that the guidance is consistent with the purpose and intent of the Secure and Fair Enforcement Banking Act of 2017 and does not inhibit the provision of financial services to a cannabis-related legitimate business in a State or political subdivision of a State that has allowed the cultivation, production, manufacture, transportation, display, dispensing, distribution, sale, or purchase of cannabis pursuant to law or regulation of such State or political subdivision.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H64FEB2842910468E823322F12CAA6356"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H58F0E4DD035942D8AD0B47D9A494912F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Depository institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>depository institution</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE4A7734782FE45E582EA964FF9B7949B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a depository institution as defined in section 3(c) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813(c)</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD52ACF8667124EDBB95E68B82BA1237E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a Federal credit union as defined in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FAD59EBF3594A6B8A51527758AFDFE5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State credit union as defined in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D74CEC20EE3445F853C159A7E17F744"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal banking regulator</header><text>The term <term>Federal banking regulator</term> means each of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the National Credit Union Administration, or any Federal agency or department that regulates banking or financial services, as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC48125E2880E4AE49C8D6377A6DAF3E1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Financial service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>financial service</term> means a financial product or service as defined in section 1002 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5481">12 U.S.C. 5481</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9CE82737976B4FD2B98C308813C31995"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Manufacturer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>manufacturer</term> means a person who manufactures, compounds, converts, processes, prepares, or packages cannabis or cannabis products.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D242935D62A4E10B0AE523F9B826273"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Cannabis-related legitimate business</header><text>The term <term>cannabis-related legitimate business</term> means a manufacturer, producer, or any person that—</text> <subparagraph id="H2CCAED90506F416B83C4416A2358496F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engages in an activity described in subparagraph (B) pursuant to a law or regulation of a State, political subdivision of a State, or a Tribal-State compact; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1042D80BA8794F0086E4C5A0D035283C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">participates in any business or organized activity that involves handling cannabis or cannabis products, including cultivating, producing, manufacturing, selling, transporting, displaying, dispensing, distributing, or purchasing cannabis or cannabis products.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E27C1A0C20042DB9791AA28629CA90C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Cannabis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cannabis</term> has the meaning given the term <term>marihuana</term> in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD6D723B8975D4F93A1858EB2F85EB567"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Cannabis product</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cannabis product</term> means any article which contains cannabis, including an article which is a concentrate, an edible, a tincture, a cannabis-infused product, or a topical.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB55578A2A6E64E88AB7686826ADB6690"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Producer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>producer</term> means a person who plants, cultivates, harvests, or in any way facilitates the natural growth of cannabis.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5936A67C98354E2D9A7B938E4E76AECE"><enum>(9)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession of the United States.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


