<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8751D0D31F4F41068A261234A16FF735" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3163 IH: Medicare Part B Home Infusion Services Temporary Transitional Payment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3163</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170706">July 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000462">Mr. Tiberi</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for a home infusion therapy services temporary transitional payment under the Medicare program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCEC5D008360B4B01958E882B71C0F028" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H89295F254DA04A9CA8B37CDE77B05A2E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicare Part B Home Infusion Services Temporary Transitional Payment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE0D3647E348C49E48253F7D45DEBE147"><enum>2.</enum><header>Home infusion therapy services temporary transitional payment</header> <subsection id="H8BFA494645084DD1AA5A0932A0B508ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1834(u) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(u)</external-xref>) is amended, by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H5772C8EC5D414D6ABB25A0C02548B852" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H1DDB0E48841543189C038A30337A4F4C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Home infusion therapy services temporary transitional payment</header> 
<subparagraph id="H36003FF4982E4DD2B12033E03A43AB80"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Temporary transitional payment</header> 
<clause id="HB9A4C7D2771B47B78A51C966F7C36A23"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, in accordance with the payment methodology described in subparagraph (B) and subject to the provisions of this paragraph, provide a home infusion therapy services temporary transitional payment under this part to an eligible home infusion supplier (as defined in subparagraph (F)) for items and services described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 1861(iii)(2)) furnished during the period specified in clause (ii) by such supplier in coordination with the furnishing of transitional home infusion drugs (as defined in clause (iii)).</text></clause> <clause id="HA3B13F3717D94BFF927429762B780ED6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Period specified</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), the period specified in this clause is the period beginning on January 1, 2019, and ending on the day before the date of the implementation of the payment system under paragraph (1)(A).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9BC4D0B57A314F71921CE7BE266F95E7" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Transitional home infusion drug defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>transitional home infusion drug</term> has the meaning given to the term <term>home infusion drug</term> under section 1861(iii)(3)(C)), except that clause (ii) of such section shall not apply if a drug described in such clause is identified in clauses (i), (ii), (iii) or (iv) of subparagraph (C) as of the date of the enactment of this paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H087ED4B3470F4DE5A695FAE6281859EC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Payment methodology</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the Secretary shall establish a payment methodology, with respect to items and services described in subparagraph (A)(i). Under such payment methodology the Secretary shall—</text> 
<clause id="H878B06CE099242318E061CBEBBE4F481"><enum>(i)</enum><text> create the three payment categories described in clauses (i), (ii), and (iii) of subparagraph (C);</text></clause> <clause id="HA6D1E8479CCC4640B19A175F64986FC5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assign drugs to such categories, in accordance with such clauses;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEE35CD1C97FC48B38926F7DAC7CFEA1D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assign appropriate Healthcare Common Procedure Coding System (HCPCS) codes to each payment category; and</text></clause> <clause id="HBBA8D3E499D6490DA8A68C3DEDC52D21"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a single payment amount for each such payment category, in accordance with subparagraph (D), for each infusion drug administration calendar day in the individual’s home for drugs assigned to such category.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H624A03234DAD4A91B802600419F7DB63"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Payment categories</header> 
<clause id="HFF1ECC6CDE394D0D93FB513F28C36A73"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Payment category 1</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall create a payment category 1 and assign to such category drugs which are covered under the Local Coverage Determination on External Infusion Pumps (LCD number L33794) and billed with the following HCPCS codes (as identified as of July 1, 2017, and as subsequently modified by the Secretary): J0133, J0285, J0287, J0288, J0289, J0895, J1170, J1250, J1265, J1325, J1455, J1457, J1570, J2175, J2260, J2270, J2274, J2278, J3010, or J3285.</text></clause> <clause id="H118EAD592964410F9552B178A7D620CD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Payment category 2</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall create a payment category 2 and assign to such category drugs which are covered under such local coverage determination and billed with the following HCPCS codes (as identified as of July 1, 2017, and as subsequently modified by the Secretary): J1559 JB, J1561 JB, J1562 JB, J1569 JB, or J1575 JB.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF927DB1E4BB8482590943A35B8B61D55"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Payment category 3</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall create a payment category 3 and assign to such category drugs which are covered under such local coverage determination and billed with the following HCPCS codes (as identified as of July 1, 2017, and as subsequently modified by the Secretary): J9000, J9039, J9040, J9065, J9100, J9190, J9200, J9360, or J9370.</text></clause> <clause id="H1289A9FFD8DE445091465DD7906E0458"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Infusion drugs not otherwise included</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to drugs that are not included in payment category 1, 2, or 3 under clause (i), (ii), or (iii), respectively, the Secretary shall assign to the most appropriate of such categories, as determined by the Secretary, drugs which are—</text> 
<subclause id="HE0CC0F5394F8439388B5237A307AC16F"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">covered under such local coverage determination and billed under HCPCS codes J7799 or J7999 (as identified as of July 1, 2017, and as subsequently modified by the Secretary); or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0A8F6AB531164B37A65B3C938022B3DD"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">billed under any code that is implemented after the date of the enactment of this paragraph and included in such local coverage determination or included in subregulatory guidance as a home infusion drug described in subparagraph (A)(i). </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA83C90737F5B44D0A9094C56BD8E811E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Payment amounts</header> 
<clause id="HB64FC6B34064411C8C70458BDB022BD7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the payment methodology, the Secretary shall pay eligible home infusion suppliers, with respect to items and services described in subparagraph (A)(i) furnished during the period described in subparagraph (A)(ii) by such supplier to an individual, at amounts equal to the amounts determined under the physician fee schedule established under section 1848 for services furnished during the year for codes and units of such codes described in clauses (ii), (iii), and (iv) with respect to drugs included in the payment category under subparagraph (C) specified in the respective clause, determined without application of any adjustment under such section.</text></clause> <clause id="H82637CF5F7064E2084A2388345903A45"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Payment amount for category 1</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), the codes and units described in this clause, with respect to drugs included in payment category 1 described in subparagraph (C)(i), are one unit of HCPCS code 96365 plus four units of HCPCS code 96366 (as identified as of July 1, 2017, and as subsequently modified by the Secretary).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H637DB5509EDF466BAB9AB1AA0331CF1D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Payment amount for category 2</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), the codes and units described in this clause, with respect to drugs included in payment category 2 described in subparagraph (C)(i), are one unit of HCPCS code 96369 plus four units of HCPCS code 96370 (as identified as of July 1, 2017, and as subsequently modified by the Secretary).</text></clause> <clause id="HC0A88EEE88AF4D0495090688CAFA5BD8"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Payment amount for category 3</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), the codes and units described in this clause, with respect to drugs included in payment category 3 described in subparagraph (C)(i), are one unit of HCPCS code 96413 plus four units of HCPCS code 96415 (as identified as of July 1, 2017, and as subsequently modified by the Secretary).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H506D9A8E45AE47F1A2BBAC73BA29A8FF"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Clarifications</header> 
<clause id="H17A310D5959B45F69AE7952F3CECAD3F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Infusion drug administration day</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, a reference, with respect to the furnishing of transitional home infusion drugs or home infusion drugs to an individual by an eligible home infusion supplier, to payment to such supplier for an infusion drug administration calendar day in the individual’s home shall refer to payment only for the date on which such drugs are administered to such individual. For purposes of the previous sentence, an infusion drug administration calendar day shall include all such drugs administered to such individual on such day.</text></clause> <clause id="H0558B9DA7C1A41ADB4B7F6625DD38957" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Treatment of multiple drugs administered on same infusion drug administration day</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that an eligible home infusion supplier, with respect to an infusion drug administration calendar day in an individual’s home, furnishes to such individual transitional home infusion drugs which are not all assigned to the same payment category under subparagraph (C), payment to such supplier for such infusion drug administration calendar day in the individual’s home shall be a single payment equal to the amount of payment under this paragraph for the drug, among all such drugs so furnished to such individual during such calendar day, for which the highest payment would be made under this paragraph.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H85D1C69764954CEFB8E545F3F1B929C9" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>No payment for self-administered drugs</header><text>No payment shall be made under this paragraph for a transitional home infusion drug if such drug is self-administered.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4BB29A8FE24441978397B47500245589"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Eligible home infusion suppliers</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>eligible home infusion supplier</term> means a supplier that is enrolled under this part as a pharmacy that provides external infusion pumps and external infusion pump supplies and that maintains all pharmacy licensure requirements in the State in which the applicable infusion drugs are administered.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF9236CA8B184426EBA65106A07F176B8"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may implement this paragraph by program instruction or otherwise.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HB29E457E7B6E437E8E0BC0380BFED937"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1842(b)(6)(I) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395u">42 U.S.C. 1395u(b)(6)(I)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or, in the case of items and services described in clause (i) of section 1834(u)(7)(A) furnished to an individual during the period described in clause (ii) of such section, payment shall be made to the eligible home infusion therapy supplier</quote> after <quote>payment shall be made to the qualified home infusion therapy supplier</quote>. </text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

