<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H58692971C6A0466F920D2F6F8FB4F918" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4569 IH: Counterterrorism Information Sharing Improvement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4569</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171206">December 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000580">Mr. Garrett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require counterterrorism information sharing coordination, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5B9FFE7689634F03B6DD61EE0E6853A5" style="OLC">
 <section id="HADCC775F6B7049808D438E75951FBAE9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Counterterrorism Information Sharing Improvement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H07E6396ED9EE43B59B2898E7FFFA1DA5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Counterterrorism information sharing coordination</header> <subsection id="H231EEA4816BC44B39AB8F6FD5BF0491C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President, acting though the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall ensure that, for counterterrorism purposes, the Department of the Homeland Security has access to biographic and biometric data collected by the United States Government on individuals associated with a terrorist organization.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H10BF453E81ED4250B360609259DBDCB4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The President shall direct the heads of relevant Federal departments and agencies to coordinate with the Secretary of Homeland Security to minimize and overcome any administrative, technical, capacity, or classification challenges to carrying out subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD19F03A06BF142EC83A38D17B0B8768E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Protections</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that all relevant laws, rules, and procedures, including the section 552(a) of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Privacy Act</quote> or the <quote>Privacy Act of 1974</quote>), regarding classification levels and civil rights and civil liberties are followed while seeking to carry out subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HC4471C91387C4A6BBA06B27E4C8F782C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header>
 <paragraph id="H05808050DC9D4434B590D3D41BA93ADE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall, consistent with the protection of classified information, submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the implementation of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE89BC42FAAC54E5B9804D4C30C200DE3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under paragraph (1) shall include a description of how the data referred to in subsection (a) is utilized for Department of Homeland Security screening and vetting purposes and any challenges associated with incorporating such data into departmental screening and vetting systems.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


