<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF9A0BAFE83694D238D1AAD5FE1040FE6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1143 IH: Hygiene Assistance for Families of Infants and Toddlers Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1143</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170216">February 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to address the increased burden that maintaining the health
			 and hygiene of infants and toddlers places on families in need, the
			 resultant adverse health effects on children and families, and the limited
			 child care options available for infants and toddlers who lack sufficient
			 diapers.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HD96F0BD4ADB140E0AF2F1BA72C594F66" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF5C16868028B45F0B2E5110F6D067E09" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hygiene Assistance for Families of Infants and Toddlers Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB764128FDE154C7A9212EACE34EC20F3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving opportunity diaper distribution demonstration project</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part P of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g">42 U.S.C. 280g</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HABB0CF9C3204419AA47D0D6ACDE5A5B1" style="OLC">
				<section id="H5D49A09EC3094B3F870FEDAF582B5516"><enum>399V–7.</enum><header>Diaper distribution demonstration project</header>
 <subsection id="H397EBBA6B86A4ED5ABED73A766A50265"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administration for Children and Families, shall make grants to eligible entities to conduct demonstration projects that implement and evaluate strategies to help families with eligible children to address the diapering needs of such children.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE5354D4F2DA9436C84B98D95773F5CD3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of Funds</header><text>Amounts provided through a grant under this section shall be used to—</text> <paragraph id="H52F03A3514FD47AA85473415518D315D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>fund diaper distribution demonstration projects that will reduce the substantial cost of diapers and diapering supplies by making diapers and diapering supplies available to low-income families;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B9D6B1A313E41EC8B87EAFDE1B9A815"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluate the effects of such demonstration projects on mitigating health risks, including diaper dermatitis, urinary tract infections, and increased rates of parental and child depression and anxiety, that can arise when low-income families do not have an adequate supply of diapers for infants and toddlers; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC076DB6F723D479285A2B3E451A4D066"><enum>(3)</enum><text>integrate the diaper distribution demonstration projects with other assistance programs serving families with eligible children.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H589823C04F3145F6A883B422EA9326AD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application that includes such information as the Secretary may require to ensure a likelihood of success in achieving the purposes of the grant listed in subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1083EDAA8C4A4CE3BD52E22F4E46C657"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall be—</text> <paragraph id="H4D8C7EB8109C4EF2A5ABBDA6CBED7B42"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a State or local governmental entity;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69CEED547EAA4E1F964D7F824D5E1D55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an Indian tribe or tribal organization (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H44135028401B4B8EA1BFB515EA0219AF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization as described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAB13044538F94B77B4A482C467032A64"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No effect on other programs</header><text>Any assistance or benefits provided to a family pursuant to a grant under this section shall be disregarded for purposes of determining the family’s eligibility for, or amount of, benefits under—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4B9E6B59FD0E4322A7BFFF7DFC7718F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any other Federal needs-based program; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E33D23739FB4FCFBB1D4E425E37977C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of a grant under this section to a State, any State-funded, needs-based program that is financed in whole or in part with Federal funds.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H97930AFDE5CF45E0B8C6EB6ACCE07867"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>As a condition of receiving a grant under this section for a fiscal year, an entity shall submit to the Secretary, not later than 6 months after the end of the fiscal year, a report that specifies—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2069835FECE741FE93C5DB1AF93D186D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of children and the number of families receiving assistance under the diaper distribution demonstration projects funded through such grant for each month of the fiscal year;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD51CBC70AF1487A8ABCF64A963E5A83"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of diapers, and the number of each type of diapering supply distributed through such projects for each month of the fiscal year;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H547D08C9A6BB48588F72E3F772F5DC7A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the method or methods the entity uses to distribute diapers and diapering supplies through such projects; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H93F15586723B4F2AB82C5B441BEEC02F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5A001CDBDBF74268848C35D77C1E3553"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with each entity that receives a grant under this section, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3CBD21963C5B42069AC80DB72BC85481"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than September 30, 2019—</text> <subparagraph id="HCA9F05DA29984832933A3FA315BE7C4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>complete an evaluation of the effectiveness of the diaper distribution demonstration projects carried out pursuant to this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D96CE6DBAF04F71A669D1FB54B3BC18"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to the relevant congressional committees a report on the results of such evaluation; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H881A8E0B798744409B0AF31D0A0F8FFF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>publish the results of the evaluation on the Internet Web site of the Department of Health and Human Services; and</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC46F889700D415FA861734B0B5F1375"><enum>(2)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE33FF0A1505341DDB52433A355D778C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than September 30, 2022, update the evaluation described in paragraph (1)(A); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD51BABF9C83B4DEAB6914B2D6983CF1D" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 90 days after completion of the updated evaluation under subparagraph (B)—</text>
 <clause id="HE3604F1DAB7D44D2B4DD491E15F5EDD1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>submit to the relevant congressional committees a report describing the results of such evaluation; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA832C603036F4C2DBD3826A6E4AD34A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>update the Web site described in paragraph (1)(C) to include the results of such evaluation.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H34FBB2322A4A455893174201887945A8"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H0D60A7472CDF4CD9B3D8844054A554AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>diaper</term> means an absorbent garment that is washable or disposable that is worn by a child who is not toilet-trained.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5A3291FE02A441DB1A7270195D517D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>diapering supplies</term> means items, including diaper wipes and diaper cream, necessary to ensure that a child using a diaper is properly cleaned and protected from diaper rash.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2002D6EA3B4433AAD73F772DFBDE7D9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>eligible child</term> means a child who—</text> <subparagraph id="H8655613C9EBE4D788309F28844DC78FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not toilet-trained;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F23F749FD104D6AA404E78C82AD2965"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has not attained 4 years of age, unless the entity determines that the child has a substantial physical or mental impairment that requires the child to wear diapers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED31A46FD3514D54932BB90D16C4B101"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is a member of a family whose income is not more than 130 percent of the poverty line (as defined by the Office of Management and Budget, and revised annually in accordance with section 673(2) of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1981) applicable to a family of the size involved.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2F81FD2276B4D4ABF0FE39B082D7729"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>toilet-trained</term> means able and willing to use a toilet consistently such that diapers are not necessary on a daily basis.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFFBE061954A74B908E72CBD08714BFC4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="H342E21413CDA4D46AFF0A47B1DAA3F11"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, $25,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H42D91CEC86BF4A279549CAA3D546D9D8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text>Funds provided to an entity under this section for a fiscal year may be expended only in the fiscal year or the succeeding fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


