<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDF51D229133C4C87BA8C1AD28F1AE2CF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4072 IH: Central Coast Heritage Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4072</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171016">October 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate certain Federal land in the State of California as wilderness, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA1A3A145E2984F9CB63A21A7A7DFC8CD" style="OLC">
		<section id="H26502D16F8C94245B1DE1BC1609E915A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H572F5331CA594E9188CFE2513A1BE11A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Central Coast Heritage Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H817E72BC88344F22AA5117088B0005C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc>
					<toc-entry idref="H26502D16F8C94245B1DE1BC1609E915A" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB0B25B981D1D4DD4A5B2FF5A2F5B00DF" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H3A592225BB4B49A69FAA7266CBB4F869" level="section">Sec. 3. Designation of wilderness.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H09464BD4DAAC452AB055F7C2978D5C80" level="section">Sec. 4. Designation of the Machesna Mountain Potential Wilderness.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBE364C9DAB984BA39C0CACA263807CA2" level="section">Sec. 5. Administration of wilderness.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8A42799395BC4254AA74872E8ADEFD38" level="section">Sec. 6. Designation of wild and scenic rivers.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HCA5CFF929FE54AB2AF88F4DAB936DEAD" level="section">Sec. 7. Designation of the Fox Mountain Potential Wilderness.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HC30BA071BF634D14B38EE17F3B157E38" level="section">Sec. 8. Designation of scenic areas.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H06F3256FF61C493BB66A724F54693245" level="section">Sec. 9. Condor National Recreation Trail.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HC2125351CB9F4450803545E6D1BE3D0F" level="section">Sec. 10. Forest service study.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H6559618B20A846BF826B8813313DDB95" level="section">Sec. 11. Nonmotorized recreation opportunities.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB6DC8C970DEA4C8F9C38F91D0C22C74D" level="section">Sec. 12. Use by members of Tribes.</toc-entry></toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="HB0B25B981D1D4DD4A5B2FF5A2F5B00DF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HD8C97AA60D174E09896BEEE35A5F9A3B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Scenic areas</header><text>The term <term>scenic area</term> means a scenic area designated by section 8(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H10668039AC4F4957AE11DA94C5253F28"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HE8CFA1A516CC4F3488422938D40B11E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to land managed by the Bureau of Land Management, the Secretary of the Interior; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB84EFB5B4C54E0790A7B75B2593CD9A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to land managed by the Forest Service, the Secretary of Agriculture.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H800600F44953439D993D0EE9B46CB712"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of California.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FAF446053EF4652831743B9E7FB2755"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Wilderness area</header><text>The term <term>wilderness area</term> means a wilderness area or wilderness addition designated by section 3(a).</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H3A592225BB4B49A69FAA7266CBB4F869"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation of wilderness</header> <subsection id="HC370C605D8554E8F81A464A92E6CD95A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.), the following areas in the State are designated as wilderness areas and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
 <paragraph id="HBD3C45B0275742D387650BD5A9ABD07A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Certain land in the Bakersfield Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 35,619 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Caliente Mountain Wilderness Area—Proposed</quote> and dated May 31, 2017, which shall be known as the <quote>Caliente Mountain Wilderness</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD935EB5A01994ADBAE83979AD0964A70"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Certain land in the Bakersfield Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 13,332 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Soda Lake Wilderness Area—Proposed</quote> and dated May 31, 2017, which shall be known as the <quote>Soda Lake Wilderness</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A303BED1EEF48488EFD0E4B69A75EE0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Certain land in the Bakersfield Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 12,585 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Temblor Range Wilderness Area—Proposed</quote> and dated May 31, 2017, which shall be known as the <quote>Temblor Range Wilderness</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0292070F6CA44138C568D36AD1B7841"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 23,670 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Chumash Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated October 4, 2017, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Chumash Wilderness as designated by the Los Padres Condor Range and River Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/301">Public Law 102–301</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 242).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF108355E1BEB46CD87CDB287E5BEBA69"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 54,221 acres, as generally depicted on the maps entitled <quote>Dick Smith Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed Map 1 of 2 (Bear Canyon and Cuyama Peak Units)</quote> and <quote>Dick Smith Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed Map 2 of 2 (Buckhorn and Mono Units)</quote> and dated October 4, 2017, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Dick Smith Wilderness as designated by the California Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/425">Public Law 98–425</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H40DFE00F94C5414FB02A727A78B93D56"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest and the Bakersfield Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 7,289 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Garcia Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated October 4, 2017, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Garcia Wilderness as designated by the Los Padres Condor Range and River Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/301">Public Law 102–301</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 242).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4891EB9BBB0B432E9ADDA10A74A5E6D9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest and the Bakersfield Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 8,671 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Machesna Mountain Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated October 4, 2017, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Machesna Mountain Wilderness as designated by the California Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/425">Public Law 98–425</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5283630A8F9E43DE916359B29C66CC54"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 30,184 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Matilija Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated October 4, 2017, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Matilija Wilderness as designated by the Los Padres Condor Range and River Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/301">Public Law 102–301</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 242).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC865F262099C4285A6BBEA716947B9D8"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 24,040 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>San Rafael Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated October 4, 2017, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the San Rafael Wilderness as designated by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/90/271">Public Law 90–271</external-xref> (82 Stat. 51), the California Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/425">Public Law 98–425</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note), and the Los Padres Condor Range and River Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/301">Public Law 102–301</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 242).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H65531AB47CDA412DBEEEF2567DCD059F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 3,115 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Santa Lucia Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated October 4, 2017, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Santa Lucia Wilderness as designated by the Endangered American Wilderness Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/237">Public Law 95–237</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71CC4D9F029E47F0A6AF05983F5CEF82"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 14,313 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Sespe Wilderness Area Additions—Proposed</quote> and dated October 4, 2017, which shall be incorporated into and managed as part of the Sespe Wilderness as designated by the Los Padres Condor Range and River Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/301">Public Law 102–301</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 242).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC86B2AA9B8F4D62B0DE51424641D484"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 17,870 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Diablo Caliente Wilderness Area—Proposed</quote> and dated October 4, 2017, which shall be known as the <quote>Diablo Caliente Wilderness</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD5C96C0BE10145A3AF029C5D53C48088"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maps and legal descriptions</header>
 <paragraph id="HD8B3DF3C5AB7474897D17C60B9E729DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall file maps and legal descriptions of the wilderness areas with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD00C31B27EE247A8A01AF9BE19C14184"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H383B01AF695349159A4A18F7F8681802"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H21FBF230867D442BBCC8E9B5A13C1FC0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct any clerical and typographical errors in the maps and legal descriptions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC412A53937B548ADA8BF9305B6313127"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions filed under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H09464BD4DAAC452AB055F7C2978D5C80"><enum>4.</enum><header>Designation of the Machesna Mountain Potential Wilderness</header>
 <subsection id="HCF8DE4BF9DF54C2F9F44C1C68AB40E75"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>In furtherance of the purposes of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.), certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 2,359 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Machesna Mountain Potential Wilderness Area</quote> and dated October 4, 2017, is designated as the Machesna Mountain Potential Wilderness Area.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H6232A4963F1A44A79837E6E3C59BB8EA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Map and legal description</header>
 <paragraph id="H6C6ED9FC999D4D388F09576D547350CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall file a map and legal description of the Machesna Mountain Potential Wilderness Area (referred to in this section as the <quote>potential wilderness area</quote>) with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H86227060CF124DB3AA555EAEB8981C36"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEE64E55E9E440F3AF270D6E397A1E59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4A0630BAFB14D0A8E2D9821A3644D2D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct any clerical and typographical errors in the map and legal description.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H60474C153CED457AA6C9C5F76979F42A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H904BC8EDC909483988B933F778007E24"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (d) and subject to valid existing rights, the Secretary shall manage the potential wilderness area in accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H36EEF800AC344C899F838CA054EC6640"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Trail use, construction, reconstruction, and realignment</header>
 <paragraph id="HDC1772088850460FABB1DF69DE93AB1E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with paragraph (2), the Secretary may reconstruct, realign, or reroute the Pine Mountain Trail.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H75050D0CA006435F9700869AB062238A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In carrying out the reconstruction, realignment, or rerouting under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H849CCFF9A8BA4E99BA6D6F50CE5C4BE0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>comply with all existing laws (including regulations); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85905C4D0660477CA5C056F29CB42800"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, use the minimum tool or administrative practice necessary to accomplish the reconstruction, realignment, or rerouting with the least amount of adverse impact on wilderness character and resources.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BA058097CC6473187C5C928EC8C208A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Motorized vehicles and machinery</header><text>In accordance with paragraph (2), the Secretary may use motorized vehicles and machinery to carry out the trail reconstruction, realignment, or rerouting authorized by this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H491FE418E22A411D9B7D78614833C962"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Motorized and mechanized vehicles</header><text>The Secretary may permit the use of motorized and mechanized vehicles on the existing Pine Mountain Trail in accordance with existing law (including regulations) and this subsection until such date as the potential wilderness area is designated as wilderness in accordance with subsection (h).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H30BBB812025C4CDCADF8BCBCC8DF1302"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land in the potential wilderness area is withdrawn from all forms of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H78DFFE6E4BE04B848FFD0A2CA90E9A84"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DDF17EDC79E4CE3B2CC9CC846DCB20C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9917AB83B4A348609F3F3A32535FCAB5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED03D2BA08B24E2CB3DBC4AD394DB88A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with State, Tribal, and local governmental entities and private entities to complete the trail reconstruction, realignment, or rerouting authorized by subsection (d).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H04BEFBBDD1DB41888E57CCD67DCBBC6C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Boundaries</header><text>The Secretary shall modify the boundary of the potential wilderness area to exclude any area within 150 feet of the centerline of the new location of any trail that has been reconstructed, realigned, or rerouted under subsection (d).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HCB55E924F9D84E4DAF4EAB727D89745C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Wilderness designation</header>
 <paragraph id="HE22D63B1731C43E696DC715BFA935FDF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The potential wilderness area, as modified under subsection (g), shall be designated as wilderness and as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System on the earlier of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H66D619DAA84441A49939F2E169ED99DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date on which the Secretary publishes in the Federal Register notice that the trail reconstruction, realignment, or rerouting authorized by subsection (d) has been completed; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5297207913DD43F085201EB7ABE95F7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date that is 20 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H09359B0A0508497DA84EC18216D5836F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration of wilderness</header><text>On designation as wilderness under this section, the potential wilderness area shall be—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB4C9879CABED49B5A535FDDD58E140C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>incorporated into the Machesna Mountain Wilderness Area, as designated by the California Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/425">Public Law 98–425</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note) and expanded by section 3; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F57B8BEDBEC4CC683C1A3EFEF3F0E8A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>administered in accordance with section 5 and the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBE364C9DAB984BA39C0CACA263807CA2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Administration of wilderness</header> <subsection id="H6C4D3CC0F8764E84B5CA1F86DAF432A8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the wilderness areas shall be administered by the Secretary in accordance with this Act and the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.), except that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEFF67503567D4C7DAFB9739C2AB71DC1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any reference in the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.) to the effective date of that Act shall be considered to be a reference to the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25BE4FD56EB5482086B32413D6E72160"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any reference in the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.) to the Secretary of Agriculture shall be considered to be a reference to the Secretary that has jurisdiction over the wilderness area.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77CEC3D5D55649ACA22A2D9B59EC7B0F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fire management and related activities</header>
 <paragraph id="H387DCF880DCD4A7F9A5E48F3BAE2C24B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may take any measures in a wilderness area as are necessary for the control of fire, insects, and diseases in accordance with section 4(d)(1) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(1)</external-xref>) and House Report 98–40 of the 98th Congress.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCBCEFA9CD25845EAA4D4BF22A74EB0F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funding priorities</header><text>Nothing in this Act limits funding for fire and fuels management in the wilderness areas.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB50DE26C3B754CDAB2C6EA2D766B0546"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Revision and development of local fire management plans</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall amend the local information in the Fire Management Reference System or individual operational plans that apply to the land designated as a wilderness area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0AE81F90395A4860941A97B5D7D62C52"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Consistent with paragraph (1) and other applicable Federal law, to ensure a timely and efficient response to fire emergencies in the wilderness areas, the Secretary shall enter into agreements with appropriate State or local firefighting agencies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC0799B59A1444CD7B1C4E98E1E7EE6F7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grazing</header><text>The grazing of livestock in the wilderness areas, if established before the date of enactment of this Act, shall be permitted to continue, subject to any reasonable regulations as the Secretary considers necessary in accordance with—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC711BDE536AF4157AA58276FD3E5D4A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 4(d)(4) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(4)</external-xref>);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BF4B9971E714E0092671036A20DED21"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the guidelines set forth in Appendix A of House Report 101–405, accompanying H.R. 2570 of the 101st Congress for land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE2D58D217F244399038A0F8BA71BBBF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the guidelines set forth in House Report 96–617, accompanying H.R. 5487 of the 96th Congress for land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6704198A64F3462F83A8E9A21A6C8BCA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>all other laws governing livestock grazing on Federal public land.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA4A604801724D95B731EB4C71EFA33A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header> <paragraph id="H69520AEBF5D94B93B2CD4B4F29BB90F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with section 4(d)(7) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(7)</external-xref>), nothing in this Act affects the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the State with respect to fish and wildlife on public land in the State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E0A1373E1BF4AB5921ED03B918E64FC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management activities</header><text>In furtherance of the purposes and principles of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.), the Secretary may conduct any management activities that are necessary to maintain or restore fish and wildlife populations and habitats in the wilderness areas, if the management activities are—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4E34BFE8EB924DB58C1E602864A729AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consistent with relevant wilderness management plans;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB4AAB89C1A44F3FBEE079B784289FCC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conducted in accordance with appropriate policies, such as the policies established in Appendix B of House Report 101–405; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB708EBCF33B4E0D852F30BCB4123259"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in accordance with memoranda of understanding between the Federal agencies and the State Department of Fish and Wildlife.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H49BCC5CBC94F4D0DB49D71EFB2467A8A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Buffer zones</header>
 <paragraph id="H049B398F30CB46D8824BD65503661A84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Congress does not intend for the designation of wilderness areas by this Act to lead to the creation of protective perimeters or buffer zones around each wilderness area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F3FAC39B9C943018ADD782820795051"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities or uses up to boundaries</header><text>The fact that nonwilderness activities or uses can be seen or heard from within a wilderness area shall not, of itself, preclude the activities or uses up to the boundary of the wilderness area.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD15ED11F76B74363AC1D2069C0DBA2F7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Military activities</header><text>Nothing in this Act precludes—</text> <paragraph id="H874108F7B22F49F893C6C7101C3EBCA5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>low-level overflights of military aircraft over the wilderness areas;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D26D992EC7D46E0B2D24DC1EAC9A6CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the designation of new units of special airspace over the wilderness areas; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H91CAE690288F457796280A5FA28126B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the use or establishment of military flight training routes over wilderness areas.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13B2205D284140B1A8CFA23AAB75B34D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Horses</header><text>Nothing in this Act precludes horseback riding in, or the entry of recreational saddle or pack stock into, a wilderness area—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8E20B58925334171870175C94E9C1100"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in accordance with section 4(d)(5) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(5)</external-xref>); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4CF951FA0190495A96E435A0A1C288E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to any terms and conditions determined to be necessary by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H11611FDD86714788AC7707FFB2A928B0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the wilderness areas are withdrawn from—</text> <paragraph id="HEB1CA34CBBAB440E87BBEEC7848C97ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6668FD04B11D4E7CAF3AAECC53B5BB26"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7381FD21C6A4AFC88F5C16FC280B0A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H05F94AFAEDB44AA1935D5CCC3C8CD794"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Incorporation of acquired land and interests</header><text>Any land within the boundary of a wilderness area that is acquired by the United States shall—</text> <paragraph id="H646291EB67A545D5897B2A45E4D7D3D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>become part of the wilderness area in which the land is located; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H468D8FB2D8D2484895B162C092126AC4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be managed in accordance with—</text> <subparagraph id="H2CCBE43CF7D2476F892539460BB7D8DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1079716C50094CB1B76F86FE903C67B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66C507CF77E5499BA913CB156F134041"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other applicable law.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD70EE4E0F4B427B9E0EAD5B2EBA22C4"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Treatment of existing water diversions in the San Rafael Wilderness Additions</header>
 <paragraph id="H3DABF270F91B47FE81D8377758F19112"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization for continued use</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture may issue a special use authorization to the owners of the 2 existing water transport or diversion facilities, including administrative access roads (in this subsection referred to as a <quote>facility</quote>), located on National Forest System land in the San Rafael Wilderness Additions in the Moon Canyon unit (T. 11 N., R. 30 W., secs. 13 and 14) and the Peak Mountain unit (T. 10 N., R. 28 W., secs. 23 and 26) for the continued operation, maintenance, and reconstruction of the facility if the Secretary determines that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFCB7341A25EB4344960176B41879690D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the facility was in existence on the date on which the land on which the facility is located was designated as part of the National Wilderness Preservation System (in this subsection referred to as <quote>the date of designation</quote>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC46A9A77E4924D56B70FC4CEC1710C27"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the facility has been in substantially continuous use to deliver water for the beneficial use on the non-Federal land of the owner since the date of designation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28D4B2E6D13C459796BDFAE40E93ECC5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the owner of the facility holds a valid water right for use of the water on the non-Federal land of the owner under State law, with a priority date that predates the date of designation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A98BA3663AE4B28A6DA27BDB526A4F5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>it is not practicable or feasible to relocate the facility to land outside of the wilderness and continue the beneficial use of water on the non-Federal land recognized under State law.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB22F53714F324425A49A9ED737BAE7FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H749A77201A18420DB2C1A5E0EBFA7251"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Required terms and conditions</header><text>In a special use authorization issued under paragraph (1), the Secretary may—</text> <clause id="H2E8BB620060443FC896C281ED966438C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>allow use of motorized equipment and mechanized transport for operation, maintenance, or reconstruction of a facility, if the Secretary determines that—</text>
 <subclause id="H29EC832CFEEF4C39BCCDE0DCBED20238"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the use is the minimum necessary to allow the facility to continue delivery of water to the non-Federal land for the beneficial uses recognized by the water right held under State law; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8AA3AD279C7B4F69A56F42B2376A4A63"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the use of non-motorized equipment and non-mechanized transport is impracticable or infeasible; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HC5E39DC3705E4F9E94070EDC6A219165"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>preclude use of the facility for the diversion or transport of water in excess of the water right recognized by the State on the date of designation.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H661CD25EB3C947779178E379E1B2922F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Discretionary terms and conditions</header><text>In a special use authorization issued under paragraph (1), the Secretary may require or allow modification or relocation of the facility in the wilderness, as the Secretary determines necessary, to reduce impacts to wilderness values set forth in section 2 of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref>) if the beneficial use of water on the non-Federal land is not diminished.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD3E47D80D8FE4CFFA24394A6626E458D"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Treatment of Existing Electrical Distribution Line in the San Rafael Wilderness Additions</header>
 <paragraph id="H33E07B95D1B6486E824366D8138F7CDD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization for continued use</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture may issue a special use authorization to the owners of the existing electrical distribution line to the Plowshare Peak communication site (in this subsection referred to as a <quote>facility</quote>) located on National Forest System land in the San Rafael Wilderness Additions in the Moon Canyon unit (T. 11 N., R. 30 W., secs. 2, 3 and 4) for the continued operation, maintenance, and reconstruction of the facility if the Secretary determines that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB9D0226695E04B999CD3DFEE450F2989"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the facility was in existence on the date on which the land on which the facility is located was designated as part of the National Wilderness Preservation System (in this subsection referred to as <quote>the date of designation</quote>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7BBE15AD3D547F58F5F32F0D63F5891"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the facility has been in substantially continuous use to deliver electricity to the communication site; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40D7ADB88E70466AA5307D853BC02E73"><enum>(C)</enum><text>it is not practicable or feasible to relocate the distribution line to land outside of the wilderness.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD796BE6D4B7741DDAA32FA6D0F6F8F99"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0D43E7B968A94CC58467621A4883D994"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Required terms and conditions</header><text>In a special use authorization issued under paragraph (1), the Secretary may allow use of motorized equipment and mechanized transport for operation, maintenance, or reconstruction of the electrical distribution line, if the Secretary determines that the use of non-motorized equipment and non-mechanized transport is impracticable or infeasible.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED90B81A46FC449EAC7E5730E0952007"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Discretionary terms and conditions</header><text>In a special use authorization issued under paragraph (1), the Secretary may require or allow modification or relocation of the facility in the wilderness, as the Secretary determines necessary, to reduce impacts to wilderness values set forth in section 2 of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD130C78EF9E346E0B9E9ABAE541D1C6F"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Climatological data collection</header><text>In accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.) and subject to terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may authorize the installation and maintenance of hydrologic, meteorologic, or climatological collection devices in the wilderness areas if the Secretary determines that the facilities and access to the facilities are essential to flood warning, flood control, or water reservoir operation activities.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H8A42799395BC4254AA74872E8ADEFD38"><enum>6.</enum><header>Designation of wild and scenic rivers</header>
 <subsection id="H749FBA4C7E7541D69BEEA28FAED016CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Indian Creek, Mono Creek, and Matilija Creek, California</header><text>Section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13E59BEA048C40FE973D1DF653D7AC84" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H85505B3B66C24784957EAC2FD363ED2F"><enum>(213)</enum><header>Indian creek, california</header><text>The following segments of Indian Creek in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4F7DF6EEFE654C67946BE0932DE289C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 9.5-mile segment of Indian Creek from its source in sec. 19, T. 7 N., R. 26 W., to the Dick Smith Wilderness boundary, as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC84603534444C4FB77078F4E4E389A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 1-mile segment of Indian Creek from the Dick Smith Wilderness boundary to 0.25 miles downstream of Road 6N24, as a scenic river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H978A708129FC491F9459C17228B4D26A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 3.9-mile segment of Indian Creek from 0.25 miles downstream of Road 6N24 to the southern boundary of sec. 32, T. 6 N., R. 26 W., as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9B91622A8824593910CFE6CF95A015A"><enum>(214)</enum><header>Mono creek, california</header><text>The following segments of Mono Creek in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H365C630A891F4DD6B453F425BE3021F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 4.2-mile segment of Mono Creek from its source in sec. 1, T. 7 N., R. 26 W., to 0.25 miles upstream of Don Victor Fire Road in sec. 28, T. 7 N., R. 25 W., as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FF9C0C8EF3040E3BDA899BC057630B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 2.1-mile segment of Mono Creek from 0.25 miles upstream of the Don Victor Fire Road in sec. 28, T. 7 N., R. 25 W., to 0.25 miles downstream of Don Victor Fire Road in sec. 34, T7N, R25W, as a recreational river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81D66B9EFFEE44BB91061807130F16E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 14.7-mile segment of Mono Creek from 0.25 miles downstream of Don Victor Fire Road in sec. 34, T. 7 N., R. 25 W., to the Ogilvy Ranch private property boundary in sec. 22, R. 26 W., T. 6 N., as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07458F19AE5D44B5B2D979557D96D3EE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The 3.5-mile segment of Mono Creek from the Ogilvy Ranch private property boundary to the southern boundary of sec. 33, T. 6 N., R. 26 N., as a recreational river.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H152CE79E2B96413098D2121C40351247"><enum>(215)</enum><header>Matilija creek, california</header><text>The following segments of Matilija Creek in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3F29F965979F4F36BF6B4DA35CF037ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 7.2-mile segment of the Matilija Creek from its source in sec. 25, T. 6 N., R. 25 W., to the private property boundary in sec. 9, T. 5 N., R. 24 W., as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06C262DB15184F44A4950838D01C5BEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 7.25-mile segment of the Upper North Fork Matilija Creek from its source in sec. 36, T. 6 N., R. 24 W., to the Matilija Wilderness boundary, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7DF31348F55E49F98D9882AAE032674A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sespe Creek, California</header><text>Section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (142) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H126A8D0EA77740D6B26790A3651F3BBC" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HB71FD8772733432DB6B2F585BDA9896C"><enum>(142)</enum><header>Sespe creek, california</header><text>The following segments of Sespe Creek in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAF74153AE7244C7C832763432E3EC310"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 2.7-mile segment of Sespe Creek from the private property boundary in sec. 10, T. 6 N., R. 24 W., to the Hartman Ranch private property boundary in sec. 14, T. 6 N., R. 24 W., as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3C2EFF600864CC8A8CC2C1770633A51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 15-mile segment of Sespe Creek from the Hartman Ranch private property boundary in sec. 14, T. 6 N., R. 24 W., to the western boundary of sec. 6, T. 5 N., R. 22 W., as a recreational river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBD53BD45DC94070AD5A6F6D00DBF3A1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 6.1-mile segment of Sespe Creek from the western boundary of sec. 6, T. 5 N., R. 22 W., to the confluence with Trout Creek, as a scenic river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A0C5F67BBDD4F91BAF89561FDD8A642"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The 28.6-mile segment of Sespe Creek from the confluence with Trout Creek to the southern boundary of sec. 35, T. 5 N., R. 20 W., as a wild river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC81757F349A94D7E8D92B06328A9C444"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sisquoc River, California</header><text>Section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (143) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H659328AA88534CA2AD225868B5DD246D" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H97C9973B75874F6D84D4E2A06379E603"><enum>(143)</enum><header>Sisquoc river, california</header><text>The following segments of the Sisquoc River and its tributaries in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H289BA67782C440228192871F96542FBE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 33-mile segment of the main stem of the Sisquoc River extending from its origin downstream to the Los Padres Forest boundary, as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24211BCE094842B18069ABFBBEC675CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 4.2-mile segment of the South Fork Sisquoc River from its source northeast of San Rafael Mountain in sec. 2, T. 7 N., R. 28 W., to its confluence with the Sisquoc River, as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4716A586D0C494EA17112C29BC36FC3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 10.4-mile segment of Manzana Creek from its source west of San Rafael Peak in sec. 4, T. 7 N., R. 28 W., to the San Rafael Wilderness boundary upstream of Nira Campground, as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA743055C4AA441C591BA52A71D2365F9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The 0.6-mile segment of Manzana Creek from the San Rafael Wilderness boundary upstream of the Nira Campground to the San Rafael Wilderness boundary downstream of the confluence of Davy Brown Creek, as a recreational river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE11F9689E4B437987FF4F63AD9CC164"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The 5.8-mile segment of Manzana Creek from the San Rafael Wilderness boundary downstream of the confluence of Davy Brown Creek to the private property boundary in sec. 1, T. 8 N., R. 30 W., as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DC17379D4B94007A17DC3AD07547F25"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The 3.8-mile segment of Manzana Creek from the private property boundary in sec. 1, T. 8 N., R. 30 W., to the confluence of the Sisquoc River, as a recreational river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C96AAD338C04B58827BAA0EA5324060"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The 3.4-mile segment of Davy Brown Creek from its source west of Ranger Peak in sec. 32, T. 8 N., R. 29 W., to 300 feet upstream of its confluence with Munch Canyon, as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECF9C2026BF644188CEDD2439EC03BFF"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The 1.4-mile segment of Davy Brown Creek from 300 feet upstream of its confluence with Munch Canyon to its confluence with Manzana Creek, as a recreational river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H798E06BEE6FC4CC9AD50428130B2B4DC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The 2-mile segment of Munch Canyon from its source north of Ranger Peak in sec. 33, T. 8 N., R. 29 W., to 300 feet upstream of its confluence with Sunset Valley Creek, as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9869BB9F7264A2FBF9CDE8F80EEBF25"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The 0.5-mile segment of Munch Canyon from 300 feet upstream of its confluence with Sunset Valley Creek to its confluence with Davy Brown Creek, as a recreational river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36322017F46F4AF3A466A315EDE1C570"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The 2.6-mile segment of Fish Creek from 500 feet downstream of Sunset Valley Road to its confluence with Manzana Creek, as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAFC364BAD8F431585AB35314FFADE79"><enum>(L)</enum><text>The 1.5-mile segment of East Fork Fish Creek from its source in sec. 26, T. 8 N., R. 29 W., to its confluence with Fish Creek, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB34C50591FA3487EA916C1A45111BC13"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Piru Creek, California</header><text>Section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (199) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF487C28B0355483FA9B629F3BCC06D6A" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H917A9E7EE0074B6BBD91AB83BFC195F3"><enum>(199)</enum><header>Piru creek, california</header><text>The following segments of Piru Creek in the State of California, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9D2185F9CA31495F9C01E660CB1AB260"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 9.1-mile segment of Piru Creek from its source in sec. 3, T. 6 N., R. 22 W., to the private property boundary in sec. 4, T. 6 N., R. 21 W., as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1ED08F8F507443AC8295FE16EDB9E004"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 17.2-mile segment of Piru Creek from the private property boundary in sec. 4, T. 6 N., R. 21 W., to 0.25 miles downstream of the Gold Hill Road, as a scenic river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8D8B75726BB4CE1A7002E9E11F00515"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 4.1-mile segment of Piru Creek from 0.25 miles downstream of Gold Hill Road to the confluence with Trail Canyon, as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD20553928B64B30BF5C9A3935A97B75"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The 7.25-mile segment of Piru Creek from the confluence with Trail Canyon to the confluence with Buck Creek, as a scenic river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6FF13FEE68B49DDB3409E2ED08152F3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The 3-mile segment of Piru Creek from 0.5 miles downstream of Pyramid Dam at the first bridge crossing to the boundary of the Sespe Wilderness, as a recreational river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38B0E9F138704FA8B7C3C5F248312ABD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The 13-mile segment of Piru Creek from the boundary of the Sespe Wilderness to the boundary of the Sespe Wilderness, as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DD966F9C4C74BB7A7FC5F5F3291D9B5"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The 2.2-mile segment of Piru Creek from the boundary of the Sespe Wilderness to the upper limit of Piru Reservoir, as a recreational river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD263C9D67C474FF193EA8965822B70EE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>The designation of additional miles of Piru Creek under subsection (d) shall not affect valid water rights in existence on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H19728A5041AB4937BB392E9A3678DE77"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Motorized use of trails</header><text>Nothing in this section (including the amendments made by this section) affects the motorized use of trails designated by the Forest Service for motorized use that are located adjacent to and crossing upper Piru Creek, if the use is consistent with the protection and enhancement of river values under the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1271">16 U.S.C. 1271</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HCA5CFF929FE54AB2AF88F4DAB936DEAD"><enum>7.</enum><header>Designation of the Fox Mountain Potential Wilderness</header>
 <subsection id="H4A19A46F70434F9ABEDDE63EA486E295"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>In furtherance of the purposes of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.), certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 41,837 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Fox Mountain Potential Wilderness Area</quote> and dated October 4, 2017, is designated as the Fox Mountain Potential Wilderness Area.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HBBC5DE4DE6C84D98AA21BF2DC0109ADF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Map and legal description</header>
 <paragraph id="H60C0699CB4B54F40B92D0B5E108A12E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall file a map and a legal description of the Fox Mountain Potential Wilderness Area (referred to in this section as the <quote>potential wilderness area</quote>) with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H24E8DE451A0549ADBF3BB7D7ADBC15CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC937FB29CB0C4F4BA0B22BAD590C4CD2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB11BF04C6734CCFB7365BEF026D1C77"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary of Agriculture may correct any clerical and typographical errors in the map and legal description.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF78F4DFE20694DAE9CDFED374B68605C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H38009EE0186046FA89BE6860CE0B2034"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (d) and subject to valid existing rights, the Secretary shall manage the potential wilderness area in accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H141BBB9A2C3F4678B75546B3CCF3B8CA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Trail use construction, reconstruction, and realignment</header>
 <paragraph id="H557EA127FD064C66B782C9D31FBBDA55"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with paragraph (2), the Secretary of Agriculture may—</text> <subparagraph id="H211CF4CC1BB3402B996862C956767142"><enum>(A)</enum><text>construct a new trail for use by hikers, equestrians, and mechanized vehicles that connects the Aliso Park Campground to the Bull Ridge Trail; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H311565BF64224F83B95C42321FE6805A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reconstruct or realign—</text> <clause id="H2BD1DAF275F4412BABCA2672B1809FA3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Bull Ridge Trail; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCBD100C73D644822ADD45F21AAA8BA8E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Rocky Ridge Trail.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87C968D239754BEC9A8743C9D55F56E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In carrying out the construction, reconstruction, or alignment under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9A337C93401B4F09A4737B0E6AE9578C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>comply with all existing laws (including regulations); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A1168135C24483D9C88D6841DD63050"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, use the minimum tool or administrative practice necessary to accomplish the construction, reconstruction, or alignment with the least amount of adverse impact on wilderness character and resources.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H931CB25DE69340BBA5E58A06AAD83CF1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Motorized vehicles and machinery</header><text>In accordance with paragraph (2), the Secretary may use motorized vehicles and machinery to carry out the trail construction, reconstruction, or realignment authorized by this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01B89509E90F4AD2BE76DB942CB5ED04"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Mechanized vehicles</header><text>The Secretary may permit the use of mechanized vehicles on the existing Bull Ridge Trail and Rocky Ridge Trail in accordance with existing law (including regulations) and this subsection until such date as the potential wilderness area is designated as wilderness in accordance with subsection (h).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H74938DA5E273446AAC152A8AEDC0868D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land in the potential wilderness area is withdrawn from all forms of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H82F53E54A8BB4B219F54275C59F11B03"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF44FD25B7D2C4A4EA17E7B71C993357C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H871251F564194E8FA1A549378A76C1D4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB542ED8106E34E23A220DB6A4882E180"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with State, Tribal, and local governmental entities and private entities to complete the trail construction, reconstruction, and realignment authorized by subsection (d).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2DD4C66367D84EE7A65EA6ACCEBD3EAA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Boundaries</header><text>The Secretary shall modify the boundary of the potential wilderness area to exclude any area within 50 feet of the centerline of the new location of any trail that has been constructed, reconstructed, or realigned under subsection (d).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H9F155B9E6EEE4919B9D4DEA1547B6634"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Wilderness designation</header>
 <paragraph id="HE8254D04A8D04C97B9D19D5CD1C42EAB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The potential wilderness area, as modified under subsection (g), shall be designated as wilderness and as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System on the earlier of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC5A1D0A3677D4671BC30D1C4F16B3999"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date on which the Secretary publishes in the Federal Register notice that the trail construction, reconstruction, or alignment authorized by subsection (d) has been completed; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF90EF5BE49740EC97A4CDF442289F23"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date that is 20 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE69AD4E8D9F44726A7FC8A0F1E418E1F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration of wilderness</header><text>On designation as wilderness under this section, the potential wilderness area shall be—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0CCADE3CCE204A9B8D9B29070F8567CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>incorporated into the San Rafael Wilderness, as designated by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/90/271">Public Law 90–271</external-xref> (82 Stat. 51), the California Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/425">Public Law 98–425</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note), and the Los Padres Condor Range and River Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/301">Public Law 102–301</external-xref>; 106 Stat. 242), and section 3; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4E7B4AF2A004540B8CE5E6088A11A0D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>administered in accordance with section 5 and the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC30BA071BF634D14B38EE17F3B157E38"><enum>8.</enum><header>Designation of scenic areas</header> <subsection id="HA04487CD5DEA4201A44CD9AA124EA634"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, there are established the following scenic areas:</text>
 <paragraph id="H26550203941745129B9D34C7348B39CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Condor Ridge Scenic Area</header><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest comprising approximately 18,666 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Condor Ridge Scenic Area—Proposed</quote> and dated October 4, 2017, which shall be known as the <quote>Condor Ridge Scenic Area</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E00443E8DA24E27811C22B83953F884"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Black Mountain Scenic Area</header><text>Certain land in the Los Padres National Forest and the Bakersfield Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management comprising approximately 16,216 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Black Mountain Scenic Area—Proposed</quote> and dated October 4, 2017, which shall be known as the <quote>Black Mountain Scenic Area</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD5EB3AE30D6B492F9CF179A32774F89A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maps and legal descriptions</header>
 <paragraph id="H5434CC34CBFA4D8BA5FFA974F81C6391"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall file a map and legal description of the Condor Ridge Scenic Area and Black Mountain Scenic Area with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H36C8855755204DC9AF98DE332F4ADCFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54AC2737947C44D387A11EA129DAF669"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H078EA5C555DB40E98B12E8EE0067C682"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary of Agriculture may correct any clerical and typographical errors in the maps and legal descriptions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H986510C6A6C546728DE5E41E23344F61"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions filed under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H644AF582331C45E0A439EFF5C0863D1A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the scenic areas is to conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the ecological, scenic, wildlife, recreational, cultural, historical, natural, educational, and scientific resources of the scenic areas.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H0B4AAB18269D46698E93F35D2F72C1BE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Management</header>
 <paragraph id="H6FCC19A36DED4197994A15407F126E9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall administer the scenic areas—</text> <subparagraph id="H41491998CE2B4123A0CF965182B5A70A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances the resources of the scenic areas, and in particular the scenic character attributes of the scenic areas; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EF12B87AFB54EAB97D0F1414F207837"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in accordance with—</text> <clause id="HC9C4A356E0024FE082C7BBD1CECA3D0E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this section;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6CC3953FCB874F22996F6A634B84B1F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Federal Land Policy and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) for land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H42222305AF084FCE89A6AA1D54B52739"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any laws (including regulations) relating to the National Forest System, for land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H173E83BFB4454881A20CF798DD38532F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other applicable law (including regulations).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA525B022F76E407A9DA2CA237898BDCB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uses</header><text>The Secretary shall only allow those uses of the scenic areas that the Secretary determines would further the purposes described in subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H38F09B8FDDB6443BA06AE52A0270A385"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land in the scenic areas is withdrawn from all forms of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H552EF56C749F41ACB333F8F9340AAF1F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6282E7F312854BF98B49281EF9EC516F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2EC622919B94CE49F7A789BC345FA0B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H34A2028BE22148D7BD5AEBF9FD0031E3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Prohibited uses</header><text>The following shall be prohibited on the Federal land within the scenic areas:</text>
 <paragraph id="HE5D2DE704F064746BC0EBBE04937DBB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Permanent roads.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H960BAA37D96949A8A27AECD6ACC5B08F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Permanent structures.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H84EAAA04E4F249E1BF80FF5F165BEC08"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Timber harvesting except when necessary for the purposes described in subsection (g).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8040470AA6D4442499859E898EFB2BFD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Transmission lines.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FAEB9CF56AC453488D3E9A7495167E6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Except as necessary to meet the minimum requirements for the administration of the scenic areas and to protect public health and safety—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA76B1097301246B69C39A1ACEA16693B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the use of motorized vehicles; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAD41DC139B44E87A3D05FA28E98C384"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the establishment of temporary roads.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCEBE7CE010446BDAEBCB13E5FA06D7A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Commercial enterprises, except as necessary for realizing the purposes of the scenic areas.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H518C2ABCDD4D41269EB84D130AE53AEE"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Wildfire, insect, and disease management</header><text>Consistent with this section, the Secretary may take any measures in the scenic areas that the Secretary determines to be necessary to control fire, insects, and diseases, including, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, the coordination of those activities with the State or a local agency.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBD4D4B7E880042F387EEF074AFD29857"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Adjacent management</header><text>The fact that an otherwise authorized activity or use can be seen or heard within a scenic area shall not preclude the activity or use outside the boundary of the scenic area.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H06F3256FF61C493BB66A724F54693245"><enum>9.</enum><header>Condor National Recreation Trail</header>
 <subsection id="H7941305C57D64498A11F4547E2C66F96"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="H552C7285EE8B4A69B1E7CEE7453AD23F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Condor National Recreation Trail is named after the California Condor, a critically endangered bird species which lives along the extent of the Condor National Recreation Trail within the Los Padres National Forest; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0077E5D669FC45D090D3556DEB027338"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Condor National Recreation Trail will traverse a diversity of geography and communities through the southern and northern sections of the Los Padres National Forest.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31675140548742C4877B2707D75A9D0D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Condor National Recreation Trail is to provide a continual hiking trail corridor spanning the entire length of the Los Padres National Forest along the coastal mountains of Central California.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2E7CE35DBB9641A1B69FC741455059B5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text>Section 5(a) of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1244">16 U.S.C. 1244(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5E8E67792AC499688EF5495262414C3" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H41B69E78F99747D380B9980595AD04A0"><enum>(31)</enum><header>Condor national recreation trail</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD43C2C8CC2B94B959459D26F5710F3DA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>After completion of the study under subparagraph (E), the Secretary shall designate the Condor National Recreation Trail, extending from Lake Piru to the Botchers Gap Campground in the Monterey County corridor.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAACFC1598C24EDAAFA364106F4E18E1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Condor National Recreation Trail (referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>trail</quote>) shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with—</text> <clause id="H16F6978FB6A3480E926664E4CEDE896F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>other Federal, State, Tribal, regional, and local agencies;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4A9FD3775A6F43C2A23830F3AEB6B9F3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>private landowners; and</text> </clause><clause id="H687399477098441B90DB6C4BFC807411"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>other interested organizations.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0A91B2C650644FEB8E515896E64DEC1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Continual route</header><text>In building new connectors, and realigning existing trails, the Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="H2CFFC6F8087840ADB5943113091231F1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide for a continual route through the southern and northern Los Padres National Forest;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H863C0D98F4EB4E2883620C8B870CF634"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>promote recreational, scenic, wilderness and cultural values;</text> </clause><clause id="HC013551C79E04D9D9DD5AE565E2B9B54"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>enhance connectivity with the overall National Forest trail system;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H16B5FE5BC2A047D1A85EDAC8E1DE8346"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>emphasize safe and continuous public access, dispersal from high-use areas, and suitable water sources; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9C2AD7799D8B4D2D96BFA858B8F85B96"><enum>(v)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, provide all-year use.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F0951B7DEC24971B78026F15D823AA4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Private property rights</header> <clause id="HCA2DED2286064C8C8FB66BB1183078A7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No portions of the trail may be located on non-Federal land without the written consent of the landowner and without obtaining a permanent easement or right-of-way.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFED922B63AB84733A8EE849C90DC2735"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The Secretary shall not acquire for the trail any land or interest in land outside the exterior boundary of any federally managed area without the consent of the owner of land or interest in land.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA64AC945DAF042C7A56F6908BF75C2A8"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph—</text> <subclause id="H3C2CF869AE7B493EBDA8065DF04005D2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>requires any private property owner to allow public access (including Federal, State, or local government access) to private property; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC606702FD0824D0BB5D745C04A2288FC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>modifies any provision of Federal, State, or local law with respect to public access to or use of private land.</text>
								</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C11066778B44BF2AA50CC45471641E9"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Study</header>
 <clause id="H0307123F04A548118407C6BBC6ADD292"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Study required</header><text>Not later than 6 years after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary of Agriculture shall submit a study, including a detailed map, that describes the entire route addresses the feasibility of, and alternatives for, connecting the northern and southern portions of the Los Padres National Forest using a trail corridor across the applicable portions of the Northern and Southern Santa Lucia Mountains of the Southern California Coastal Range to—</text>
 <subclause id="H4D1ECC750DE24866A182FE330454797D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HFF7887B6F2D549F59D192D52A1E92F23"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H24F5BB4BC9374A21B12E7B8506363C91"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Additional requirement</header><text>In completing the study required by clause (i), the Secretary of Agriculture shall consult with—</text> <subclause id="H8698202DF87D46F1B73A40B202272598"><enum>(I)</enum><text>appropriate Federal, State, Tribal, regional, and local agencies;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4B36CFB3CF444BECBC7AE3F9D6A7F584"><enum>(II)</enum><text>private landowners;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HD4D95D41C2B64709B8E0BE22E3303D58"><enum>(III)</enum><text>nongovernmental organizations; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1D45CE52C2FE4D16865ADDB5B70CFA75"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>members of the public.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9EDA7F5EB61343B5B070A04D6C6BE92F" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HDE961ACADE714CBF8929C16210597988"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The map referred to in subparagraph (E)(i) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H65C687BBF9454E048939E7A76A6E44D7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>In carrying out this section (including the amendments made by this section), the Secretary of Agriculture may enter into cooperative agreements with State, Tribal, and local government entitles and private entities to complete needed trail construction, reconstruction, and realignment projects authorized by this section (including the amendments made by this section).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HC2125351CB9F4450803545E6D1BE3D0F"><enum>10.</enum><header>Forest service study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 6 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture (acting through the Chief of the Forest Service) shall study the feasibility of opening a new trail, for vehicles measuring 50 inches or less, connecting Forest Service Highway 95 to the existing off-highway vehicle trail system in the Ballinger Canyon off-highway vehicle area.</text>
 </section><section id="H6559618B20A846BF826B8813313DDB95"><enum>11.</enum><header>Nonmotorized recreation opportunities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 6 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with interested parties, shall conduct a study to improve nonmotorized recreation trail opportunities (including mountain bicycling) on land not designated as wilderness within the Santa Barbara, Ojai, and Mt. Pinos ranger districts.</text>
		</section><section id="HB6DC8C970DEA4C8F9C38F91D0C22C74D"><enum>12.</enum><header>Use by members of Tribes</header>
 <subsection id="H24B291EC97714742888844511A0F9AF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Access</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that Tribes have access, in accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.), to the wilderness areas, scenic areas, and potential wilderness areas designated by this Act for traditional cultural and religious purposes.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H895200B2DA564873B85FFEE3CAEE12DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Temporary closures</header>
 <paragraph id="H75B54B453A9E4C4D897C160DBB2D8A52"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary, on request of a Tribe, may temporarily close to the general public one or more specific portions of a wilderness area, scenic area, or potential wilderness area designated by this Act to protect the privacy of the members of the Tribe in the conduct of traditional cultural and religious activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H72ED46119C7148989CF5ED4FB3041A26"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Any closure under paragraph (1) shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="HF911412FF3DC425D9FC862945F9A3BEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>made in such a manner as to affect the smallest practicable area for the minimum period of time necessary for the activity to be carried out; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2603B953220846138B4EABDE7A5F49C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be consistent with the purpose and intent of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/341">Public Law 95–341</external-xref> (commonly known as the American Indian Religious Freedom Act) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996</external-xref>) and the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


