<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H80C9276E2A9E440FA188EA40ACF55E4C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1103 IH: Child Abuse Accountability Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1103</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170216">February 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H001056">Ms. Herrera Beutler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000578">Mr. Reichert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000184">Mrs. Noem</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for garnishment pursuant to a court order to
			 satisfy a judgment against a retired member of the uniformed services for
			 physically, sexually, or emotionally abusing a child.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H884CD98A25514C15A3E3E88752E68421" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4B095E98CB7A49CD886444AD65D0A16A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Child Abuse Accountability Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H14E07C3D0DA84AA1A3CDFE4D4716461F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Garnishment to satisfy judgment rendered for physically, sexually, or emotionally abusing a child</header> <subsection id="H14EB2A6CE60046638EC1D76CAE812AD9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Garnishment authority</header><text>Section 1408 of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H1A7788F33B3C4BF6A38D09FB5C871722" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H9B3FC86A7ADB4C1091D7979D485343BD"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Garnishment To satisfy a judgment rendered for physically, sexually, or emotionally abusing a child</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3BE535CD4BA24BB88BD7544DADD9DD8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any payment of retired pay that would otherwise be made to a member shall be paid (in whole or in part) by the Secretary concerned to another person if and to the extent expressly provided for in the terms of a child abuse garnishment order.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C00EDE3062342C1A9EFD0F2B37A9B0F" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In this section, the term <quote>court order</quote> includes a child abuse garnishment order.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F22B908CBAF4880954ABA1787569AF4" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>child abuse garnishment order</quote> means a final decree issued by a court that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H40895CE668D84CCFB60F8D5EDE080A35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is issued in accordance with the laws of the jurisdiction of that court; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BC98675A75F49B49100629AEC55C0ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides in the nature of garnishment for the enforcement of a judgment rendered against the member for physically, sexually, or emotionally abusing a child.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H736144A5AC9E49C49B23D8A59A53443B" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, a judgment rendered for physically, sexually, or emotionally abusing a child is any legal claim perfected through a final enforceable judgment, which claim is based in whole or in part upon the physical, sexual, or emotional abuse of an individual under 18 years of age, whether or not that abuse is accompanied by other actionable wrongdoing, such as sexual exploitation or gross negligence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H64565410F0344F658D377C1E8D75B9AB" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>If the Secretary concerned is served with more than one court order with respect to the retired pay of a member, the disposable retired pay of the member shall be available to satisfy such court orders on a first-come, first-served basis, with any such process being satisfied out of such moneys as remain after the satisfaction of all such processes which have been previously served.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H67F70835E5264516B18FF1AC5DF2701C" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary concerned shall not be required to vary normal pay and disbursement cycles for retired pay in order to comply with a child abuse garnishment order.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDAFA8D5280884906A110A8EE7E2BF4F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of amendment</header><text>Subsection (l) of section 1408 of title 10, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall apply with respect to a court order received by the Secretary concerned on or after the date of the enactment of this Act, regardless of the date of the court order.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


