<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3F6B9A76CD46491AB30442914F16A63C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4469 IH: To amend title 40, United States Code, to permit commercial filmmaking and photography on the United States Capitol grounds, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4469</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171128">November 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 40, United States Code, to permit commercial filmmaking and photography on the
			 United States Capitol grounds, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HEBB9D590524A436E9BE6AE6BF43FAA20" style="OLC">
		<section id="HD639067EEEA847AEBDA6443527C22D96" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Permitting commercial filmmaking and photography on United States Capitol Grounds</header>
 <subsection id="H50B6461D5330445DA96630D1A5823CFB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5106 of title 40, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4B3AEB979B64F4BB2AF3A5077D56E5A" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H7326019552624664A10BE7462B8FF3CE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Commercial Filmmaking and Photography</header>
 <paragraph id="H0DD04E09405E4370824D4980BEAB7545"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization by Capitol Police</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 5104(c) or any other provision of this chapter which restricts commercial activity on the United States Capitol Grounds, the Chief of the United States Capitol Police (hereafter in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Chief</quote>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4D39ED47CB3E432FA63B8EE41D426F58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may issue a permit authorizing a person to engage in appropriate commercial filmmaking and photography activity on the United States Capitol Grounds (other than any Capitol Buildings described in section 5101), so long as the person only engages in such activity on a day on which neither House of Congress is in session; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7564DFC1426C4F79941BB96825D1285D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under the terms and conditions of such a permit, may require the person to whom the permit is issued to pay an appropriate fee to cover any costs incurred by the Architect of the Capitol as a result of the issuance of the permit.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD75A9F932F674BE7B1571B3D287E368B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Types of activities and fees permitted</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="HDC19F33B40C447118D59368621ABD5BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commercial filmmaking and photography activity shall be considered appropriate only if the activity is similar to the types of commercial activity permitted in Union Square prior to the transfer of jurisdiction and control of Union Square to the Architect of the Capitol under section 1202 of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1811">2 U.S.C. 1811</external-xref> note); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95C856B7A4484BCCAE326310D0437F67"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a fee shall be considered appropriate only if the fee is similar to the fee collected by the Director of the National Park Service for commercial activity permitted in Union Square prior to such transfer of jurisdiction and control.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H460CF1FA8F5D48D4893DEFA378E9F6F5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of fees</header><text>Immediately upon receiving any fees collected under paragraph (1)(B), the Chief shall transfer the fees to the Capitol Trust Account established under section 213(c) of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/5102">40 U.S.C. 5102</external-xref> note).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F509228F07F489CB1116F55E09BE0B8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief shall carry out this subsection in accordance with such regulations as the Capitol Police Board may promulgate pursuant to the Board's authority under section 14 of the Act of July 31, 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1969">2 U.S.C. 1969</external-xref>), except that the Board shall promulgate the regulations in consultation with the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B28D07DCD794D608BA00948E713AD25"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Union Square defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>Union Square</term> means the area for which jurisdiction and control was transferred to the Architect of the Capitol under section 1202 of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1811">2 U.S.C. 1811</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H85607DEC15BF4CD08BA53834DD8563C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming Amendment Relating to Capitol Trust Account</header><text>Section 213(c) of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/5102">40 U.S.C. 5102</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>subsection (b)(2)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>subsection (b)(2) or section 5106(d) of title 40, United States Code</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


