<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1DDD8A72D5D345D5BD30174AB952136A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2165 IH: TSA Misconduct Accountability Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2165</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170426">April 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to direct the Administrator of the Transportation Security
			 Administration (TSA) to make certain improvements in managing TSA employee
			 conduct, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA16876FE7E6547E5B86AC98DE86B85D9" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8C40201729694442B6DB7A943C570B58" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>TSA Misconduct Accountability Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA77F005765904B7E9EECF4F3B2294804"><enum>2.</enum><header>TSA requirements for addressing employee misconduct</header> <subsection id="HB406C5247BD24DEA8E95526D7D0363D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/449">chapter 449</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4667EFEBBDAB49D4BEB2712A1E195377" style="USC">
					<section id="H7A4A3B3A5632416CAE67A4FEC9911F26"><enum>44947.</enum><header>Requirements for addressing employee misconduct</header>
 <subsection id="H2938AE2054FA4764B40D10769D85796F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB6646F39FAFC42229DD5BEB9A372DAAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>revise TSA’s employee code of conduct policy to include—</text> <subparagraph id="H2BD819E05D104793A82AE06A14B37843"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a process for disciplining an employee who, as determined by the Administrator, has received within a certain timeframe a certain number of disciplinary or adverse actions in response to violations of such policy; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF07D53BADCEF41119296B25191DECB8D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>guidance on how employees should report misconduct;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6BE44D14BE14A4AA942CCDAAD76A46F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify methods for addressing employee misconduct, including revising agency-wide, baseline <quote>table of offenses and penalties</quote> used for both non-disciplinary and disciplinary actions regarding misconduct, including all acceptable non-disciplinary, disciplinary, and adverse actions that may be administered for misconduct;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E7B8A061DB8420392475361B74BDD6D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>submit to the Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security such code of conduct policy and such table of offenses and penalties for review by such Officer in consideration of Department policies and regulations, in accordance with subsection (e); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BECE751310B402FBFE0001492FEF620"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify a senior TSA official responsible for overseeing TSA’s employee code of conduct policy and table of offenses and penalties.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H345B3E74C92B4F458E92CBE2D28695EA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator of the TSA shall instruct TSA managers how to appropriately administer discipline related to employee misconduct.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF848CB45E09247DCA33686DB01366FF3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Identification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator of the TSA shall identify and address causes of employee misconduct by—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0D8962FB9A154D4789AD5FA2F8951E6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>monitoring misconduct trends through a quarterly review and analysis of misconduct data; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A72679C6F9848BFBE067FDCD9DD3153"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishing specific outcome measures to assess performance.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF32802C099849B4AC81A4240FB89FA0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Initiatives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator of the TSA shall, in consultation with the Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security, implement human capital initiatives to address TSA employee misconduct by—</text>
 <paragraph id="H652105E997BB494B8B73B0C23F5B1FCF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modifying the annual or periodic performance plans of Federal Security Directors to include the extent to which such Directors ensure that disciplinary actions administered at the airport for which they are responsible are consistent with TSA policy;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFCF000E49B9A4DC9AFD8498E72E4F9E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>notifying applicants of disqualifying offenses in employment announcements for job descriptions or during the application process to ensure that appropriately qualified candidates apply and are hired for such positions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1AF99BDB680E43BA9E04BABEDFEF8628"><enum>(3)</enum><text>developing and delivering training and on-the-job resources for supervisors to address misconduct issues in accordance with TSA policy.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDADDB70B1BCA41DD8A11D21C5D48BE67"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Chief Human Capital Officer</header>
 <paragraph id="HF415383CCBF74DB7AEED9E219E6DFF6A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after receipt of the TSA employee code of conduct policy and the table of offenses and penalties under subsection (a), the Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security shall review such policy and such table to ensure that such policy and such table align, as appropriate, with the policies and tables developed by the Chief Human Capital Officer for the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3792EBA91774BC6AE41BEA11B15D330"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Monitoring</header><text>The Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security shall, as part of existing working groups established by such Officer, monitor through fiscal year 2020 the implementation under subsection (b) of the TSA employee code of conduct.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6FF3EB6E8D5B409DA334397AFCC7BB0D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HB6B7C4B5607B4FD5A508A51ABDD9633D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>actions</quote> means consequences for employee misconduct, up to and including removal from Federal service, established by TSA policy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H79BC3B1BC00F49388688074E83BC23BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Misconduct</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>misconduct</quote> means the failure of a TSA employee to comply with a performance plan, rule, regulation, or law within the scope of such employee’s duties, responsibilities, or functions.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF42C64CA94AD4DACBB17A71285F80399"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on new funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds are authorized to carry out this section and the amendment made by this section. This section and such amendment shall be carried out using amounts otherwise made available.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H49217C6AD8F54D549B2C54E26693DF27"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/449">chapter 449</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44946">section 44946</external-xref> the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8638039B6FB2408CB2D8021750A77FBE" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">44947. Requirements for addressing employee misconduct.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


