<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" dms-id="HCBBDD8C9200448C3921B9D5D5782424F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 1242 ENR: 400 Years of African-American History Commission Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>One Hundred Fifteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress> <session>At the First Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Tuesday, the third day of January, two thousand and seventeen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1242</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To establish the 400 Years of African-American History Commission, and for other purposes. </official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H9842CF49FC154034A88319AFE4ABAE35" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1FBE6A53EFEB4ADA84795B64B2A58806" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>400 Years of African-American History Commission Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HA09A6C97ABC34EAF9B863D97FC3CCA65"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE2A4FEE5DCE24BEDAB46DF24FF168070"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commemoration</header><text>The term <term>commemoration</term> means the commemoration of the 400th anniversary of the arrival of Africans in the English colonies, at Point Comfort, Virginia, in 1619.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H14FD9B66FF5D464B98B699499255C23B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the 400 Years of African-American History Commission established by section 3(a).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAAA16040B8B040D98AACF40B65F51724"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph></section> <section id="H7CBC8D3E4EB44FFF9DD6BED7A654EB22"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment</header> <subsection id="H09EA2AB34E4F400C9A40B986B0307773"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established a commission, to be known as the <quote>400 Years of African-American History Commission</quote>.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H964ED5DFA04C4473B3955C9631277671"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header> 
<paragraph id="HFA2C4AFCAA7641C495719CFA8F0EF6BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Commission shall be composed of 15 members, of whom—</text> <subparagraph id="HFBB72FD2C5EA4A27827515BEF7B47CB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>three members shall be appointed by the Secretary after considering recommendations of Governors, including the Governor of Virginia;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5E20773D45F54100B8ED2BBF06E72B9C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>six members shall be appointed by the Secretary after considering recommendations of civil rights organizations and historical organizations;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C6D04A2C1074A66985760125255AF50"><enum>(C)</enum><text>one member shall be an employee of the National Park Service having experience relative to the historical and cultural resources related to the commemoration, to be appointed by the Secretary;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAD2A3C7622C0444F84F6ABAF611C1DA3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>two members shall be appointed by the Secretary after considering the recommendations of the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H56FB161A4CCA4BF5A779DF58EF6CC641"><enum>(E)</enum><text>three members shall be individuals who have an interest in, support for, and expertise appropriate to the commemoration, appointed by the Secretary after considering the recommendations of Members of Congress.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0089625E674E4CA59BF7870E8C77E38B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Time of appointment</header><text>Each appointment of an initial member of the Commission shall be made before the expiration of the 120-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C50270E4684480F841FFC0CFD2ECAC9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Term; vacancies</header> <subparagraph id="H8C573899E900483C82AA4C796F183D28"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Term</header><text>A member of the Commission shall be appointed for the life of the Commission.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H49C2AE404C474A4A8F83CD95D9ADFBAA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Vacancies</header> 
<clause id="H9F33E083D65A4AC1976D3A15E521C982"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A vacancy on the Commission shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.</text> </clause> <clause id="H1C34D9F773AD4698833EE754E7158A9D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Partial term</header><text>A member appointed to fill a vacancy on the Commission shall serve for the remainder of the term for which the predecessor of the member was appointed.</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDAF65500A5F6405D99C0AA1C7D22EDF3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Continuation of membership</header><text>If a member of the Commission was appointed to the Commission as an employee of the National Park Service, and ceases to be an employee of the National Park Service, that member may continue to serve on the Commission for not longer than the 30-day period beginning on the date on which that member ceases to be an employee of the National Park Service.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBEEBE7B0A2454C45B47C52EE4BBC875C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Commission shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H07283DA864244DCE9D89A48D1FCB8A5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>plan, develop, and carry out programs and activities throughout the United States—</text> <subparagraph id="H8911ACDE21A1498C85BF0E18FBB89D07"><enum>(A)</enum><text>appropriate for the commemoration;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H38A7CD4617AB4C5999BD87DC587FCC6F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to recognize and highlight the resilience and contributions of African-Americans since 1619;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H01FCECF193EF4700BD95CE308C605C3B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to acknowledge the impact that slavery and laws that enforced racial discrimination had on the United States; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF5C7D069F39C41558C990E2922A177D1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to educate the public about—</text> <clause id="H70853EF634BD4BF18B06802F9477BAD4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the arrival of Africans in the United States; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H3D92AC48062D4CAFBDC856F39A9C9DE9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the contributions of African-Americans to the United States;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D1792F3E3EE4F16857E4EDB3C99E32F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourage civic, patriotic, historical, educational, artistic, religious, economic, and other organizations throughout the United States to organize and participate in anniversary activities to expand understanding and appreciation of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDFB9F721E49B452D97633AF13B10F7FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the significance of the arrival of Africans in the United States; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDBB1D3D7DC6F4F6292160142A0779E54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the contributions of African-Americans to the United States;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF5528B51921149CAA7BEC57ACC720D75"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to States, localities, and nonprofit organizations to further the commemoration;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H57E80E7CE82648ACA70CA70CA6870889"><enum>(4)</enum><text>coordinate and facilitate for the public scholarly research on, publication about, and interpretation of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9C1FB59597194E649BCDDDD13BFE068C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the arrival of Africans in the United States; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEFB35104CD1A400583D9EA6D6AE18535"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the contributions of African-Americans to the United States;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1A0C925901424B9BB2581B579314DE9F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>ensure that the commemoration provides a lasting legacy and long-term public benefit by assisting in the development of appropriate programs; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HA481F118A6984173BE38113A5B47ACD1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>help ensure that the observances of the commemoration are inclusive and appropriately recognize the experiences and heritage of all individuals present at the arrival of Africans in the United States.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H2BE9D99493454AF1A74DF82ACD2B2CE8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Commission meetings</header> 
<subsection id="HBADB2E26694B4B2C832FA3C1F8A36BE1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which all members of the Commission have been appointed, the Commission shall hold the initial meeting of the Commission.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H761C40B3AEE44C3388D77BBBB36704ED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Commission shall meet—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBC3D059D23D744DA9D8511D335A48BDA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at least three times each year; or</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H99B4824F52F34F659D067FFB36C7E286"><enum>(2)</enum><text>at the call of the Chairperson or the majority of the members of the Commission.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB393B655F32A4F3BA342DA7075664077"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the voting members shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number may hold meetings.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HF89CA5DFDFE349809E6F4F818CF15C8B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Chairperson and vice chairperson</header> <paragraph id="H7015452A5A84416E845B158A3715F5B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Election</header><text>The Commission shall elect the Chairperson and the Vice Chairperson of the Commission on an annual basis.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE88C01BB5595476A864CC06265B88C8A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Absence of the chairperson</header><text>The Vice Chairperson shall serve as the Chairperson in the absence of the Chairperson.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC14324A64FF846DEA5F354F02406FEAF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Voting</header><text>The Commission shall act only on an affirmative vote of a majority of the members of the Commission.</text> </subsection></section> 
<section id="HF0B109A557444E6C989F6215136028B2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Commission powers</header> 
<subsection id="H326CD1A25A6A4530A3CD8C5983184268"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Gifts</header><text>The Commission may solicit, accept, use, and dispose of gifts, bequests, or devises of money or other property for aiding or facilitating the work of the Commission.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H4C8BE6089AA144A7B814768DB5AAF416"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointment of advisory committees</header><text>The Commission may appoint such advisory committees as the Commission determines to be necessary to carry out this Act.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD2BAAFAECC4147BBAE38439EDCD0229A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of action</header><text>The Commission may authorize any member or employee of the Commission to take any action that the Commission is authorized to take under this Act.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H99E2105BD9AF4F3CAAAFA26DCE42943A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Procurement</header> <paragraph id="HDC86E347B1BD46458113E62F484316B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission may procure supplies, services, and property, and make or enter into contracts, leases, or other legal agreements, to carry out this Act (except that a contract, lease, or other legal agreement made or entered into by the Commission shall not extend beyond the date of termination of the Commission).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE584E77A8CD74911B705F2D95B0C537A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Commission may not purchase real property.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD53BDF3CA6A44838B1648534BCA50346"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Postal services</header><text>The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other agencies of the Federal Government.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC38871A4B6E04A5984A511BCDC812C34"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Grants and technical assistance</header><text>The Commission may—</text> <paragraph id="H8C82F69DCB5C4036AA5AB9A82E9470E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide grants in amounts not to exceed $20,000 per grant to communities and nonprofit organizations for use in developing programs to assist in the commemoration;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7ABEF34E6A514C4A9527B3F5ECD75574"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide grants to research and scholarly organizations to research, publish, or distribute information relating to the arrival of Africans in the United States; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0C2B29A302049DAA6DA8BF42FE76966"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to States, localities, and nonprofit organizations to further the commemoration.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6565CAD760C84FC98DACF3AEE3BFC643"><enum>6.</enum><header>Commission personnel matters</header> 
<subsection id="H3F773A41F05F4B4F944412345D7745BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Compensation of members</header> 
<paragraph id="H54ED0B7BDA814FE28A8376322CE4238B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), a member of the Commission shall serve without compensation.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8FC05D97E9446FE85D7A9DC5D00EC62"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal employees</header><text>A member of the Commission who is an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall serve without compensation other than the compensation received for the services of the member as an officer or employee of the Federal Government.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H06C9034E6CA6411AAE012D99F26E8E6C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>A member of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for an employee of an agency under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from the home or regular place of business of the member in the performance of the duties of the Commission.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H63B45BC3A1B74DBEA727043015A10DAF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Director and staff</header> <paragraph id="HF57D1A6941A344A588C235774B530D17"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Chairperson of the Commission may, without regard to the civil service laws (including regulations), nominate an executive director to enable the Commission to perform the duties of the Commission.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H998C3812BEC3427FB798DB7DE9254EFC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Confirmation of executive director</header><text>The employment of an executive director shall be subject to confirmation by the Commission.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H134A44EC61154A1782902E6F60CFB505"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Compensation</header> <paragraph id="H031F07BE68934554857AED185B496E40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Commission may fix the compensation of the executive director and other personnel without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0A9F2E0A9FAD4A4CAC1AB708F9AE734E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum rate of pay</header><text>The rate of pay for the executive director and other personnel shall not exceed the rate payable for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of title 5, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H749BBC8C1556464281F4425839C343F9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Detail of government employees</header> <paragraph id="H0186210BC4B34A039419D34D65151448"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal employees</header> <subparagraph id="H85A6BAECA58F43F2B4602A46776057B8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Detail</header><text>At the request of the Commission, the head of any Federal agency may detail, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, any of the personnel of the agency to the Commission to assist the Commission in carrying out the duties of the Commission under this Act.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBAED639368EC4319BE9ECC45D979DC6A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Civil service status</header><text>The detail of an employee under subparagraph (A) shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E1B342B214B4C69AE4B14B6277AEC99"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State employees</header><text>The Commission may—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H68D709365BDB4E76B3476F899550F775"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accept the services of personnel detailed from the State; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD6EA1291E57C4BDCACAE5438C0EDC10A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reimburse the State for services of detailed personnel.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCAD3A36242504E9087BC4F5B423BD330"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Procurement of temporary and intermittent services</header><text>The Chairperson of the Commission may procure temporary and intermittent services in accordance with section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code, at rates for individuals that do not exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of such title.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HE53A59D01455402A8F1D82851A0335F7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Volunteer and uncompensated services</header><text>Notwithstanding section 1342 of title 31, United States Code, the Commission may accept and use such voluntary and uncompensated services as the Commission determines to be necessary.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HB98A18B862754E6C8E122C53136C086C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Support services</header> 
<paragraph id="HD6BCB59D090045C4B5779526D2B12731"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall provide to the Commission, on a reimbursable basis, such administrative support services as the Commission may request.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H00CDB7B59E7F43B6B4A451351195BDE6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header><text>Any reimbursement under this paragraph shall be credited to the appropriation, fund, or account used for paying the amounts reimbursed.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3AAB85DDF8E84E62BCB477C5A0C77B9F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>No effect on authority</header><text>Nothing in this section supersedes the authority of the National Park Service with respect to the commemoration.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H2EA78607205A4DC099C4FE8595D25C84"><enum>7.</enum><header>Plans; reports</header> <subsection id="HC3D51FDFF69C4EF6A209E6766E9EF0E6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategic plan</header><text>The Commission shall prepare a strategic plan for the activities of the Commission carried out under this Act.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H5579B7D5D9FB4D12918D986E3BF1006B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than July 1, 2020, the Commission shall complete and submit to Congress a final report that contains—</text> <paragraph id="HEC6D23F237ED4857AB5F623E545943EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of the activities of the Commission;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCF40257743D7404586EC3619A036ECC5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a final accounting of funds received and expended by the Commission; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H65CEE4A09FCD4A2198D4AE7DDE42BF43"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the findings and recommendations of the Commission.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6BC09E6138A14EC0BD5B6C7CA9A1D7F1"><enum>8.</enum><header>Termination of Commission</header> 
<subsection id="H81781A12BB764AEFB65C8A972F16B7E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Date of termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall terminate on July 1, 2020.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H76123FD324FF41B69FC9F14CD7E73F7D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer of documents and materials</header><text>Before the date of termination specified in subsection (a), the Commission shall transfer all documents and materials of the Commission to the National Archives or another appropriate Federal entity.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H0EE73C90B41C4A75A071D614CC9AAAA2"><enum>9.</enum><header>Expenditures of Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">All expenditures of the Commission shall be made solely from donated funds.</text> </section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

