<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4F9C4B053CEB4DCA8D5973321FDE2329" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 143 IH: Health Insurance Industry Antitrust Enforcement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 143</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170103">January 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit anticompetitive activities and to provide that health insurance issuers and medical
			 malpractice insurance issuers are subject to the antitrust laws of the
			 United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HBA935930523C498C805202F6E836A416" style="OLC">
 <section id="H332D2C087F3C416A90A3408BECACB79A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Insurance Industry Antitrust Enforcement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB0FF6B0FDC0E45D39FAB160054CEB791"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition of anticompetitive activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, nothing in the Act of March 9, 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1011">15 U.S.C. 1011 et seq.</external-xref>, commonly known as the <quote>McCarran-Ferguson Act</quote>), shall be construed to permit health insurance issuers (as defined in section 2791 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91</external-xref>)) or issuers of medical malpractice insurance to engage in any form of price fixing, bid rigging, or market allocations in connection with the conduct of the business of providing health insurance coverage (as defined in such section) or coverage for medical malpractice claims or actions.</text>
		</section><section id="H05738848FB114F6188BBE92B4CA551BC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Restoring the application of antitrust laws to health sector insurers</header>
 <subsection id="H6D4D317FBAA74F0D9CE022D3A9C8FB61"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment to McCarran-Ferguson Act</header><text>Section 3 of the Act of March 9, 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1013">15 U.S.C. 1013</external-xref>), commonly known as the McCarran-Ferguson Act, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HF62266723B3248648519A3C7B3AA415A" style="OLC">
 <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58CFEAD689BD4E8E9156FBEC7A0873A9"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing contained in this Act shall modify, impair, or supersede the operation of any of the antitrust laws with respect to the business of health insurance. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term <quote>antitrust laws</quote> has the meaning given it in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act, except that such term includes section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act to the extent that such section 5 applies to unfair methods of competition.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0C1EE1B8464F44DA8C5E2D2E1EC913F0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Related Provision</header><text>For purposes of section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>) to the extent such section applies to unfair methods of competition, section 3(c) of the McCarran-Ferguson Act shall apply with respect to the business of health insurance without regard to whether such business is carried on for profit, notwithstanding the definition of <quote>Corporation</quote> contained in section 4 of the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


