<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE258D7C7697F4A3E897C12D663AFA85E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4631 IH: Access to Congressionally Mandated Reports Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4631</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171212">December 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001290">Mr. Brat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Director of the Government Publishing Office to establish and maintain a website
			 accessible to the public that allows the public to obtain electronic
			 copies of all congressionally mandated reports in one place, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HDBC2E78470434C6AA561DF5F63E66B04" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF0E409EB51794964AD56252EB2678E73" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Access to Congressionally Mandated Reports Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6152227E8D874CC1A87C3B4A29A7968F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H85EE847416CB4917AA7184AD714CBB04"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Congressionally mandated report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>congressionally mandated report</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H775AE37892874A0CA838106354E9C627"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a report that is required to be submitted to either House of Congress or any committee of Congress, or subcommittee thereof, by a statute, resolution, or conference report that accompanies legislation enacted into law; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3AB1D8D612B419EBB95944A7607E7F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a report required under part B of subtitle II of title 36, United States Code.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H592C7F0F364546BAB55781CC16A253AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Government Publishing Office.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E745E50708343EE8677F8C8498AF4EA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal agency</term> has the meaning given that term under section 102 of title 40, United States Code, but does not include the Government Accountability Office.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H76D3089F21E24CC9BD0C3CA436B2411B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Open format</header><text>The term <term>open format</term> means a file format for storing digital data based on an underlying open standard that—</text> <subparagraph id="H65A404129E3D4964BB0D48D218EDEA31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not encumbered by any restrictions that would impede reuse; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62FF5A3C33AA424F9D1DE62C0E549578"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is based on an underlying open data standard that is maintained by a standards organization.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59B648C840CD443493EBF4B48F67463C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reports website</header><text>The term <term>reports website</term> means the website established under section (3)(a).</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H3362B1AB2A4446E6AFB4429165AA65BF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of website for congressionally mandated reports</header>
			<subsection id="H41DFEE435AE748CDA1502B2CB00B6427"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement To establish website</header>
 <paragraph id="H02317FB63D5941BA91D21DDF7DE1B97D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall establish and maintain a website accessible by the public that allows the public to obtain electronic copies of all congressionally mandated reports in one place. The Director may publish other reports on the website.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB80523083D5747F49894D8A9958A2372"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Existing functionality</header><text>To the extent possible, the Director shall meet the requirements under paragraph (1) by using existing websites and functionality under the authority of the Director.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F9EC30085154BA4A3D664D272696EB5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out this Act, the Director shall consult with the Clerk of the House of Representatives, the Secretary of the Senate, and the Librarian of Congress regarding the requirements for and maintenance of congressionally mandated reports on the reports website.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63F97CE06FA6474AAF1E8EE74009F5FD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content and function</header><text>The Director shall ensure that the reports website includes the following:</text> <paragraph id="H877F8C375C6B4DDB800ABF1C1D529262"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subject to subsection (c), with respect to each congressionally mandated report, each of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0DD10D94FDED49F0BB6ABE01236BAAE5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A citation to the statute, conference report, or resolution requiring the report.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01E86E511C6E405CAC9E84D9F761DA31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An electronic copy of the report, including any transmittal letter associated with the report, in an open format that is platform independent and that is available to the public without restrictions, including restrictions that would impede the re-use of the information in the report.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AF886F305904170973999589057D277"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The ability to retrieve a report, to the extent practicable, through searches based on each, and any combination, of the following:</text>
 <clause id="H623286813B8642759420652AAAC286D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The title of the report.</text> </clause><clause id="HCE4E25CB640749DD80354C86DFFB7A8F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The reporting Federal agency.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H215B454F6C2848B0A89224B4EF6B8409"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The date of publication.</text> </clause><clause id="H49C2817338A74A5FADD3D2E9D96EF7C6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Each congressional committee receiving the report, if applicable.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2BE78467945941ADA92608CD502C96C9"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The statute, resolution, or conference report requiring the report.</text> </clause><clause id="HED46B3ED00204ED4ACD4D17B948D77F3"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Subject tags.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0769D5F9B7074DA0A4926E5EA9000D2B"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>A unique alphanumeric identifier for the report that is consistent across report editions.</text> </clause><clause id="H1C84B450D9B6410CB04D5B8854138BC2"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The serial number, Superintendent of Documents number, or other identification number for the report, if applicable.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HCADDEB634F074C588EDAFD548F57D27D"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Key words.</text> </clause><clause id="H32E265BE02094AA39D0D3F70240BC23D"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Full text search.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAC3CC9B48DD446F096CADBFE858CA64E"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>Any other relevant information specified by the Director.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC9A6AF8E94F4EA9AB03B676E7F0DA86"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The date on which the report was required to be submitted, and on which the report was submitted, to the reports website.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EF6F9C9B9F348DBAD832C797AF6486D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Access to the report not later than 30 calendar days after its submission to Congress.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB35A02DEC0CD451DAC581DA6F2BD3A7E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>To the extent practicable, a permanent means of accessing the report electronically.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H708A8661C5494027848F83F6C73895BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A means for bulk download of all congressionally mandated reports.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H743C3FFFD24D43BBB912FE1DC417C478"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A means for downloading individual reports as the result of a search.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H78C6FD1468BE435BB3E88F1700B69707"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An electronic means for the head of each Federal agency to submit to the reports website each congressionally mandated report of the agency, as required by section 4.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9E1A3B4A44E84DC59BFC03762CD84041"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In tabular form, a list of all congressionally mandated reports that can be searched, sorted, and down­loaded by—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H75D9355DA00B475A9D335ECC2C8A1A13"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reports submitted within the required time;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H08BE9739B4904E92BCD8D85909F08160"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reports submitted after the date on which such reports were required to be submitted; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB3C87048F5574087B98D3538CE42A9FC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reports not submitted.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H224029FD093C4F82B9E240FB69C2DBA4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Noncompliance by Federal agencies</header> <paragraph id="H202CE6AC230249C3AA58227418BAFFE5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports not submitted</header><text>If a Federal agency does not submit a congressionally mandated report to the Director, the Director shall to the extent practicable—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5F8FE913AA434761AD640421FC2D3C19"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include on the reports website—</text> <clause id="HF6AA6D86713746839FA8FE9544A36048"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the information required under clauses (i), (ii), (iv), and (v) of subsection (b)(1)(C); and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA5BA046FB4B149B6AFC9DDE90F07ECB1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the report was required to be submitted; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25E0BB49135544198859DBB7B66FBD26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include the congressionally mandated report on the list described in subsection (b)(5)(C).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CBC452F646A4C9991E4B6DE632BC328"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports not in open format</header><text>If a Federal agency submits a congressionally mandated report that is not in an open format, the Director shall include the congressionally mandated report in another format on the reports website.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDCCAA17A1CFB40F88EBA848643A48BEC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Free access</header><text>The Director may not charge a fee, require registration, or impose any other limitation in exchange for access to the reports website.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H324AD97E4A7F4DDBA452DA03EE4628C7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Upgrade capability</header><text>The reports website shall be enhanced and updated as necessary to carry out the purposes of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HC788A763E10842618F97562605CF8886"><enum>4.</enum><header>Federal agency responsibilities</header>
 <subsection id="H15A53F3F529846B39A8ACC12F0CC7465"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Submission of electronic copies of reports</header><text>Concurrently with the submission to Congress of each congressionally mandated report, the head of the Federal agency submitting the congressionally mandated report shall submit to the Director the information required under subparagraphs (A) through (D) of section 3(b)(1) with respect to the congressionally mandated report. Nothing in this Act shall relieve a Federal agency of any other requirement to publish the congressionally mandated report on the website of the Federal agency or otherwise submit the congressionally mandated report to Congress or specific committees of Congress, or subcommittees thereof.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1297E990211E466CA6C50D255C209849"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 240 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Director, shall issue guidance to agencies on the implementation of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBA927D21DC5F40749AE6DB8964075A92"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Structure of submitted report data</header><text>The head of each Federal agency shall ensure that each congressionally mandated report submitted to the Director complies with the open format criteria established by the Director in the guidance issued under subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1C68D62CFE7847D09C952A5D51A575CA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Point of contact</header><text>The head of each Federal agency shall designate a point of contact for congressionally mandated report.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA36F393A20994F0699E5D3D5DBC28E64"><enum>(e)</enum><header>List of reports</header><text>As soon as practicable each calendar year (but not later than April 1), and on a rolling basis during the year if feasible, the Librarian of Congress shall submit to the Director a list of congressionally mandated reports from the previous calendar year, in consultation with the Clerk of the House of Representatives, which shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H50019E79F0FD4B9AA85B6F0F477DF8D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be provided in an open format;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A01634C38A54AF0A904555FA084A4E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include the information required under clauses (i), (ii), (iv), (v) of section 3(b)(1)(C) for each report;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB6FD7B1E54264C3087196C05D16AF305"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include the frequency of the report;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD35D513C7AC34EC19EBB2B7ACB1FA959"><enum>(4)</enum><text>include a unique alphanumeric identifier for the report that is consistent across report editions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADD2183FCAF443CB9033E3A94202B8D9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>include the date on which each report is required to be submitted; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H83BDC2E8F2854BD7BE5CEA720D58752E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>be updated and provided to the Director, as necessary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F8C32CB55284CAD8C4885B8FB437B28" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Removing and altering reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A report submitted to be published to the reports website may only be changed or removed, with the exception of technical changes, by the head of the Federal agency concerned if—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3819F186F8CE4DF88F6AA27B242A38AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the head of the Federal agency consults with each congressional committee to which the report is submitted; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6121113B77184952BB29D95091B58D18"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress enacts a joint resolution authorizing the changing or removal of the report.</text> </paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="H351E69F2D0D44F90AD0B46AD44CD57BD"><enum>6.</enum><header>Relationship to the Freedom of Information Act</header> <subsection id="HEABC904641FF48CDA96932EDCD55A76A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to require the disclosure of information or records that are exempt from public disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code, or to impose any affirmative duty on the Director to review congressionally mandated reports submitted for publication to the reports website for the purpose of identifying and redacting such information or records.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBDE032917B7A45D3A704708784613CC7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Redaction of report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each congressionally mandated report, the head of each relevant Federal agency shall redact any information that may not be publicly released under section 552(b) of title 5, United States Code, before submission for publication on the reports website, and shall—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H6BEAE85263474F478E198FC6DE108CB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">redact only such information from the report;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H40A0FCCE3B59499BB562F3F60B26C8C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify where any such redaction is made in the report; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0B9DA72092D24D7B9D2ACC49D19D5FB5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify the exemption under which each such redaction is made.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H591E938297EA41FF90B27BD6F4B96E57"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Withholding information</header> <paragraph id="HE338CB0436134358A7BB60D50B4CB306"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A Federal agency—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEC6817978DCE44FC9B5C717440EC67E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may withhold information otherwise required to be disclosed under this Act only if—</text> <clause id="H2ACC79AE13304DCF974900178955464C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal agency reasonably foresees that disclosure would harm an interest protected by an exemption described in section 552(b) of title 5, United States Code; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9C6666C8F5454066AF0EC926A4437B02"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>disclosure is prohibited by law; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE405B43F6734ABB9FC99000D0483B67"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall—</text>
 <clause id="H98A3A006C2274AC5B964574669E63BC0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consider whether partial disclosure of information otherwise required to be disclosed under this Act is possible whenever the Federal agency determines that a full disclosure of the information is not possible; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H524E4EC08054403E93A8B33AB6657FEF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>take reasonable steps necessary to segregate and release nonexempt information.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H367574B48D1C4015A5E41EDB14EB6A19"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection requires disclosure of information that is otherwise prohibited from disclosure by law, or otherwise exempted from disclosure under section 552(b)(3) of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H365EFFA3D4FD4F1C941E9718308643E6"><enum>7.</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as provided in section 4(c), this Act shall be implemented not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act and shall apply with respect to congressionally mandated reports submitted to Congress on or after the date that is 1 year after such date of enactment.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


