<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFBCDCBF063AF47758BF806C482B6F234" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2437 IH: Back the Blue Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2437</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170516">May 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000577">Mr. Graves of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect law enforcement officers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF5AD172EFFC54A52993AF44709686DBD" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5C96869DAA3F403781103ABE14ED4091" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Back the Blue Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE3190B04ACEC4CBC86A34382572584D5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Protection of law enforcement officers</header> <subsection id="H9016274750A84AEC964E8D5621EEB666"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Killing of law enforcement officers</header> <paragraph id="HFFC76C495EAC41F6A627F58281BDD24A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Offense</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/51">Chapter 51</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3450B93959CA4D999DBB8A63E53B1B76" style="USC">
						<section id="H2F8B1A3859AA4059973A222D5D6AEEED"><enum>1123.</enum><header>Killing of law enforcement officers</header>
 <subsection id="H8955EC2941394C2C98EB507F80F0FEEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="HCF95EF3B74F24F60ADC8EB407550EAD5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the terms <term>Federal law enforcement officer</term> and <term>United States judge</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 115;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7D30508042143A0B74C88565B4EE9F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>federally funded public safety officer</term> means a public safety officer or judicial officer for a public agency that—</text> <subparagraph id="H72A210E645504255B103DF16E52E8312"><enum>(A)</enum><text>receives Federal financial assistance; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C34BF624C2442EFBD81C3CB12A228B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is an agency of an entity that is a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or any territory or possession of the United States, an Indian tribe, or a unit of local government of that entity;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H57204CA1CCDA454FB532A7BCCD7E0801"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>firefighter</term> includes an individual serving as an official recognized or designated member of a legally organized volunteer fire department and an officially recognized or designated public employee member of a rescue squad or ambulance crew;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B82ACF64D4B4000AA1F410369DC1D4F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>judicial officer</term> means a judge or other officer or employee of a court, including prosecutors, court security, pretrial services officers, court reporters, and corrections, probation, and parole officers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC85AB035A98A42FE9B1C38C1A40FAD7B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>law enforcement officer</term> means an individual, with arrest powers, involved in crime or juvenile delinquency control or reduction or enforcement of the laws;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFCEDBE90E07443F482A0D72579320FB5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>public agency</term> includes a court system, the National Guard of a State to the extent the personnel of that National Guard are not in Federal service, and the defense forces of a State authorized by section 109 of title 32; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B8E3174EF75474A92FDF75AEB1502BD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>public safety officer</term> means an individual serving a public agency in an official capacity, as a law enforcement officer, as a firefighter, as a chaplain, or as a member of a rescue squad or ambulance crew.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65C2926BAF8142288600A835971CC464"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Offense</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any person to—</text> <paragraph id="H41148AE2E8454866BE13586F1C6911FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>kill, or attempt or conspire to kill—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H50F5358A8E1D4C1ABA2AB0BCC10FA4A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States judge;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EB7A14481084AB0A5FF371AB19BB4F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a Federal law enforcement officer; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B79DEF36AEA4F74ABF7C5D99C89E50A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a federally funded public safety officer while that officer is engaged in official duties, or on account of the performance of official duties; or</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC18A240EC6124AB8A5570B7B1C62FC52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>kill a former United States judge, Federal law enforcement officer, or federally funded public safety officer on account of the past performance of official duties.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5B48B6227B064BD2A5B4661F355503F6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Any person that violates subsection (b) shall be fined under this title and imprisoned for not less than 10 years or for life, or, if death results, shall be sentenced to not less than 30 years and not more than life, or may be punished by death.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33463D53630A49428BF1ADF5DAF06520"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HB64974E7778647D3A5FCF0A7D232F5F7" style="USC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry idref="H2F8B1A3859AA4059973A222D5D6AEEED" level="section">1123. Killing of law enforcement officers.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H695F63BE0FC144E88EA3BFD324EED6D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assault of law enforcement officers</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HBE28E0DB8583401497F094F2C7549424"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Offense</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/7">Chapter 7</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H718582DFBB4543ABA0B3FCAC6C798F9A" style="USC"> <section id="H405762D306FB4815A3DF54B80C5B6E2B"><enum>120.</enum><header>Assaults of law enforcement officers</header> <subsection id="HAEBCB2219C9B4E30B08EA9811D9990F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>federally funded State or local law enforcement officer</term> means an individual involved in crime and juvenile delinquency control or reduction, or enforcement of the laws (including a police, corrections, probation, or parole officer) who works for a public agency (that receives Federal financial assistance) of a State of the United States or the District of Columbia.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7375C93743E645E8BBC7E0804937DE8B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Offense</header><text>It shall be unlawful to assault a federally funded State or local law enforcement officer while engaged in or on account of the performance of official duties, or assaults any person who formerly served as a federally funded State or local law enforcement officer on account of the performance of such person's official duties during such service, or because of the actual or perceived status of the person as a federally funded State or local law enforcement officer.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2AD1D4ED62214F9D966CC25A6A62862C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Any person that violates subsection (b) shall be subject to a fine under this title and—</text> <paragraph id="H4E1A69C2399D41828E0DBF5C50669378"><enum>(1)</enum><text>if the assault resulted in bodily injury (as defined in section 1365), shall be imprisoned not less than 2 years and not more than 10 years;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE25BF3B9E1D9473289ECE9454E460A8A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the assault resulted in substantial bodily injury (as defined in section 113), shall be imprisoned not less than 5 years and not more than 20 years;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9645A328F6F4CE8B5C62F064690E996"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if the assault resulted in serious bodily injury (as defined in section 1365), shall be imprisoned for not less than 10 years;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAAE93A2EDE974AB1997B7046B68C3B79"><enum>(4)</enum><text>if a deadly or dangerous weapon was used during and in relation to the assault, shall be imprisoned for not less than 20 years; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H28E46A7609F746F69B388417005F59B2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>shall be imprisoned for not more than 1 year in any other case.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD793DE80BCBC42B1958FB767697200DE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Certification requirement</header> <paragraph id="H5E2E0FD4A482409383092BBF308C9D89"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No prosecution of any offense described in this section may be undertaken by the United States, except under the certification in writing of the Attorney General, or a designee, that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H315C1BB11CA04FB7841425E0849DE8F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the State does not have jurisdiction;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33BAE28D2FF34CCCBBCF27E130705796"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the State has requested that the Federal Government assume jurisdiction;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC7C97F454AC4F83AD721E97E6DA32DD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the verdict or sentence obtained pursuant to State charges left demonstratively unvindicated the Federal interest in eradicating bias-motivated violence; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC55C569A9304B15B6EFE80B8823DB4F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a prosecution by the United States is in the public interest and necessary to secure substantial justice.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCFF31CE74074A63B2F8FB6E0647F22F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit the authority of Federal officers, or a Federal grand jury, to investigate possible violations of this section.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3636EBF23562448D82609B9BFB06D3BC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Statute of limitations</header>
 <paragraph id="H8683683431D64E7EB89931E7A5D3E3D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Offenses not resulting in death</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), no person shall be prosecuted, tried, or punished for any offense under this section unless the indictment for such offense is found, or the information for such offense is instituted, not later than 7 years after the date on which the offense was committed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB738710535E3493491788A2F8CE70493"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Offenses resulting in death</header><text>An indictment or information alleging that an offense under this section resulted in death may be found or instituted at any time without limitation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H72B79F616640408CBAA135070F5875DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H98FE08B1DCA24201B0F9EECC5E0384CD" style="USC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry idref="H2F8B1A3859AA4059973A222D5D6AEEED" level="section">120. Killing of law enforcement officers.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEBAB92FA9B004E64BCC2C635F2CA15A7"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Flight To avoid prosecution for killing law enforcement officials</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0676478EAAC448C0871A627DC688FA06"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Offense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/49">Chapter 49</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83FA215C48144031B2A29ACA556164F4" style="USC"> <section id="H4BC426ED526440C582D7A678281DB1B4"><enum>1075.</enum><header>Flight to avoid prosecution for killing law enforcement officials</header> <subsection id="HF3E7609211D74E9981C5F3C7A2C08465"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Offense</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any person to move or travel in interstate or foreign commerce with intent to avoid prosecution, or custody or confinement after conviction, under the laws of the place from which the person flees or under section 1114 or 1123, for a crime consisting of the killing, an attempted killing, or a conspiracy to kill a Federal judge or Federal law enforcement officer (as those terms are defined in section 115), or a federally funded public safety officer (as that term is defined in section 1123).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H365A20B120FB4303B5CF1DADC3DCF071"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Any person that violates subsection (a) shall be fined under this title and imprisoned for not less than 10 years, in addition to any other term of imprisonment for any other offense relating to the conduct described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E53A8983A1844B68BE2696353EC4BFA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/49">chapter 49</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H7EF8A1AABFCB44E69BA8F6E6F8961B85" style="USC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry idref="H4BC426ED526440C582D7A678281DB1B4" level="section">1075. Flight to avoid prosecution for killing law enforcement officials.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6BD2098B31584990A6DB5F3FFFEF7A9B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Specific aggravating factor for Federal death penalty killing of law enforcement officer</header>
 <subsection id="H857268BB9584482DAE364A07B677E14B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Aggravating factors for homicide</header><text>Section 3592(c) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after paragraph (16) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED58834EC7B34ADEB9AA406BBC704A2F" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HB16110FDCB1048E9966278B0EF4FEA9D"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Killing of a law enforcement officer, prosecutor, judge, or first responder</header><text>The defendant killed or attempted to kill a person who is authorized by law—</text> <subparagraph id="HBC1ABC0B88214A249ECA86E7C949DD14"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to engage in or supervise the prevention, detention, or investigation of any criminal violation of law;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4EBCA2D7AB994A6087533FE420B30D3C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to arrest, prosecute, or adjudicate an individual for any criminal violation of law; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93D02EF668724ED7ACEADFD406789A17"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to be a firefighter or other first responder.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H39163878E6CB47C084730103AB457B40"><enum>4.</enum><header>Limitation on Federal habeas relief for murders of law enforcement officers</header>
			<subsection id="H7ECB5B5447FE4317B6AF682B036DAC77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Justice for law enforcement officers and their families</header>
 <paragraph id="H3B5F2826440443029500FF9E150F55C3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 2254 of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB6A5694C28E4425A7709599F201AAB0" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H7E6EBEA232154EB99709FB76F08CE423"><enum>(j)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H74DCEF32CE084B4FA1805FB75342FEB6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For an application for a writ of habeas corpus on behalf of a person in custody pursuant to the judgment of a State court for a crime that involved the killing of a public safety officer (as that term is defined in section 1204 of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3796b">42 U.S.C. 3796b</external-xref>)) or judge, while the public safety officer or judge was engaged in the performance of official duties, or on account of the performance of official duties by or status as a public safety officer or judge of the public safety officer or judge—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H113315AA2F6E4CC99AEE67CCBB9FE91E" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the application shall be subject to the time limitations and other requirements under sections 2263, 2264, and 2266; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63AE79CDF99D4874ACC19B0DD487FC93" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the court shall not consider claims relating to sentencing that were adjudicated in a State court.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF3071D1F8CC409ABE97D5E6B14FDAB5" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Sections 2251, 2262, and 2101 are the exclusive sources of authority for Federal courts to stay a sentence of death entered by a State court in a case described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A6B869F0CC046A18DDE07509521271F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rules</header><text>Rule 11 of the Rules Governing Section 2254 Cases in the United States District Courts is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>Rule 60(b)(6) of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure shall not apply to a proceeding under these rules in a case that is described in section 2254(j) of title 28, United States Code.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H993471E5DC034D3EBAF8E843B94B11BF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Finality of determination</header><text>Section 2244(b)(3)(E) of title 28, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>the subject of a petition</quote> and all that follows and inserting: <quote>reheard in the court of appeals or reviewed by writ of certiorari.</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DB3F1B16CA04497890FAED664C6F5DC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effective date and applicability</header> <subparagraph id="H94F38FADC4E5417CB1E79F3A36C084C5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This paragraph and the amendments made by this paragraph shall apply to any case pending on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63889EC475CA4E29A96D9E6441111BE0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Time limits</header><text>In a case pending on the date of enactment of this Act, if the amendments made by this paragraph impose a time limit for taking certain action, the period of which began before the date of enactment of this Act, the period of such time limit shall begin on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H109867E7480240C49C658222FBC817B6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The amendments made by this paragraph shall not bar consideration under section 2266(b)(3)(B) of title 28, United States Code, of an amendment to an application for a writ of habeas corpus that is pending on the date of enactment of this Act, if the amendment to the petition was adjudicated by the court prior to the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H49274A62550047C2BD455AE5732A7F5B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Limitation on recovery of certain damages for individuals engaged in felonies or crimes of violence</header>
 <subsection id="HD2B3C972EF7047F9A796F5BD9CBC951A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1979 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1983">42 U.S.C. 1983</external-xref>) is amended by—</text> <paragraph id="H3C5C9F9A99D44E5A9F92BA8C5F9E5614"><enum>(1)</enum><text>striking <quote>except that in any action</quote> and all that follows through <quote>relief was unavailable.</quote> and inserting the following: “except that—</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8B07B3E6485A4224A7E7AE39990363A4" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H2A8A3A55C147472F97A49D1C003BE8B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in any action brought against a judicial officer for an act or omission taken in the judicial capacity of that officer, injunctive relief shall not be granted unless a declaratory decree was violated or declaratory relief was unavailable; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2FC6DA94AC6B470884B001AB4CD3F0DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in any action seeking redress for any deprivation that was incurred in the course of, or as a result of, or is related to, conduct by the injured party that, more likely than not, constituted a felony or a crime of violence (as that term is defined in section 16 of title 18, United States Code) (including any deprivation in the course of arrest or apprehension for, or the investigation, prosecution, or adjudication of, such an offense), a court may not award damages other than for necessary out-of-pocket expenditures and other monetary loss.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF15BBC098B6949069E5DAC6AAF978173"><enum>(2)</enum><text>indenting the last sentence as an undesignated paragraph.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C4F953BFD5F495D800A5416123BE096"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Attorney’s fees</header><text>Section 722(b) of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1988">42 U.S.C. 1988(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>except that in any action</quote> and all that follows and inserting the following: “except that—</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16B55FEE56764EEF820C4A341A5C9AA1" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H71D475E24B1C4D5E8839E57EDA9CB034"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in any action brought against a judicial officer for an act or omission taken in the judicial capacity of that officer, such officer shall not be held liable for any costs, including attorneys fees, unless such action was clearly in excess of the jurisdiction of that officer; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C2E35315BBC421AA490282F05F51362"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in any action seeking redress for any deprivation that was incurred in the course of, or as a result of, or is related to, conduct by the injured party that, more likely than not, constituted a felony or a crime of violence (as that term is defined in section 16 of title 18, United States Code) (including any deprivation in the course of arrest or apprehension for, or the investigation, prosecution, or adjudication of, such an offense), the court may not allow such party to recover attorney’s fees.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H537B0187F0564D12BBA336CD92AD4593"><enum>6.</enum><header>Self-defense rights for law enforcement officers</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HD207C159BA6C4BC4A7FDD932FA0CE071"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/203">Chapter 203</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/3053">section 3053</external-xref> the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H08A5C1328EE74DFC81700C854FC4D73B" style="USC">
 <section id="H5BE24F322D924EAAB6C14851E9B281A7"><enum>3054.</enum><header>Authority of law enforcement officers to carry firearms</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any sworn officer, agent, or employee of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision thereof, who is authorized by law to engage in or supervise the prevention, detection, investigation, or prosecution of any violation of law, or to supervise or secure the safety of incarcerated inmates, may carry firearms if authorized by law to do so. Such authority to carry firearms, with respect to the lawful performance of the official duties of a sworn officer, agent, or employee of a State or a political subdivision thereof, shall include possession incident to depositing a firearm within a secure firearms storage area for use by all persons who are authorized to carry a firearm within any building or structure classified as a Federal facility or Federal court facility, as those terms are defined under section 930, and any grounds appurtenant to such a facility.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCE85E1C3652548FE962FAED7E5319957"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Carrying of concealed firearms by qualified law enforcement officers</header><text>Section 926B(e)(2) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>any magazine and</quote> after <quote>includes</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H92849CEF882A4B30A88110D75429A76D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Carrying of concealed firearms by qualified retired law enforcement officers</header><text>Section 926C(e)(1)(B) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>any magazine and</quote> after <quote>includes</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEF72E6383B9A4386BE8E2D2365B94E5B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>School zones</header><text>Section 922(q)(2)(B)(vi) title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>or a qualified law enforcement officer (as defined in section 926B(c))</quote> before the semicolon.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H0265A77111CB4905B018DB5E1239EFD3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations required</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall promulgate regulations allowing persons described in section 3054 of title 18, United States Code, to possess firearms in a manner described by that section. With respect to Federal justices, judges, bankruptcy judges, and magistrate judges, such regulations shall be prescribed after consultation with the Judicial Conference of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE2046AC6C9DE42E7A707011DA6D5E47F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/203">chapter 203</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/3053">section 3053</external-xref> the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HAF8D9C99E9CB4412B3B895819AC6E23F" style="USC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry idref="H5BE24F322D924EAAB6C14851E9B281A7" level="section">3054. Authority of law enforcement officers to carry firearms.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H76A6CBA26AE64147BAE8DB98C03B04AD"><enum>7.</enum><header>Improving the relationship between law enforcement agencies and the communities they serve</header>
 <subsection id="HB78C04C1C693454B8DE2667A2C9B7B82"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, the Attorney General using covered amounts shall, using such amounts as are necessary not to exceed $20,000,000, award grants to State, local, or tribal law enforcement agencies and appropriate nongovernmental organizations to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6E65EB5A3C074F7F955E8C1ECFEC208D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote trust and ensure legitimacy among law enforcement agencies and the communities they serve through procedural reforms, transparency, and accountability;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB604E9F9732B42AF9D1181488B5FAB5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop comprehensive and responsive policies on key topics relevant to the relationship between law enforcement agencies and the communities they serve;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H57AE4765058E4C259CF88821BA074EF2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>balance the embrace of technology and digital communications with local needs, privacy, assessments, and monitoring;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E73E3DFFFCB49A0A63F81FD53C7C943"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourage the implementation of policies that support community-based partnerships in the reduction of crime;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1EE5798E83A5493192151EAF53EF2E81"><enum>(5)</enum><text>emphasize the importance of high quality and effective training and education through partnerships with local and national training facilities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDBF74807D00F4CA189B8C9F91309514D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>endorse practices that support officer wellness and safety through the re-evaluation of officer shift hours, including data collection and analysis.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEF563B674DB44DFDAA6E88C564B8DDF8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered amounts defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered amounts</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="HC1997B997662461A9AF2EE952AB614FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any unobligated balances made available under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-intermediate" style="appropriations">GENERAL ADMINISTRATION</header-in-text></quote> under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-major" style="appropriations">DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE</header-in-text></quote> in an appropriations Act in a fiscal year;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD48C9C86AA6D49F9AB47ED0303BA021A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any amounts made available for an <quote>Edward Byrne Memorial criminal justice innovation program</quote> under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-small" style="appropriations">STATE AND LOCAL LAW ENFORCEMENT ASSISTANCE</header-in-text></quote> under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-intermediate" style="appropriations">OFFICE OF JUSTICE PROGRAMS</header-in-text></quote> under the heading <quote><header-in-text level="appropriations-major" style="appropriations">DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE</header-in-text></quote> in an appropriations Act in a fiscal year; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6430CE365FFC4ACBB814CC5D2C43AA29"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any combination of amounts described in paragraphs (1) and (2).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


