<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1249AFB98C1948C496891593E5BEB44A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3202 IH: Cyber Vulnerability Disclosure Reporting Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3202</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170712">July 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to submit a report on cyber vulnerability
			 disclosures, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H00F3EFECDA604190A5F7A546342392DD" style="OLC">
 <section id="H94C9B491EC5B4413A065A2A726FA364E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cyber Vulnerability Disclosure Reporting Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H748EE2D29A614F4486DFF3A1D020A395"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on cyber vulnerabilities</header> <subsection id="H343248FB3F27433C967CCFE691A1DFCB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 240 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report that contains a description of the policies and procedures developed for coordinating cyber vulnerability disclosures, in accordance with section 227(m) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/148">6 U.S.C. 148(m)</external-xref>). To the extent possible, such report shall include an annex with information on instances in which such policies and procedures were used to disclose cyber vulnerabilities in the year prior to the date such report is required and, where available, information on the degree to which such information was acted upon by industry and other stakeholders. Such report may also contain a description of how the Secretary is working with other Federal entities and critical infrastructure owners and operators to prevent, detect, and mitigate cyber vulnerabilities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCA150372684942B1A20AB25B7AC450C1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subsection (b) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


