<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H76B18BB6F565422C851FDE624B148A56" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 799 IH: Shift Back to Society Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 799</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170201">February 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000819">Mr. Walker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000584">Mrs. Love</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, to establish a
			 pilot program to make grants to historically Black colleges and
			 universities to provide educational programs to offenders who have
			 recently been, or will soon be, released from incarceration, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA737AC7A16C9417696575C7321E33E41" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7F5724C4A7E8479CA5827A5F85617D83" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Shift Back to Society Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6FA8EB2BD45641F5BD49AA42AD574698"><enum>2.</enum><header>Offender education re-entry pilot program</header> <subsection id="HDA5635995C074D8B872618712EF98C88"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall establish a pilot program for 5 years which makes grants to not more than 10 historically Black colleges and universities to provide educational programming to eligible offenders in order to facilitate re-entry into the community.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF220201EAF4344BF8361BCD7BF798C5C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chief executive officer of a historically Black college or university seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Attorney General an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H333EDD5D3E3945F1A1EEEC9AEF6C1B3F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Matching funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The portion of the costs of a program provided by a grant under subsection (a) may not exceed 50 percent. The recipient of a grant under this section may meet the matching requirement under this subsection by making in-kind contributions of goods or services that are directly related to the purpose for which such grant was awarded.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFA599D7455494E81AA9348DBB6F6A636"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H64AA65A92A4543A191A52FD54B5C811C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>educational programming</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H42451EDEB1AF4784A8C5B1C8CDE8AEB3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>general education development (GED) programming; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H390B43455B244C388DC4DD547AE76992"><enum>(B)</enum><text>educational courses which are transferable for course credit at that historically Black college or university.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6150888F69924A16A5D19FB7181B0F2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>eligible offender</term> means an individual who was convicted of a criminal offense and—</text> <subparagraph id="H68DDB84BC46B49F38C71E034AA1004DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has been released from incarceration for not longer than one year; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C4ECC8DCF944F039B333BF2EC4681A0"><enum>(B) </enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is scheduled to be released from incarceration in not longer than one year.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD24884E1961B486F9953D81396BF784E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>historically Black college or university</term> has the meaning given the term <term>part B institution</term> under section 322(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061(2)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C15ED4EB1234FCE953E559E130F9E46"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H51F991C5E353471D87057C222731AABE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibition on new authorization of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall be carried out using amounts otherwise appropriated or made available to the Department of Justice. No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H57095BEBB7874272990DC1BEFCA29690"><enum>3.</enum><header>GAO Study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the conclusion of the pilot program under section 2, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report which describes the results of the pilot program.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


