<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8F7414B2F5CE4000ACDEA22C27A22183" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3727 IH: To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to include additional telehealth services for purposes of MA organization bids, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3727</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170911">September 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001273">Mrs. Black</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001284">Mrs. Brooks of Indiana</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to include additional telehealth services for
			 purposes of MA organization bids, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HDF88B9CA546A4ABEB2C7EA7700246C07" style="OLC">
		<section id="H0BA27C2D10D8457FBA856247883564D8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Inclusion of additional telehealth services in Medicare Advantage organization bids</header>
 <subsection id="H8009C709CBAC43F882432A6D689C53D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1852 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-22">42 U.S.C. 1395w–22</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H294CDD36ECAE4713BBB073278E39E352"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)(B)(i), by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>For plan year 2020 and each subsequent plan year, for purposes of subsection (m) and section 1854, in the case that an MA plan makes an election described in subsection (m)(1) with respect to such plan year, additional telehealth services shall be treated as a service included as a benefit under the original medicare fee-for-service program option with respect to such plan and plan year.</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0D49275B139F47B1855DCE507F73995D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block id="H9458B123A22343158DF5578674BCFDB4" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HA579CC4280F24826B88DE01650E1B049"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Provision of additional telehealth services</header> <paragraph id="HA1EA0B8DD2AB49E5AF558DEE567447CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>M<enum-in-header>A</enum-in-header> plan option</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a)(1)(B)(i), an election described in this paragraph, with respect to an MA plan and plan year, is an election by the sponsor of such plan to provide under the plan for such plan year, in accordance with the subsequent provisions of this subsection, additional telehealth services (as defined in paragraph (2)) as a benefit under the original medicare fee-for-service program option. Such additional telehealth services, with respect to a plan year, shall be in addition to benefits included under the original medicare fee-for-service program option for such year.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H13D9C30912DA4F958C945C263957D78E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional telehealth services defined</header>
 <subparagraph id="H6BD2A5AE495B4C15A5498ECDD4FAAD53"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this subsection and section 1854, the term <quote>additional telehealth services</quote> means, subject to subparagraph (C), services—</text> <clause id="H7711309A5E324E86B90B35AA4BC07C6F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for which payment may be made under part B (without regard to application of section 1834(m));</text>
 </clause><clause id="H09CDAB025E354808821704362BF526EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that, if furnished via a telecommunications system, would not be payable under section 1834(m);</text> </clause><clause id="H66E8B6EE41034B4F9C4DF9AC2785DD81"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">furnished using electronic information and telecommunications technology;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3635A3B59A5F409CAD614A4CC71FE81E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>furnished in accordance with such requirements as the Secretary specifies pursuant to paragraph (3); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA726A672F71249199DE05154699C28EA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>which are identified annually by the Secretary as appropriate to furnish using electronic information and telecommunications technology where a physician (as defined in section 1861(r)) or practitioner (described in section 1842(b)(18)(C)) furnishing the service is not at the same location as the plan enrollee.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H767BBCC8F7AA4298960563470AA7AE2D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Flexibility for phasing in identifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making identifications under subparagraph (A)(iv), the Secretary may make such identifications in a manner that results in additional telehealth services being phased in, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61CE18E671234DE08A863E887BE3CCA4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exclusion of capital and infrastructure costs and investments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection and section 1854, the term <quote>additional telehealth services</quote> does not include capital and infrastructure costs and investments relating to such benefits provided pursuant to this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H453D7264614F4F8F9156FE2BD83CE58D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements for additional telehealth services</header><text>The Secretary shall specify requirements for the provision of additional telehealth services with respect to—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC8BA547E1E4448C4BF783271554AB1E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>qualifications (other than licensure) of physicians and practitioners who furnish such services;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H85024119BD114A2B9429C3A651B9A7DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the technology used in furnishing such services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF32D78C2F507413299B321E81F835750"><enum>(C)</enum><text>factors necessary for coordination of additional telehealth services with other services; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H061D814B49CA42778441A9AED81D36D0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such other criteria (such as clinical criteria) as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8193EF67AA5E455884B507A260DA6E94"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Enrollee choice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An MA plan that provides a service as an additional telehealth service may not, when furnished without use of electronic information and telecommunications technology, restrict access to the equivalent in-person service, including by encouraging or discouraging an individual from being furnished such service as an additional telehealth service.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H85DB155F672744B495ECF1CCB3416E32"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Construction</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF321CF62AF1344B7B8E31AB3FDA020CE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In determining if an MA organization or MA plan, as applicable, is in compliance with each requirement specified in subparagraph (B), such determination shall be made without regard to any additional telehealth services covered by the plan offered by such organization or plan pursuant to this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79D31F4458EF45779F86B78B3ECC9249"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements specified</header><text>The requirements specified in this subparagraph are the following:</text> <clause id="H2F2032A103F241B2BEF2611DEEB35D3C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements under subsection (d).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA8E29B1FCA0C45BB9DB4724836D1315A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement under subsection (a)(1) with respect to covering benefits under the original medicare fee-for-service program option, as defined in the first sentence of paragraph (B)(i) of such subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H741A4C828A764B9182EBE5B065522604"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion of additional telehealth services in MA organization bid amount</header><text>Section 1854(a)(6)(A)(ii)(I) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-24">42 U.S.C. 1395w–24(a)(6)(A)(ii)(I)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including, for plan year 2019 and subsequent plan years, the provision of such benefits through the use of additional telehealth services under section 1852(m)</quote> before the semicolon at the end.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H23D55C89F7D24AF198B2B5E206B6A06C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Use of telecommunications systems in furnishing chronic care management services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1848(b)(8) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395(b)(8)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A4582F553D14991AE90A6995CFF4C62" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HEBDD639D95D240B5B24C3F4448986982"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this paragraph, with respect to chronic care management services, the Secretary may, subject to subparagraph (B), make payment for such services furnished through the use of secure messaging, Internet, store and forward technologies, or other non-face-to-face communication methods determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HB2FF407A7547423883EB10140CA14E9E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress regarding parity of telehealth services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that there should be—</text> <paragraph id="HCBF717796B3B4A75B9DDEBEC32365850"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">parity, with respect to access to telehealth, between the original medicare fee-for-service program under parts A and B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act and the Medicare Advantage program under part C of such title; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF44A09487FDB409EA6827F46F9A03996"><enum>(2)</enum><text>access to medically appropriate, quality telehealth for all Medicare beneficiaries.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

