<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9C97A496997649C8ABF1FBBD9594EFCA" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1838 IH: Ambulatory Surgical Center Quality and Access Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1838</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170330">March 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000181">Mr. Nunes</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001036">Mr. Hensarling</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000174">Mr. Sam Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to modernize payments for ambulatory surgical
			 centers under the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA601FDA840904F36972AB1CC25309420" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA29E459C747A4516BAF3919AEDC6C5F2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ambulatory Surgical Center Quality and Access Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD65B68BFB8B54437AF9A0CF1E995BF5F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Aligning updates for ambulatory surgical center services with updates for OPD services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1833(i)(2)(D) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(i)(2)(D)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H558AF3298011441B9844DD63996F1C93"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (v)—</text> <subparagraph id="H0FDF74DC38304BB8AA1D9A7336BE0A9B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by inserting before the period the following: <quote>and, in the case of 2018 or a subsequent year, by the adjustment described in subsection (t)(3)(G) for the respective year</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H389560A9F68844C69D7BFBBF05FD14FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by moving the margin 6 ems to the left;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C349F4B23114DB8A66E7B5B5D950573"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (vi) as clause (vii); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H154041D267484284AB7C8AA2543F0B42"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (v) the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59E7C6FC7C4D42609A4EFD6E4504EBCA" style="OLC"> <clause id="H2C774113F3314DAC82C56DA1B262E19F" indent="up3"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In implementing the system described in clause (i) for 2018 and each subsequent year, there shall be an annual update under such system for the year equal to the OPD fee schedule increase factor specified under subsection (t)(3)(C)(iv) for such year, adjusted in accordance with clauses (iv) and (v).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HABE3A517F3BC4FC89AAEF9969BCCBA4C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transparency of quality reporting and Medicare beneficiary information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (7) of section 1833(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(i)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HB60FA594009C4347917C86DF31E378B3">
 <subparagraph id="H3C5477D8B72C4F3797F35C68C66D3761" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To the extent that quality measures implemented by the Secretary under this paragraph for ambulatory surgical centers and under section 1833(t)(17) for hospital outpatient departments are applicable to the provision of surgical services in both ambulatory surgical centers and hospital outpatient departments, the Secretary shall make reported data on such centers and departments available on the website <term>Medicare.gov</term> in a manner that will permit side-by-side comparisons on such measures for ambulatory surgical centers and hospital outpatient departments in the same geographic area.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00B825045D9D4F919062A742BC13D7AF" indent="up2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Secretary shall ensure that an ambulatory surgery center and a hospital has the opportunity to review, and submit any corrections for, the data to be made public with respect to the ambulatory surgery center under subparagraph (C) prior to such data being made public.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35ECC6A1AEA04ABD8CC470542E999FA4" indent="up2"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop materials and inform beneficiaries under this title of publicly available comparisons provided for in subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HDB26953B760C4317B89CC8D3553A4AE4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Advisory Panel on Hospital Outpatient Payment Representation</header>
 <subsection id="HD5D327D097224F789EA916BFCA655849"><enum>(a)</enum><header>ASC representative</header><text>The second sentence of section 1833(t)(9)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(t)(9)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>and suppliers subject to the prospective payment system (including at least one ambulatory surgical center representative)</quote> after <quote>an appropriate selection of representatives of providers</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H770EF173C8A141C29F18A82A8DED369E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HD6992DCDDA714802AE98689D49A072C8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reasons for excluding additional procedures from ASC approved list</header> <subsection id="H5B99BF0860E44793846CA22EE6EACB66"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1833(i)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(i)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>In updating such lists for application in years beginning after the date of the enactment of this sentence, for each procedure that was requested to be included in such lists during the public comment period but which the Secretary does not propose (in the final rule updating such lists) to so include in such lists, Secretary shall cite in such final rule the specific criteria in paragraph (b) or (c) of section 416.166 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, based on which the procedure was excluded. If paragraph (b) of such section is cited for exclusion of a procedure, the Secretary shall identify the peer reviewed research or the evidence upon which such determination is based. The Secretary may not use or cite section 416.166(c)(7) of such title as criteria or a basis for exclusion of a procedure from such lists.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H44992BBE7B524896B5BE07628623A22D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to lists of ambulatory surgery procedures for application in years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


