<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H492AE3A0BBB24AD2852C4DFDABEEF67F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3442 IH: Reset Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3442</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170727">July 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a study and reconsideration by Congress of certain major rules, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA41DAF3637D0486E83428F8B51081972" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H968CCFBACD25450992D25403749E8CAC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reset Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAE14FE35EA5149319E47CED34848D112"><enum>2.</enum><header>Government accountability office study of rules</header> <subsection id="H475F26B6223E4FEEB1C362B0C3DCA439"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study to determine, as of the date of the enactment of this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="H81C369DFF3F1417EA9C1205CE7B83D09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how many rules (as such term is defined in section 804 of title 5, United States Code) were in effect;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63C38CA4AEAD455F88216E2211535A19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how many major rules (as such term is defined in section 804 of title 5, United States Code) were in effect; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H621837F9080F4D9EA46FC0A005D00D64"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the total estimated economic cost imposed by all such rules.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA96FFFAB15AD42E8B555093723024138"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit a report to Congress that contains the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA2E0A503FD194CD1ACD464B2648553E4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Major rules currently in effect</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the case of any major rule (as such term is defined in section 804 of title 5, United States Code) that is in effect on the date of enactment of this Act, for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, the rule shall be deemed to be a major rule for which a report was submitted under section 801(a)(1) of such title on the date the report under section 2 is submitted, and the provisions of such chapter shall apply for purposes of providing for a period of review in which a joint resolution of disapproval may be enacted.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

