<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF1EAE4629D9B45BF870ECFC4D4FE3E0E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 827 IH: Imperial Valley Desert Conservation and Recreation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 827</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170202">February 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish certain conservation and recreation areas in the State of California, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4BF47836B3564E8F92A0B1F73BC412EC" style="OLC">
 <section id="H42F47FF218F84F708949C30B636250B3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Imperial Valley Desert Conservation and Recreation Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H316B8CCE440744DCBB528BEB7535213B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transfer of land to Anza-Borrego Desert State Park, California</header> <subsection id="H7DC68C9E122147C58FD31481E203A261"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On termination of all mining claims to the land described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall transfer the land described in that paragraph to the State.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE87AB6EE88DC417491938701036A736C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Description of land</header><text>The land referred to in paragraph (1) is certain Bureau of Land Management land in San Diego County, California, comprising approximately 934 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Table Mountain Wilderness Study Area Proposed Transfer to the State</quote> and dated March 17, 2015.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H5C5DA66AB8AD41C79620CD79B3CD95B7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management</header>
 <paragraph id="HEFC58AE3F0B341248D8FCD07DA313772"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The land transferred under paragraph (1) shall be managed in accordance with the provisions of the California Wilderness Act (California Public Resources Code sections 5093.30–5093.40).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAB0156FFF0F4CA1AE3F859DDF7ACF41"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the land transferred under paragraph (1) is withdrawn from—</text> <subparagraph id="HD3264BA0A76B42519C5DCD53307D2EB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1439E77E6B2D409690DBA9D08BBFBDAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CE1FBCDC76A460D825EFA6E028B5729"><enum>(C)</enum><text>disposition under all laws relating to mineral and geothermal leasing.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H33569B0CF75244CE833FBA9F40F1AAF1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reversion</header><text>If the State ceases to manage the land transferred under paragraph (1) as part of the State Park System or in a manner inconsistent with the California Wilderness Act (California Public Resources Code sections 5093.30–5093.40), the land shall revert to the Secretary at the discretion of the Secretary, to be managed as a Wilderness Study Area.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H51D4337DD43B49A5B004F9873D5DF51F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Holtville Airport, Imperial County</header>
 <subsection id="H1C647174509C4998AA9DE6F50AE49E0C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On the submission of an application by Imperial County, California, the Secretary of Transportation shall, in accordance with section 47125 of title 49, United States Code, and section 2641.1 of title 43, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations) seek a conveyance from the Secretary of approximately 3,500 acres of Bureau of Land Management land adjacent to the Imperial County Holtville Airport (L04) for the purposes of airport expansion.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H10C2B5CDAE6A4887A039D619CA3D9E13"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Segregation</header><text>The Secretary (acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management) shall, with respect to the land to be conveyed under subsection (a)—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H2D06685095934C1B851B6F7EC045A3E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>segregate the land;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2A5AD2512AFB4A76A8DAA7A5CE16847A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>endeavor to develop a joint Memorandum of Understanding with the Imperial County Board of Supervisors, the Department of Defense, and the Department of Transportation; such an agreement shall not impose any obligation, term, or condition on the property owned by Imperial County; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9F95DD115DEB496399AA138A4AC4A67D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prohibit the appropriation of the land until—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD400F23A8E3A4C2692A7033B10F4D76B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date on which a joint Memorandum of Understanding is signed by the parties listed in paragraph (2);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE026D41277114AD3B549C2CBB1518179"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date on which a notice of realty action terminates the application; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF1FEDC4A598249729F4DFDFA5DE54920"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the date on which a document of conveyance is published.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2EC1ED51BE364B23801A49696E210F6A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Vinagre Wash Special Management Area</header>
 <subsection id="H2DA5F8DD478C4351AC8755DB3ECBA6AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established the Vinagre Wash Special Management Area in the State, to be managed by the El Centro Field Office and the Yuma Field Office of the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB4B566CA47EE4D05BC62A82FC58B8127"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Management Area is to conserve, protect, and enhance—</text> <paragraph id="H69227786144145C39AB3A2BEB6ED3038"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the plant and wildlife values of the Management Area; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H62F44267FA5448119EFD6C3F32273BF6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the outstanding and nationally significant ecological, geological, scenic, recreational, archaeological, cultural, historic, and other resources of the Management Area.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5410EB4FD334245A1561B16A1F191EE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Boundaries</header><text>The Management Area shall consist of the public land in Imperial County, California, comprising approximately 81,880 acres, as generally depicted on the map.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H67467CC5EB454EF7A805467834826E00"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Map; legal description</header>
 <paragraph id="HB9790F59511A4E92A6648196810868A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable, but not later than 3 years, after the date of enactment of this title, the Secretary shall submit a map and legal description of the Management Area to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H74BFF267924B43ADA0E9D1F76149EAC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23BEE177B7FF484DBC439DA6566E8678"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H688C7E79C8F949FBA10DF9EC2063CAA4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>The map and legal description submitted under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this title, except that the Secretary may correct any errors in the map and legal description.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H889E0B52C7C14F8AAD727CDBDA56D281"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Copies of the map submitted under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2B3A71FA59384FFBB7681117B81C002B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Office of the Director of the Bureau of Land Management; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30C5517D1792484CB0355FEA5BF613DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the appropriate office of the Bureau of Land Management in the State.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0C78C0E2527A429BAF5DBB7C4C24AE3D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Management</header>
 <subsection id="H8BD0291FBB414816B9EC39E297199037"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall allow hiking, camping, hunting, and sightseeing and the use of motorized vehicles, mountain bikes, and horses on designated routes in the Management Area in a manner that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE6C85C1708984B84B6EA34525CB8B8D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is consistent with the purpose of the Management Area described in section 4(b);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1045D3295121442EAD17A04748C40AC2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensures public health and safety; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9704B8E5A97045BD85D879DB9D5B2AE4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is consistent with applicable laws and regulations, including the Desert Renewable Energy Conservation Plan.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3469B2D60AFB4B9DA066C78F72FE08D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Off-Highway vehicle use</header>
 <paragraph id="HDD062324CAB44E4FB934B389AB41B34D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) and all other applicable laws, the use of off-highway vehicles shall be permitted on routes in the Management Area generally depicted on the map.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DC51579F758493AAB6425E062C12E86"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Closure</header><text>The Secretary may temporarily close or permanently reroute a portion of a route described in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEBA1AE98792444A6B98213E221A3495A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to prevent, or allow for restoration of, resource damage;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2939AE7B91349989B9F9FE2EAA2B5B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to protect tribal cultural resources, including the resources identified in the tribal cultural resources management plan;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88B92221BF1E46528ABEED8A815CB129"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to address public safety concerns; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H632E42A44AC24166B3BD443B06D2247C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>as otherwise required by law.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H303EE2584A464771B03EB4E240A97D96"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Designation of additional routes</header><text>During the 3-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this title, the Secretary—</text> <subparagraph id="HA6E5C1DDC70C4460A1CA08BBE7E8C16B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall accept petitions from the public regarding additional routes for off-highway vehicles; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C30979872E1429C9774DCDEC51C2A19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may designate additional routes that the Secretary determines—</text> <clause id="HE5CA42EE37DE4CAC99C0B8FC6A585EF0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>would provide significant or unique recreational opportunities; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8B8074C004B24585B02674D8CA6AF40A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are consistent with the purposes of the Management Area.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB201476AC6EE42F7B62F958005964208"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, all Federal land within the Management Area is withdrawn from—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEA9AD86F3078485FBF8A10D607AAE14F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D59630566F442B2A58E341107C8BA37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H640F4BF773C1411FA94C763C66211904"><enum>(3)</enum><text>right-of-way, leasing, or disposition under all laws relating to—</text> <subparagraph id="H6E6D9132E01D4ED29B823CB20433624C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>minerals; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA41BD63F3714781AC826371A10A529D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>solar, wind, and geothermal energy.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H44225042C41D467A88FA63592DB646B7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No buffers</header><text>The establishment of the Management Area shall not—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7EA63B5EB65B4E408BF058F673AB252B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>create a protective perimeter or buffer zone around the Management Area; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H512EFF16BD5646F79C94AF6DF1D7857E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>preclude uses or activities outside the Management Area that are permitted under other applicable laws, even if the uses or activities are prohibited within the Management Area.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E365E8EAE2743A79BE4E28E05B39C25"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Notice of available routes</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that visitors to the Management Area have access to adequate notice relating to the availability of designated routes in the Management Area through—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0EBAE50C53E344E798707B2FB8EBC7BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the placement of appropriate signage along the designated routes;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA87096F99CAB4025867F4C04B1A8AF1D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the distribution of maps, safety education materials, and other information that the Secretary determines to be appropriate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAAE0D6F96A642F291B60D8A14B2FDB0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>restoration of areas that are not designated as open routes, including vertical mulching.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8FE28B297BA64F41B11183B13267E797"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Stewardship</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with Indian tribes and other interests, shall develop a program to provide opportunities for monitoring and stewardship of the Management Area to minimize environmental impacts and prevent resource damage from recreational use, including volunteer assistance with—</text>
 <paragraph id="H913600D3D749447B8460FEDD9DBB7B4A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>route signage;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F6111D156D34AF7B979C7EC9F25B236"><enum>(2)</enum><text>restoration of closed routes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2ABBC2B63624300BB77C53893F7B7A8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>protection of Management Area resources; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H368EF7DE18D940F0A7F5237A07E14E45"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recreation education.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F7168498FF548E6A0D80795686006A4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Protection of tribal cultural resources</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this title, the Secretary, in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/2003">chapter 2003</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code, and any other applicable law, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H532C26364FD04C388EBC41FBDD5A316C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prepare and complete a tribal cultural resources survey of the Management Area; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5B3F04FED224D588E9E118E82010FE0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consult with the Quechan Indian Nation and other Indian tribes demonstrating ancestral, cultural, or other ties to the resources within the Management Area on the development and implementation of the tribal cultural resources survey under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBCB27E5D37644759B4D25BD240697126"><enum>6.</enum><header>Potential wilderness</header>
			<subsection id="HBB78DB333D824E4C98D13F73AB1CEB4E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Protection of wilderness character</header>
 <paragraph id="H08EB8219F26141DAAB8A8F88529FC233"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall manage the Federal land in the Management Area described in paragraph (2) in a manner that preserves the character of the land for the eventual inclusion of the land in the National Wilderness Preservation System.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E0C7D7C536E4C07B5425978F4477781"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Description of land</header><text>The Federal land described in this paragraph is—</text> <subparagraph id="H28230F01CEF2465B883A2E5D5E78FFFE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the approximately 10,860 acres of land, as generally depicted as the Indian Pass Additions on the map entitled <quote>Vinagre Wash Proposed Special Management Area</quote> and dated November 10, 2009;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6B2343E04594E2D897BA2EF898A8DD4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the approximately 17,250 acres of land, as generally depicted as Milpitas Wash Potential Wilderness on the map entitled <quote>Vinagre Wash Proposed Special Management Area</quote> and dated November 10, 2009;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49DF04D3F49447F8847B346A1A7B1538"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the approximately 11,840 acres of land, as generally depicted as Buzzards Peak Potential Wilderness on the map entitled <quote>Vinagre Wash Proposed Special Management Area</quote> and dated November 10, 2009; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H292FC9037EA04D69B4E0FF4CD2E218A6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the approximately 9,350 acres of land, as generally depicted as Palo Verde Mountains Potential Wilderness on the map entitled <quote>Vinagre Wash Proposed Special Management Area</quote> and dated November 10, 2009.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF059580DAEB342EC9D081FEBDD98944B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of land</header>
 <subparagraph id="H448EA33886804459BE9422A36244C95B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Military uses</header><text>The Secretary shall manage the Federal land in the Management Area described in paragraph (2) in a manner that is consistent with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.), except that the Secretary may authorize use of the land by the Secretary of the Navy for Naval Special Warfare Tactical Training, including long-range small unit training and navigation, vehicle concealment, and vehicle sustainment training, in accordance with applicable Federal laws.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB50DDCD2A0D4E5DAE284F142E4D4148"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibited uses</header><text>The following shall be prohibited on the Federal land described in paragraph (2):</text> <clause id="HC9218B3656A944448F9ECA2D87684368"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Permanent roads.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAF5D7F6350F247FF839377858A4AEABC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Commercial enterprises.</text> </clause><clause id="H8F39F03CCD9547868744682F607C42AF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Except as necessary to meet the minimum requirements for the administration of the Federal land and to protect public health and safety—</text>
 <subclause id="HF54FBC924BAC4463A6C30B12516B63A9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the use of mechanized vehicles; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HCD188DF5421E4A9995B59B9424D9AB7A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the establishment of temporary roads.</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E47020AAEC74785B66B0B793EB8C1C1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Wilderness designation</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0EB5DF71910345CB829DFF37C52BB064"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal land described in paragraph (2) shall be designated as wilderness and as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System on the date on which the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, publishes a notice in the Federal Register that all activities on the Federal land that are incompatible with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.) have terminated.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4163200FB3E844EC9D5ABBD450211175"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>On designation of the Federal land under clause (i)—</text> <clause id="H3CE21727ECE1478384F84E5CA06522D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the land described in paragraph (2)(A) shall be incorporated in, and shall be considered to be a part of, the Indian Pass Wilderness;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF1C836D3A5B04AF2A669FEC4493B4240"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the land described in paragraph (2)(B) shall be designated as the <quote>Milpitas Wash Wilderness</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="H208D7BAF5B714E76800F72DCE69994CF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the land described in paragraph (2)(C) shall be designated as the <quote>Buzzard Peak Wilderness</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7443853584F448FA8EA8E2A6262D925C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the land described in paragraph (2)(D) shall be incorporated in, and shall be considered to be a part of, the Palo Verde Mountains Wilderness.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H43ACA68AA8B34793853F18CAF2CF1B1D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration of wilderness</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the land designated as wilderness or as a wilderness addition by this title shall be administered by the Secretary in accordance with this Act and the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H3D0DEC742B454B929D015750F3CF35B9"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H2E436DD2413D4851AF1980263BF602B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Management area</header><text>The term <term>Management Area</term> means the Vinagre Wash Special Management Area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F5874B875924D8491015E14654CF677"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>map</term> means the map entitled <quote>Vinagre Wash Proposed Special Management Area; Indian Pass Mountains and Palo Verde Mountains Potential Wilderness Additions, and Buzzards Peak, Milpitas Wash Potential Wilderness</quote> and dated February 19, 2015.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2390C49A683D4CC99FF9D1409D8B8169"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public land</header><text>The term <term>public land</term> has the meaning given the term <term>public lands</term> in section 103 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1702">43 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB29F98B0C1624F529DF42C20FD4D1FB9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F6A306B8BEA4D90B8378E11C2AABA33"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of California.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

