<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF2A095D3EA5546438D72D8CD183C04F3" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2397 IH: DPRK Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2397</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170504">May 4, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004 to authorize further actions to promote freedom
			 of information and democracy in North Korea, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HFDCD8C00FB5148779CA2B1241BD2A2D3" style="OLC">
 <section id="H856C452AD6024C139509D5D9271B4825" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Distribution and Promotion of Rights and Knowledge Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote>DPRK Act of 2017</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H72EC53D8853B486B87BA533E92293EDC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Actions to promote freedom of information and democracy in North Korea</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004 is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE93E9D957A7D4744980124B5C252068F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a) of section 103 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7813">22 U.S.C. 7813</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H25900DED81AF4438B94EF1048EE1EEF2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>radio broadcasting</quote> and inserting <quote>broadcasting, including news rebroadcasting,</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF72AB58F80CE400E96D0E1336FF0B2D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>increase broadcasts</quote> and inserting <quote>increase such broadcasts, including news rebroadcasts,</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H464EE7999B8D4A079BD0E2E07909ABF5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a) of section 104 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7814">22 U.S.C. 7814</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3BF8FCC9800F4BF4AF2D002060215AA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The President</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H92FD2AE4348E44119CF5E22FA717B104" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H571405394B944D1B8FA2E4AA0E23AB97"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA224380081494EA79941852EA50BC0D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, USB drives, micro SD cards, audio players, video players, cell phones, wi-fi, wireless internet, webpages, internet, wireless telecommunications, and other electronic media that shares information</quote> before the period at the end; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BDF05F73D4145E0A92A0F3CB9E1A49D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H673BC737A1E24DE18383375F1C05C870" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H4D0986B13ED840FAA9449ED4916F3892"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with the sense of Congress described in section 103, the President, acting through the Secretary of State, is authorized to distribute or provide grants to distribute information receiving devices, electronically readable devices, and other informational sources into North Korea, including devices and informational sources specified in paragraph (1). To carry out this paragraph, the President is authorized to issue directions to facilitate the free-flow of information into North Korea.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69CC8EE1A07F4F22817156DB8FBABE02"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Research and development grant program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with the authorization described in paragraphs (1) and (2) to increase the availability and distribution of sources of information inside North Korea, the President, acting through the Secretary of State, is authorized to establish a grant program to make grants to eligible entities to develop or distribute (or both) new products or methods to allow North Koreans easier access to outside information. Such program may involve public-private partnerships.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H41D232FBBEC642AFBBC4E421E110BBD3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Culture</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with the sense of Congress described in section 103, the Broadcasting Board of Governors may broadcast American, Korean, Chinese, and other popular music, television, movies, and popular cultural references as part of its programming.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6E4C9EE23F64A9A95FFB61453974A68"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rights and laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with the sense of Congress described in section 103, the Broadcasting Board of Governors shall broadcast to North Korea in the Korean language information on rights, laws, and freedoms afforded through the North Korean Constitution, the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, the United Nations Commission of Inquiry on Human Rights in the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea, and any other applicable treaties or international agreements to which North Korea is bound.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9A2A4B22F3749EA8E2B4F1686187F9C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Broadcasting report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than—</text> <subparagraph id="H0296B13C70714101A296BC6AD8AB7B3F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>180 days after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Broadcasting Board of Governors, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that sets forth a detailed plan for improving broadcasting content for the purpose of targeting new audiences and increasing listenership; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF3297719A52429C91F1997CCF459334"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one year after the date of the enactment of this paragraph and annually thereafter for each of the next five years, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Broadcasting Board of Governors, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the effectiveness of actions taken pursuant to this section, including data reflecting audience and listenership, device distribution and usage, technological development and advancement usage, and other appropriate information to fully inform Congress.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


