<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H481A04BDAEE541F2862A50DC527CB66E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 265 IH: Jerusalem Embassy and Recognition Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 265</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170104">January 4, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To recognize Jerusalem as the capital of Israel, to relocate to Jerusalem the United States Embassy
			 in Israel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5AD7782FFF46457CA5AFC004F4788BE5" style="OLC">
 <section id="HDEB4C8C0F44240A6A8B696C6CD855449" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Jerusalem Embassy and Recognition Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB998C54116044F3393721DB9AE2627D9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Recognition of Jerusalem as the capital of Israel and relocation of the United States Embassy to Jerusalem</header> <subsection id="HC7EC6F67489D45E08B9C4DD61EA91692"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States to recognize Jerusalem as the undivided capital of the State of Israel, both de jure and de facto.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7822D27B9A504E76B916D25D9D98D50B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H6EF1275C8A334CF3A31024670BBF7111"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Jerusalem must remain an undivided city in which the rights of every ethnic and religious group are protected as they have been by Israel since 1967;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CAB98D845B24E719FCF7C6C2E44BA49"><enum>(2)</enum><text>every citizen of Israel should have the right to reside anywhere in the undivided city of Jerusalem;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H34AFDDCD55E44582A22DF9007BC9747F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the President and the Secretary of State should publicly affirm as a matter of United States policy that Jerusalem must remain the undivided capital of the State of Israel;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF852AF7C06F8400E930D9A2EC03E9176"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the President should immediately implement the provisions of the Jerusalem Embassy Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/5">Public Law 104–5</external-xref>) and begin the process of relocating the United States Embassy in Israel to Jerusalem; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H26C5F51D2D7C45E18E9BC85FE71B89A9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>United States officials should refrain from any actions that contradict United States law on this subject.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFA369BF93E9C46D780BA0742420372DB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Removal of waiver authority</header><text>The Jerusalem Embassy Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/45">Public Law 104–45</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H5A053ADDAFB648E28E9ABB44A20A49B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking section 7; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E43A73EA213443A894BE8D230A409BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating section 8 as section 7.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFFD96A1519B7418EA4F453D3939FA2B2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Identification of Jerusalem on Government documents</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any official document of the United States Government which lists countries and their capital cities shall identify Jerusalem as the capital of Israel.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H57363324AC83437F90ABC566C0008ACD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Timetable</header>
 <paragraph id="H6D4D035C9951431FA7ACE77762AC5FFE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States that the United States Embassy in Israel should be established in Jerusalem as soon as possible, but not later than January 1, 2019.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE2901805A184C33A5401034E901D8F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Opening determination</header><text>Not more than 50 percent of the funds appropriated to the Department of State for fiscal year 2017 for <quote>Acquisition and Maintenance of Buildings Abroad</quote> may be obligated until the Secretary of State determines and reports to Congress that the United States Embassy in Jerusalem has officially opened.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H71014AE41A3C400E9BC337BEFFA44F72"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Fiscal years 2017 and 2018 funding</header>
 <paragraph id="H5F611D03DF28485C8D9C40E03E2A483C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fiscal year 2017</header><text>Of the funds authorized to be appropriated for <quote>Acquisition and Maintenance of Buildings Abroad</quote> for the Department of State for fiscal year 2017, such sums as may be necessary should be made available until expended only for construction and other costs associated with the establishment of the United States Embassy in Israel in the capital of Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H75D9819E6F1D44928B2AE48DB6815816"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fiscal year 2018</header><text>Of the funds authorized to be appropriated for <quote>Acquisition and Maintenance of Buildings Abroad</quote> for the Department of State for fiscal year 2018, such sums as may be necessary should be made available until expended only for construction and other costs associated with the establishment of the United States Embassy in Israel in the capital of Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8269EBBCEB984FA8BA2E86D479828D64"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>United States Embassy</quote> means the offices of the United States diplomatic mission and the residence of the United States chief of mission.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


