<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H210A150DD6EF4F2B96C9FB8A5381E698" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2585 IH: 21st Century Glass-Steagall Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2585</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170522">May 22, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reduce risks to the financial system by limiting banks’ ability to engage in certain risky
			 activities and limiting conflicts of interest, to reinstate certain
			 Glass-Steagall Act protections that were repealed by the
			 Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9AEA01E3085E4EE58891E730594844B1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H04EE11354FCA4208BDDD528FB64F9F1D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>21st Century Glass-Steagall Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9FFAFE6F98164451A1AE6BCB403B8ABF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header> <subsection id="H392405AB1586462985E3324F77322E11"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H903A387E1FA94A238BA3BA4224CB0B02"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in response to a financial crisis and the ensuing Great Depression, Congress enacted the Banking Act of 1933, known as the <quote>Glass-Steagall Act</quote>, to prohibit commercial banks from offering investment banking and insurance services;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H04B419297074494DBB58E8CB597E4C21"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a series of deregulatory decisions by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, in addition to decisions by Federal courts, permitted commercial banks to engage in an increasing number of risky financial activities that had previously been restricted under the Glass-Steagall Act, and also vastly expanded the meaning of the <quote>business of banking</quote> and <quote>closely related activities</quote> in banking law;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3EA302CAAC541998983B0E3159D50FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in 1999, Congress enacted the <quote>Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act</quote>, which repealed the Glass-Steagall Act separation between commercial and investment banking and allowed for complex cross-subsidies and interconnections between commercial and investment banks;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2A04C41E89F4F3D8EAB682729B09547"><enum>(4)</enum><text>former Kansas City Federal Reserve President Thomas Hoenig observed that <quote>with the elimination of Glass-Steagall, the largest institutions with the greatest ability to leverage their balance sheets increased their risk profile by getting into trading, market making, and hedge fund activities, adding ever greater complexity to their balance sheets.</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBECA6A987FF5425B8BFB441B6387029B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Financial Crisis Inquiry Report issued by the Financial Crisis Inquiry Commission concluded that, in the years between the passage of the Gramm-Leach Bliley Act and the global financial crisis, <quote>regulation and supervision of traditional banking had been weakened significantly, allowing commercial banks and thrifts to operate with fewer constraints and to engage in a wider range of financial activities, including activities in the shadow banking system.</quote> The Commission also concluded that <quote>[t]his deregulation made the financial system especially vulnerable to the financial crisis and exacerbated its effects.</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2208F5206B2749F79D926E8D55CA2124"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a report by the Financial Stability Oversight Council pursuant to section 123 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5333">12 U.S.C. 5333</external-xref>) states that increased complexity and diversity of financial activities at financial institutions may <quote>shift institutions towards more risk-taking, increase the level of interconnectedness among financial firms, and therefore may increase systemic default risk. These potential costs may be exacerbated in cases where the market perceives diverse and complex financial institutions as ‘too big to fail,’ which may lead to excessive risk taking and concerns about moral hazard.</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H02E824043DBB4C849E7301C7960BF909"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations report, <quote>Wall Street and the Financial Crisis: Anatomy of a Financial Collapse</quote>, states that repeal of the Glass-Steagall Act <quote>made it more difficult for regulators to distinguish between activities intended to benefit customers versus the financial institution itself. The expanded set of financial services investment banks were allowed to offer also contributed to the multiple and significant conflicts of interest that arose between some investment banks and their clients during the financial crisis.</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB5ABB42737734970B0E4BC7F91AD85EC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations report, <quote>JPMorgan Chase Whale Trades: A Case History of Derivatives Risks and Abuses</quote>, describes how traders at JPMorgan Chase made risky bets using excess deposits that were partly insured by the Federal Government;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC7ED66C7A404AF99D811BA62D43A018"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in Europe, the Vickers Independent Commission on Banking (for the United Kingdom) and the Liikanen Report (for the Euro area) have both found that there is no inherent reason to bundle <quote>retail banking</quote> with <quote>investment banking</quote> or other forms of relatively high risk securities trading, and European countries are set on a path of separating various activities that are currently bundled together in the business of banking;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB3D2A61CF6224F3ABC4A839CCEACD564"><enum>(10)</enum><text>private sector actors prefer having access to underpriced public sector insurance, whether explicit (for insured deposits) or implicit (for <quote>too big to fail</quote> financial institutions), to subsidize dangerous levels of risk-taking, which, from a broader social perspective, is not an advantageous arrangement; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H275A0C1B63B0458089C9172D5C6683C4"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the financial crisis, and the regulatory response to the crisis, has led to more mergers between financial institutions, creating greater financial sector consolidation and increasing the dominance of a few large, complex financial institutions that are generally considered to be <quote>too big to fail</quote>, and therefore are perceived by the markets as having an implicit guarantee from the Federal Government to bail them out in the event of their failure.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC997CBDD90A4C8E90376C85202BF19F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are—</text> <paragraph id="HEEFC7B0EE2A647E38D4368F09BBB62A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to reduce risks to the financial system by limiting the ability of banks to engage in activities other than socially valuable core banking activities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD464371C796A43D4BDC72788DC91128E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to protect taxpayers and reduce moral hazard by removing explicit and implicit government guarantees for high-risk activities outside of the core business of banking; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFC60ABA43DFF4D528F99EFB7B134B6A2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to eliminate any conflict of interest that arises from banks engaging in activities from which their profits are earned at the expense of their customers or clients.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0FC9EDF400B24DA3AD7D3AD86198E214"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H884494F73151445EA4E0F7908CC2BC9A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>bank holding company</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1841">12 U.S.C. 1841</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B8CEE688F734E68B27BAECAFEA6A51E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the terms <term>insurance company</term>, <term>insured depository institution</term>, <term>securities entity</term>, and <term>swaps entity</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 18(s)(6)(D) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, as added by section 4(a) of this Act.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HCAD59077E3F544068D71CEB0AF2CF4F1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Safe and sound banking</header>
 <subsection id="HD87A45BED7E744A2B685799645B5C9FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Covered insured depository institutions</header><text>Section 18(s) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1828">12 U.S.C. 1828(s)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C83637482AF443384064D31ECDE93CF" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H6642CE4603ED424BB7965EA3C8610ADA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Limitations on banking affiliations</header>
 <subparagraph id="H649447DFB8994A03A50B75AC571544A3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Prohibition on affiliations with nondepository entities</header><text>A covered insured depository institution may not—</text> <clause id="H8C50A920AF1C4DE5A6E4FADC43F519F1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be or become an affiliate of any insurance company, securities entity, or swaps entity;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H256E4CF724314FF0A8969B9A3B3C4EF1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be in common ownership or control with any insurance company, securities entity, or swaps entity; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE5C8CAFAF2B5414BBB91067B88A98415"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engage in any activity that would cause the covered insured depository institution to qualify as an insurance company, securities entity, or swaps entity.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AF89C593EE8486BB243492AC64FE187"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Individuals eligible to serve on boards of depository institutions</header>
 <clause id="H6212AB51CD3043E293832DF97F92A6E2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who is an officer, director, partner, or employee of any securities entity, insurance company, or swaps entity may not serve at the same time as an officer, director, employee, or other institution-affiliated party of any covered insured depository institution.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HED1AC076808747989BD1BCB5DC485E7D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause (i) shall not apply with respect to service by any individual which is otherwise prohibited under clause (i), if the appropriate Federal banking agency determines, by regulation with respect to a limited number of cases, that service by such an individual as an officer, director, employee, or other institution-affiliated party of a covered insured depository institution would not unduly influence—</text>
 <subclause id="HA4FD97D816D14C7788FA369B606338BC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the investment policies of the institution; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="HB8E3F2A6A24D46049110C366855151DC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the advice that the institution provides to customers.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H4F5E9C64CD6B4AB3AFBA9B6A62A74B7A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Termination of service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless the appropriate Federal banking agency makes a determination under clause (ii), an individual described in clause (i) who, as of the date of enactment of this paragraph, is serving as an officer, director, employee, or other institution-affiliated party of any covered insured depository institution shall terminate such service as soon as is practicable after such date of enactment, and in no event later than the end of the 60-day period beginning on that date of enactment.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFD556DB4233410490063FED3D29E56D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Termination of existing affiliations and activities</header>
 <clause id="H0418048B416547569F93321A3F7B0900"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Orderly termination of existing affiliations and activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any affiliation, common ownership or control, or activity of a covered insured depository institution with any securities entity, insurance company, swaps entity, or any other person, as of the date of enactment of this paragraph, which is prohibited under subparagraph (A) shall be terminated as soon as is practicable, and in no event later than the end of the 5-year period beginning on that date of enactment.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H886C7083A29A4A69A1BF3C6F4D580576"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Early termination</header><text>The appropriate Federal banking agency, at any time after opportunity for hearing, may order termination of an affiliation, common ownership or control, or activity prohibited by clause (i) before the end of the 5-year period described in clause (i), if the agency determines that such action—</text>
 <subclause id="HB619D671B2664F1F8CDA13AB67140AC2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is necessary to prevent undue concentration of resources, decreased or unfair competition, conflicts of interest, or unsound banking practices; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0FF7B8207F704441A47B8534C59456A9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is in the public interest.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H2AD20CF00C8840A2A918BFE2BFEED2BA"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>An appropriate Federal banking agency may extend the 5-year period described in clause (i) upon the request of a covered insured depository institution described in clause (i) for a period of not more than 6 months for each request received, if—</text>
 <subclause id="HBA1C326804314CE7868A8551492686AB"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the appropriate Federal banking agency certifies that an extension would promote the public interest and would not pose a significant threat to the stability of the banking system or financial markets in the United States; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3A04A962B3114BA08823442943605457"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any extensions granted under this clause, in the aggregate, do not exceed 1 year for any particular covered insured depository institution.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HFE4EBBFA361E4CC0A1E7DACFA783A28E"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Requirements for entities receiving an extension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receipt of each extension under clause (iii), the covered insured depository institution shall notify shareholders of the covered insured depository institution and the general public that it failed to comply with the requirements of clause (i).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2033A6A183040A3B44B8D58F0944582"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the following definitions shall apply:</text> <clause commented="no" id="H1BA9914A58C841AF8F198E2D0FCC7131"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Covered insured depository institution</header><text>The term <term>covered insured depository institution</term>—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="HD73658A5E8A342A59D1B9CD82EAB257D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term in section 3(c)(2); and</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HD630AEF5BD14429F9A9F290806C91276"><enum>(II)</enum><text>does not include a savings association controlled by a savings and loan holding company, as described in section 10(c)(9)(C) of the Home Owners' Loan Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1467a">12 U.S.C. 1467a(c)(9)(C)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HB40554797EE74EDC9CDEEC03E3EC6556"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Insurance company</header><text>The term <term>insurance company</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2(q) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1841">12 U.S.C. 1841(q)</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H8FA3DA4139F1428693E8E99D0F580695"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Securities entity</header><text>The term <term>securities entity</term>—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="HF1BF92D7FE314B53BCC95D00D84D6F2B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>includes any entity engaged in—</text>
 <item commented="no" id="H1D7B070F2A4442BA91206B3EEBECA014"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the issuance, flotation, underwriting, public sale, or distribution of stocks, bonds, debentures, notes, or other securities;</text>
 </item><item commented="no" id="HEA3EE13CFAA444F3B199C43E923BF6F0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>market making;</text> </item><item commented="no" id="H8220C0BDF791404189EDC91B9F984AA5"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>activities of a broker or dealer, as those terms are defined in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>);</text>
 </item><item commented="no" id="H852BCA90E4D14C109B63FC9FF3906356"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>activities of a futures commission merchant;</text> </item><item commented="no" id="H3CDBD6CA23EC490583309D0191B393B1"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>activities of an investment adviser or investment company, as those terms are defined in section 202(a) of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80b-2">15 U.S.C. 80b–2(a)</external-xref>) and section 3(a)(1) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-3">15 U.S.C. 80a–3(a)(1)</external-xref>), respectively; or</text>
 </item><item commented="no" id="H13DB3C6C32B4475CB172C660E3457B79"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>hedge fund or private equity investments in the securities of either privately or publicly held companies; and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H64002D91388C4BBFA37EF2A7D415A473"><enum>(II)</enum><text>does not include an entity that, pursuant to its authorized trust and fiduciary activities—</text> <item commented="no" id="HA0EABE32171649DA85E6E1862E94C070"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>purchases and sells investments for the account of its customers; or</text>
 </item><item commented="no" id="HA780394FB9BF4DE6AFBAF25E0A193087"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>provides financial or investment advice to its customers.</text> </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H2D64C21393A244FBBA711780446DD23E"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Swaps entity</header><text>The term <term>swaps entity</term> means any swap dealer, security-based swap dealer, major swap participant, or major security-based swap participant, that is registered under—</text>
 <subclause id="H669D58EFA9C043A7A045215BD94F300E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1">7 U.S.C. 1</external-xref> et seq.); or</text> </subclause><subclause id="HF7ABD41BF46E40D6824089A813ABF3C2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78a">15 U.S.C. 78a</external-xref> et seq.).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H49F3130066C34624A66B7784F1630B21"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on banking activities</header><text>Section 21 of the Banking Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/378">12 U.S.C. 378</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD29261946347468597ADF592E2C0D181" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HDBC260A4C304439198B39C80EAF800EB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Business of receiving deposits</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>business of receiving deposits</term> includes the establishment and maintenance of any transaction account (as defined in section 19(b)(1)(C) of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/461">12 U.S.C. 461(b)(1)(C)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF0435C780D5E4A5FAF34C62AA54956C4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Permitted activities of national banks</header><text>The paragraph designated as <quote>Seventh</quote> of section 5136 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/24">12 U.S.C. 24</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73EE9DFF1F9049B2BE01508C08C957D8" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H23EC5CB339E846318A392742FA58FC1B"><enum>Seventh.</enum><header>Permitted activities</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H021BEDE06B294E0582DB8E5C0871DF62"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To exercise by its board of directors or duly authorized officers or agents, subject to law, all such powers as are necessary to carry on the business of banking.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7317926173E4095ADBB78485D83F163" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Business of banking</header><text>As used in this paragraph, the term <term>business of banking</term> shall be limited to the following core banking services:</text> <clause id="H1297357DAD39446A9B35DD44344FFD04"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Receiving deposits</header><text>A national banking association may engage in the business of receiving deposits.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H065A4DC112B34034AB35C21E68B27AC0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Extensions of credit</header><text>A national banking association may—</text> <subclause id="HAA51DF7A639346CB9668A80B179B65DD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>extend credit to individuals, businesses, not for profit organizations, and other entities;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD9DAEF95096E47DEB85D33F01D50F7D7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>discount and negotiate promissory notes, drafts, bills of exchange, and other evidences of debt; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2075057E82A74303AAF894F75B0FE143"><enum>(III)</enum><text>loan money on personal security.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HF644F0CF620943C9B08D1E13A944FDA5"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Payment systems</header><text>A national banking association may participate in payment systems, defined as instruments, banking procedures, and interbank funds transfer systems that ensure the circulation of money.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6C0C86FE4773453B9D53185BB35F3343"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Coin and bullion</header><text>A national banking association may buy, sell, and exchange coin and bullion.</text> </clause><clause id="HA5A5CCE1B0014AE081383B16BF2AABDC"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Investments in securities</header> <subclause id="H7BEA1761E3234186AF46BFBDFC5D3BAC"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A national banking association may invest in investment securities, defined as marketable obligations evidencing indebtedness of any person, copartnership, association, or corporation in the form of bonds, notes, or debentures (commonly known as <quote>investment securities</quote>), obligations of the Federal Government, or any State or subdivision thereof, and includes the definition of <term>investment securities</term>, as may be jointly prescribed by regulation by—</text>
 <item id="HEF2B805B16A648A4AEC6BD74FCAA59CC"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the Comptroller of the Currency;</text> </item><item id="HCE93D2F1645E4C5C9D7321D74D4590AC"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation; and</text>
 </item><item id="HBCD80964E397404E873DD77B13C6D0F2"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="H209CA89214384CD18DCA7A8EF08AE955"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The business of dealing in securities and stock by a national banking association shall be limited to—</text>
 <item id="HB655516FA41D405090F717E76F9A1AF3"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>purchasing and selling such securities and stock without recourse, solely upon the order, and for the account of, customers, and in no case for its own account, and the national banking association shall not underwrite any issue of securities or stock; and</text>
 </item><item id="H726BECD63A064935B0C4B34B18B81E4D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>purchasing for its own account investment securities under such limitations and restrictions as the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System may jointly prescribe, by regulation.</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H7B156C9741AE4427BF16D93854289EF3"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Prohibition on amount of investment</header><text>In no event shall the total amount of the investment securities of any single obligor or maker, held by the association for its own account, exceed 10 percent of its capital stock actually paid in and unimpaired and 10 percent of its unimpaired surplus fund, except that such limitation shall not require any association to dispose of any securities lawfully held by it on August 23, 1935.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB217D6A7C3A34B8C91C0773CCF8B9D6B" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Prohibition against transactions involving structured or synthetic products</header><text>A national banking association may not—</text> <clause id="H97F68D79B0D24A1DA6BF9DAC24A19785"><enum>(i)</enum><text>invest in a structured or synthetic product, a financial instrument in which a return is calculated based on the value of, or by reference to the performance of, a security, commodity, swap, other asset, or an entity, or any index or basket composed of securities, commodities, swaps, other assets, or entities, other than customarily determined interest rates; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H634F3C36E2F2418998B3860C42F3C2D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>otherwise engage in the business of receiving deposits or extending credit for transactions involving structured or synthetic products.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6F6C13379E784202AD37485C27225608"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Permitted Activities of Federal Savings Associations</header><text>Section 5(c)(1) of the Home Owners' Loan Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1464">12 U.S.C. 1464(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HCE26CD943CE74FC2964AC98B35510488"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (Q); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6EC4E5C3FEB46B2B0AE20F2BF128D39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (R) through (U) as subparagraphs (Q) through (T), respectively.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H61BE1983DE984AE881C39C819E2B9EF3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Closely related activities</header><text>Section 4(c) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1843">12 U.S.C. 1843(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H2B8877BC07864E4B81CF659312F72DE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>had been determined</quote> and all that follows through the end and inserting the following: “are so closely related to banking so as to be a proper incident thereto, as provided under this paragraph or any rule or regulation issued by the Board under this paragraph, provided that for purposes of this paragraph, closely related shall not be considered to include—</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F8D0663614F48A2B377D669B9146A78" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H1A680784858D4024A8A15783B637799B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serving as an investment adviser (as defined in section 2(a) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-2">15 U.S.C. 80a–2(a)</external-xref>) to an investment company registered under that Act, including sponsoring, organizing, and managing a closed-end investment company;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H339CE18674D946EC8767E5416B7F0E54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>agency transactional services for customer investments, except that this subparagraph may not be construed as prohibiting purchases and sales of investments for the account of customers conducted by a bank (or subsidiary thereof) pursuant to the bank’s trust and fiduciary powers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97D3DA60ABCB4DFF9063403CB8803E3C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>investment transactions as principal, except for activities specifically allowed by paragraph (14); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4710863F22114661B775F77A7C4B12BA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>management consulting and counseling activities;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA9830A7A0BF04B47819447B068EDFB13"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (13), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2EBFDEB4B9E94173BE9EAEB811945721"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (14) as paragraph (15); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3EB4FE3CEE354E41A0A2E6B5C94ACB06"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (13) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51F33AC1A96846E6A58660B9DAE1D685" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HF9E874FDEFA94EA49FEB4E7B24435B13"><enum>(14)</enum><text>purchasing, as an end user, any swap, to the extent that—</text> <subparagraph id="HA700DF4FF1644008878D644AA9C3995E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the purchase of any such swap occurs contemporaneously with the underlying hedged item or hedged transaction;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB408B401662B42608C0A539EFB83F766"><enum>(B)</enum><text>there is formal documentation identifying the hedging relationship with particularity at the inception of the hedge; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF5FA7E92B0449BB98B5715732126C9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the swap is being used to hedge against exposure to—</text> <clause id="H8E4B9D53FF054A52AFDD9BF192505E53"><enum>(i)</enum><text>changes in the value of an individual recognized asset or liability or an identified portion thereof that is attributable to a particular risk;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE4302F7CD2904DCDBE6E2D3ECABEEFC2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>changes in interest rates; or</text> </clause><clause id="HA38D9FB3FA624919AA476106AA33F77B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>changes in the value of currency; or</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H1BEB1443C1F94C308322FC63C621F3F0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Prohibited activities</header><text>Section 4(a) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1843">12 U.S.C. 1843(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H16B4A55E09844E3B80B2AFD6A6579A03"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>, or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBA53BFA4A297486F962432DBDD5341ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the <quote>requirements of this Act.</quote> and inserting <quote>requirements of this Act; or</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0D40DFBBE0194AB28CFBB67879BF7A93"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting before the undesignated matter following paragraph (2) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H887C61AF78914A57B702E32363838BD5" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H449A4131AFEE4886A586AEB2AC3883D2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>with the exception of the activities permitted under subsection (c), engage in the business of a <quote>securities entity</quote> or a <quote>swaps entity</quote>, as those terms are defined in section 18(s)(6)(D) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, including dealing or making markets in securities, repurchase agreements, exchange traded and over-the-counter swaps, as defined by the Commodity Futures Trading Commission and the Securities and Exchange Commission, or structured or synthetic products, as defined in the paragraph designated as <quote>Seventh</quote> of section 5136 of the Revised Statutes of the United States, or any other over-the-counter securities, swaps, contracts, or any other agreement that derives its value from, or takes on the form of, such securities, derivatives, or contracts;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC877F6E40B144F109406D4DE9C854BAC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>engage in proprietary trading, as provided by section 13, or any rule or regulation under that section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H552B1D740B6F4EBCAF27C9E4846F7BD0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>own, sponsor, or invest in a hedge fund, or private equity fund, or any other fund, as provided by section 13, or any rule or regulation under that section, or any other fund that exhibits the characteristics of a fund that takes on proprietary trading activities or positions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B1DDAB35C2A4F7F956B4143336BDBCA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>hold ineligible securities or derivatives;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5C362938BEED43D88E436F5CD7841A77"><enum>(7)</enum><text>engage in market-making; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H170993569D5245A3B962A53B64B3BCB6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>engage in prime brokerage activities.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H398907AFB5FD4C09B506E5A1213D6D71"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Anti-Evasion</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H40F2031883C04C2EADF5FBDA76C46F56"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any attempt to structure any contract, investment, instrument, or product in such a manner that the purpose or effect of such contract, investment, instrument, or product is to evade or attempt to evade the prohibitions described in section 18(s)(6) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, section 21(c) of the Banking Act of 1933, the paragraph designated as <quote>Seventh</quote> of section 5136 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/24">12 U.S.C. 24</external-xref>), section 5(c)(1) of the Home Owners’ Loan Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1464">12 U.S.C. 1464(c)(1)</external-xref>), or section 4(a) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1843">12 U.S.C. 1843(a)</external-xref>), as added or amended by this section, shall be considered a violation of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1811">12 U.S.C. 1811</external-xref> et seq.), the Banking Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/73/66">Public Law 73–66</external-xref>; 48 Stat. 162), section 5136 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/24">12 U.S.C. 24</external-xref>), the Home Owners’ Loan Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1461">12 U.S.C. 1461</external-xref> et seq.), and the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1841">12 U.S.C. 1841</external-xref> et seq.), as appropriate.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H756C6CFA85FD47B88AF867178B8F6ED6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HBF614013D67645FA8DDDBAC1B7C2B57D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if a Federal agency has reasonable cause to believe that an insured depository institution, securities entity, swaps entity, insurance company, bank holding company, or other entity over which that Federal agency has regulatory authority has made an investment or engaged in an activity in a manner that functions as an evasion of the prohibitions described in paragraph (1) (including through an abuse of any permitted activity) or otherwise violates such prohibitions, the Federal agency shall—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HBF2175A0687043B58DE95D45679FA975"><enum>(i)</enum><text>order, after due notice and opportunity for hearing, the entity to terminate the activity and, as relevant, dispose of the investment;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7465DF807CF4484EBBA6A9CD5E551B6C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>order, after the procedures described in clause (i), the entity to pay a penalty equal to 10 percent of the entity’s net profits, averaged over the previous 3 years, into the Treasury of the United States; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4D2B64E86C2746269944F651240360D5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>initiate proceedings described in section 8(e) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1818">12 U.S.C. 1818(e)</external-xref>) for individuals involved in evading the prohibitions described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9AC63A3FE98F40078A462999CFF4709C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to limit the inherent authority of any Federal agency or State regulatory authority to further restrict any investments or activities under otherwise applicable provisions of law.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9F6C7FFF29F442EB1B0AE93B91EC4BF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every year thereafter, each Federal agency having regulatory authority over any entity described in paragraph (2)(A) shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and make available to the public a report, which shall identify—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H236882129F2D453DB2EA6BDCDD9AE223"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number and character of any activities that took place in the preceding year that function as an evasion of the prohibitions described in paragraph (1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72C972DA27EA47829B842D98A9DAAD76"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the names of the particular entities engaged in those activities; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7AE0C2049694FF8ABE5C19BA37612CB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the actions of the Federal agency taken under paragraph (2).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HEDA9152F3726491C95AB7E2EEAE60CB0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Attestation</header><text>Section 4 of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1843">12 U.S.C. 1843</external-xref>), as amended by section 5(a) of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDEC28588A9014DD393DD4CC79BB64764" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H2782C04EE76A43C1AE98FE4A940ADFF1"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Attestation</header><text>Executives of any bank holding company or its affiliate shall attest in writing, under penalty of perjury, that the bank holding company or affiliate is not engaged in any activity that is prohibited under subsection (a), except to the extent that such activity is permitted under subsection (c).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H80C75FB3CB95436BAAA115AF75BF66B2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Repeal of Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act provisions</header>
			<subsection id="HC94345D34DD64288B2DC32357D77C1D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Termination of financial holding company designation</header>
 <paragraph id="H2DD7BD08743D4E99B8ABD9B9546952B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 4 of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1843">12 U.S.C. 1843</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsections (k), (l), (m), (n), and (o).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H5123EDE30E9C48C58869B49AF9339948"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transition</header>
 <subparagraph id="H824A0D60173C4CC5BF3395894014AE49"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Orderly termination of existing affiliation</header><text>In the case of a bank holding company which, pursuant to the amendments made by paragraph (1), is no longer authorized to control or be affiliated with any entity that was permissible for a financial holding company on the day before the date of enactment of this Act, any affiliation, ownership or control, or activity by the bank holding company that is not permitted for a bank holding company shall be terminated as soon as is practicable, and in no event later than the end of the 5-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE72F2D6C982B4EB8A811A2D3CA1420CF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Early termination</header><text>At any time, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System (in this section referred to as the <quote>Board</quote>), after opportunity for hearing, may terminate an affiliation prohibited by subparagraph (A) before the end of the 5-year period described in subparagraph (A) if the Board determines that such action—</text>
 <clause id="H9C73897B0C584D7D9BD8A545688876B4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is necessary to prevent undue concentration of resources, decreased or unfair competition, conflicts of interest, or unsound banking practices; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7DDC50F018DA4DBF9E8314E2A5125C0B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is in the public interest.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26056689F0484BFD8DB79C94436264AB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>The Board may extend the 5-year period described in subparagraph (A) upon the request of a bank holding company described in subparagraph (A) for a period of not more than 6 months for each request received if—</text>
 <clause id="HF883D3E92E6B4050AAB53420B4657358"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Board certifies that an extension would promote the public interest and would not pose a significant risk to the stability of the banking system or financial markets of the United States; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H53B78F34434D400B9A32E51DA1550E89"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any extensions granted under this subparagraph, in the aggregate, do not exceed 1 year for any particular bank holding company.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6202718690DD447FA434F56341ECA64B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Requirements for entities receiving an extension</header><text>Upon receipt of each extension under subparagraph (C), a bank holding company shall notify the shareholders of the bank holding company and the general public that the bank holding company has failed to comply with the requirements of subparagraph (A).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE4CE7D33BD944160A2FD0D844201BA6A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Financial subsidiaries of national banks disallowed</header>
 <paragraph id="H84E61151D6CD4E3481A0E06069390000"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 5136A of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/24a">12 U.S.C. 24a</external-xref>) is repealed.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H872AA54CC7C54577933412F2EF681F6A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transition</header> <subparagraph id="H12CDE0583C9C4171BBB52FD9F7DE2C76"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Orderly termination of existing affiliation</header><text>In the case of a national bank which, pursuant to the amendment made by paragraph (1), is no longer authorized to control or be affiliated with a financial subsidiary as of the date of enactment of this Act, such affiliation, ownership or control, or activity shall be terminated as soon as is practicable, and in no event later than the end of the 5-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4588E7FAF7E244748DDCDDC2F9E1BD5F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Early termination</header><text>At any time, the Comptroller of the Currency (in this section referred to as the <quote>Comptroller</quote>), after opportunity for hearing, may terminate an affiliation prohibited by subparagraph (A) before the end of the 5-year period described in subparagraph (A) if the Comptroller determines that such action—</text>
 <clause id="H832DF8C6E18341B5A1BE6ACDEA8454E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is necessary to prevent undue concentration of resources, decreased or unfair competition, conflicts of interest, or unsound banking practices; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9BAE8F839B60484187217872DED880C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is in the public interest.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE58573AB36F44153BD012F516B5E3D63"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Extension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller may extend the 5-year period described in subparagraph (A) upon the request of a national bank described in subparagraph (A) for a period of not more than 6 months for each request received if—</text>
 <clause id="H4FA6DA5448F643BDB5555F0ADAD2385F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Comptroller certifies that an extension would promote the public interest and would not pose a significant risk to the stability of the banking system or financial markets of the United States; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H810B274E5B664A1FBAA3BF168BD5358E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any extensions granted under this subparagraph, in the aggregate, do not exceed 1 year for any particular national bank.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2538E307EB814B64BA3012B92768698C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Requirements for entities receiving an extension</header><text>Upon receipt of each extension under subparagraph (C), a national bank shall notify the shareholders of the national bank and the general public that the national bank has failed to comply with the requirements described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEEC2BD339F54DF0B324C8088EBB125C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for chapter one of title LXII of the Revised Statutes is amended by striking the item relating to section 5136A.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBBE5685E95C546DB862802AAD10830E8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Repeal of provision relating to foreign banks filing as financial holding companies</header><text>Section 8(c) of the International Banking Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/3106">12 U.S.C. 3106(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (3).</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H511AE7E40CFD4C5FBF63E8C0B13767E6"><enum>6.</enum><header>Repeal of bankruptcy provisions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title 11, United States Code, is amended by repealing sections 555, 559, 560, and 562.</text> </section><section id="H4592B775D52D464F9C1253CEB8C9A181"><enum>7.</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header> <subsection id="H7E927EB14F5D4280AA77618B1ADB5ADC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Bank Holding Company Act of 1956</header><text>The Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1841">12 U.S.C. 1841</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD2AD9E670E434D46B418754D755212EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 2 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1841">12 U.S.C. 1841</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="HE3A9BF2F128445658A209E5EA3D3B705"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (p); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCD9E2AD845B4A13AED3581F8023711C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (q) as subsection (p); and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AB9A2BC984846ACBA8735773ECA13E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 5 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1844">12 U.S.C. 1844</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEB268896ED1F49DFB4C408C110DC1E61"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking the last sentence;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39F112076DB445CEA4C0456ECA8B602A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking paragraphs (3), (4), and (5); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A6BCE47BD05430C8DEFA3FEDCF3D9E6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subsection (g).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8FC00ED4EBD34CDB9471B1950021C050"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bank Holding Company Act Amendments of 1970</header><text>Section 106(a) of the Bank Holding Company Act Amendments of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1971">12 U.S.C. 1971(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the last sentence.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H45159B8ADFCE4A7BB1A83F356A0188AA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clayton Act</header><text>Section 7A(c) of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/18a">15 U.S.C. 18a(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H20342177FA9C419EBFADA7880127D59F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>, except that</quote> and all that follows and inserting a semicolon; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E40D7C98CD4460490D50C426117754C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>, except that</quote> and all that follows and inserting a semicolon.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9A67D56F6B24D80852FD8529B2BFAE8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Commodity Exchange Act</header><text>The Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1">7 U.S.C. 1</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4DC52C83FFC04F74AB9ECFF6992E6D15"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 1a(21)(G) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1a">7 U.S.C. 1a(21)(G)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>(as defined in section 2 of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956)</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA92ABE7701E5417EB2F228E8E17BDBCD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 2(c)(2)(B)(i)(II)(dd) (7 U.S.C. 2(c)(2)(B)(i)(II)(dd)), by striking <quote>(as defined in section 2 of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956)</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D4C5C12A85540BC85E4EBA655DB91AA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 2(h)(7)(C)(i)(VIII) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2">7 U.S.C. 2(h)(7)(C)(i)(VIII)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>, as defined in section 4(k) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H92C28701EAD24909BBBC1B6396DDE24F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Community Reinvestment Act of 1977</header><text>Section 804 of the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/2903">12 U.S.C. 2903</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2348E4C399214232A50AC7C23EF03216"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (c); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1182CC7EE15C4FFA87AC6616D8148D1E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H492B7669793B4132AECFEBAB17E3C71E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act</header><text>Section 201(a)(11)(B) of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5381">12 U.S.C. 5381(a)(11)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>for purposes of section 4(k) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1843">12 U.S.C. 1843(k)</external-xref>)</quote> each place that term appears.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFF44233C5D9A4EA8B70DD01D689F39F6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Federal Deposit Insurance Act</header><text>The Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1811">12 U.S.C. 1811</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD1077AF461CC4E14BC407BEF9D3C0807"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 8(b)(3) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1818">12 U.S.C. 1818(b)(3)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>section 50</quote> and inserting <quote>section 48</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4B9A53B1E474F6E89C57290C0FDD72F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 18(u)(1)(B) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1828">12 U.S.C. 1828(u)(1)(B)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>or section 45 of this Act</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE757BEB2B97E4701B4A7A18CDE843074"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking sections 45 and 46 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1831v">12 U.S.C. 1831v</external-xref> and 1831w); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4278F85AD3684B2EB1AFA102C3BCE717"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by redesignating sections 47 through 50 as sections 45 through 48, respectively.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57F2EF57233A458E8645573383EF7D1D"><enum>(h)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal Reserve Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/221">12 U.S.C. 221</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H138BB784DB3C43928432556494505719"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the 20th undesignated paragraph of section 9 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/335">12 U.S.C. 335</external-xref>), by striking the last sentence; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6EAC1171880642F28E5B7D55D8A08D11"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 23A (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/371c">12 U.S.C. 371c</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A3CF6896A734B99981B0F5B40E4A64E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(11), by striking <quote>subparagraph (H) or (I) of section 4(k)(4) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 or</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H20867B3CE91446F6965D84FE19B3FED7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subsection (e); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD5D11AF9E8240049A44A4C81280154C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (f) as subsection (e).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED6B73E2347F453DB8B2A928D2563037"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Financial Stability Act of 2010</header><text>The Financial Stability Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5301">12 U.S.C. 5301</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8A9B85D3EE9D40DDAD86A73B05119B66"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 113(c)(5) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5323">12 U.S.C. 5323(c)(5)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>(as defined in section 4(k) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956)</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D0FB15BFE844EAEA56B714961308F36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 163 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5363">12 U.S.C. 5363</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76AD7360EA214D38A6FDD5549A97A2C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7AC6BB17334B48A4AF079E124416B780"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>(a)</quote> and all that follows through <quote>For purposes</quote> and inserting <quote>For purposes</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC10609151E154DD58ED49A14327DEF70"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 167(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5367">12 U.S.C. 5367(b)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>under section 4(k) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956</quote> each place that term appears; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H675006EE9A7644C9BDB2FB7026DC441B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 171(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5371">12 U.S.C. 5371(b)</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0A7AD7328D843DEA3D14C0CC049A4DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C71AECAB5314BAFA70D34124487AAB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (4) through (7) as paragraphs (3) through (6), respectively.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H092B86B6430E4C1095A5A4B2569F0932"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act</header><text>The Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/102">Public Law 106–102</external-xref>; 113 Stat. 1338) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA97854AC23B147488CD8D7270C558618"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking section 115 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1820a">12 U.S.C. 1820a</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF28D7A968C7B45D294C6A7DAA8D65553"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 307(f) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6715">15 U.S.C. 6715(f)</external-xref>), by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H55FCDA0A7BE44173A01FABB72C9288AA" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H0977A12BA0254497920C08510F4C5DF7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Board</header><text>The term <term>Board</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1841">12 U.S.C. 1841</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD583055F9EC49CDA73A52217420EEF4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 505(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6805">15 U.S.C. 6805(c)</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="HD03EFE3CDD5E463890715770F163EE6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 47(g)(2)(B)(iii) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act </quote> and inserting <quote>section 45(g)(2)(B)(iii) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8EF1BDC289414DCAAD4F5D75C16B7C4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 47(a)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 45(a)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4CB4EDA9020434C8961955C1F7BA6BF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 509(3)(A) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6809">15 U.S.C. 6809(3)(A)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>as described in section 4(k) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8AECB35CF4034332879A993B7B67D548"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Home Owners' Loan Act</header><text>Section 10(c) of the Home Owners' Loan Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1467a">12 U.S.C. 1467a(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CE299606CA540359A818ADEABB27323"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking subparagraph (H); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H650CA9802AD047D490576D2796A75D98"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (9)(A), by striking <quote>permitted</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>permitted under paragraph (1)(C) or (2) of this subsection.</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11E72A83AEDE480485F7033E93209F0F"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Internal Revenue Code</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/864">Section 864(f)(4)(C)(ii)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>(within the meaning of section 2(p) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1841">12 U.S.C. 1841(p)</external-xref>)</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA331F8C7041B47BCBE80001FD7C9DDBB"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Payment, Clearing, and Settlement Supervision Act of 2010</header><text>Section 803(5)(A) of the Payment, Clearing, and Settlement Supervision Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5462">12 U.S.C. 5462(5)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80A0DA6CA6CE42E5A502C78D51633144"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (viii), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H251F349178404FAB9A78E762B43E4286"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (ix), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a period; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6AB2D89D04524665B118CCD8E6816939"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking clause (x).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF274FCCCF00249D3ACB1AF03A9DB5044"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Securities Exchange Act of 1934</header><text>The Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78a">15 U.S.C. 78a</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H79CB325E1A14499A902619567BBCAC59"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 3(a)(4)(B)(vi)(II) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)(4)(B)(vi)(II)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>other than</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>other than a registered broker or dealer.</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEEE1E69B37D4408C9AC248E968F570C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 3C(g)(3)(A) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c-3">15 U.S.C. 78c–3(g)(3)(A)</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3423671B8E90452BB1ED68C77A15F0D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (vi), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB698E1AB1039422D9A034D4CF62CD51B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (vii), by striking the semicolon and inserting a period; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF552478F0BF14212915431482BDAD771"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking clause (viii).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCF9105ABAAF64D0DBAA967577B5FCB70"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Title 11</header><text>Title 11, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H968081FAACF44EC1A9630C254A608207"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 101—</text> <subparagraph id="H686D4AF3EFDC4A638BBC3F84AC8311B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (25)(E), by striking <quote>, measured in accordance with section 562</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EEC117C40B246459409056AA6A671EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (47)(A)(v), by striking <quote>, measured in accordance with section 562 of this title</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC15421380D7648FCAA44617E90A1A500"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (53B)(A)(vi), by striking <quote>, measured in accordance with section 562</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4AEFE8A117B4BB0A837D8E7F7AB7D76"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 103(a), by striking <quote>555 through 557, and 559 through 562</quote> and inserting <quote>556, 557, and 561</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C0FFB5E809D4E1B91777A907E52A5F0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 362(b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H473DC12059A249B085A29378D08A7110"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>555 or</quote> each place that term appears;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29F08C4990864B44A6516A57D84A3D5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>(as defined in section 559)</quote> each place that term appears;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A857BF26BAE42C8B4128BCAD0F5668A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (17), by striking <quote>(as defined in section 560)</quote> each place that term appears; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H079512DA2C6449B681EDDD927FFFD55A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (27), by striking <quote>(as defined in section 555, 556, 559, or 560)</quote> each place that term appears and inserting <quote>(as defined in section 556)</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0CEDE37AD7F40B48DA805C774919998"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 502(g)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF11687E1F156478EB97590E5EEBA76F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(1)</quote> before <quote>A claim</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1C3EC8C2BCB4041BE03BDBDD7300050"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2);</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7E0AF6EA2EA4117B80D5EB8D6C5E6D6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 553—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0B671B22488D4976A1A86AC4438ECA59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="H1EC545F6E6974640B0DDB58E47BA15E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(B)(ii), by striking <quote>555, 556, 559, 560, or 561</quote> and inserting <quote>556 or 561</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD85EC5410F3F4F819001A090BCE6912E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(C), by striking <quote>555, 556, 559, 560, or 561</quote> and inserting <quote>556 or 561</quote>; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5016B9A2D91D4D46A0932FEF4B48E230"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by striking <quote>555, 556, 559, 560, 561</quote> and inserting <quote>556, 561</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCAADDC4C36834854B552EED482E6776E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in section 561(b)(1), by striking <quote>555, 556, 559, or 560</quote> and inserting <quote>556</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BB7A42CAFA842A8A5AA23330B7602C5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in section 741(7)(A)(xi), by striking <quote>, measured in accordance with section 562</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB705DAB85B4749ADB0204730DCF9E781"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in section 761(4)(J), by striking <quote>, measured in accordance with section 562</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BEA178367104D5CA9AE54DEB76A9F5C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in section 901(a), by striking <quote>555, 556, 557, 559, 560, 561, 562</quote> and inserting <quote>556, 557, 561</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


