<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7DF644C770B04DE2B4AE177B3E4CFD50" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3778 IH: Direct Creation, Advancement, and Retention of Employment Opportunity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3778</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170914">September 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award grants for the recruitment, retention, and advancement of direct care workers.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4629B5ACAECE469AB97D2483194E1D2F" style="OLC">
 <section id="H93C377A67BE54373B3B2AAE39B146067" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Direct Creation, Advancement, and Retention of Employment Opportunity Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Direct CARE Opportunity Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB74AD6A0B933489D992A708E8A382E28"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H9AC5450971804ED780729E0896F0C8F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Millions of seniors and persons with disabilities in the United States require assistance with activities of daily living in order to live independently and participate in their communities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB8FC07D72B54F2A9D9DFBBB14CC9CD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The assistance of direct care workers allows seniors and persons with disabilities to live with dignity, safety and independence in their own homes and communities and in the most integrated settings appropriate to their needs and preferences.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA4BD66D664A45F2A18CADBE952E7E0A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Institute of Medicine has found that direct care workers provide the bulk of services for older adults in nursing homes, assisted living facilities, and individuals’ homes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H701600B5DC6E445589163F77246C6B45"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau of Labor Statistics projects that personal care aides and home health aides will be two of the occupations with the most new jobs created in the country by 2024.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D3519DD1748475FA2975ED6AA6D290E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Many direct care workers lack access to a career ladder or advanced training opportunities and, according to PHI, more than half of home care workers have completed no formal education beyond high school, making quality, transferable training essential to success on the job.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9CEEC039942468D85504F27665FD81D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>According to PHI, direct care workers earn a median wage of just over $10 an hour and frequently are not provided the workplace-based benefits that would allow them to care for themselves and their families.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1DC149FA1DE54B5994AED07974DB0DCC"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to National Women’s Law Center's analysis of Census Bureau data, the vast majority of direct care workers are women, and women of color represent nearly half of the direct care workforce.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA07E5ACC9604C1DA9052507C4CAAFEF"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the Federal Commission on Long-Term Care, there is high turnover and workforce shortages in direct care occupations, which can contribute to reduced care quality.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H498074A474FC4337933B4572F08C1759"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Institute of Medicine found that to ensure that the United States is prepared to meet the health care needs of older Americans during the 21st century, it is essential that the capacity of the direct care workforce be enhanced in both size and ability to meet their health care and quality of life needs.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H14E6AC47652643F091990C09502006BF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants for recruitment, retention, and advancement of direct care workers</header>
 <subsection id="H6376C1C3E7A84507AC9174EBC1DAB8C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To award grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall award grants to not more than 15 eligible entities to conduct projects for purposes of recruiting, retaining, or providing advancement opportunities to direct care workers.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HE0539D867BC346A28BC030259CB2AC83"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header>
 <paragraph id="H4F48725A01D24B92880346394287EB94"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grant period</header><text>A grant under this section shall be for not less than 5 years.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC46800BFE2F14C368EF54BF1557B1CC7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Length of project</header><text>A project assisted with a grant awarded under this section shall be conducted for not less than 3 years.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C54EFE699464D6299F052FF4101DC0F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Project plans</header>
 <paragraph id="HA0439A6CC7EA449187657DE9F2C8D5CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary a project plan at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may determine, which shall contain the information described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H831A8BE9117346C4BDBF71E26DDD6D85"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each project plan submitted by an eligible entity under paragraph (1) shall include a description of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF7783234047B4ABAB69C0716BD937AD2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Current or projected workforce vacancies and supply of direct care workers in the State or region to be served by the eligible entity, and the geographic scope of the workforce to be served.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0A47619A677478B8FDE79162C44BB92"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Specific efforts and strategies that the project will undertake to reduce barriers to recruitment, retention, and advancement of direct care workers, including whether such efforts will include—</text>
 <clause id="H9020C29EC8D64E13955FB6DD823106CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assessment of the wages or other compensation or benefits necessary to recruit and retain direct care workers, conducted in consultation with individuals employed as direct care workers, representatives of such workers, individuals assisted by such workers, and the families of such individuals;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H82BB73061D8F44409365D756C1977026"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analysis of reliable data that has previously been collected with respect to such wages or other compensation or benefits;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBFB42A3596E947A3B7C74FF53E58C990"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">validation and implementation of successful training models, standards, and curricula (such as the models, standards, and curricula used in the grants awarded under section 2008(b) of the Social Security Act for developing training competencies and certification programs for direct care workers (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397g">42 U.S.C. 1397g</external-xref>)) or through work-based learning strategies, career pathways, supervision, or mentoring; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3223967B6966473C95F09D1B6B4003F8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other supportive services or benefits provided to create or sustain employment for direct care workers.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0A270CC1C5934BA69B7916331077ACEB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The models, standards, and curricula the eligible entity will carry out under subparagraph (B).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DB3210B071E4A6C839D6D1E5D03FAD0"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other supportive services provided to assist in the goals of the project, if applicable.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H42A1D9156151490AB8330E1BEDA8848D"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of advancement opportunities and strategies to expand career pathways for direct care workers in the State or region to be served by the eligible entity, if applicable.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A07FFEB50B94DB5A2AF7449D4008041"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How the eligible entity will collect and submit to the Secretary workforce data and outcomes of the project to be assisted with the grant under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42BD5A415CBA4673AA2398027FF1B308"><enum>(G)</enum><text>How the eligible entity will consult on the implementation of the project, or coordinate the project with, each of the following entities, to the extent that each such entity is not a part of the eligible entity:</text>
 <clause id="HD0BA027A71B641DF8FED1C8899A979B5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State agency responsible for administering the State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act (or waiver of the plan).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H189D4D6D2FD24EE3A9CFB2166E27ACA9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Local boards and State boards for the State or region to be served by the eligible entity.</text> </clause><clause id="H8F85E535D5644099AA80A72FFACC9424"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nonprofit organizations with demonstrated experience in the recruitment, training, employment, or career consultation of direct care workers or the development of curricula or coursework to be used in the training under the project.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6494727B8C104A6893167C2984254F40"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nonprofit organizations that foster the professional development and collective engagement of direct care workers, including labor organizations.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H51C28B8DE5C94E829F2490074924E064"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nonprofit organizations with an expertise in identifying and addressing the care needs of local seniors and people with disabilities and their caregivers (including area agencies on aging, centers for independent living, and aging and disability resource centers).</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H0FAEBCDB5CC9428891374CB3AD6B9042"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Nonprofit State provider associations that represent providers who employ direct care workers, where such associations exist.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48E056EA12794473818DF4387611EF8F"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How the eligible entity will consult with individuals employed as direct care workers, representatives of such workers, individuals assisted by such workers, and the families of such individuals throughout the project.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6E9837B375804296886AE1583A10AFFF"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Outreach efforts to individuals for participation in such project, including targeted outreach to recipients of assistance under a State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act or individuals who are eligible for such assistance.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H740AA0B87DF0424EAFCF9D4352207155"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>In selecting eligible entities to receive a grant under this section, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H685FCE165A7640FC8D199183DBDDA7B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure—</text>
 <clause id="H5FC132EBD73A4626AA4A0D0FA9A86A1A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>geographic and demographic diversity, including rural and urban areas; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HC284833D39E04EF6AB1B5B89023AF8F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that selected eligible entities will serve areas where direct care, or related occupations, is considered an in-demand industry sector or occupation; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00C1F413005F40E091B93060F6751EF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluate the efficacy of each project plan submitted under paragraph (2)—</text> <clause id="HA71B743A4C164080ABB1A6D71B62AD87"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for recruiting, retaining, and providing advancement opportunities for direct care workers; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBC8CEF9C9D934493924CC3DA8713E0D9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on the methods used to recruit, retain, and provide advancement opportunities to direct care workers.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC5E923F83CA9405BA115B7F0205ECB46"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall encourage each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section—</text> <paragraph id="H6F25B814E4AE40298334E6C8230C8556"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in developing and carrying out a project under this section, to consult with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7CFD2C2859D04DEDA987A75AB4185371"><enum>(A)</enum><text>institutions of higher education;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H223F35C0891B418F9D79C1D099DA6709"><enum>(B)</enum><text>entities that employ direct care workers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA86140E9AD3F4D72B0038C215AD079C6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the State Apprenticeship Agency recognized under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>), for the State or region to be served by the eligible entity or, if no such agency has been recognized in the State or region, the Office of Apprenticeship of the Department of Labor; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H46ABAEEDB61B41F3AA292C8755313821"><enum>(D)</enum><text>one-stop centers; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB5918C1922D46FA94C5AC5C33B0A683"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in carrying out a project under this section, to coordinate, to the extent practicable, activities under the project with activities under the grants awarded under section 2008 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397g">42 U.S.C. 1397g</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H95D3415C6B7A428294C5EE74562FADEB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall use such funds to carry out a project or to continue a project commenced prior to receipt of such grant that develops and implements a strategy for the recruitment, retention, or advancement of direct care workers, which includes the activities described in subsection (c)(2), and that provides compensation to each eligible direct care worker for any training received under the project.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF3C6AA440A774931B95E710EC084F04E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity receiving a grant under this Act shall use such grant only to supplement, and not supplant, the amount of funds that, in the absence of such grant, would be available to address the recruitment, retention, and advancement of direct care workers in the State or region served by the eligible entity.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H461790796FA04F5197502045DA93C844"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header>
				<paragraph commented="no" id="HA0981B53436946B0A85D2417ECB68B0C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header>
 <subparagraph id="HADC68B18413942A8BCE957B5F64E9E39"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later 6 months after the completion of each project assisted with a grant under this section, the eligible entity that received such grant shall submit to the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Health and Human Services a report on the progress and outcomes of the project, which data shall be disaggregated in the manner described in subparagraph (B), and shall include the following:</text>
 <clause id="H497AC12B20094F0CBBC3A9BA3D9E62BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of individuals served by the project, including—</text> <subclause id="H0B800515AA1B4D4482D828D9E8E838E4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of individuals recruited to be employed as an direct care worker; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA2669BDD76154285AD096C41BD4D38F4"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of individuals who attained employment as an direct care worker.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H4A5E1CADC97C428583263074671F8849"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The percentage of individuals described in clause (i)(II) employed as an direct care worker in the manner described in subclause (I) of section 116(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3141">29 U.S.C. 3141(b)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H67DA2C6101544E1C99056604DC8674DA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The percentage of individuals described in clause (i)(II) employed in the manner described in subclause (II) of section 116(b)(2)(A)(i) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3141">29 U.S.C. 3141(b)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDBFA17F41EEA4440A18FF4BD04314435"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of individuals or families assisted by direct care workers.</text> </clause><clause id="HEB5C1D577C9349F3AE4F989F6212970E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The number of direct care workers who received and completed the following training or education in the field of direct care, if applicable:</text>
 <subclause id="HDA854B103EAB4CD7A7867D0571CA2A27"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Entry-level training.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H7C36AC01C0204D06896B4EBF5002048A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Advanced-level training.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H84D8B02939F6490CB0B6489970F59265"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Continuing education.</text> </subclause><subclause id="HDFF3351DF4284FD2A6C87E978FD124AA"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Professional development, mentoring, or supervision.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H5088D7D977DB4164923406473FB029D8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The median earnings of individuals completing each type training or education described in clause (v), as determined in accordance with section 116(b)(2)(A)(i)(III) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3141">29 U.S.C. 3141(b)(2)(A)(i)(III)</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H177ED86065AF405D8B9934DC5E85B61A"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How the project assessed satisfaction with respect to—</text> <subclause id="H8F703B03696948B3B530EC1ECEA4C9CD"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">direct care workers assisted by the project;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4EA1899DDB3D4FD381B3430841DB18C6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>individuals receiving services delivered by such workers, including any impact on the health care outcomes of such individuals; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC8C93762A90B48E881FBCE3EBFDEC50E"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employers of such workers, as determined in accordance with section 116(b)(2)(A)(i)(VI) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3141">29 U.S.C. 3141(b)(2)(A)(i)(VI)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HF1B7E910F35D4EFE835BAE5B446FF1F0"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other services, benefits, or supports (other than the services, benefits, or supports described in clause (v)) provided to assist in the recruitment, retention, and advancement of direct care workers, the number of individuals who accessed such services, benefits, or supports, and the impact of such services, benefits, or supports.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52DB4F0853E34C868EEBB31811B6F4B1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disaggregation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The data collected under clauses (i) through (vi) of subparagraph (A) shall be disaggregated by race, ethnicity, sex, and age in accordance with section 116(d)(2)(B) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3141">29 U.S.C. 3141(d)(2)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE4100B5467E546969E2AA0E6F3DDEA28"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Supplemental outcomes information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible entities shall submit supplemental information detailing the outcomes of the project, including explanations of the information provided in accordance with (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD82C155E55844DFEA668AAF046FBD442"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretaries</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the completion of each project assisted with a grant under this section, the Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall prepare and submit to Congress a report containing—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9C180B9AD30041B881EB14E7B586F6DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the progress and outcomes of the project submitted by the eligible entity under paragraph (1);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEDDD6FA7D674F38905E63308C27B58F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the workforce supply, current and projected shortages, and distribution of direct care workers at a national, regional, and State level; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C71F72C777D4C3D8D90999B5B4FA855"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations for such legislative or administrative action as the Secretaries determine appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2E53B6ED39A44064997BD2BFF6E3160E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the completion of each project assisted with a grant under this section, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study and submit to Congress a report including—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H90D1ABE9BC7A4B9FB7B8BE6549A6B783"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of how the project assisted in the recruitment, retention, and advancement of direct care workers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H829B078F4DC048869062C415C18C82C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such recommendations for legislative or administrative changes as the Comptroller General determines are appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC406DA53CFA54B308B194D1836CD52C7"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor shall provide technical assistance to eligible entities, for purposes of compliance with subsection (g)(1) of this section, on—</text>
 <paragraph id="H70CE9928E1DA4FE4AAEEDECB330B9CC8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the disaggregation requirements of section 116(d)(2)(B) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3141">29 U.S.C. 3141(d)(2)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9DAEC9706F604D1D9A7C5C5FE8AE618E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the data collection requirements of section 116(b)(2)(A)(i) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3141">29 U.S.C. 3141(b)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB9CAB124DDAF4C41A5965180682736DC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such funds as may be necessary to carry out this section for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H12C3EA2EB5864714B4CE1AF2B0F868CC"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HCDA1D0E9C2514D73AA0C55400510687E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Career pathway</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>career pathway</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5A8AEF033E541A1AB5E24DEDA6DAD64"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Direct care worker</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>direct care worker</term> has the meaning given the term in section 799B of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/295p">42 U.S.C. 295p</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC66AF50AE95491EA2F6B264959BFAD1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HECA6438C0F33439D86B3E5BBD7DE6651"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA81D7584355141B7A61592A61E3240B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a nonprofit organization, labor organization, or an entity with shared labor-management oversight—</text>
 <clause id="H2F857287003D4B97A855AC49E2086CC3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with an established record of recruiting or providing training to direct care workers; or</text> </clause><clause id="H7E8B1738FA9E4E5FADFEB2517BB8281D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that established a training program in consultation with an organization with an established record of providing training to direct care workers;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E408301A24B4820AC7FE42D814A84A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a local board;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21AF2AEE56EF445C86AF3530A3AF7D88"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a nonprofit entity carrying out a registered apprenticeship program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AD31DFB47C0415DB10DC93FDDE78947"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Indian tribe or tribal organization; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7989B8C50F9E4FE1B0A621EB30B7A91D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a consortium of entities listed in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), or (E) which may include an institution of higher education.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1F5F9A5F92714826891E246F5AF7C6F2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Employ; employer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>employ</term> and <term>employer</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H30724F07926A48AE980CCB9B8316F572"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Indian tribe; tribal organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>Indian tribe</term> and <term>tribal organization</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H37A7683B123849BCB6704F2005D48B78"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99ED16498D0D455E8C4D02BA426BC312"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Local board</header><text>The term <term>local board</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8EDFFDB0601406BBE7C48B04D81D6D4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>In-demand industry sector or occupation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>in-demand industry sector or occupation</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25432C4BFFE843CAA866E1D42E5CCED5"><enum>(9)</enum><header>One-stop center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>one-stop center</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H12E66C09B0AC4F95BCDE5DF8353D4704"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Region</header><text>The term <term>region</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9B27F85D8AA04BB5B8405D19AF7B6ED1"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Registered apprenticeship program</header><text>The term <term>registered apprenticeship program</term> has the meaning given the term in section 171(b) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3226">29 U.S.C. 3226(b)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25C0BCFF3E3B4AE9AC6F06AD1B3FC692"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H40BF19A1229D43DD9FACD8CF5FA779BB"><enum>(13)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States or the District of Columbia District of Columbia, and any commonwealth, possession, or other territory of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H29427F0E9545402AAB793565D04A676E"><enum>(14)</enum><header>State board</header><text>The term <term>State board</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEED5774653B14E4C81A9EB5ABEADE634"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Work-based learning strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>work-based learning strategy</term> means a strategy (which may be a registered apprenticeship) that provides workers with paid work experience and corresponding classroom instruction, as appropriate, delivered in an employment relationship that both the employer and worker intend to be permanent.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


