<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF4F3AD6464464CEA9E589D20DA163D3B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 418</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170110">January 10, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a pilot program to improve access to supportive services and community coordination for families of disabled veterans.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF8FB5EE715B347BF957C832BF00934E1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H194D324AADDD4130A814E3E0EA48A2B8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Early Intervention for Veterans and their Families Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFA5585E7DA36465C9B5B5B8C5FE9AC69" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program for greater direct access to supportive services and community coordination for disabled veterans families</header> <subsection id="HB891A2684B744FDFB9884CDD5CB0E66B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Commencing not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a three-year pilot program with community partners to provide intensive community care coordination and supportive services to disabled veteran families who lack access to direct wellness services provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs or other entities.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8BCCA22BB5ED4DD6B3A799D6BD744FC2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agreements with community partners</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall enter into partnership agreements with community partners using a competitive and merit-based award process for individual grants and for multi-service site grants to test service delivery efficiencies and generate best practices.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEE4A2293D41B4B46BDB7F3DE0944D8A3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Community care coordination and supportive services</header><text>The community care coordination and supportive services referred to in subsection (a) are the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H625D6F83E87B4BFEB26948A1489032F0" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Services provided by a community partner to improve the well-being and address the needs of disabled veteran families who otherwise lack access to adequate direct wellness services provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs or other entities. Such assistance and services may include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H820CB8D73BFA4098AE284F47FD2F0C5F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Care coordination and case management services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA0C7A6B57A6B49B5A70D34E1238C255F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Outreach services.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBDFED6926DB3410C8C00DDDC9B8A3D2B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Assistance in obtaining any benefits from the Department which the veteran may be eligible to receive, including vocational and rehabilitation counseling, employment and training service, educational assistance, and health care services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H906C2022C50D4927A9473500977F93AD" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Assistance in obtaining and coordinating the provision of other public benefits provided by department or agencies of the Federal Government or a State or local government or by community partners, including with respect to—</text> <clause id="HC2D2F07FD98741D1812C1D9085E4D9F0" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>marriage counseling;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA0DFBF31251841798510B37138048A04" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>services for children;</text></clause> <clause id="H8C0157A54BBB4078B17B02ADFA3A92EE" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>suicide prevention;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8C1A8FCE71234D78845CD3B6B81C30D5" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>substance abuse awareness and treatment;</text></clause> <clause id="HBA3F06155C8C49C8B0EED838E7957AF7" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>mental health awareness and treatment;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0E148DCAC3094D9A9DF45914C5C2E7DA" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>financial counseling;</text></clause> <clause id="H8EE1D96FA69B4B1DABDA501B68E4BEB0" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>anger management counseling;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8537E3360FE142BE97C66A66D589454F" commented="no"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>domestic violence awareness and prevention;</text></clause> <clause id="H7D578295366443EEA42C0DBEA8DC6BF3" commented="no"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>employment assistance;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H53B4620BD8B34252B0695036AEFB8710" commented="no"><enum>(x)</enum><text>transportation services;</text></clause> <clause id="HB085E66001E94B3B8E80F6462BCDF12E" commented="no"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>child care;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H44453FA93F1D4176BE5BD75F3D7B9E94" commented="no"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>housing counseling;</text></clause> <clause id="H6ADDA1B789A549A099EBF908EFA422FC" commented="no"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>preparing and updating family care plans;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9E584092843C4B93A9BAADDD42905B47" commented="no"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>development of strategies for living with a veteran with post-traumatic stress disorder or traumatic brain injury;</text></clause> <clause id="HE79CFF7DE4034554A7663299658A259C" commented="no"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>accessing emergency financial assistance through philanthropic efforts; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3833B5C754C0412B8750220639358421" commented="no"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text>other services that are determined by the Secretary to be appropriate to improve the well-being and address the unique needs of disabled veteran families who lack access to such direct wellness services.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05070F5744884757AF087FE596916F47" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Providing the direct services specified in paragraph (1)(D) that are necessary to improve the well-being and address the needs of the disabled veteran families but are otherwise unavailable through existing public or private programs.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6F57A10CE98A44F1836BF0593787721C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H768C9965868F483BB3F626931A66F4DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>community partner</term> means a private nonprofit organization.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2FB341EE001E4BFBB305E012BA8AC0A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>disabled veteran</term> means a United States citizen or United States national who—</text> <subparagraph id="HCC76E6336DBA4AC0A2B3815DF0DAD14E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was honorably discharged from the Armed Forces; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDED8055A6064487D86EE3D8DDD167B9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is entitled to disability compensation (or who but for the receipt of military retired pay would be entitled to disability compensation) under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs or was discharged or released from active duty in the Armed Forces because of a service-connected disability under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/61">chapter 61</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB97B2BD1CF484C14BBBBF00105584542"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>disabled veterans family</term> means the dependents of a disabled veteran.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9D6D6CDC1E2E4B42A08A98FDEFC0A59C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs $2,000,000 to carry out the pilot program under subsection (a) for each fiscal year in which the Secretary carries out such pilot program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9AA67C212E3D4A9E99D417F1955C66D2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days before the completion of the pilot program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the results of the pilot program, including the number of disabled veteran families served and service linkages or referrals and a description and assessment of the effectiveness and achievements of the pilot program with respect to services and treatments and mitigation of risks, including homelessness, unemployment and suicide as well as recommended best practices for improving access to supportive services and coordination of care for disabled veteran families.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

