<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB2066B0B912648D699F2E62857C094FE" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3976 IH: Access to Marketplace Insurance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3976</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171005">October 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001197">Ms. McSally</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000289">Mr. Goodlatte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001290">Mr. Brat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000533">Mr. Duncan of Tennessee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to allow for certain third-party payments.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H12249716575444FB9A50131DDA40E018" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3DAFFD7F5C5E4435AE4031D569A3B3AF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Access to Marketplace Insurance Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF63FCE982E9F427AB2662101D3E8335E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Payment of premiums by certain third parties on behalf of qualified individuals</header> <subsection id="HC6EF650595634C76811CF6B76DEBCCF1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1312 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18032">42 U.S.C. 18032</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDF23D66E92324415ACD1BF1F578B0A1E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) through (f) as subsections (d) through (g), respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H73891FA466954836B188534784816C38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HC185DCF4A02245D0807D7FF999CE810E" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HFF032A18F5C345BE8C0E944C09538484"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Payment of premiums by certain qualified third parties on behalf of a qualified individual</header><text>A qualified individual enrolled in any qualified health plan may allow certain third parties to pay any applicable premium or cost sharing owed by such individual to the health insurance issuer issuing such qualified health plan, and the health insurance issuer shall accept and count toward the annual limitations in section 1302(c) such payments made on behalf of qualified individuals, including payments from the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H9D085D3A8181480B8F5BD076947B6EA9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A State or Federal government program, including assistance provided under a grant under title XXVI of the Public Health Service Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03E66680AD0249A994502FEBE846ED6F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Indian tribes, tribal organizations, or urban Indian organizations.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H341F40F637BB4E8B9A7A0E2274EEE3E5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A program conducted by an organization which is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H31D4C9CCC9614DA0B289DEFE6B7F3A35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>exempt from taxation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0387EFDFA18E449D9763A124FF954D14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>described in clause (i) or (vi) of section 170(b)(1)(A) of such Code; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H007D20EF0E834E1B9F62B363664AB2AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>operated in compliance with applicable Federal laws, including sections 3729 through 3733 of title 31, United States Code (known as the False Claims Act).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4450BD28BE204466AD8A3992001A87C2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Education</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to make and enforce such regulations as necessary to assure that individuals eligible for the Medicare program under part A of title XVIII of the Social Security Act, the Medicaid program under title XIX of such Act, or coverage under an available Medicare supplemental health insurance policy under section 1882 of such Act receive proper education related to all of their coverage options, including qualified health plan coverage.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB98D720BC94B41E88CDDB8B41F9ADBD6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to premiums and cost-sharing paid on or after the date that is 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


