<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6BF93C7D56054F8F8E9BAF9D96E5E17B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 173 IH: Middle Class Health Benefits Tax Repeal Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 173</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170103">January 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to repeal the excise tax on high cost employer-sponsored
			 health coverage.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC6F2618147494442A6FEE9063F6F0222" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE968B11C49074B50A5C595B9BE05E391" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Middle Class Health Benefits Tax Repeal Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H945185DF21174E8C8315B54A6BE4D49C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Repeal of excise tax on high cost employer-sponsored health coverage</header> <subsection id="HE616B3A922154C4BAFDF628594AB569D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/43">Chapter 43</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking section 4980I.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H97170BC254024397A1B549CC401149AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 6051 of such Code is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H58EC191B55224062B70E537F5F44500F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (14) of subsection (a), by striking <quote>section 4980I(d)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (g)</quote>, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H607FF0E435264EE787C26E8ADB776E2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C7ECA0491CD4C479CCCE04432EF1F97" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H04DB432F2B8E41DA88B36FD68203D55C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Applicable Employer-Sponsored Coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a)(14)—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3CBC461958E14EC0B34E0EF6277C038C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>applicable employer-sponsored coverage</term> means, with respect to any employee, coverage under any group health plan made available to the employee by an employer which is excludable from the employee’s gross income under section 106, or would be so excludable if it were employer-provided coverage (within the meaning of such section 106).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H51777068921C49EBBF108980C697909A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The term <term>applicable employer-sponsored coverage</term> shall not include—</text> <subparagraph id="H8CC23AC2C2994BAC90A67D5FEF7F8FE2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any coverage (whether through insurance or otherwise) described in section 9832(c)(1) (other than subparagraph (G) thereof) or for long-term care,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACFC8BC925594F29A23DF16AD9482A50"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any coverage under a separate policy, certificate, or contract of insurance which provides benefits substantially all of which are for treatment of the mouth (including any organ or structure within the mouth) or for treatment of the eye, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H983D1C60D9044F4C95CBD376FA6D2590"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any coverage described in section 9832(c)(3) the payment for which is not excludable from gross income and for which a deduction under section 162(l) is not allowable.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC75531C65F04940BFEAF22C46015A33"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coverage includes employee paid portion</header><text>Coverage shall be treated as applicable employer-sponsored coverage without regard to whether the employer or employee pays for the coverage.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6AFBF799847E41449BF40740CA601D21"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Governmental plans included</header><text>Applicable employer-sponsored coverage shall include coverage under any group health plan established and maintained primarily for its civilian employees by the Government of the United States, by the government of any State or political subdivision thereof, or by any agency or instrumentality of any such government.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HFC51D7F8E52F4C3DB2BB8529BA5FAF3A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Cost of coverage</header>
 <subparagraph id="H25B857ABCDED4D6E80987EE57F96F577"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Health FSAs</header><text>In the case of applicable employer-sponsored coverage consisting of coverage under a flexible spending arrangement (as defined in section 106(c)(2)), the cost of the coverage shall be equal to the amount determined under rules similar to the rules of section 4980B(f)(4) with respect to any reimbursement under the arrangement reduced by the contributions described in subsection (a)(14)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA8033E53AAA42F5B23BD0955E72144F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Archer MSAs and HSAs</header><text>In the case of applicable employer-sponsored coverage consisting of coverage under an arrangement under which the employer makes contributions described in subsection (b) or (d) of section 106, the cost of the coverage shall be equal to the amount of employer contributions under the arrangement.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H999EDDFF90A740CA93568A93D5D6DEBA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Allocation on a monthly basis</header><text>If cost is determined on other than a monthly basis, the cost shall be allocated to months in a taxable period on such basis as the Secretary may prescribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA55757FAA58744FFBEB8DBABEB4B823E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for chapter 43 of such Code is amended by striking the item relating to section 4980I.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5457A49A1C6D47F0B8659BF948B97AAE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

