<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCB602DEC7B3842EC8BCF09A50B1D584F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4037 IH: VA Fairness in Hiring Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4037</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171012">October 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for the non-applicability of non-Department of
			 Veterans Affairs covenants not to compete to the appointment of certain
			 Veterans Health Administration personnel.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE3FF6843DF474F9FBAA67AEB556689B1" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC14028E2E0074C119598A8D8553AD38D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>VA Fairness in Hiring Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9ACE79E7F2BD45AAB8ED8DC181F63A1D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Non-applicability of non-Department of Veterans Affairs covenants not to compete to appointment of Veterans Health Administration personnel</header> <subsection id="H2CE465887EB54C30B7C89E16F1D2C776"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/74">chapter 74</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA116F7A0621424EABA911EB453DD95C" style="USC">
					<section id="H3400126BD2D941EAA610B0A19632AEE7"><enum>7413.</enum><header>Effect of non-Department covenants not to compete</header>
 <subsection id="HB4C44D50060D4C95853D0A356FC01511"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Non-Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), in the case of an individual who is an applicant for appointment to a position in the Veterans Health Administration described in section 7401 of this title, any covenant not to compete into which the individual has entered with a non-Department facility or employer shall have no force or effect with respect to the appointment of the individual to such a position.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6211CCDEA33243E49E892F731D847F5C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination of Department employment</header><text>In the case of an individual who is appointed to such a position in the Veterans Health Administration who has entered into a covenant not to compete that is rendered non-applicable pursuant to subsection (a), if the individual’s employment at the Veterans Health Administration is terminated for any reason before the specified period of time in such covenant, then such covenant shall apply with respect to that individual for the period beginning on the date of the termination of the individual’s employment at the Veterans Health Administration and ending on the last day of such specified period of time.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD940F87430B64B70A77D937D23C626C3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covenant not To compete</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>covenant not to compete</quote> means an agreement—</text> <paragraph id="H518517A3F8A540B1A762F78BE3CEBB4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>between an employee and employer that restricts such employee from performing—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2FCA3B1C1A5245ED8ADEC22ED204AFC2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any work for another employer for a specified period of time;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FC1931FD4B14EEF913868D13F0151E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any work in a specified geographical area; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68A56D7D83964B0A84806227C9AB435E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>work for another employer that is similar to such employee's work for the employer included as a party to the agreement; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5DE0334F43D48EB9F07C48EC467E9E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that is entered into after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H73C272664A7A414B889CBE5747E6AA30"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7412 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75A8C4411E4443AA860CFF263D09D66A" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">7413. Effect of non-Department covenants not to compete.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


