<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H72D6835D72C7456EB85D9A27CDC308B1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 876 IH: Aviation Employee Screening and Security Enhancement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 876</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170206">February 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000132">Mr. Vela</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to reform programs of the Transportation Security
			 Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H6D9F00A5BE504D14ABDFFDA892B86761" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA14AD385EFA9494587F26D44A47398F0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Aviation Employee Screening and Security Enhancement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section commented="no" id="HBA6A1AB7B27E45E4BF771088BF17D565" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HD4C1DAFF8E904D9EA7BCF1F09B7088D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The term <term>Administration</term> means the Transportation Security Administration.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H22F3D872126C49EA9B74807F362496BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF592D4DC1A25457F80FAEA494A58F41D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Air carrier</header><text>The term <term>air carrier</term> has the meaning given such term in section 40102 of title 49, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF97DA00896504625B76FD6CC634D49F3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H55555807B7CA4EE78C0CF31EBA143A06"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Foreign air carrier</header><text>The term <term>foreign air carrier</term> has the meaning given such term in section 40102 of title 49, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H962C1D3E0CC848DD8080E8A903C8F980"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Intelligence community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>intelligence community</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>).</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HFDCF7CF0BF8441CAB3C0233323370A5A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Cost and feasibility study</header>
 <subsection id="H6ADA16A7FC4E4416B2B3B4628FDAD637"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in consultation with the Aviation Security Advisory Committee (established under section 44946 of title 49, United States Code), shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Comptroller General of the United States a cost and feasibility study of a statistically significant number of Category I, II, and X airports to ensure that all employee entry and exit points that lead to secure areas of such airports are comprised of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H989E13D5B55D4A898B3F31498715DB2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A secure door utilizing card and pin entry or biometric technology.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H968E03C26AFC4602AE3E09260095BCF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Surveillance video recording, capable of storing video data for at least 30 days.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5C9CD1BA9F845A4B4783C0B85AE29F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Advanced screening technologies, including at least one of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H801740293A4741E3B2B57532B084B86B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Magnetometer (walk-through or hand-held).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC82D5C44DE9444589748F3B7A8078E5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Explosives detection canines.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEB2849C1D3E42A9929243D7846001F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Explosives trace detection swabbing.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H315DECB644104F538A836CE6D94DBC08"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Advanced imaging technology.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B9D181DE9204B87B0B00D918A999A60"><enum>(E)</enum><text>X-ray bag screening technology.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1EB17AB72B6C4320B2CD587DCBCF95D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study required under subsection (a) shall include information related to the employee screening costs of those category I, II, and X airports which have already implemented practices of screening 100 percent of employees entering secure areas of airports, including the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H37C8E922F12946D0ACA9D51C3D65AC63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Costs associated with establishing an operational minimum number of employee entry and exit points.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4ED3BCDD510C497CAF40CCFD6B358EC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A comparison of costs associated with implementing the requirements specified in paragraph (1), based on whether such implementation was carried out by the Administration or airports.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5B41CBCFD40D49CC8A417189856FB015"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Comptroller General assessment</header>
 <paragraph id="H033CB578545345CEA34D64FDFEDDD256"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon completion of the study required under subsection (a), the Comptroller General of the United States shall review such study to assess the quality and reliability of such study.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H14502E2C89694F178CC66638B2A98AA5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the receipt of the study required under subsection (a), the Comptroller General of the United States shall report to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate on the results of the review required under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE0473E1C92E64FC089C238FE7752BABB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Airport worker education and security awareness</header>
 <subsection id="H36433C7452414897BE5F75816CB318E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cooperative efforts To enhance airport security awareness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall work with air carriers, foreign air carriers, airport operators, airport vendors, and airport concessionaires to enhance security awareness of credentialed airport populations regarding insider threats to aviation security and best practices related to airport access controls.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H211F470616C442139D3E33B0A4B91360"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credentialing standards</header>
 <paragraph id="H304BE3A7669E443395C260D5A5AA83B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall, in consultation with air carriers, foreign air carriers, airport operators, vendors, and airport concessionaires, assess credentialing standards, policies, and practices to ensure that insider threats to aviation security are adequately addressed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEAE0771FFB644D4AAB584991352FD271"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 30 days after completion of the assessment required under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall report to the appropriate congressional committees on the results of such assessment.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCE0CCC618A694CB5A428E549952A9673"><enum>(c)</enum><header>SIDA applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall revise the application submitted by an individual applying for a credential granting access to the Secure Identification Display Area (as such term is defined in section 1540.5 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations) of an airport to require the social security number of such individual in order to strengthen security vetting effectiveness.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HCB1FCB5EC28A4D9EA855738E6C5714C5"><enum>5.</enum><header>Securing airport worker access</header>
 <subsection id="H3DCFC4E014F744E1B2A59D696E0F4593"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall work with airport operators to identify advanced technologies, including biometric identification technologies, for securing employee access to the secure and sterile areas of airports (as such terms are defined in section 1540.5 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H60C2AD5931174A71943C615ADFBBE1C4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rap Back vetting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall ensure that all credentialed aviation worker populations are continuously vetted through the Federal Bureau of Investigation’s Rap Back Service, in order to more rapidly detect and mitigate insider threats to aviation security.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7E79EE0457DB4A7B825A1D14902799FD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Insider threat education and mitigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall identify means of enhancing the Administration’s ability to leverage the resources of the Department of Homeland Security and the intelligence community to educate Administration personnel on insider threats to aviation security and how the Administration can better mitigate such insider threats.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFB419D5CAEB340F0BF0C49580570D563"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Playbook operations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall ensure that Administration-led employee screening efforts, known as Playbook operations, are targeted, strategic, and focused on providing the greatest level of security effectiveness.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HE7BB005AE8EC4861BF0269C54FFEA717"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Covert testing</header>
 <paragraph id="H557F9D774D2143B2A4CFBCFCD8E349E2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall increase covert testing of employee screening operations at airports and measure existing levels of security effectiveness. The Administrator shall provide to air carriers, foreign air carriers, airport operators, airport vendors, and airport concessionaires—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF0B9828177B94117A94B576BA9071D4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of such testing; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69E6865F4D8B4FBF924281BBCE86BBE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations based on such results and measurements on how to improve such security screening operations.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCD0431F7201C41F1B313FC795CC8BC86"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual reporting</header><text>The Administrator shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an annual report on the frequency, methodology, strategy, and effectiveness of employee screening operations at airports.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H45FD21DAF23B4353B4BE53ED69AE1CA3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Centralized database</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in consultation with the Aviation Security Advisory Committee, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H453086E8C6AC4EB4BCDA740B3E87DEA0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a national database of Administration employees who have had either their airport or aircraft operator-issued badge revoked for failure to comply with aviation security requirements;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B56473644B442FE97C1C623F1CC9463"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine the appropriate reporting mechanisms for airports and air carriers and foreign air carriers to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD45DD88F8ACE4CC89287F2F83605F138"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit to the Administration data regarding employees described in paragraph (1); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67E134A4339C4C5F9AB057EC298FB374"><enum>(B)</enum><text>access the database established pursuant to such paragraph; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9946D9E28364358925906B9C3CC30AE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish a process that allows individuals whose names were mistakenly entered into such database to have their names removed and have their credentialing restored.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H349827D545174D3E9F1F70EB70EEC41C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Insider threat coordination efforts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Department of Homeland Security is the lead interagency coordinator pertaining to insider threat investigations and mitigation efforts at airports. The Department shall make every practicable effort to coordinate with other relevant Government entities when undertaking such investigations and efforts.</text>
 </section><section id="H7B8DB38EBC09472CAFF8B11EF7B02DED"><enum>7.</enum><header>Information technology security</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a plan to conduct recurring reviews of the operational, technical, and management security controls for Administration information technology systems at airports.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
</bill>


