<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD7510748DEFA4FA0A7B7F84F10AD475A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4317 IH: Mahoney Lake Hydroelectric Project Licensing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4317</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171108">November 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to issue an order continuing a stay of a
			 hydroelectric license for the Mahoney Lake hydroelectric project in the
			 State of Alaska, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC3D775A73EB5495AB13FDD173879FDF1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4C098D7D1F8F464CBE7F47C76DF34755" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mahoney Lake Hydroelectric Project Licensing Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9A85D1296FED4E7989FF7A82C61B3DA0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Stay and Reinstatement of FERC License No. 11393 for the Mahoney Lake Hydroelectric Project</header> <subsection id="H0424241F548C41E5825974FC06B9EAB9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1727D9521BC94227973BA63E87C5DEBA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4856C831D24F4A0BA43C2F9F140BCA58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>License</header><text>The term <term>license</term> means the license for the Commission project numbered 11393.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEFF31C7B2AD44242804E836FAEC9C7A9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Licensee</header><text>The term <term>licensee</term> means the holder of the license.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4F0E2A303864F1AAC13FD98DAF1787A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Stay of license</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the request of the licensee, the Commission shall issue an order continuing the stay of the license.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H22904F4470F544B7815C213D8C68D0C5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Lifting of stay</header><text>On the request of the licensee, but not later than 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H34BED7FE4D06465DB509312920085545"><enum>(1)</enum><text>issue an order lifting the stay of the license under subsection (b); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7EDF40CFF85B479197A57BEACCE49460"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make the effective date of the license the date on which the stay is lifted under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H72B2EBF61FF7459793B9159A4593B297"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Extension of license</header>
 <paragraph id="HF375D1C078B747F087195C64C732219E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the time period specified in section 13 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/806">16 U.S.C. 806</external-xref>) that would otherwise apply to the Commission project numbered 11393, the Commission may, at the request of the licensee, and after reasonable notice, in accordance with the good faith, due diligence, and public interest requirements of, and the procedures of the Commission under, that section, extend the time period during which the licensee is required to commence the construction of the project for not more than 3 consecutive 2-year periods from the date of the expiration of the extension originally issued by the Commission.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HB320E53A072342FE8FC842FD92B9F90D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reinstatement of expired license</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD452D7521A064FEA8D21F926FC6C882C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the period required for the commencement of construction of the project described in paragraph (1) has expired prior to the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission may reinstate the license effective as of the date of the expiration of the license.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A9A2F0C08364B948C8B0CBD81360B2E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>If the Commission reinstates the license under subparagraph (A), the first extension authorized under paragraph (1) shall take effect on the date of that expiration.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H108916B39B7647ABA787D7B3A805D55C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this Act prioritizes, or creates any advantage or disadvantage to, Commission project numbered 11393 under Federal law, including the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/791a">16 U.S.C. 791a</external-xref> et seq.) or the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2601">16 U.S.C. 2601</external-xref> et seq.), as compared to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB041D847503E4F7FB18B8B2E91158EC6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any electric generating facility in existence on the date of enactment of this Act; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6101C21449354E8DA897A92C9EACA1BF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any electric generating facility that may be examined, proposed, or developed during the period of any stay or extension of the license under this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


