<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H319B093DEFA94A39A83B3709D2A0E9E7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2343 IH: United States Library Trust Fund Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2343</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170503">May 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow taxpayers to designate income tax overpayments as contributions to the United States Library Trust Fund.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE56C03A33049495A9E29D0EC9E06F1E5" style="OLC"> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93D515EAE3224C92B594869C83CB97A0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States Library Trust Fund Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8CEB6CE318934A30BB04181E97501D49"><enum>2.</enum><header>United States Library Trust Fund</header> <subsection id="H5870224E67EF48D19F879E6D756DE102"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation of overpayments as contributions to United States Library Trust Fund</header><text>Subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/61">chapter 61</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new part:</text>
<quoted-block id="H8D7E4CD83F114571A876BD5DF2F4A3E8">
<part id="HB8CB9DC81C974AB5905BB7741B853544"><enum>IX</enum><header>Designation of overpayments as contributions to United States Library Trust Fund</header>
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 6097. Designation.</toc-entry></toc>
<section id="HE5DD399B2AF544CB874E6B6035DA3515"><enum>6097.</enum><header>Designation</header>
<subsection id="HE6277865DBEA4F539D547A150DA14442"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every taxpayer who makes a return of the tax imposed by subtitle A for any taxable year may designate that a specified portion (not less than $1) of the amount of any overpayment of tax for such taxable year shall be paid over to the United States Library Trust Fund in accordance with the provisions of section 9512.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0DEAC1DA3DE342BDB13FD796C44B3BF1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Manner and time of designation</header><text>A designation under subsection (a) may be made with respect to any taxable year—</text>
<paragraph id="H6C48C76E23A24A7BB21072D4503CEE4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at the time of filing the return of the tax imposed by chapter 1 for such taxable year, or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4F976A0933D64DAC84C4E301EE21C46A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>at any other time (after the time of filing the return of the tax imposed by chapter 1 for such taxable year) specified in regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">Such designation shall be made in such manner as the Secretary prescribes by regulations except that such designation shall be made either on the first page of the return or on the page bearing the taxpayer’s signature.</continuation-text></subsection>
<subsection id="HD233BF9A1D3943D19C25E73F35F10137"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Overpayments treated as refunded</header><text>For purposes of this title, any portion of an overpayment of tax designated under subsection (a) shall be treated as being refunded to the taxpayer as of the last date prescribed for filing the return of tax imposed by chapter 1 (determined without regard to extensions).</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HAD6ADE2926A448C3B69CAB0430EC7963"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Creation of trust fund</header><text>Subchapter A of chapter 98 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
<quoted-block id="H7E0267137F274573A4ADA77401E0E3A4">
<section id="HD46E6472D48346C6B21C8D5BACE89474"><enum>9512.</enum><header>United States Library Trust Fund</header>
<subsection id="H31DAEC5B863C4D9FA0B7940FF84D7004"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Creation of trust fund</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the <quote>United States Library Trust Fund</quote>, consisting of such amounts as may be credited or paid to such trust fund as provided in section 6097.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7565DDFD0D1A4C718D8FCE8F73AD0845"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfers to trust fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are hereby appropriated to the United States Library Trust Fund amounts equivalent to the amounts of the overpayments of tax to which designations under section 6097 apply.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H2F74D3A0C53744048FE7E5D57A7AE639"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expenditures from trust fund</header><text>Amounts in the United States Library Trust Fund shall be available, as provided in appropriation Acts, only for purposes of making expenditures to carry out section 3 of the <short-title>United States Library Trust Fund Act</short-title>.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HA95751054D844C35BC47B4E3D9663BE1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header> <paragraph id="HB512E7ED93984E179D4621D68337864E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The table of parts for subchapter A of chapter 61 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
<quoted-block id="H2DA142E52E844051BB05547DC33B7262" style="OLC">
<toc>
<toc-entry idref="HB8CB9DC81C974AB5905BB7741B853544" level="part">Part IX. Designation of overpayments as contributions to United States Library Trust Fund</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF84E92072FDF4BF7864C5BFBB5E33C73"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The table of sections for subchapter A of chapter 98 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block id="H55B1967F91934E5491FC96D34D532085" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 9512. United States Library Trust Fund.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H111C598A4D7E4555A7AB4765D15EDDC6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years ending after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HAAF47A4B006148D0B27A79DF9818BE9E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants to libraries</header>
<subsection id="H98117A11C1EC42B28D0AB267769742C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligibility of public libraries and public school libraries</header><text>A public library or public school library is eligible to receive a grant under this section from the United States Library Trust Fund established pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9512">section 9512</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for any fiscal year by submitting an application to the Office of Library Services that includes—</text> <paragraph id="H5D906F10908A453DA9EA05F46E86F4C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>certification that the library does not have the financial resources available to purchase new books or collections;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC3AB6D6D29014A2C85F5399061EC21E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assurances that funds received under this section will be used only to purchase materials for the library;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E11D594E54B41E184FF8B58A09EE878"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assurances that funds received under this section will be used to supplement, not supplant, other funds received by such library; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCFF3A03AC7274164850626BB9373AB85"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an agreement to make available any financial records that the Office of Library Services may need for audit purposes.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7381DB8374464217B46D8A0D606C8571"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant selection</header><text>The Office of Library Services shall select the number of grant awards made under this section and the amount of each such award based upon economic need in accordance with regulations published by the Office.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

