<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1A54F150409744FFB4218624556B6ED6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1263 IH: Protecting Allies from Visa Exclusion (PAVE) Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1263</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170228">February 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To exclude from the application of Executive Order 13796 certain Iraqi and Afghani special
			 immigrants and refugees, to render certain Afghanis eligible for Priority
			 2 processing under the refugee resettlement priority system, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HEEFD1640EE194212A30452C9AFDF5786" style="OLC">
 <section id="H355D6CB3A9104130A86BD8047BC6DD0B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Allies from Visa Exclusion (PAVE) Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF43E7503F8BB47AF841192CA106C2B4B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on entry inapplicable to certain special immigrants</header> <subsection id="H54F0C049ECA549A9B52F7A37635FDEC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Iraqi special immigrants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3(c) of Executive Order 13769, entitled <quote>Protecting the Nation from Foreign Terrorist Entry into the United States</quote> (January 27, 2017), or any other provision of an Executive order, regulation, informal rule of guidance, or memorandum issued by the President or any other official in the executive branch precluding issuance of visas to, revoking visas issued to, or precluding entry or admission of, a class or classes of aliens, shall not apply to an alien who is a national of Iraq or Afghanistan and has been granted special immigrant status under section 101(a)(27) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(27)</external-xref>) pursuant to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4ACA3E03273F4501B11B943339B49BA9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 1244 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref> note);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H07B110F7D47D41BFB9866F273D0862F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 1059 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> note); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H987C6230FE164072931F35C68BDE2EE9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>section 602 of the Afghan Allies Protection Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> note).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5A368B43C5144704BDE75D69005137C8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Refugees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5 of Executive Order 13769, or any other provision of an Executive order, regulation, informal rule of guidance, or memorandum issued by the President or any other official in the executive branch precluding issuance of visas to, revoking visas issued to, or precluding entry or admission of, a class or classes of aliens, shall not apply to an alien who has been granted refugee status, has been approved for refugee admission, or is a refugee applicant in the United States Refugee Admissions Program under a Priority 2 designation pursuant to section 1243 of National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref> note) or section 3 of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEF591EEF361F43BEA25E974B0B1F581E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall take effect as if enacted concurrent with Executive Order 13769.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H84065D1264CA4D68BDB0D5CBD8DA4395"><enum>3.</enum><header>United states refugee program processing priorities for Afghanis</header> <subsection id="H8451C896372A43509F1EF85E6D66EFCE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Refugees of special humanitarian concern eligible for Priority 2 processing under the refugee resettlement priority system who may apply directly to the United States Admission Program shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H875B5D59DBED4ABAB8F3C0B7756D6DB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Afghanis who were or are employed by the United States Government in Afghanistan;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE48FBE976DDC4CA89C136D1088CB9D4F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Afghanis who establish to the satisfaction of the Secretary of State that they are or were employed in Afghanistan by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD29E5FF2B9544E5B9904AE7A26D23D55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a media or nongovernmental organization headquartered in the United States; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCB278947BC64F9788D374F462CB1EA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an organization or entity closely associated with the United States mission in Afghanistan that has received United States Government funding through an official and documented contract, award, grant, or cooperative agreement;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H107F7935F31A4D138119D3EEED9C1670"><enum>(3)</enum><text>spouses, children, and parents whether or not accompanying or following to join, and sons, daughters, and siblings of aliens described in paragraph (1) or paragraph (2);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H949A1BA8BD8E4EEBA4DB955BDBD3293C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">spouses, children, and parents whether or not accompanying or following to join, and sons, daughters, and siblings of Afghanis granted the status of a special immigrant under section 101(a)(27) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(27)</external-xref>) based on faithful and valuable service to the United States Government; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2A48D004EE4C4CECAFE4D51FB2948B8B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Afghanis who are members of a religious or minority community, have been identified by the Secretary of State, or the designee of the Secretary, as a persecuted group, and have close family members (as described in section 201(b)(2)(A)(i) or 203(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(b)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref> and 1153(a))) in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H857440D7D608459BBE5600076E67D82E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification of other persecuted groups</header><text>The Secretary of State, or the designee of the Secretary, is authorized to identify other Priority 2 groups of Afghanis, including vulnerable populations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H55C779466D5F45F48229FE9FFD3F5726"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ineligible organizations and entities</header><text>Organizations and entities described in subsection (a)(2) shall not include any that appear on the Department of the Treasury’s list of Specially Designated Nationals or any entity specifically excluded by the Secretary of Homeland Security, after consultation with the Secretary of State and the heads of relevant elements of the intelligence community (as defined in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/401a">50 U.S.C. 401a(4)</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H21A4B644A76A4694AC965E4448A7ECC6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability of other requirements</header><text>Aliens under this section who qualify for Priority 2 processing under the refugee resettlement priority system shall satisfy the requirements of section 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>) for admission to the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H021631C09E3F4487BCC51FD86A23193C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Numerical limitations</header><text>In determining the number of Afghani refugees who should be resettled in the United States under paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of subsection (a) and subsection (b) of section 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>), the President shall consult with the heads of nongovernmental organizations that have a presence in Afghanistan or experience in assessing the problems faced by Afghani refugees.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1FDF796C9F9A40D7A35740E770444F2F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Eligibility for admission as refugee</header><text>No alien shall be denied the opportunity to apply for admission under this section solely because such alien qualifies as an immediate relative or is eligible for any other immigrant classification.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


