<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H23FD78127C554B7C9809F313F869A79E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3350 IH: Transparency in Music Licensing and Ownership Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3350</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170720">July 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 17, United States Code, to establish a database of nondramatic musical works and
			 sound recordings to help entities that wish to publicly perform such works
			 and recordings to identify and compensate the owners of rights in such
			 works and recordings, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H920A678509D54398A7250E80BAF5E97D" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF690DB40BC6F4E6B98C576B7B4832831" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transparency in Music Licensing and Ownership Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H73E001A97A9F4DA9B324F153FEC59BD1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of database for nondramatic musical works and sound recordings</header> <subsection id="HA3DB0CE67CC8431FAD44A78CDD92174E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Nondramatic musical works and sound recordings database</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/17/7">Chapter 7</external-xref> of title 17, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4EF1499C8AE4E1098DBDA2336B341BE" style="USC">
					<section id="HEA4FB9E2EA174F5AB0CBDAF954437530"><enum>711.</enum><header>Nondramatic musical works and sound recordings database</header>
 <subsection id="HED1A681EF12141F4A6F7BC9C5961F4B2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment and maintenance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Register of Copyrights shall establish and maintain an informational database of nondramatic musical works and sound recordings subject to protection under this title.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0A0B5015B2ED48D5ACB32DF76FAB85CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The database established under subsection (a) shall include, at a minimum, for each nondramatic musical work and sound recording subject to protection under this title, the following information:</text>
 <paragraph id="H8CC219E62469494BBB3208D05845DEFE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The title.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDCF696B68ECB4426A29996E08EE70696"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The copyright registration date, if any.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1083737790142929FEBD84117719E73"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An identification of each owner of the copyright of the work or recording.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H18A1CA9FB74949C1BE2E52CD40522300"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An identification of any entity, including a performing rights society, music publisher, or record label, through which the work or recording may be licensed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC46B80DE56C3486F9E77AFE110324ADF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The international standard musical work code or the international standard recording code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BBD7BABE2C74CAFB190501526235142"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The name of each recording artist featured on the work or recording.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H175993976A584EA9BA497DB23FD8ED0A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Each album title containing the work or recording.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC732FC0C15B14B52BF507A8BC3FED5A6"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each catalog number and each label name used on phonorecords of the work made and distributed to the public.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63EC60D5EA164DAE8841741781A4FCEF"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other information the Register of Copyrights determines to be appropriate or necessary.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H937B1D755C0045F09B09524215D26265"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Accessibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Register of Copyrights shall make the database established under subsection (a) publicly available, in its entirety, without charge, in a format that reflects current technological practices. The Register of Copyrights may revise and update the technical requirements of the database as necessary to ensure continued accessibility.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H2CA52AC2C7BB40A6A45B8F67ADF4F8BA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on remedies</header>
 <paragraph id="H071E50E4F72B46DF81EB7F8EAAD8801F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding sections 502 through 506, in an action brought under this title for infringement of the exclusive right to perform publicly, reproduce, or distribute a nondramatic musical work or sound recording, the remedies available to a copyright owner that has failed to provide or maintain the information described in subsection (b) shall be limited to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4D55A451D2614F889773A47626F3AABA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an order requiring the infringer to pay to the copyright owner actual damages for the public performance, reproduction, or distribution of the infringed work; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7882D99ADBFF4A82AD59DDC28A8B3D0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">injunctive relief to prevent or restrain any infringement alleged in the civil action.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA49274DDBDA64D8F9D6E37FE7336804D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reliance on database information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In an action described in paragraph (1), any relief granted by the court shall, to the extent practicable, account for the reliance of an infringer on any information included in the database established under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E4B17E3087349A8AFB5D687A1299E7E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The limitation described in paragraph (1) only applies to an action brought against the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HF3A71AD04B434895BAA2983226C7FA21"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An establishment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F4E4CB5EE8C463F9CE8576B61C4885A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A food service or drinking establishment.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H406B1B32B6384D25BC90091F8546CBD4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A terrestrial broadcast station licensed as such by the Federal Communications Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF17A2D23E148445D9F6FA876B290D0F8"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity operating under one of the statutory licenses described in section 112, 114, or 115.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8F70C6D489148ED8E1F88CEAFE3F8DA"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity performing publicly, reproducing, or distributing musical works or sound recordings in good faith as demonstrated by evidence such as a license agreement in good standing with a performing rights society or other entity authorized to license the use of musical works or sound recordings.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA9D4951611C47C39B43EBFFFAAF60B5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Initial technical requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Register of Copyrights shall adopt technical requirements, subject to public notice and comment and a 90-day trial period, in the establishment of the database described under subsection (a), that ensures the database meets the following requirements:</text>
 <paragraph id="HEE8FB682EADE4DE0804A6212DDB1C05B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Publicly available from a website maintained by the Copyright Office and hosted from the copyright.gov domain.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDAA7D5E0D323417684DEDDDF7A406460"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Accessible, in a machine-readable format, through both real-time and bulk application programming interfaces.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HABA24D9800F042A1A20572C597FA0330"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Searchable through the website described in paragraph (1) and the application programming interfaces described in paragraph (2) by the information required under subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB1E4FB795A649CB91DF76A677BA087E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exportable in its entirety to non-proprietary document formats compatible with standard spreadsheet programs, Extensible Markup Language, and such other formats as may be determined by the Register.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C4997393EA14B1CA0AAE2CA3EF33565"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Working group</header>
 <paragraph id="HB368F3C8BC004EBC9F5C4C9C4F65ECD1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 45 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Register of Copyrights shall establish a working group of technical experts representing a wide range of stakeholders to identify, report, and recommend performance objectives, technical capabilities, and technical standards for the database established under subsection (a), including meeting the initial requirements described in subsection (e).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0DD6BEE8CCB74CC68DCE5D617E4C4965"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointment of members</header><text>The Librarian of Congress, in consultation with the Register of Copyrights, shall appoint the members of the working group, who shall be individuals or organizations representing, in equal parts, owners and licensors of copyrighted works, users and licensees of copyrighted works, and consumers and public interest entities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01A61F8A08CA4846B6953C98D38CD8AD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 9 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the working group shall submit to the Register of Copyrights a report on the activities and recommendations of the working group described in paragraph (1). Not later than 14 days after receipt of the report, the Register of Copyrights shall make the report and recommendations of the working group subject to public notice and comment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6087AB847BA49AFA105D1C0642E937B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Copyright office assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Register of Copyrights may appoint an employee of the Copyright Office—</text> <subparagraph id="H3DC5883100034E31B81E0132B7A72231"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to moderate and direct the work of the working group under this subsection; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FD09A6E9AD640239D97EFFB964BC428"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide technical assistance to members of the working group, as appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0F4F7238FE04974AC2DD8D9BC6ACFCB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>The initial meeting of the working group shall take place not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H19D25E762F52408C8965B45D82C1F197"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Technical review and updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the establishment of the database described in subsection (a), and every 3 years thereafter, the Register of Copyrights shall review the technical capabilities of the database and make any necessary revisions. In conducting the review, the Register shall establish a working group subject to the requirements described in subsection (f). Any updates to the technical capabilities of the database shall be subject to public notice and comment and a 90-day trial period.</text>
						</subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2D36E6116F3C4D9193B8F43F1B01289C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/17/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 17, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2BD8B5A188741DBB0F9F24CBF6BCFA1" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">711. Nondramatic musical works and sound recordings database.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6D49B0B5AE504F859AD8C9D402584A88"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


