<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD52D71A801A6487AB2A96D8FCBFA2023" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1351 IH: Strengthening Oversight of TSA Employee Misconduct Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1351</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170302">March 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to direct the Administrator of the Transportation Security
			 Administration (TSA) to make certain improvements in managing TSA’s
			 employee misconduct, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H19B2C35C343349B78D91BEEDE454E742" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF1EECD3A580A4737A4C51BEE3A506131" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Oversight of TSA Employee Misconduct Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1D19CF7B24A34F2986A2B1103349D6FB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>TSA Misconduct Inspection Plan</header> <subsection id="HA4D8D383BF2E454EB5B64C32C1995967"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 44935 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H376C86B025F84F168144644744811832"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating the second subsection (i) (relating to accessibility of computer-based training facilities) as subsection (k); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC60CA90793A34EC792B1A4E96567160D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A4A3531E0674111A0D012433E23678B" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H6A40B01D95A34B019F2B117EC806BEC0"><enum>(l)</enum><header>TSA misconduct inspections</header> <paragraph id="H7D93A1EAD32D406BA331A9BA815B9AE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4F04385F4D264F21B0702E2F6F319847"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designate a senior official to implement a plan to oversee unannounced inspections of the types of actions taken in response to employee misconduct allegations, including actions taken by managers at airports to address any such allegations through corrective actions, including dismissal if warranted, in accordance with Department of Homeland Security and TSA policies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FFABFE5FEE04CEF8C0940CBCAAC3371"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on a quarterly basis thereafter until September 30, 2022, the official specified in subparagraph (A) shall certify to the Administrator that the unannounced inspections referred to in such paragraph were completed across a sufficient number of airports such that all airports are inspected before such date;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBBD95A5EB3A4966A04C530C44FDEB12"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designate a senior official to review the results of such unannounced inspections to identify root causes of any variances in the way actions taken in response to employee misconduct allegations and develop corrective actions (including dismissal if warranted), as appropriate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5D3E86A3BA04509BC6757857E5DB8D8"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that the official specified in subparagraph (A) implements the recommendations made by the official specified in subparagraph (C).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H05CD61647EDA4224B5BECA4E80125A15"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department of Homeland Security review</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB7D6A81318BD4D9CB5144EFC7C0648FF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On a quarterly basis, the official specified in paragraph (1)(A) shall provide to the Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security the results of unannounced inspections conducted pursuant to such paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69D15903867243F89F157A4F361294A9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Identification</header><text>The Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security shall review the results of the unannounced inspections conducted pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) to identify trends and, as appropriate, make recommendations, including timeframes for implementation, to the Administrator of the TSA to address employee misconduct.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83B5FF93663E4DBE92DC9990490A64ED"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Administrator of the TSA shall implement recommendations made by the Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security within the timeframes established by the Chief Human Capital Officer.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF6C5F69F9004FCE8AFE1E09AE8648AD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the TSA shall make misconduct information identified under this subsection readily available to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H88FF169728984B44A1799BA712241010"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H180D76A4B80B4530A48B59BE3B7C0513"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9ADA5AE5174242E0B5EB6476ECB3F9C9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as appropriate, personnel of the Department of Homeland Security, as determined by the Administrator.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4F65DC1ADEF4F18A414866C3C452432"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7B5C3D7A96741C59BA086D085818AA4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Actions</header><text>The term <quote>actions</quote> means consequences for employee misconduct established by the Transportation Security Administration’s misconduct policy and related documents under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD55993558C204C18A29B0C9FD14B6D85"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Misconduct</header><text>The term <quote>misconduct</quote> means the failure of a Transportation Security Administration employee to comply with a performance plan, rule, regulation, or law within the scope of such employee’s duties, responsibilities, or functions.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9991D61F40034B0D95EF60C0B1E6DDAF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Unannounced inspections</header><text>The term <quote>unannounced inspections</quote> means a review of information without providing notice to the party under review.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB1B282DCE5164B7EB4F0B91500BA135A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No additional funds authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this Act and the amendments made by this Act. Such requirements shall be carried out using amounts otherwise authorized.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


