<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H83813215B279483FBFA4F257F1EF46CF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1444 IH: Voluntary Protection Program Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1444</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20170309">March 9, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000591">Mrs. Roby</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001073">Mr. Hurd</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To authorize the Department of Labor’s voluntary protection program.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HE3545E2B7ACE4FEFAD3A0CF08E09B76E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6DB3CB9AE9DC4BE784A60942189DCCAA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Voluntary Protection Program Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7EF943B1CBD24AC9BD2B354438CD062B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Voluntary protection program</header> <subsection id="HCF632C0622F44038BE32442E709BDA86"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall establish a program of entering into cooperative agreements with employers to encourage the establishment of comprehensive safety and health management systems that include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3496D8E550624295B7DE7CAC9F581D8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>requirements for systematic assessment of hazards;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C5BF69BF56A4F499E3316E63600E06F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>comprehensive hazard prevention, mitigation, and control programs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5DDE4896E1CC46A88BFF917F2902A480"><enum>(3)</enum><text>active and meaningful management and employee participation in the voluntary program described in subsection (b); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H198D9F82BCA045D5B196597691A745DF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>employee safety and health training.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2353AD9201F249299799B5212A3C763D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Voluntary protection program</header> 
<paragraph id="H77BF4D777B874F278B639CDC25270BAA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall establish and carry out a voluntary protection program (consistent with subsection (a)) to encourage excellence and recognize the achievement of excellence in both the technical and managerial protection of employees from occupational hazards.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBB7F618A7C0482C8BCB9D173B9F47B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program requirements</header><text>The voluntary protection program shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFD22970107FC457C854B038F90DEB960"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Employers who volunteer under the program shall be required to submit an application to the Secretary of Labor demonstrating that the worksite with respect to which the application is made meets such requirements as the Secretary of Labor may require for participation in the program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H51C836FF060543488620FB0AEF709B7C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Onsite evaluations</header><text>There shall be onsite evaluations by representatives of the Secretary of Labor to ensure a high level of protection of employees. The onsite visits shall not result in enforcement of citations under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/651">29 U.S.C. 651</external-xref> et seq.).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H749FA3E3435343D497648A9167174713"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Information</header><text>Employers who are approved by the Secretary of Labor for participation in the program shall assure the Secretary of Labor that information about the safety and health program shall be made readily available to the Secretary of Labor to share with employees.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H731548C06C2C4E1D94D78622AEAD3899"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Reevaluations</header><text>Periodic reevaluations by the Secretary of Labor of the employers shall be required for continued participation in the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H945DCDA3103C47D4ABAD87DA28DF82D3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Monitoring</header><text>To ensure proper controls and measurement of program performance for the voluntary protection program under this section, the Secretary of Labor shall direct the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Occupational Safety and Health to take the following actions:</text> <subparagraph id="H87E913473DF04E9DA63676648F24308A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Develop a documentation policy regarding information on follow-up actions taken by the regional offices of the Occupational Safety and Health Administration in response to fatalities and serious injuries at worksites participating in the voluntary protection program.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H87FAE47B6E8640F398546BF00A794318"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Establish internal controls that ensure consistent compliance by the regional offices of the Occupational Safety and Health Administration with the voluntary protection program policies of the Occupational Safety and Health Administration for conducting onsite reviews and monitoring injury and illness rates, to ensure that only qualified worksites participate in the program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F37EBC4A6D64C84BAB29540D78FEFDA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Establish a system for monitoring the performance of the voluntary protection program by developing specific performance goals and measures for the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47C352F588F84A5DBE34999DCB2F7C29"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text>A site with respect to which a voluntary protection program has been approved shall, during participation in the program, be exempt from inspections or investigations and certain paperwork requirements to be determined by the Secretary of Labor, except that this paragraph shall not apply to inspections or investigations arising from employee complaints, fatalities, catastrophes, or significant toxic releases.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2EDDAA235D6D45E481CEA93E0D523ACE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>No payments required</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall not require any form of payment for an employer to qualify or participate in the voluntary protection program.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8682AA4DD57C48DBB822EABFAC5CE827"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transition</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall take such steps as may be necessary for the orderly transition from the cooperative agreements and voluntary protection programs carried out by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration as of the day before the date of enactment of this Act, to the cooperative agreements and voluntary protection program authorized under this section. In making such transition, the Secretary shall ensure that—</text> <paragraph id="H65EA9E0FF80647A7B7CEEA2CF4985725"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the voluntary protection program authorized under this section is based upon and consistent with the voluntary protection programs carried out on the day before the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H701CA082188D4C8BA3A0C0936991BF7D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each employer that, as of the day before the date of enactment of this Act, had an active cooperative agreement under the voluntary protection programs carried out by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration and was in good standing with respect to the duties and responsibilities under such agreement, shall have the option to continue participating in the voluntary protection program authorized under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4B29AEA9158D4D02B404C8843A536DFF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations and implementation</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor shall issue final regulations for the voluntary protection program authorized under this section and shall begin implementation of the program.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H04300133AC814A8980948AD2EAD23BC9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act such sums as may be necessary.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

