<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1957927858654C0DB651B4E039D07644" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1540 IH: Social Security Disability Insurance Return to Work Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1540</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170315">March 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To help individuals receiving disability insurance benefits under title II of the Social Security Act obtain rehabilitative services and return to the workforce, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H972949E89BD04B8C964D664770252188" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC66BA85E10FE4525B7ABD2845AAB168F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
<subsection id="H6FF1447FB00F44AD8C2C0825566A62B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Social Security Disability Insurance Return to Work Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7CE72343978846228FD5F33F9072FF3F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
<toc>
<toc-entry idref="HC66BA85E10FE4525B7ABD2845AAB168F" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H972E95729E654BF88CB1CC28A881FB53" level="section">Sec. 2. Revising disability classifications.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HE1F609A0F77A4167A6D94C97583686BB" level="section">Sec. 3. Requiring periodic continuing disability reviews for certain beneficiaries.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HEB01091F2FCA414DAC20505AC40C4807" level="section">Sec. 4. Regulations related to disability classifications and CDRs.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H9B45E065C1A24FBAA61644998341542A" level="section">Sec. 5. Time-limiting disability benefits for MIE and MIL individuals.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HF27166D22EE94B3B977447683BC6BFE5" level="section">Sec. 6. Encouraging work by MIE and MIL individuals.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HA1BC951CB8494D05B9AB7904B5174618" level="section">Sec. 7. Increased funding for continuing disability reviews.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section>
<section id="H972E95729E654BF88CB1CC28A881FB53"><enum>2.</enum><header>Revising disability classifications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 221 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/421">42 U.S.C. 421</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block act-name="" id="H6352F69BC2434BDB93F20CF3E567ACA9" other-style="archaic" style="other"> <subsection id="H1059763FDF5D45C8BA5C925594424BDA"><enum>(n)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCB2A6A0A3BD047EFB2AAE28A411582D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Commissioner of Social Security shall establish a system for classifying any individual who is determined to be entitled to disability insurance benefits under this title or to monthly benefits under section 202 by reason of being under a disability in the following manner:</text>
<subparagraph id="H26076A79C27644FC9620776D168E04CD" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An individual shall be classified as <term>medical improvement expected</term> if the impairment or combination of impairments causing the individual to be disabled is expected to medically improve to the point where the individual will no longer be disabled in 12 to 24 months.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H80846A3FA5EE481D96FE3459043AB5FC" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An individual shall be classified as <term>medical improvement likely</term> if the impairment or combination of impairments causing the individual to be disabled is expected to medically improve to the point where the individual will no longer be disabled in 25 months to 60 months.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H72079DC934554C0D8179356DE60BB044" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An individual shall be classified as <term>medical improvement possible</term> if the impairment or combination of impairments causing the individual to be disabled is not expected to medically improve to the point where the individual will no longer be disabled in 60 months, but future improvement is possible.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCCD3B37084FE4CABAB47853543389175" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An individual shall be classified as <term>medical improvement not expected</term> if the individual has an impairment or combination of impairments that is chronic or progressive with permanent, irreversible structural or functional loss, and for which there is no known effective therapy, treatment, or surgical intervention that could result in medical improvement to the point where the individual is no longer disabled.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE41EC6A6419F4DC589660FD6C26E3CD9" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In classifying an individual under the system established under this subsection, the Commissioner of Social Security shall not classify an individual as <term>medical improvement not expected</term> solely by reason of such individual's age where a lesser classification is appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDFBE4D0EDA4F4D1AAA191FD19C9E259B" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Notwithstanding section 205(b)(1) or subsection (c)(1) or (d) of this section, there shall be no review of, or right to appeal, a classification made under the system established under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="HE1F609A0F77A4167A6D94C97583686BB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requiring periodic continuing disability reviews for certain beneficiaries</header>
<subsection id="H12E61015EE90427F82C3D79E597920AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 221(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/421">42 U.S.C. 421(i)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF257702B99084355B0A42E1B9F37A441"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE1F758642854B97B8986287FCB4EF17" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H1AB421E9D66C4A7AB2AB9F4596AB305D" indent="up1"><enum>(1)</enum>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H08412BDAE86C47D39DFE17DB06950222"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In the case of any individual who has not attained age 63, is determined to be under a disability, and is classified as <term>medical improvement possible</term> or <term>medical improvement not expected</term>, the applicable State agency or the Commissioner of Social Security (as may be appropriate) shall, for purposes of determining such individual's continuing disability—</text> <clause id="H462A84760EF2420BB00613BF4D856977" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>if the individual is classified as <term>medical improvement possible</term>, conduct a review to determine whether the individual remains under a disability during the 5th year following the first month after the individual's waiting period (as defined in section 223(c)(2)); and</text></clause>
<clause id="H9543743BD5DE4A2FB7F13E817330A3C7" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the individual is classified as <term>medical improvement not expected</term>, conduct a review to determine whether the individual remains under a disability during the 10th year following the first month after the individual's waiting period (as so defined).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5D6518B4BF1C41D083B2599B6B1BAEAA" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In addition to the continuing disability reviews required under subparagraph (A) and notwithstanding how an individual is classified under the system established by the Commissioner of Social Security under subsection (n), if the Commissioner has reason to believe that an individual that has been determined to be under a disability is not under a disability, the Commissioner may review such individual's case at such time and in such manner as the Commissioner determines appropriate except that the Commissioner shall not initiate a review on the basis of income earned by an individual who is a participant in the process established under section 223(l).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2240A036D7A04C77AFD12D2793FFB7ED" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Reviews of cases which are required or permitted under this paragraph shall be in addition to, and shall not be considered as a substitute for, any other reviews which are required or provided for under or in the administration of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8CF3C193F164A749FDBCF04A8E74460"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H94AE15A6D8A649BABA57EA2168A422CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) through (5) as paragraphs (2) through (4), respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H02FED93222FF41F8BB8956F14CA2136E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Standard of review for continuing disability reviews</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H8DAFC8C853D14B46B15E7017ED88C02C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 223(f) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/423">42 U.S.C. 423(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HD1EE4A55900E472DABE651F3C2ACFF56"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HDBA74974BBCB43B4B2722C4FA7FF63D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6318C7639AAB48B0A8FC654A789E7555" style="OLC">
<paragraph commented="no" id="H42652B540FD84CE7BD6E4256C6A003B1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in the case of a continuing disability review under section 221(i), evidence that would be sufficient to support a finding in an initial determination that the individual is not under a disability and is able to engage in substantial gainful activity.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H72691F1C13F2468989CA55B81BD0448D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the flush matter at the end, by inserting <quote>, except that, in the case of a continuing disability review under section 221(i), the Commissioner shall not consider the fact that an individual is engaged in substantial gainful work as part of the process established under subsection (l) as evidence that the individual is able to engage in substantial gainful activity</quote> after <quote>secured by the Commissioner of Social Security</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HC5F95D85E2D14628A99E06C3D3BB410F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment to definition of disability</header><text>Section 223(d)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/423">42 U.S.C. 423(d)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H349EA71D5E63475DAACB9D95F8C68280"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>An individual</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subparagraph (D), an individual</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HCCA40EE62E0B44A59F0069E19CD273F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1B7C10F16BF04708883CF22202B701F0" style="OLC"> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB565AD837A9C47E1A3BFFDF7446B7CD7" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>In the case of a continuing disability review under section 221(i), an individual may be found to be under a disability even though the individual is engaged in substantial gainful work as part of the process established under subsection (l).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB01091F2FCA414DAC20505AC40C4807"><enum>4.</enum><header>Regulations related to disability classifications and CDRs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commissioner of Social Security shall promulgate or revise, as appropriate, regulations relating to the determination, classification, and review of the disability status of individuals who apply for or receive disability insurance benefits under title II of the Social Security Act and related provisions of agency guidance to carry out section 2 and the amendments made by section 3.</text></section> <section id="H9B45E065C1A24FBAA61644998341542A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Time-limiting disability benefits for MIE and MIL individuals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 223 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/423">42 U.S.C. 423</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H3B552BB4FAE84D838CAC1DF4A066CEA8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1), in the flush language after and below subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>subsection (e)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (e) and (k)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2138EE20D6F48C0BDAA5FC430E9CB02"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6042D32621B4F42B55C1DCF2890BB4A" other-style="archaic" style="other">
<subsection id="HA6CB7DD5712644079615FFFF5A8CD18D"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Time-Limited disability benefits</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7CEF0468D6AA43CEBC404364DB6D0C59"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the case of an individual who files an application for disability insurance benefits under this section or for monthly benefits under section 202 by reason of being under a disability for any month that begins on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Social Security Disability Insurance Return to Work Act</short-title>, is determined to be under a disability, and is classified by the Commissioner of Social Security as <term>medical improvement expected</term> or <term>medical improvement likely</term>, the termination month applicable to the individual shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="HED2AA80661DA48C096BFB2408D07F49B" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the individual has been classified as <term>medical improvement expected</term>, the 23rd month following the first month after the individual's waiting period (as defined in subsection (c)(2)); or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8BC01DB04734489C9A3298915779E3E1" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the individual has been classified as <term>medical improvement likely</term>, the 59th month following the first month after the individual's waiting period (as so defined).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5016DF32F8648F9BA684DDC88536421" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDCA7D90082084C868C428D5872F59E3E"><enum>(A)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H11016ABD5712475698927E6C36BCF0D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>timely reapplication</term> means an application for disability insurance benefits under this section or for monthly benefits under section 202 by reason of being under a disability that is submitted—</text>
<subclause id="H042CABDD819E4C7B9638160E98D44F45" indent="up2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by an individual who is a recipient of such benefits; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8018B51DFEE84697BA5DDA653BDA8FA3" indent="up2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>during the period that is 14 months before the end of the termination month applicable (or most recently applicable) to the individual under paragraph (1) as of the date of such application and ending with the date that is 12 months before the end of such termination month.</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="HB560F54469AE43D78E0452B895343257" indent="up2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Notwithstanding clause (i), the Commissioner of Social Security may deem an application for disability insurance benefits under this section or for monthly benefits under section 202 by reason of being under a disability submitted by an individual who is a recipient of such benefits that is submitted after the period described in clause (i)(II) to be a timely reapplication if—</text> <subclause id="H024F4FA21116471EBFA2EEA069CEB396"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the individual can show good cause for why the application was not submitted during such period; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H681951F80F864E089247EF51358398CE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the application is submitted not later than 6 months before the end of the termination month applicable (or most recently applicable) to the individual under paragraph (1) as of the date of such application.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA668499732F04A0CABD7D7CDA3A2B38E" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H86D567C856D840DFB0B665D5096A5680"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An individual who submits a timely reapplication and who is determined to be under a disability shall be deemed to have satisfied the waiting period applicable under subsection (c)(2).</text></clause>
<clause id="H7FD0F58ECBA24C2BAB895F630016C704" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H94883EE816E94B4F9519DFA3DAFCEAE0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>If the Commissioner of Social Security fails to make an initial determination with respect to the timely reapplication of an individual who is a recipient of disability insurance benefits under this section or monthly benefits under section 202 by reason of being under a disability before the end of the termination month applicable to the individual as of the date of such reapplication, such individual shall continue to be entitled to such benefits until an initial determination with respect to such timely reapplication is made.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8628E2BA4D674C50BD8F9829ECADA9FD" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>If the Commissioner of Social Security makes an initial adverse determination with respect to the timely reapplication of an individual who is a recipient of disability insurance benefits under this section or monthly benefits under section 202 by reason of being under a disability and such individual files a timely request for a hearing under section 221(d), such individual may elect to have the payment of such benefits (as well as any other benefits payable under this title or title XVIII on the basis of such individual's entitlement to such benefits) continue in the same manner and subject to the same conditions as an election made under subsection (g).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF6E07DBACF6443A59D3EAB6F899C1D5D" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For purposes of reviewing a timely reapplication submitted by an individual who is a recipient of disability insurance benefits under this section or monthly benefits under section 202 by reason of being under a disability—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A566EF2695D45DCACE776E3F27B3383"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the fact that the individual was previously found to be under a disability shall have no evidentiary weight;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8DEC52B2F0004D178FEAA9ACD21BCCBB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the fact that the individual participated in the process established under subsection (l) may be taken into account for purposes of determining whether such individual is under a disability; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H18492112FBEB40C490C8855322820F03"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>subsection (f) shall not apply.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF27166D22EE94B3B977447683BC6BFE5"><enum>6.</enum><header>Encouraging work by MIE and MIL individuals</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63090FC1D39E45A187759BB36F30FD32"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 223 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/423">42 U.S.C. 423</external-xref>), as amended by section 5, is further amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC579DB21CCD444569AEF4CDC19465670"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2), by striking <quote>section 202(q) and section 215(b)(2)(A)(ii)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (l) and sections 202(q) and 215(b)(2)(A)(ii)</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3E48E0A83774065B0B6B16DE70618B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block act-name="" id="HEC4771195FAF477AA1C84E3CFF0C9BC4" other-style="archaic" style="other"> <subsection id="HC1770864D1DD4A668586DC5A4FD1BAF7"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Treatment of work performed by certain disabled individuals</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE2DBD180DB3D432BAD0E2B74AFCFF086"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of Social Security shall establish a process whereby an eligible individual who is entitled to a disability insurance benefit under this section may elect to return to employment and receive an adjusted disability insurance benefit amount (as determined pursuant to paragraph (3)).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9885870EA45148D4842C0F8F07E54499" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2D7491AEA0ED41A1B9101673E7E8345E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>eligible individual</term> means an individual who has been classified as <term>medical improvement expected</term> or <term>medical improvement likely</term>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5A86B60678A24782A64017D8509A2063" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Participation by an eligible individual in the process established under this subsection shall be suspended if such individual has no reported wages or self-employment income for the 4 preceding calendar quarters (as defined in section 213(a)(1)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDD05D3789EF24154B3431D7E7F884919" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1284D9B39406446DB6C01F58A7CA30D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a)(2), the amount of the disability insurance benefit provided to an eligible individual who has elected to return to employment for any month shall be equal to—</text> <clause id="HF3CF4C409BF84FF18B24F1C7AD84C95C" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an individual who has average monthly earnings (as determined under subparagraph (B)) equal to or less than the level of monthly earnings established by the Commissioner to represent substantial gainful activity, the amount otherwise applicable for such individual under subsection (a)(2); or</text></clause>
<clause id="H233A48A31D5B43B3A85F513F1E38438E" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of individual who has average monthly earnings (as determined under subparagraph (B)) that are in excess of the level of monthly earnings established by the Commissioner to represent substantial gainful activity, the amount of the disability insurance benefit that would otherwise apply for such individual under subsection (a)(2) reduced (but not below zero) by an amount equal to 50 percent of the excess of such individual's average monthly earnings over the level of monthly earnings established by the Commissioner to represent substantial gainful activity.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7539C93A85194E678841A3090A85BEF6" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H871EBF5F1DC6430BBC16ECCB5F40ED5F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The average monthly earnings for an eligible individual shall be equal to the quotient of—</text>
<subclause id="H73EBF0F570824938B43CB27ED60EC9EC" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of wages and self-employment income for such individual in any eligible months during the 2 calendar quarters (as defined in section 213(a)(1)) that precede the most recently completed calendar quarter, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H5854FA6C163E490BB0ADD2237DEFE31B" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of eligible months during such 2-calendar-quarter period.</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H4AC575269AA84D519140B39FE63B2DBC" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), the term <term>eligible month</term> means any month subsequent to the month in which an eligible individual became entitled to a disability insurance benefit.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD9E5728FA37743588EE22BD355792FF0" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (3)(B), wages and self-employment income of an individual shall be determined based on relevant information for such individual as provided by the State agency responsible for the administration of State unemployment compensation law.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDBD26702696A4101B2BEFA2F86B7A51F" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of an eligible individual who has elected to return to employment under this subsection, any services performed or earnings derived from services during the period of such participation shall not be considered for purposes of demonstrating an individual's ability to engage in substantial gainful activity under subsection (d)(4) and shall not be considered substantial gainful activity for purposes of subsection (e).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8E92CF6908246F799888319319D8503" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this title, the disability insurance benefit received by an individual under this subsection shall not be applied for purposes of determining any monthly benefits payable to any other individuals entitled to benefits for any month based on the wages and self-employment income of such individual.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H881E387AFE914DF0B96DDF0B6B9683B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 221(m)(2)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/421">42 U.S.C. 421(m)(2)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(unless such individual is participating in the process established under section 223(l))</quote> before the period.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3A9BD2230F9430595550748E1653101"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to benefits payable for months beginning on or after April 1, 2018.</text></subsection></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1BC951CB8494D05B9AB7904B5174618"><enum>7.</enum><header>Increased funding for continuing disability reviews</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for any calendar year after 2017—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE4CA6661B0E4F8D99F32EB08D9ABE31"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Commissioner of Social Security shall determine the amount of any reduction in expenditures from the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund (as defined in section 201(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/401">42 U.S.C. 401(b)</external-xref>)) during the preceding calendar year by reason of the provisions of this Act and the amendments made by this Act; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B9136DC10D347D3AEA8913511594B6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>10 percent of the amount determined under paragraph (1) shall be authorized to be made available from the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund for continuing disability reviews (as defined in section 201(g)(1)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/401">42 U.S.C. 401(g)(1)(A)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

