<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB3D631E69F944B3E956C59DFE565F08B" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1558 RH: Repeatedly Flooded Communities Preparation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 196</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1558</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–276]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170316">March 16, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00" deleted-display-style="italic">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action><action-date>August 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000820">Mrs. Mimi Walters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000409">Mr. Rohrabacher</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action>
			<action-date>August 15, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 16, 2017</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to ensure community accountability for areas
			 repetitively damaged by floods, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H3EEB805E9083403C872E248F2410CE0C" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="H09AE3A8E4D9841C58910EE4278C8511E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Repeatedly Flooded Communities Preparation Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB85837C21166421BA10A464DEB5F2233"><enum>2.</enum><header>Community accountability for repetitively flooded areas</header> <subsection id="H2C3C37E968164E93930B591ED830C0AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1361 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4102">42 U.S.C. 4102</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" id="H9F493919BE9B4A82A30C7DA0C3405B03" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H5EC19058603D4B56AAD32E55010020ED"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Community accountability for repetitively damaged areas</header>
 <paragraph id="H0D7E82AE29694BAC8DF96EBD25EA7F77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall, by regulation, require any covered community (as such term is defined in paragraph (5))—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6AB4BB1625654D149AF4320C1C69CCDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to identify the areas within the community where properties described in paragraph (5)(B) or flood-damaged facilities are located to determine areas repeatedly damaged by floods and to assess, with assistance from the Administrator, the continuing risks to such areas;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE43B761E3BD64E5680E5D1995622AABE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to develop a community-specific plan for mitigating continuing flood risks to such repetitively flooded areas and to submit such plan and plan updates to the Administrator at appropriate intervals;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5642302C86A4080BE300F67F31328D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to implement such plans;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00E357E2E63D4C4EAA5A6A629210AC81"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to make such plan, plan updates, and reports on progress in reducing flood risk available to the public, subject to section 552a of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H11DAEF322002467FA84BD4E1899EE2AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Incorporation into existing plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Plans developed pursuant to paragraph (1) may be incorporated into mitigation plans developed under section 1366 of this Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4104c">42 U.S.C. 4104c</external-xref>) and hazard mitigation plans developed under section 322 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5165">42 U.S.C. 5165</external-xref>).</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H252AE01657AC4B1CB2507F3167B1087B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assistance to communities</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF3F0C93146C34C11A81942919134D589"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To assist communities in preparation of plans required under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall, upon request, provide covered communities with appropriate data regarding the property addresses and dates of claims associated with insured properties within the community.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC033869B6DE482BA293262771A0BA76"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mitigation grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making determinations regarding financial assistance under the authorities of this Act, the Administrator may consider the extent to which a community has complied with this subsection and is working to remedy problems with addressing repeatedly flooded areas.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H092FCCA4724B462FBD82C6B199EC6117"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sanctions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H4D4D10B9862A41298087B5980740AF21"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall, by regulations issued in accordance with the procedures established under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, regarding substantive rules, provide appropriate sanctions for covered communities that fail to comply with the requirements under this subsection or to make sufficient progress in reducing the flood risks to areas in the community that are repeatedly damaged by floods.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57D58D22E12C44BCBBE518A3B1633C55"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Before imposing any sanction pursuant to this paragraph, the Administrator shall provide the covered community involved with notice of the non-compliance that could result in the imposition of sanctions, which shall include recommendations for actions to bring the covered community into compliance.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54B3C53209694B9D9961237169145E10"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining appropriate sanctions to impose under this paragraph, the Administrator shall consider the resources available to the covered community involved, including Federal funding, the portion of the covered community that lies within an area having special flood hazards, and other factors that make it difficult for the covered community to conduct mitigation activities for existing flood-prone structures.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H155DFE71EADF4ADF99350AC167BC5CCE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered community</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>covered community</quote> means a community—</text> <subparagraph id="HA08147ED19DB423E8D1BD332C373D54F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is participating, pursuant to section 1315, in the national flood insurance program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3990F8D1E09545BB9E6B836B94B6F6F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>within which are located—</text> <clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB2A21734AEC4909854B88C6CFBB49D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">50 or more repetitive loss structures for each of which, during any 10-year period, two or more claims for payments under flood insurance coverage have been made with a cumulative amount exceeding $1,000;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1C0AADB9E16F4BBC94C48D0FD002C7A9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>5 or more severe repetitive loss structures (as such term is defined in section 1366(h)) for which mitigation activities meeting the standards for approval under section 1366(c)(2)(A) have not been conducted; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HADDF9464E1F642098841D972B2C7974F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a public facility or a private nonprofit facility (as such terms are as defined in section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122</external-xref>)), that has received assistance for repair, restoration, reconstruction, or replacement under section 406 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172</external-xref>) in connection with more than one flooding event in the most recent 10-year period.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDB8BF9BD22D4696A0E4E763AF05ADCC"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Repetitive-loss structure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>repetitive loss structure</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1370 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4121">42 U.S.C. 4121</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB0B7735C6E74CA89E547DF9DD1FE78A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Reports to congress</header><text>Not later than the expiration of the 6-year period beginning upon the date of the enactment of this subsection, and not less than every 2 years thereafter, the Administrator shall submit a report to the Congress regarding the progress in implementing plans developed pursuant to paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H34D8A81A6DAF4D859189F66A043B2F75"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall issue regulations necessary to carry out subsection (e) of section 1361 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, as added by the amendment made by subsection (a) of this section, not later than the expiration of the 12-month period that begins on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HD0A71DE4BB024B0DAD174C9BCFFC59AA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Monthly installment payment of premiums</header>
 <subsection id="HDCA0ED5882BE45B3809AEF2E767525DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (g) of section 1308 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4015">42 U.S.C. 4015(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H76F42A6A30DF4EE8A733D17A2DF009DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the subsection designation and all that follows through <quote>With respect</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D427338EEB64E9F89CC8686BA63D3D1" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H118AAAFB9B014664A62CC94895A9D407"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Frequency of premium collection</header> <paragraph id="H7F89B5DD8B6643CEB901C4057F368760"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Options</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DBB0E186B574D61AA1653951C768A06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" id="HB287B77085694518B3ADD0ECF419B856" reported-display-style="italic"> <paragraph id="HA8BEF7E6DB544492934AA690DF8945A0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Monthly installment payment of premiums</header> <subparagraph id="H670734D26F7D41ACBC9AB8062181DE0C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Exemption from rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Until such time as the Administrator promulgates regulations implementing paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Administrator may adopt policies and procedures, notwithstanding any other provisions of law and in alignment and consistent with existing industry escrow and servicing standards, necessary to implement such paragraph without undergoing notice and comment rulemaking and without conducting regulatory analyses otherwise required by statute, regulation, or Executive order.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7467090228B14AA383576C315042F985"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text>The Administrator may initially implement paragraph (1) of this subsection as a pilot program that provides for a gradual phase-in of implementation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H013A751E4F6142A1ACA67D616E74F7CF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Policyholder protection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may—</text> <clause id="HCE9EAB715DD14D0A8E1546047C48D327"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during the 12-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this subparagraph, charge policyholders choosing to pay premiums in monthly installments a fee for the total cost of the monthly collection of premiums not to exceed $25 annually; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4505CA63A968489FA7DF4AC2E804EDBD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">after the expiration of the 12-month period referred to in clause (i), adjust the fee charged annually to cover the total cost of the monthly collection of premiums as determined by the report submitted pursuant to subparagraph (D).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA4619683FBA46C3B2F2F96E0762DFE7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, that sets forth all of the costs associated with the monthly payment of premiums, including any up-front costs associated with infrastructure development, the impact on all policyholders including those that exercise the option to pay monthly and those that do not, options for minimizing the costs, particularly the costs to policyholders, and the feasibility of adopting practices that serve to minimize costs to policyholders such as automatic payments and electronic payments.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE1B554B90764583BE84A851DA697CD1"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Annual Reports</header><text>On an annual basis, the Administrator shall report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate the ongoing costs associated with the monthly payment of premiums.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD414D1365106413C979E32F07F58C5A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause (ii) of section 1307(a)(1)(B) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4014">42 U.S.C. 4014(a)(1)(B)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before <quote>any administrative expenses</quote> the following: <quote>the costs associated with the monthly collection of premiums provided for in section 1308(g) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4015">42 U.S.C. 4015(g)</external-xref>), but only if such costs exceed the operating costs and allowances set forth in clause (i) of this subparagraph, and</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>August 15, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc display="yes">Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


