<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF197E98F5CF64025AB901EFC9E2A14EC" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 304 IH: Protecting Patient Access to Emergency Medications Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 304</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170105">January 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001056">Ms. Beutler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000387">Mr. Knight</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000374">Mr. Abraham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Controlled Substances Act with regard to the provision of emergency medical services.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HFB5ECB6B9493441685E4C5E7D21F93AC" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1FEC6B4529A54E699F32F44FF189AFEB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Patient Access to Emergency Medications Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H754D8AB2021D4DBB984B19AB0A484021"><enum>2.</enum><header>Emergency medical services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 303 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7649A05EE10D4CAF8E4C4EAAFCA52BC6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (j) as subsection (k); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H42995E66D9EE4179B467122CC98B763C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (i) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7ECA32CEFF374EA39131D606B5FAF5BF" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H629074F64688482CBE59EA37377A0E17"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Emergency medical services that administer controlled substances</header>
 <paragraph id="H1FA38926689842738024CBFDC505143F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Registration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of enabling emergency medical services professionals to administer controlled substances in schedule II, III, IV, or V to ultimate users receiving emergency medical services in accordance with the requirements of this subsection, the Attorney General—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8117E098A715430697B20F7E01C1105B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall register an emergency medical services agency if the agency submits an application demonstrating it is authorized to conduct such activity under the laws of each State in which the agency practices; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H632ECA49F4394D2D802A186E3C399D57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may deny an application for such registration if the Attorney General determines that the issuance of such registration would be inconsistent with the requirements of this subsection or the public interest based on the factors listed in subsection (f).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF463F5C9C14A4136AA3C05C1DEB54563"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Option for single registration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In registering an emergency medical services agency pursuant to paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall allow such agency the option of a single registration in each State where the agency administers controlled substances in lieu of requiring a separate registration for each location of the emergency medical services agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D815240DBEA4838AC2D2B95EB30F010"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Hospital-based agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a hospital-based emergency medical services agency is registered under subsection (f), the agency may use the registration of the hospital to administer controlled substances in accordance with this subsection without being registered under this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H57AFEA55B4CC41B797E208070F4E280A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administration outside physical presence of medical director or authorizing medical professional</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Emergency medical services professionals of a registered emergency medical services agency may administer controlled substances in schedule II, III, IV, or V outside the physical presence of a medical director or authorizing medical professional in the course of providing emergency medical services if the administration is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H570F8FE678B247AD8A5EC8CF3FAA67A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>authorized by the law of the State in which it occurs; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H791B46FD545B4414A70AB4947934BD17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>pursuant to—</text>
 <clause id="H9A5FAA960E84490697EBE09BBB3633E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a standing order that is issued and adopted by one or more medical directors of the agency, including any such order that may be developed by a specific State authority; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H112F4ABEDA1F4EEA92572A121F637E55"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a verbal order that is—</text> <subclause id="HFDA4E135EE6D44F0ADD2C4F3ADA33413"><enum>(I)</enum><text>issued in accordance with a policy of the agency;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H69E316E318864CBC934B8DD29FC870D7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provided by an authorizing medical professional in response to a request by the emergency medical services professional with respect to a specific patient;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3ABEA799F3C549B89F2DAAB99AD88142"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in the case of a mass casualty incident; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H5A814CE980BA44E0ACB0D3C197EE3E40"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>to ensure the proper care and treatment of a specific patient.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C8678523B154C82B50C0B14BB505757"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Delivery</header><text>A registered emergency medical services agency may deliver controlled substances from a registered location of the agency to an unregistered location of the agency only if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC67574DF9913473A85D258EE81B2BEDA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the agency designates the unregistered location for such delivery; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C52257AE8AC4113A419EFB001A0A261"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notifies the Attorney General at least 30 days prior to first delivering controlled substances to the unregistered location.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0065A2301762434CB768469887AF59FA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Storage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A registered emergency medical services agency may store controlled substances—</text> <subparagraph id="HEC65BC765FAD4B0A8FA90D84127B26E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at a registered location of the agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAF23B2E94DD4BB7A299855790EF7B0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at any designated location of the agency or in an emergency services vehicle situated at a registered or designated location of the agency; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H125F4378D1C045B1A80F6B1E5EC92E2B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in an emergency medical services vehicle used by the agency that is—</text> <clause id="H86335AE967964B02B56262F443DABCF3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>traveling from, or returning to, a registered or designated location of the agency in the course of responding to an emergency; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H59B1DA4ACFE54495B7137402CC57A473"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>otherwise actively in use by the agency.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H84A13A41A1CB44169C6FCCF87550AEC8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>No treatment as distribution</header><text>The delivery of controlled substances by a registered emergency medical services agency pursuant to this subsection shall not be treated as distribution for purposes of section 308.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H543C7581FEB642C2A361107FC0A0070A"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Restocking of emergency medical services vehicles at a hospital</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (13)(J), a registered emergency medical services agency may receive controlled substances from a hospital for purposes of restocking an emergency medical services vehicle following an emergency response, and without being subject to the requirements of section 308, provided all of the following conditions are satisfied:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8681AFCDCDAE4434BD850FF816C688B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The registered or designated location of the agency where the vehicle is primarily situated maintains a record of such receipt in accordance with paragraph (9).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB116C6C317F74A37BF8626FB1B6D1E37"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The hospital maintains a record of such delivery to the agency in accordance with section 307.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E0B393D0D4244929258CFC682BC5CE4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the vehicle is primarily situated at a designated location, such location notifies the registered location of the agency within 72 hours of the vehicle receiving the controlled substances.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B4CB0E0400E4A0987EF69B3FB3E490A"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Maintenance of records</header>
 <subparagraph id="HFFE3BF26D6B44EC8B92192E851065030"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A registered emergency medical services agency shall maintain records in accordance with subsections (a) and (b) of section 307 of all controlled substances that are received, administered, or otherwise disposed of pursuant to the agency's registration, without regard to subsection 307(c)(1)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEF5F2E9CD5B4BBFAA81DFBFD3E85941"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Such records—</text> <clause id="H4D682EA80C144785AA61204727C06FF7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall include records of deliveries of controlled substances between all locations of the agency; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H54A8BF486B824015B8125FFFF127D61C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be maintained, whether electronically or otherwise, at each registered and designated location of the agency where the controlled substances involved are received, administered, or otherwise disposed of.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65E90157376B4F51A0DEBD5A2D68E036"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Other requirements</header><text>A registered emergency medical services agency, under the supervision of a medical director, shall be responsible for ensuring that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H547513265E08411AA5A78973A807CAFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all emergency medical services professionals who administer controlled substances using the agency's registration act in accordance with the requirements of this subsection;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE4D016B5F63409DAE13B54EB3E3CBA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the recordkeeping requirements of paragraph (9) are met with respect to a registered location and each designated location of the agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC956FD5520A646C6843BB6D50FCB66B5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the applicable physical security requirements established by regulation of the Attorney General are complied with wherever controlled substances are stored by the agency in accordance with paragraph (6); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E863719FD514F88BB94B7652AF71324"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the agency maintains, at a registered location of the agency, a record of the standing orders issued or adopted in accordance with paragraph (9).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA96040C4F95A412E8AFE2A6AB3A88A47"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Attorney General may issue regulations—</text> <subparagraph id="HCA08F22F3270422FAEF355C3EB70A74C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specifying, with regard to delivery of controlled substances under paragraph (5)—</text>
 <clause id="HAC9B35C43C8448F385497FF482E117C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the types of locations that may be designated under such paragraph; and</text> </clause><clause id="H87B2BB494AB4489AB85BC04E1FEDF228"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the manner in which a notification under paragraph (5)(B) must be made;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAB96FA9E192416385CEC70C1086A766"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specifying, with regard to the storage of controlled substances under paragraph (6), the manner in which such substances must be stored at registered and designated locations, including in emergency medical service vehicles; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFACC9BAFB3D146CE8120F18758A8C969"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">addressing the ability of hospitals, registered locations, and designated locations to deliver controlled substances to each other in the event of—</text>
 <clause id="H514E9AA8E4D94DCB9756E4525CA09129"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shortages of such substances;</text> </clause><clause id="H1DD5A1DC45D44B1AA4C8B2BCC28717AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a public health emergency; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBDCF2014FC2F493A9273E6A0BA32D752"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a mass casualty event.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA9615DD5D784F678CA92AE9F4ACA6C5"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H86A23A2A44B343F1BD0280D0B81E8B95"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to limit the authority vested in the Attorney General by other provisions of this title to take measures to prevent diversion of controlled substances; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA291E82EB6AB492991C892322CC35883"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to override the authority of any State to regulate the provision of emergency medical services.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC43FF53EAE7497EB9B0F4EBFB69FF1E"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE26C66D4347F47759A7A08D9039936BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <quote>designated location</quote> means a location designated by an emergency medical services agency under paragraph (5).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56BF364A9A7F412E90A431CE6E8D286F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <quote>emergency medical services</quote> means emergency medical response and emergency mobile medical services provided outside of a fixed medical facility.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19F6826063E7475C94BF2D814E887A16"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <quote>emergency medical services agency</quote> means an organization providing emergency medical services, including such an organization that—</text> <clause id="H1BE3F611A1D5422AA430CECD30F29AEB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is governmental (including fire-based and hospital-based agencies), nongovernmental (including hospital-based agencies), private, or volunteer-based;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H44A4120FF02F4CC6A17C56166D542592"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides emergency medical services by ground, air, or otherwise; and</text> </clause><clause id="HFD4D9B277B51450BA90D3F2ECB6BB2E9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is authorized by the State in which the organization is providing such services to provide emergency medical care, including the administering of controlled substances, to members of the general public on an emergency basis.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D4AEDE53D3F45D38E466F7D807E947E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The term <quote>emergency medical services professional</quote> means a health care professional (including a nurse, paramedic, or emergency medical technician) licensed or certified by the State in which the professional practices and credentialed by a medical director of the respective emergency medical services agency to provide emergency medical services within the scope of the professional’s State license or certification.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H779A1F531E9048EEABBCBCEEF3285924"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>emergency medical services vehicle</quote> means an ambulance, fire apparatus, supervisor truck, or other vehicle used by an emergency medical services agency for the purpose of providing or facilitating emergency medical care and transport or transporting controlled substances to and from the registered and designated locations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2296957113C14849A0C412968E010D81"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The term <quote>hospital-based</quote> means, with respect to an agency, owned or operated by a hospital.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FBBFD25AED242CE88F7D5AE005145B1"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>medical director</quote> means a physician who is registered under subsection (f) and provides medical oversight for an emergency medical services agency.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H014B8E6F02A14DFCB8F5D41FBDD2F246"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The term <quote>medical oversight</quote> means supervision of the provision of medical care by an emergency medical services agency.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8EB507AD16D43719788B8857673FAA0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The term <quote>medical professional</quote> means an emergency or other physician, or another medical professional (including an advanced practice registered nurse or physician assistant) whose scope of practice under a State license or certification includes the ability to provide verbal orders.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1145119DBC0B4F9EA961F09B8A866D5B"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>registered location</quote> means a location that appears on the certificate of registration issued to an emergency medical services agency under this subsection or subsection (f), which shall be where the agency receives controlled substances from distributors.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81305B9CD32D4E2DACC131ACF0A35FA4"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The term <quote>registered emergency medical services agency</quote> means—</text> <clause id="H4F8B72B8A2214531AAE9858339F944F6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an emergency medical services agency that is registered pursuant to this subsection; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1D56F35D7A904954AC27C1B9D22EDAEF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a hospital-based emergency medical services agency that is covered by the registration of the hospital under subsection (f).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H899EC6183D8F4B179A42153F00863CF7"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>specific State authority</quote> means a governmental agency or other such authority, including a regional oversight and coordinating body, that, pursuant to State law or regulation, develops clinical protocols regarding the delivery of emergency medical services in the geographic jurisdiction of such agency or authority within the State that may be adopted by medical directors.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H245BC5EB01064ECE9C774BBC89C72F65"><enum>(M)</enum><text>The term <quote>standing order</quote> means a written medical protocol in which a medical director determines in advance the medical criteria that must be met before administering controlled substances to individuals in need of emergency medical services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H036235B161D04669BF6D3A9C56CF0560"><enum>(N)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>verbal order</quote> means an oral directive that is given through any method of communication including by radio or telephone, directly to an emergency medical services professional, to contemporaneously administer a controlled substance to individuals in need of emergency medical services outside the physical presence of the authorizing medical director.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


