<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2C6E4E92D1ED40B080170B573EE707CB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4530 IH: Gaming Accountability and Modernization Enhancement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4530</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171204">December 4, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide that a person or governmental entity is not subject to civil or criminal liability under
			 Federal law for gaming activity that is lawful under State law, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2EB5B51B63054C8793BB59C7A0F01F9A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H160C7EFBA1664E61AE190C3E3B6A806C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gaming Accountability and Modernization Enhancement Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GAME Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H46F936E2B81F4005B394F59688439A91"><enum>2.</enum><header>No Federal liability for gaming activity lawful under State law</header> <subsection id="H0EA1C0BB267F4C77902F989F480DACF4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b) and notwithstanding any other law, a person or governmental entity is not subject to civil or criminal liability under any provision of Federal law for engaging through a gaming facility in gaming activity that is lawful under the law of the State in which such person or governmental entity engages in such activity.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HADD3D389D27942759095969F91EBBBBB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum consumer protections</header><text>Subsection (a) does not apply to a person or governmental entity with respect to gaming activity engaged in by the person or governmental entity in a State unless the law of the State provides for consumer protections with respect to such activity that include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HDDFF0FBF887B47AC9AD457474E5A7095"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Licensing of gaming facilities</header><text>Appropriate licensing or certification mechanisms for gaming facilities.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H63467E43D9534E0380F86D0E912E6BA0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting requirements for gaming facilities</header><text>Appropriate mechanisms, including reporting requirements, to ensure, to a reasonable degree of certainty, that gaming facilities are operating in a fair and transparent manner.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF681423265344A792B81CA3CE5CE735"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition of underage gaming</header><text>Appropriate safeguards to ensure, to a reasonable degree of certainty, that an individual placing a bet or wager is not under the minimum legal age for placing such a bet or wager established by the State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8136E51B48264D5FADB17AEDECE64B18"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prohibited locations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriate safeguards to ensure, to a reasonable degree of certainty, that an individual placing a bet or wager is physically located in a jurisdiction that has not prohibited such bet or wager at the time the bet or wager is placed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFE6B07048FC4EBD8DB5A7EBBF86A32F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Mandatory collection or reporting of customer taxes</header><text>Appropriate mechanisms to ensure, to a reasonable degree of certainty, that all Federal and State taxes relating to the placement of a bet or wager are collected from or reported by the person placing such bet or wager, as required by law, at the time of any payment of the proceeds of such bet or wager.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB607FFF98D354EC0BB4E0092942DCA53"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Mandatory collection or reporting of taxes on operator of gaming facility</header><text>Appropriate mechanisms to ensure that—</text> <subparagraph id="H45D78562F3104FA7B34E67B59D1E15B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all Federal and State taxes relating to the operation of a gaming facility are collected or reported, as required by law; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H908403FE07A045B391C5CA23EEEBAC6E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>adequate records are maintained to enable later audit or verification of such collection or reporting.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD815B233FAD4E68BB7F6257318FB1CE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Safeguards against financial crime</header><text>Appropriate safeguards to prevent, to a reasonable degree of certainty, fraud, money laundering, and financing of terrorism.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BD2876C19F14577983B498BC4259955"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Safeguards against compulsive play</header><text>Appropriate safeguards to combat compulsive gambling.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8FDACFCA31B24F19B366187F7FFC2614"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Privacy and data security safeguards</header><text>Appropriate safeguards to protect, to a reasonable degree of certainty, the privacy and online security of any person placing a bet or wager.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H09F11AAFF4A74998A822C744C89DFFFE"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Prevention of cheating</header><text>Appropriate safeguards to ensure, to a reasonable degree of certainty, that a bet or wager is fair and honest, and to prevent, to a reasonable degree of certainty, cheating (including collusion and the use of a cheating device).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E2A4DB052264361AE41F5D60069B9D9"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Integrity safeguards</header><text>In a State in which betting or wagering relating to sporting events is lawful under the law of the State, appropriate safeguards to ensure, to a reasonable degree of certainty, the integrity of the sporting event, including limitations on a bet or wager accepted during the sporting event.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H64E06A318CDF4E699BA7E54464168190"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Redress</header><text>Appropriate recourse mechanisms for persons affected by noncompliance with the consumer protections required by this subsection and any other consumer protections implemented by the State with respect to the placement of bets or wagers or the operation of gaming facilities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE183705202B248BCB6F3658C56651FCE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal Trade Commission filing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A gaming facility that accepts bets or wagers from persons in more than one State shall submit to the Commission a description of how the gaming facility has complied with the law of each such State with respect to each of the consumer protections described in subsection (b) that is provided for by the law of such State.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HEC807AE51DD74B1BA274345A22E9D905"><enum>3.</enum><header>Use of credit card to verify age prohibited</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any person to accept a credit card payment as a method of age verification for placing any bet or wager.</text>
		</section><section id="H66DA321125444440B51429441BB640AA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Enforcement</header>
			<subsection id="H3203969EFEBC462E83E956620A4B0264"><enum>(a)</enum><header>By Federal Trade Commission</header>
 <paragraph id="H9FE25F194E8642E9BB22EF3D62BF462B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of section 2(c) or 3, or a rule prescribed under such section, shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD82A767789E489689842FDC030D87A0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41</external-xref> et seq.) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act. Any person who violates section 2(c) or 3, or a rule prescribed under such section, shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79BEB37DB7D341F0A317DB83C11507B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>By State attorneys general</header>
 <paragraph id="HFDB17FFD6F274B66BD68640A129AA88C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the attorney general of a State has reason to believe that any person has violated or is violating section 2(c) or 3, or a rule prescribed under such section, the attorney general, in addition to any authority the attorney general may have to bring an action in State court under the consumer protection law of the State, may bring a civil action in any appropriate United States district court or in any other court of competent jurisdiction, including a State court, to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6ACF06A7C858438FB4019499BF1A1159"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enjoin further such violation by the defendant;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54E1237A93514536B7509C65F7A65B26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enforce compliance with such section or such rule;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2CF55725EC246DCBA89B95DB7A4DCD9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>obtain civil penalties; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4931D7D6AE4D4488AB73CB17BC327140"><enum>(D)</enum><text>obtain damages, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of residents of the State.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE71FC9254B34290B163D0BBCEF23559"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice and intervention by FTC</header><text>The attorney general of a State shall provide prior written notice of any action under paragraph (1) to the Commission and provide the Commission with a copy of the complaint in the action, except in any case in which such prior notice is not feasible, in which case the attorney general shall serve such notice immediately upon instituting such action. The Commission shall have the right—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H28CFB1501A324942AD5BAAA243B1F95B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to intervene in the action;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE4E22E174BB436690742A0B2AE3F14C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon so intervening, to be heard on all matters arising therein; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEC2054CB0964FBAACCBBA43EDECA4DC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to file petitions for appeal.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H093EBCE3F3F84A92A335358AEC565116"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on State action while Federal action is pending</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Commission has instituted a civil action for violation of section 2(c) or 3 (including a rule prescribed under such section), no State attorney general may bring an action under this subsection during the pendency of that action against any defendant named in the complaint of the Commission for any violation of such section (including such rule) alleged in the complaint.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H144E51ADFC37456CB7B37842A20ECE82"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Attorney general defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>attorney general</quote> means, with respect to a State, the attorney general or chief law enforcement officer of the State, or another official or agency designated by the State to bring civil actions on behalf of the State or the residents of the State.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H60665137AC484908B9BEC4DF0D14C5E6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may prescribe rules under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, to implement sections 2(c) and 3.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H88F2F4269E88452EB780BB7703F5A5DD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Preservation of authority of Commission</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed in any way to limit or affect the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HBF33804A933C484CB6B211CCBA948BB5"><enum>5.</enum><header>Gambling addiction prevention and treatment</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HAAE13EA186544E92B44F182A014F937A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To address gambling in Department of Health and Human Services authorities</header><text>Section 501(d) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290aa">42 U.S.C. 290aa(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H0889D6562C5D47EEA6B75A3ECEE4EC28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (24);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4BEC6A745F3345ECADFE9BE87CCEDDCA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (25) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB21A82DA96B84D5EB0B7DFD683D3CE1A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HC98965E6C1E44E92A3968FDA27AC77D0" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H903E157981B343CD870D8AE94E887D64"><enum>(26)</enum><text>establish and implement programs for prevention and treatment of gambling addiction.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H78B5B4BA2BC54B268B7C38601587977C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advisory Committee</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H072C72D8F05A451EA415749F2176C778"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may establish a Gambling Addiction Research Advisory Committee (in this paragraph referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>) within the National Institutes of Health to coordinate research conducted or supported by the Department of Health and Human Services on gambling addiction.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF74CC135857D45FF964FB9B30A58CDD7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Committee shall include representatives of the National Institute on Drug Abuse, the National Institute of Mental Health, the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism, the Indian Health Service, the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8322361AB5474F488BAB21E1A970FC41"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Committee shall prepare and submit to the Secretary an annual report on the research described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC9D1E178952C4E62B491BDC4B29EB9A9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Surveillance of gambling addiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title III of the Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 317T of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-22">42 U.S.C. 247b–22</external-xref>) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HDD516D0A41464E77A0D26D2E602FAAFB" style="OLC">
					<section commented="no" id="HE3D18AD72C9049D0B9C1C02E3C2CC26A"><enum>317U.</enum><header>Surveillance of gambling addiction</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HB406FF5624ED42459AABCCD6BDCC2821"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and in coordination with other appropriate agencies, shall, as appropriate—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HE6707E1B0B08497AB779904FAE7EE447"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enhance and expand infrastructure and activities to track the epidemiology of gambling addiction; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H89CE323D30074ACAB0952E4560F5B15B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>incorporate information obtained through such infrastructure and activities into an integrated surveillance system, which may consist of or include a registry, to be known as the National Gambling Addiction Surveillance System.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H13A10FFCD788448FB2B93788C03AEC30"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the National Gambling Addiction Surveillance System, if established, is designed in a manner that facilitates further research on gambling addiction.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H38C3B94E4592403390390D93ED456E7D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public access</header><text>Subject to subsection (d), the Secretary shall ensure that information and analysis in the National Gambling Addiction Surveillance System, if established, are available, as appropriate, to the public, including researchers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H1CC8788D50034D169B745C79EC257CCC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Privacy</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that information and analysis in the National Gambling Addiction Surveillance System, if established, are made available only to the extent permitted by applicable Federal and State law, and in a manner that protects personal privacy, to the extent required by applicable Federal and State privacy law, at a minimum.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H800E74F6A92847B2A396000881BFD3AE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="H6ACEF6330033418E9753401D3CEFC623"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H471DD6C7CE174554A7E48B2E98781CA9"> <enum>(1)</enum><header>Amateur sports organization</header> <text>The term <term>amateur sports organization</term> means—</text>
				<subparagraph id="H483B1A563ECD4447B3EC7D66CEB636EA">
					<enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>a person or governmental entity that sponsors, organizes, schedules, or conducts a competitive game in which one or more amateur athletes participate; or</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A2011D2273D4C9DAE47E8A73EB92342">
					<enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>a league or association of persons or governmental entities described in subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE232E44E5F4A450CA0E5A4722DB67C75"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bet or wager</header> <subparagraph id="H42CC83E4B82F44D1BC9A749BD5C70942"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>bet or wager</term> means the staking or risking by any person of something of value, including virtual currency and actual or virtual items that can be sold or otherwise exchanged for cash at the gaming facility or elsewhere, upon the outcome of a contest of others, a sporting event, a game subject to chance, or a game in which the outcomes reflect the relative knowledge and skill of the participants, upon an agreement or understanding that the person or another person will receive something of value in the event of a certain outcome.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E336EA4C8864F40996882ED7824E15B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>Such term includes the following:</text> <clause id="HA7691222DC514B7ABD6A8E3AEE3DF9E6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The purchase of a chance or opportunity to win a lottery or other prize.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9549A581C43244CDA582974EAC35A9A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any lottery, sweepstakes, or other betting, gambling, or wagering scheme based, directly or indirectly (through the use of geographical references or otherwise), on one or more competitive games in which amateur or professional athletes participate, or are intended to participate, or on one or more performances of such athletes in such games.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDAFAA3B4AA1A42C1A5BC9503F57C0D1B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any instructions or information pertaining to the establishment or movement of funds by the bettor or customer in, to, or from an account with the business of betting or wagering.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HEF2538F3BFD04A99B87AA8B761A18912"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Participation in any fantasy or simulation sports or e-sports game or contest, including those in which (if the game or contest involves a team or teams) no fantasy or simulation sports team is based on the current membership of an actual team that is a member of an amateur sports organization or professional sports organization and including those that meet any of the following conditions:</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H619DA012FE9D4E2F9038F0813FF708A8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>All prizes and awards offered to winning participants are established and made known to the participants in advance of the game or contest and their value is not determined by the number of participants or the amount of any fees paid by those participants.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HFCA507A15EF5491685C66489F34B7BC3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>All winning outcomes reflect the relative knowledge and skill of the participants and are determined predominantly by accumulated statistical results of the performance of individuals (athletes in the case of sports events) in multiple real-world sporting or other events.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HAA8A31EB5ED04B43B01E5EA88A50E1A6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>No winning outcome is based—</text> <item commented="no" id="H901953AC4706448E893DC383ED1D4CBA"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>on the score, point-spread, or any performance or performances of any single real-world team or any combination of such teams; or</text>
 </item><item commented="no" id="HBD60F9853E6B430BA718E2062B30DB91"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>solely on any single performance of an individual athlete in any single real-world sporting or other event.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD240C7C9744495AAB77063D318E75D9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>Such term does not include the following:</text> <clause id="H6B1276F17D1E404A87714A1CC5DC723E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Any activity governed by the securities laws (as defined in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>)) for the purchase or sale of securities (as defined in such section).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEEC90E034F6B4F60BB4B3C81479C4B75"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Any transaction conducted on or subject to the rules of a registered entity or exempt board of trade under the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1">7 U.S.C. 1</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5E975AF9180846CDBED2D6A220E95266"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any over-the-counter derivative instrument.</text> </clause><clause id="H49428074BB5E41079CB60F5740703076"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Any other transaction that—</text>
 <subclause id="HA592C3051E1B48AB94288DD94E954B3B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is excluded or exempt from regulation under the Commodity Exchange Act; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H704B64A29F514C48905A2916A176521C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is exempt from State gaming or bucket shop laws under section 12(e) of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/16">7 U.S.C. 16(e)</external-xref>) or section 28(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78bb">15 U.S.C. 78bb(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HD06AECD31BC14123BA684A43F3EB6926"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Any contract of indemnity or guarantee.</text> </clause><clause id="HDAC904B1719B43939A6374F42E8F1BBA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Any contract for insurance.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD3BCBAF58A834DAC88E0E75860F666B5"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Any deposit or other transaction with an insured depository institution.</text> </clause><clause id="HA39DBEA92CB94DD79C186093E4A78C6C"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Participation in any game or contest in which participants do not stake or risk anything of value other than—</text>
 <subclause id="H77DB09E1AB944936AEA731CAF2F16D29"><enum>(I)</enum><text>personal efforts of the participants in playing the game or contest or obtaining access to the internet; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD8C0B2900C97469EBD9D8E551098738E"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">points or credits that the sponsor of the game or contest provides to participants free of charge that can be used or redeemed only for participation in games or contests offered by the sponsor and that cannot be sold or otherwise exchanged for cash at the gaming facility or elsewhere.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD24B8F5BB02743D7A6EAD33B6E527679"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Business of betting or wagering</header><text>The term <term>business of betting or wagering</term> does not include the activities of a person who is—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4ED23A259615495CBAC1185594384081"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a financial transaction provider, to the extent such person is acting as such a provider, except with respect to an activity described in paragraph (10)(C)(ii); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCFB1801367624A78B53F48DA3A6D40A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a provider of an interactive computer service or telecommunications service, to the extent such person is acting as such a provider, except with respect to an activity described in paragraph (10)(C)(ii).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5B561C0F00A4145A75EE63345F0EC4F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF53D731B197A46129697EAA37D6E5401"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Credit; creditor; and card issuer</header><text>The terms <term>credit</term>, <term>creditor</term>, and <term>card issuer</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 103 of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1602">15 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1D2FE0EB7ADC41D08CF176440DDA9CBA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Electronic fund transfer</header><text>The term <term>electronic fund transfer</term>—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H59C76247107A41428EC442A67BB6EA98"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term in section 903 of the Electronic Fund Transfer Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1693a">15 U.S.C. 1693a</external-xref>), except that the term includes transfers that would otherwise be excluded under section 903(7)(E) of that Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H72B5FCB78B0D49E699A41DA07170325E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any fund transfer covered by Article 4A of the Uniform Commercial Code, as in effect in any State.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EFCA6DCE6DC4C3FAD5FF5DCFB2C885E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>E-sports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>e-sports</term> means a multiplayer video game played competitively for spectators.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB7CE759D5532449F85E899A302017199"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Financial institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>financial institution</term> has the meaning given the term in section 903 of the Electronic Fund Transfer Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1693a">15 U.S.C. 1693a</external-xref>), except that such term does not include a casino, sports book, or other business at or through which a bet or wager may be placed or received.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEF1B6CE7C2CB4457B9FD82664E0EFCD3"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Financial transaction provider</header><text>The term <term>financial transaction provider</term> means a creditor, card issuer, financial institution, operator of a terminal at which an electronic fund transfer may be initiated, money transmitting business, or international, national, regional, or local payment network utilized to effect a credit transaction, electronic fund transfer, stored value product transaction, or money transmitting service, or a participant in such network, or other participant in a system utilized by an entity described in this paragraph that could be utilized in connection with, or to facilitate, any transaction described in paragraph (10)(A)(iii).</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H6232C1D3339546DE85D811350E89C21D"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Gaming activity</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD425F8E7FBF149889D910BB35088476F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>gaming activity</term> means—</text> <clause id="H49698A478F574E0583956A4B916B23E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>placing, receiving, or otherwise transmitting a bet or wager;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8F257F6A94584ADEA094012F5831D8F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>transmitting—</text> <subclause id="H21BFB441ACE648BC8B2A2A005309A12A"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information assisting in the placing of a bet or wager; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H31F1A12920984E87B435FDC3611A0A20"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a wire communication which entitles the recipient to receive money or credit—</text> <item id="H2EC226D4DD16454BA16989725B857504"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>as a result of a bet or wager; or</text>
 </item><item id="H82CCBC145A9146B1A321667718F80468"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for information assisting in the placing of a bet or wager;</text> </item></subclause></clause><clause id="HAE1127F2AD0044BCA936E3BA7E816BD4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the knowing acceptance, by any person engaged in the business of betting or wagering, in connection with the placing, receiving, or otherwise transmitting of a bet or wager by another person, of credit or payment of any type; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFC9F4212C6F14105A82E336E6012EFB8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sponsoring, operating, advertising, or promoting (or, in the case of a governmental entity, sponsoring, operating, advertising, promoting, licensing, or authorizing by law or compact) a lottery, sweepstakes, or other betting, gambling, or wagering scheme based, directly or indirectly (through the use of geographical references or otherwise), on one or more competitive games in which amateur or professional athletes participate, or are intended to participate, or on one or more performances of such athletes in such games.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9FC9360ED4C42EA92EDDF6903F43C50"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such term does not include any activity or transaction described in paragraph (2)(C) or, in the case of a contract or other instrument described in such paragraph, any activity or transaction relating to such contract or other instrument.</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3CA87A3106E24C74AF4A93519D6A5423"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Financial transaction providers and providers of interactive computer service or telecommunications
			 service</header>
 <clause id="HA6923FCAC0B24640849CEABE4EDEF873"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Generally excluded</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), such term does not include any activity of a person who is—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H06731917A814455793A626CC11678C72"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a financial transaction provider, to the extent such person is acting as such a provider; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H9A5C4FF32AE34EDDBF96B4503E730E5F"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a provider of an interactive computer service or telecommunications service, to the extent such person is acting as such a provider.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HFD0BE8C064524F9786FD93E98BD0DC58"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Operation of gaming websites or other facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding clause (i), such term includes an activity of a financial transaction provider or provider of an interactive computer service or telecommunications service to the extent that such provider has actual knowledge and control of bets or wagers and—</text>
 <subclause id="HB9A4340834764E8AA2DED41340EC8190"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">operates, manages, supervises, or directs a website or other facility through which a bet or wager is initiated, received, or otherwise made, whether transmitted by telephone, internet, satellite, or other wire or wireless communication facility, service, or medium and whether or not the transmissions cross State boundaries; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4BD495EE0D234D6CA40D1EA25CD284FD"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">owns or controls, or is owned or controlled by, any person who operates, manages, supervises, or directs a website or other facility through which a bet or wager is initiated, received, or otherwise made, whether transmitted by telephone, internet, satellite, or other wire or wireless communication facility, service, or medium and whether or not the transmissions cross State boundaries.</text>
						</subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEB838C49D3834E1AB3C3FE324644BE74"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Gaming facility</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE3C5CE3C80E746BD85E3F638B37ED3DE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>gaming facility</term> means—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H3EDEFD3EC8B24EF1AD29A557709AAE03"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a facility that permits bets or wagers to be placed in a casino, on a riverboat, at a race track, or in another facility that hosts gaming activity in one physical location; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H9D398EE9976E48C88CE0EC63A88CD890"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a website or other facility through which a bet or wager is initiated, received, or otherwise made, whether transmitted by telephone, internet, satellite, or other wire or wireless communication facility, service, or medium and whether or not the transmissions cross State boundaries.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81794321B28A44F4BF83E84E0C8378C5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such term does not include any facility to the extent such facility is engaged in an activity or transaction that is excluded from the definition of <term>gaming activity</term> by subparagraph (B) or (C) of paragraph (10).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H692BA495B48F4FD5A14C9F6F5E8069BC"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Governmental entity</header><text>The term <term>governmental entity</term> means a State, a political subdivision of a State, or an entity or organization, including an entity or organization described in section 4(5) of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2703">25 U.S.C. 2703(5)</external-xref>), that has governmental authority within the territorial boundaries of the United States, including on lands described in section 4(4) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2703">25 U.S.C. 2703(4)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4D948B25C16E403B9AB017CE8A3EFEC2"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Insured depository institution</header><text>The term <term>insured depository institution</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HA04F5A21DDD040428C089C92CFC61567"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term in section 3(c) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813(c)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E254678B1604E45ABF454C8EEA4EB25"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes an insured credit union (as defined in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FCA4332744E424CBF2B5A071D5F2B09"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Interactive computer service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>interactive computer service</term> has the meaning given such term in section 230(f) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/230">47 U.S.C. 230(f)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF1C19415EF254EA6B0C65CD7F911ADAE"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Money transmitting business and money transmitting service</header><text>The terms <term>money transmitting business</term> and <term>money transmitting service</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 5330(d) of title 31, United States Code (determined without regard to any regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury thereunder).</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="H883D81D76E3C4CEE92D5700DAE47EF4C">
				<enum>(16)</enum><header>Professional sports organization</header>
 <text>The term <term>professional sports organization</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H429895CE690F4EA697DFFF7261E72C2D"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>a person or governmental entity that sponsors, organizes, schedules, or conducts a competitive game in which one or more professional athletes participate; or</text>
				</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC11650BC3A54BF29853D92D43A2AD4B">
					<enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>a league or association of persons or governmental entities described in subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02DF91A19A024993AED596FBC9688DE9"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H37BC44BB41994997854CBBD3A62AAC8F"><enum>(18)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A088027EEA54CE8A02E85CA9A61589A"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Telecommunications service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>telecommunications service</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/153">47 U.S.C. 153</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H91CD36D9175242E6B1D947FBC2C1D88A"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effect on other law</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H186F4349F878429AB3E93AFFC9102578"><enum>(a)</enum><header>No effect on State law or Tribal-State compacts relating to gambling</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed as altering, limiting, or extending any State law or Tribal-State compact prohibiting, permitting, or regulating gambling within the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5182EAE96215467BBAC3EB8BFCC7A0C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No effect on Indian Gaming Regulatory Act</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to have any effect on a gaming activity within the scope of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2701">25 U.S.C. 2701</external-xref> et seq.), any successor provision of such Act, or any Tribal-State compact or authority pursuant to such Act or successor provision.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1DFD98CEF8554F2BB44B49DE480C2B8E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No effect on Illegal Gambling Business Act</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to supersede or otherwise limit section 1955 of title 18, United States Code (commonly referred to as the Illegal Gambling Business Act).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4BC74C9E8A854593AF98CA287F6E3B27"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No effect on Interstate Horse Racing Act</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to supersede or otherwise limit the Interstate Horse Racing Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3001">15 U.S.C. 3001</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H1AF45D49AC4545C082CCFAF9C8F28B15"><enum>8.</enum><header>Repeal</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H143C3279440E434D9634FCCC6B3A7365"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/178">Chapter 178</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code (commonly referred to as the Professional and Amateur Sports Protection Act) is repealed.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H545CA79BB2F244FD80753FC2A433DDA5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of chapters for part VI of title 28, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to chapter 178.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


