<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE760D117321E4C50BE2B110343E1D173" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1082 IH: Medicaid Home Owner Maximum Equity Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1082</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170215">February 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to eliminate the State option to reduce the home
			 equity exemption amount for purposes of eligibility for long-term care
			 assistance under Medicaid, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H811B2D2D18244421A69743B6052744FF" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6B38C105CD564E6BA1D07F289211BA3E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicaid Home Owner Maximum Equity Improvement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Medicaid HOME Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA5BAA2A14F3C4266B1DD26E4E6562DA2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Eliminating State option to reduce medicaid home equity exemption amount for purposes of determining eligibility for long-term care assistance</header> <subsection id="HF1EFF7D7F6EF4ACBB8930343DA162E5F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1917(f)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396p">42 U.S.C. 1396p(f)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H364041000A2042EA997ACCDCD0AF60B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>subparagraphs (B) and (C)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (B)</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5B441C282C74414ABEB24FBFA9DB736"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4663C7B3188640FDAE7D875BE3D56866"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (B); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H168A46B774DC40A1AE04F440955C06E0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>dollar amounts specified in this paragraph</quote> and inserting <quote>dollar amount specified in subparagraph (A)</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1CEFF291A1E6439680DCD3C9E27178CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="HFB825E0EAED7483F88B9582BD40A4E1E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to eligibility determinations made after the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9BE406EAF94B4798B360263DF014C509"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for State legislation</header><text>In the case of a State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act that the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation in order for the respective plan to meet any requirement imposed by amendments made by this section, the respective plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such title solely on the basis of its failure to meet such an additional requirement before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session shall be considered to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


