<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7A19AC5BFC5E4690BDDD4B25E8E171E6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 547 IH: National Infrastructure Development Bank Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 547</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170113">January 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000523">Mr. Price of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster of New Hampshire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000263">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000480">Mrs. Lowey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To facilitate efficient investments and financing of infrastructure projects and new job creation
			 through the establishment of a National Infrastructure Development Bank,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HCFFF6743FA204BAEB2A154576F03D5BB" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4F75A1B659D14A37A3757FC0117678BD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Infrastructure Development Bank Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB3511470AA044383ADB89079C3DC9F9F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H29631B0B176A4F04BAF83BEB70DAA73F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Investment in infrastructure has always created jobs and economic growth for the United States and has been a key component of maintaining a global competitive edge for the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD3E631D700A4D13B5C4BE1AC8BFFC51"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Erie Canal, the transcontinental railroad, the Hoover Dam, rural electrification, and the interstate highway system are all examples of investments in infrastructure that created the conditions for future economic growth.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9FE3B59D0994F13BC14582AF482A204"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the World Economic Forum Global Competitiveness Report, the United States ranks 11th overall in infrastructure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB617F230CB940CDA5D66734AC54E582"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the American Society of Civil Engineers, the current condition of the infrastructure in the United States earns a grade point average of D+, and an estimated $3,600,000,000,000 investment is needed by 2020 to meet adequate conditions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFAFEB1516D4242C9A419F9934B302D2E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Environmental Protection Agency projects that—</text> <subparagraph id="H79F1415AB48C4DD485E24424C1395A93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$384,200,000,000 is needed to invest in infrastructure improvements over 20 years to ensure the provision of safe water; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B9E907AA735474A969F20F05107753D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$271,000,000,000 is needed for publicly owned wastewater systems-related infrastructure needs over 20 years.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F6EA2AF7D2D41729D726396AE17485E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>According to the Edison Electric Institute, the electric power industry will need to invest $298,000,000,000 in the Nation’s transmission system in the next 20 years in order to maintain reliable service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE95AE0F92E84CC0B6A8C15966672AC8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Although grant programs of the Government must continue to play a central role in financing the transportation, environment, energy, and telecommunications infrastructure needs of the United States, current and foreseeable demands on existing Federal, State, and local funding for infrastructure expansion exceed the resources to support these programs by margins wide enough to prompt serious concerns about the United States ability to sustain long-term economic development, productivity, and international competitiveness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE5D83D9CAAC4DB1BA197E8E1A60D0AE"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The capital markets, including central banks, pension funds, financial institutions, sovereign wealth funds, and insurance companies, have a growing interest in infrastructure investment. The establishment of a United States Government-owned institution that would provide this investment opportunity to finance qualifying infrastructure projects would attract needed capital for United States infrastructure development.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H640FE697025B41B5A4FA980CFC3B33F0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the following definitions apply unless the context requires otherwise:</text> <paragraph id="H3B669C9ED3A2432BA628710401ADFF75"><enum>(1)</enum><header>American Infrastructure Bond</header><text>The term <quote>American Infrastructure Bond</quote> means a bond described under section 17.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01FC36EFC4314017B668B5D2356F5B4A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bank</header><text>The term <quote>Bank</quote> means the National Infrastructure Development Bank established under section 4(a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H49B4A8FCEA684AC7BC4CB9D02F9509B3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Board</header><text>The term <quote>Board</quote> means the National Infrastructure Development Bank Board.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE858F30939CB4D829EC663AFA3C0E03B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Chief asset and liability management officer</header><text>The term <quote>chief asset and liability management officer</quote> means the chief individual responsible for coordinating the management of assets and liabilities of the Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0AE139F27B8C42A4BAD1CA9E3886E787"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Chief compliance officer</header><text>The term <quote>chief compliance officer or CCO</quote> means the chief individual responsible for overseeing and managing the compliance and regulatory affairs issues of the Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70F1D92DDC8741EC94A114FE3E4088F5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Chief executive officer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>chief executive officer or CEO</quote> means the individual serving as the executive director of the bank.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E0F08586CB247D08FB94AFFCFE7E30A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Chief financial officer</header><text>The term <quote>chief financial officer or CFO</quote> means the chief individual responsible for managing the financial risks, planning, and reporting of the Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4B565A4B8214AEEACA76069B66870D7"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Chief loan origination officer</header><text>The term <quote>chief loan origination officer</quote> means the chief individual responsible for the processing of new loans provided by the Bank.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF64287D7ECF4A1E85D19AF3E2CCBF1E"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Chief operations officer</header><text>The term <quote>chief operations officer or COO</quote> means the chief individual responsible for information technology and the day-to-day operations of the Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC28C05023CA4EBA8A7DBF8D9196A1C9"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Chief risk officer</header><text>The term <quote>chief risk officer or CRO</quote> means the chief individual responsible for managing operational and compliance-related risks of the Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E4AD63C42194911B900C946A0BCDC10"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Chief treasury officer</header><text>The term <quote>chief treasury officer</quote> means the chief individual responsible for managing the Bank’s treasury operations.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE66F64F4D1A4DA08F260DF13DFB824E"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Development</header><text>The terms <quote>development</quote> and <quote>develop</quote> mean, with respect to an infrastructure project, any—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8318C1E829EA4EA89DBD02F5BACCEA04"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preconstruction planning, feasibility review, permitting, design work, life-cycle maintenance planning, and other preconstruction activities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H869504B52CDF4ED597495591037D9EC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation, replacement, or expansion.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F44525B8DCB4DFFA1E433C28439B617"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Direct loan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>direct loan</quote> has the same meaning as in section 502 of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/661a">2 U.S.C. 661a</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03D74EDB049C4F5A8769D1ECD0D42F1B"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Disadvantaged community</header><text>The term <quote>disadvantaged community</quote> means a community with a median household income of less than 80 percent of the statewide median household income for the State in which the community is located.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDD4D17DBA094716B17FA8641C3801B3"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Energy infrastructure project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>energy infrastructure project</quote> means any project for energy transmission and distribution, energy efficiency enhancement for buildings, public housing, health facilities, schools, and energy storage.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4C43D878955412CAC8F19468090B05E"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>entity</quote> means an individual, corporation, partnership (including a public-private partnership), joint venture, trust, and a State or other governmental entity, including a political subdivision or any other instrumentality of a State or a revolving fund.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H79D1CD79A4B644FE82657C305B8C924B"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Environmental infrastructure project</header><text>The term <quote>environmental infrastructure project</quote> means any project for the establishment, maintenance, or enhancement of any drinking water and wastewater treatment facility, storm water management system, flood gate, dam, levee, dredging, open space management system, wetland restoration, infill development, solid waste disposal facility, hazardous waste facility, or industrial site cleanup or remediation projects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD98F50FB0AF94CE699F4EE17E648BFC8"><enum>(18)</enum><header>General counsel</header><text>The term <quote>general counsel</quote> means the individual who serves as the chief lawyer for the Bank.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H628EBD6BA33849218AD2A182EAA44DB7"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Greenhouse gases</header><text>The term <quote>greenhouse gases</quote> means any of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3EACFC7216F54D4A96FE994115D21B91"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Carbon dioxide.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF822C546A1324767BFFB21992644A7F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Methane.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95BD90A6B6584AF38B5BC48D5F6F80BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Nitrous oxide.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H288EFA7154804E5D8E8A2C7591230F07"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Sulfur hexafluoride.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50840EDBA4B947CBA66EB4DCCE32BA5B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Hydrofluorocarbons.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD8815DEDA844C9BB5DA0868C5A5C5BD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any perfluorocarbon.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAE0E71DABA344E39F701520DD91C144"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Nitrogen trifluoride.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE01311047224A8D9D8326C34B97E6F9"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Any other anthropogenic gas designated as a greenhouse gas by the Environmental Protection Agency Administrator.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DDF63CF28CE48B9BE92772D0E545F4F"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Infrastructure project</header><text>The term <quote>infrastructure project</quote> means any energy, environmental, telecommunications, or transportation infrastructure project.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H82E4B04769714D90B5E0787705568DAA"><enum>(21)</enum><header>Loan guarantee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>loan guarantee</quote> has the same meaning as in section 502 of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/661a">2 U.S.C. 661a</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C69684C05CA4DE097CE2D8DAB9AC50B"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Public Benefit Bond</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Public Benefit Bond</quote> means any bond issued in accordance with this Act if—</text> <subparagraph id="H311A765AE50A4813A1B97612A446EE8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the proceeds from the sale of the bond are to be used for expenditures incurred after the date of issuance with respect to any infrastructure project or other purpose, subject to such rules as the Bank may provide;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86F98B5368A04782B8A17FE303C208F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the bond is issued in registered form;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB16612B3F15244169AC416E0C98CF480"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the bond has such terms, and carries interest in such an amount, as determined by the Bank; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2880C5CC1F4941B0B2E373D1D58345DD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>payments of interest and principal with respect to the bond is the obligation of the Bank and is backed by the full faith and credit of the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H59663F7F00DA4445A69462D37A01A48E"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Public-private partnership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>public-private partnership</quote> means any entity—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HF5D993B1C997417FBCFC8C2534EBA2CC"><enum>(A)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H04E1953FC8D74353957042C7F1391CDF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which is undertaking the development of all or part of an infrastructure project, which will have a public benefit, pursuant to requirements established in one or more contracts between the entity and a State or an instrumentality of a State; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H0BF3937A66364B12B070E45E5BA6C8D8" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the activities of which, with respect to such an infrastructure project, are subject to regulation by a State or any instrumentality of a State; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7ADD4D99769C42E0AD472F8ADE89268F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which owns, leases, or operates, or will own, lease, or operate, the project in whole or in part, and at least one of the participants in the entity is a nongovernmental entity.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H16C211FF31624F89B9AA1B5FA825DC10"><enum>(24)</enum><header>Revolving fund</header><text>The term <quote>revolving fund</quote> means a fund or program established by a State or a political subdivision or other instrumentality of a State, the principal activity of which is to make loans, commitments, or other financial accommodation available for the development of one or more categories of infrastructure projects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52ABFD670B714FCAA50BE6943CFAB700"><enum>(25)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Treasury or the designee of the Secretary.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1DBF37343D02474BB2A6080B08A6C95F"><enum>(26)</enum><header>Smart grid</header><text>The term <quote>smart grid</quote> means a system that provides for any of the smart grid functions set forth in section 1306(d) of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17386">42 U.S.C. 17386(d)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF278252FFFB348EC8A3959A07DC886F9"><enum>(27)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> includes the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of Northern Mariana Islands, and any other territory of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C0AFB56CA0C42609E3E3319793DB452"><enum>(28)</enum><header>Telecommunications infrastructure project</header><text>The term <quote>telecommunications infrastructure project</quote> means any project involving infrastructure required to provide communications by wire or radio.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC1A834AE8444C6CB3E3C13E2E97AF39"><enum>(29)</enum><header>Transportation infrastructure project</header><text>The term <quote>transportation infrastructure project</quote> means any project for the construction, maintenance, or enhancement of highways, roads, bridges, transit and intermodal systems, inland waterways, commercial ports, airports, high speed rail and freight rail systems.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H9371BA8F925C4F1EB8B246C08C2A2D84"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of national infrastructure development bank</header>
 <subsection id="H19D420D21BC744EA8E6CEA74B3291902"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of national infrastructure development bank</header><text>The National Infrastructure Development Bank is established as a wholly owned Government corporation subject to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/91">chapter 91</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Government Corporation Control Act</quote>), except as otherwise provided in this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H69F8AECEC5774C3A829CB254BC2743C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibility of the secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall take such action as may be necessary to assist in implementing the establishment of the bank in accordance with this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H356E730F05CE48B692E0A418E9A0F22B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 9101(3) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting after subparagraph (N) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F5E8586B50D474494CB5D4A977ED83A" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H094388D95279474B950B331314C9B006"><enum>(O)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Infrastructure Development Bank.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section><section id="HEAC67C1CDFA145DC91460B0D2D1C1706"><enum>5.</enum><header>Board of directors</header> <subsection id="H6E220E68112643769A71A41558A43090"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bank shall have a Board of Directors consisting of 7 members appointed by the President and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H39F1F82E3B1346FB95172A9C84F71870"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>The directors of the Board shall include individuals representing different regions of the United States and—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4269FFB9D2E84F41880F4A8359A321DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>2 of the directors shall have public sector experience;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4EB1675DB89340C0B1AF9F2846BEC9B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>2 of the directors shall have private sector experience; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2755DDB74D0F4B3BB149A0299B1006E5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>3 of the directors shall have finance experience.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF5182042197F4664BEF7D305A901B67B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chairperson and vice chairperson</header><text>As designated at the time of appointment, one of the directors of the Board shall be designated chairperson of the Board by the President and one shall be designated as vice chairperson of the Board by the President.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HF484DC6C931049F2994FD230578E3E25"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Terms</header>
 <paragraph id="H4621F7DFB7704CD888BFDF08E4BA5FD1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2) and subsection (f), each director shall be appointed for a term of 6 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF3945BB020442C5A5F5CC83C8580C8D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial staggered terms</header><text>Of the initial members of the Board—</text> <subparagraph id="HFB025E20B6744E608C4824F6239A6844"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the chairperson and vice chairperson shall each be appointed for terms of 6 years;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6564C33276F3468585F1AFADDDA0E0C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>3 shall be appointed for a term of 4 years; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B92A46464BF4E4380FB79D6B4D822E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed for a term of 2 years.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE34EC1DE63D49739F4FBA53D32500E8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Congressional recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the majority leader of the Senate, the minority leader of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the minority leader of the House of Representatives shall each submit a recommendation to the President for appointment of a member of the Board of Directors, after consultation with the appropriate committees of Congress.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H21E7E1E9F15D43E0B25F6983A68E4201"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Date of initial nominations</header><text>The initial nominations by the President for appointment of directors to the Board shall be made not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H619D891FDACF4AB89BC76F20FF5736CA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Vacancies</header>
 <paragraph id="HD1FBA79D3B84418AB9CE797A20237FEB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A vacancy on the Board shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H186BA3628C544E50BDD03128AB64F305"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointment to replace during term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any director appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which the director’s predecessor was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of the term.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H49FA2188DD5D454CAFD4D8CF30BAD1E0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A director may serve after the expiration of that director’s term until a successor has taken office.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC4A352094EB0486CA78C3B6E6D2B6747"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>Four directors shall constitute a quorum.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HB4725D025B67476A9AA46EEFDB54AF20"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reappointment</header><text>A director of the Board appointed by the President may be reappointed by the President in accordance with this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0CEFB9A7C5404B6F9B07580CF39E36A3"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Per diem reimbursement</header><text>Directors of the Board shall serve on a part-time basis and shall receive a per diem when engaged in the actual performance of Bank business, plus reasonable reimbursement for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H64270D36D8D142CBB314A2EC842A4F38"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A director of the Board may not participate in any review or decision affecting a project under consideration for assistance under this Act if the director has or is affiliated with a person who has an interest in such project.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H873F443A9E584E58968510659F4A1023"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The Board shall—</text> <paragraph id="H71ECE49A29B64C8BB79482544834BA01"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as soon as is practicable after the date on which the last director is appointed, establish an Executive Committee, Risk Management Committee and Audit Committee as prescribed by this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H28E579AC78614B99B7335266249A41D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date on which the last director is appointed develop and approve the bylaws of the Bank, including bylaws for the regulation of the affairs and conduct of the business of the Bank, consistent with the purpose, goals, objectives, and policies set forth in this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H959C6DD369EC4947A05A6FA9BEF21AD4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that the Bank is at all times operated in a manner that is consistent with this Act, by—</text> <subparagraph id="HF811B17A495D4369B274C14EF6BC71BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>monitoring and assessing the effectiveness of the Bank in achieving its strategic goals;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79C71EEC44474E9DBC0F3547A51F1A12"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">periodically reviewing internal policies submitted by the chief executive officer;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A8019BF8AD24544BF60CD36B2BA99F7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reviewing and approving annual business plans, annual budgets, and long-term strategies submitted by the chief executive officer;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFAB08F742A941D080BDBAEDA3709AB9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>reviewing and approving annual reports submitted by the chief executive officer;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB91CA182D7EE4318A5A806857EB11592"><enum>(E)</enum><text>reviewing risk management and audit practices of the Bank; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8289B09D5EC744EBA0A5876911BF81DC"><enum>(F)</enum><text>reviewing and approving all changes to the organization of the Bank; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDC3008122F845E7A1DFDDA4D9CE2321"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish such other criteria, requirements, or procedures as the Board may consider to be appropriate in carrying out this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H59F032101B48439990DE08D537FC6378"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Meetings</header>
 <paragraph id="HF5704B936BBB4F23B42837FB82D4E290"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Open to the public; notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All meetings of the Board held to conduct the business of the Bank shall be open to the public and shall be preceded by reasonable notice.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD17CBEB3013A4E47A7019D1824D94489"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall meet not later than 90 days after the date on which the last director is appointed and otherwise at the call of the Chairperson.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H97DCBBFE19E54511828AB128C442F4B2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for closed meetings</header><text>Pursuant to such rules as the Board may establish through their bylaws, the directors may close a meeting of the Board if, at the meeting, there is likely to be disclosed information which could adversely affect or lead to speculation relating to an infrastructure project under consideration for assistance under this Act or in financial or securities or commodities markets or institutions, utilities, or real estate. The determination to close any meeting of the Board shall be made in a meeting of the Board, open to the public, and preceded by reasonable notice. The Board shall prepare minutes of any meeting which is closed to the public and make such minutes available as soon as the considerations necessitating closing such meeting no longer apply.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H89B655B9423E4289B85EAF3928B13E5F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Powers and limitations of the Board</header>
 <subsection id="HB6C6F2446DA8470C95139887F7241DA7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Powers</header><text>In order to carry out the purposes of the Bank as set forth in this Act, the Board shall be responsible for monitoring and overseeing infrastructure projects and have the following powers:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2E1205E03FD147F182B791C4370AA16A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To make senior and subordinated direct loans on such terms as the Board may determine, in the Board’s discretion, to be appropriate to assist in the financing or refinancing of an infrastructure project.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25B1795AABBB477C85BB8A1079CBC8BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To make loan guarantees on such terms as the Board may determine, in the Board’s discretion, to be appropriate to assist in the financing or refinancing of an infrastructure project.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCE7537133F03400EABFADC931FC8AEF7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To issue Public Benefit Bonds, to provide financing to infrastructure projects from amounts made available from the issuance of such bonds.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H88F0F314B0584836A63986151FAB8AF7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To pay an interest subsidy on American Infrastructure Bonds to the issuer of such bonds.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1BC077C0750D445A93A9C07178519A58"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To make agreements and contracts with any entity in furtherance of the business of the Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6456DA6ECAF749909219E0FC51B9A651"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To monitor and oversee infrastructure projects financed, in whole or in part, by the Bank.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H173B5B52362F484687896F48B0C081A2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>To sue and be sued in the Bank’s corporate capacity in any court of competent jurisdiction, except that no attachment, injunction, or similar process, may be issued against the property of the Bank or against the Bank with respect to such property.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35FE73C074224D02A002FD0FC640E21A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>To indemnify the directors and officers of the Bank for liabilities arising out of the actions of the directors and officers in such capacity, in accordance with, and subject to the limitations contained in, this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H79CBAFF5C521411AB7B3564A5C739247"><enum>(9)</enum><text>To serve as the primary liaison between the Bank and the Congress, the executive branch, and State and local governments, and to represent the Bank’s interests.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF83E344B2FB47F8A376548B72D4FDA7"><enum>(10)</enum><text>To exercise all other lawful powers which are necessary or appropriate to carry out, and are consistent with, the purposes of the Bank.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58361BD2EC7C4C1490701FFAC88F1C38"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations</header>
 <paragraph id="H481005A5764D45FEAC92639E49D7863E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Issuance of Public Benefit Bonds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board may not issue any Public Benefit Bond without the prior consent of the Secretary.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H83EE4F066AC74C849C590E6F02D5181A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employee protections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to providing any financial assistance for an infrastructure project involving reconstruction, rehabilitation, replacement or expansion that may impact current employees on the project site, the interests of employees affected by the financial assistance shall be protected under arrangements the Secretary of Labor concludes are fair and equitable.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBD3B60E4BE8847E7823B82A4F243976F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Actions consistent with self-Supporting entity status</header><text>The Board shall conduct its business in a manner consistent with the requirements of this section.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HE0108808D55747A2BD2500A98E0BEE87"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination with state and local regulatory authority</header><text>The provision of financial assistance by the Board pursuant to this Act shall not be construed as—</text>
 <paragraph id="H85A9307926F24796BD3764053C919120"><enum>(1)</enum><text>limiting the right of any State or political subdivision or other instrumentality of a State to approve or regulate rates of return on private equity invested in a project; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4CD3CCDBC12049E79ADC07BB6D25EA00"><enum>(2)</enum><text>otherwise superseding any State law or regulation applicable to a project.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H43237E2CA7B8450484F888024699E917"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal personnel requests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall have the power to request the detail, on a reimbursable basis, of personnel from other Federal agencies with specific expertise not available from within the Bank or elsewhere. The head of any Federal agency may detail, on a reimbursable basis, any personnel of such agency requested by the Board and shall not withhold unreasonably the detail of any personnel requested by the Board.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H2F2A9E63457C4C5AA71A3CF28B79E542"><enum>7.</enum><header>Executive committee</header>
 <subsection id="HEBE9B94A7A3D43D08F9EA1CAA9BF7421"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall establish an Executive Committee consisting of 9 members, headed by the chief executive officer of the Bank.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBB37F75BB7E1498998F255C5A88D0526"><enum>(b)</enum><header>CEO</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A majority of the Board shall have the authority to appoint and reappoint the chief executive officer with such executive functions, powers, and duties as may be prescribed by this Act, the bylaws of the Bank, or the Board.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF79739551A4D4167A640CC11ACE1222B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>CEO responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The CEO shall have responsibility for the development and implementation of the strategy of Bank, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H281808EE0C5B454EB8C01A76642591E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the development and submission to the Board of the annual business plans and budget;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D14D282242F4E9CAA33F5B104F9EA44"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the development and submission to the Board of a long-term strategic plan; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B5CA4A192514DE8BD6510DCECF2FA71"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the development, revision, and submission to the Board of Directors of internal policies.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H669163DF486143F7884382DC971F11BD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Other executive officers</header><text>The Board shall appoint, remove, fix the compensation, and define duties of 8 other executive officers to serve on the Executive Committee as the—</text>
 <paragraph id="H92B5A1D05EAE48A5BA7BBEC576F85435"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">chief compliance officer;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H325588ED552440DCA99182A4E187A514"><enum>(2)</enum><text>chief financial officer;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1A501215660438CA8FA6C77C8265EA3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>chief asset and liability management officer;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H28C7E13D927848C3A74D0BD6A4CCF316"><enum>(4)</enum><text>chief loan origination officer;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5D2C028B82234B6D84F1E19EA725BC97"><enum>(5)</enum><text>chief operations officer;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H153A7F19AB9B4947BDD4EBB6D6632ED8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>chief risk officer;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H57FF241D49F44E259CAEC43F4EE4A97B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>chief treasury officer; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H459F0885202848B7B4672A28B2CA4A0C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>general counsel.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5E3C004AD80C4EA6BDEE95B9962CDC0D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>The CEO shall have experience and expertise in finance and the other executive officers shall have demonstrated experience and expertise in one or more of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1BCD72CB098149D1897B776C725F0C14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Transportation infrastructure.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD97B8FAB9CC47E09BB91B533AC41B17"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Environmental infrastructure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA74AF97C0EF4CFE966208FEEBE46196"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Energy infrastructure.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H82DD3915F4154A61AB627482903EC876"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Telecommunications infrastructure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE9915FA85E34172991881C9B53D45EB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Economic development.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H82130A16FE5F47F3B0DBB1A5BF1407EF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Workforce development.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B221CFFDE354CD0A46D0724728294AE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Public health.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF634BCDEF4134C2FA5F5226D6AA689D4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Private or public finance.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H38AEC33AA3F84739B859E24DCF3542E9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>In order to carry out the purposes of the Bank as set forth in this Act, the Executive Committee shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H13D7E474EEEE4DDBB57E4D66915AF7DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish and submit to the Board disclosure and application procedures for entities nominating projects for assistance under this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA31518E3F80404DABB9BCF949D88BBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish and submit to the Board standardized terms and conditions, fee schedules, or legal requirements of a contract or program to carry out this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF15B94905D88470CB3785C5C47536523"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish and submit to the Board guidelines for the selection and approval of projects and specific criteria for determining eligibility for project selection;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9D6C2B7F3604236BD4376008AC048EE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>accept, for consideration, project proposals relating to the development of infrastructure projects, which meet the basic criteria established by the Executive Committee, and which are submitted by an entity;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB03046D60E6942DBBA0C0C245A426F65"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide recommendations to the Board and place project proposals accepted by the Executive Committee on a list for consideration for financial assistance from the Board;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H945E59F67C8B42E68055DF73D31AF964"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommend to the Board the percentage subsidy amount for an approved application for an American Infrastructure Bond, with such recommendation based on the strength of the related infrastructure project’s ability to meet the criteria described under section 11 and the ability of such project to attract private investment in an infrastructure project’s early development stages;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD4ECCE20C1844A5ACCD9EBCD8025DEC"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide technical assistance, including public-private partnership infrastructure project value for money assessments, long-term economic benefit projections, and contract evaluations, to entities receiving financing from the Bank and otherwise implement decisions of the Board; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9BB56373D9CA4133B27602429DEEFAE6"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide technical assistance to State and local governments who wish to have the Bank’s approval to issue American Infrastructure bonds.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD1B6B2B7534D4158B1E0BAB0C50DDB27"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A vacancy in the position of CEO and other executive officers of the Executive Committee shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7AA34E2F27E74E08A317868811A38C65"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The compensation of the CEO and other executive officers of the Executive Committee shall be determined by the Board.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE205E79077334DA9B2DBAFDCB09B5C16"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The CEO and other executive officers of the Executive Committee may be removed at the discretion of a majority of the Board.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBC9ACB6CA86C41FE819F9EBDC01ADE6B"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The CEO and other executive officers of the Executive Committee shall serve a 6-year term and may be reappointed in accordance with this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H56A143E951EE4A5DAE732DE82F403AEF"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The CEO and other executive officers of the Executive Committee shall not—</text> <paragraph id="H60ED17B56C1D45DBAC19185A0D5C5954"><enum>(1)</enum><text>hold any other public office;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF47A12C8E4EE4390BD453D21B875188C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have any interest in an infrastructure project considered by the Board;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8CE1DE3B655E4D57AD28AA00F67BB073"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have any interest in an investment institution, commercial bank, or other entity seeking financial assistance for any infrastructure project from or investing in the Bank; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H531E8461ECBC448DBA239E5F6ACC45A0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>have any such interest during the 2-year period beginning on the date such officer ceases to serve in such capacity.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1C80D7E65CCF454BA404DC8EDAE10882"><enum>8.</enum><header>Risk management committee</header>
 <subsection id="H420607539D454B4BB37AE5BA6C7C287F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of risk management committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall establish a risk management committee consisting of 5 members, headed by the chief risk officer.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF141756E94124C2FBDDEEE965BE774FE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A majority of the Board shall have the authority to appoint and reappoint the CRO of the Bank.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H9E00CEF47C7F498CB06FA3FAFAD40C30"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions; duties</header> <paragraph id="H813E623A64F94DC08FB02295BE69ADC5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The CRO shall have such functions, powers, and duties as may be prescribed by one or more of the following: This Act, the bylaws of the Bank, and the Board. The CRO shall report directly to the Board.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H030D2018076B4AABB63152FF6D3DB503"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Risk management duties</header><text>In order to carry out the purposes of this Act, the risk management committee shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H3E27027BFCA141FF8EFCF8C1059C014F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">create financial, credit, and operational risk management guidelines and policies to be adhered to by the Bank;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BFD9B74A7894E71B41930099DFB4578"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">set guidelines to ensure diversification of lending activities by both geographic region and infrastructure project type;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D67E305010147D0B4B40049B42A925A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">create conforming standards for all financial assistance provided by the Bank;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46FEF71B76064E12B2013F211A454CA9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>monitor financial, credit and operational exposure of the Bank; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E1E506333A2414CB45B100B2319EFC5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provide financial recommendations to the Board.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C9B9B50E15447E3944F4CEC6EB6E2E4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duty with respect to American Infrastructure Bonds</header><text>The risk management committee shall ensure that the aggregate amount of interest subsidies provided for American Infrastructure Bonds in a given calendar year do not exceed an amount equal to 28 percent of interest payable under all such bonds.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H23DFF3716E1F4DBEA2ACD1D764D57268"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Other risk management officers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall appoint, remove, fix the compensation, and define the duties of 4 other risk management officers to serve on the risk management committee.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB86B1CA2CB024A04887EB52D9B848E62"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>The CRO and other risk management officers shall have demonstrated experience and expertise in one or more of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF0EA21E88A4C4889A41A1D3FB9FD2B88"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Treasury and asset and liability management.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE85CE4CCB9DF45178788069D7E34A628"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Investment regulations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB253A95EFD6B432D9E7728F1BDB6BCAF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Insurance.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4020150673434129B6CD17A3505A6E47"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Credit risk management and credit evaluations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H458E3D19CF96479F95DD5C4A7ED5C56B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Related disciplines.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC2F05F06F7624507ACC0AA152BFAAF5F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A vacancy in the position of CRO and other risk management officers of the risk management committee shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H08798A9B700446048D71FE183F99EA4A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The compensation of the CRO and other risk management officers of the risk management committee shall be determined by the Board.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H281A157644DE48E9B679EBEBEB667694"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The CRO and other risk management officers of the risk management committee may be removed at the discretion of a majority of the Board.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD392C3174C8C45F184DC204DD3793D19"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The CRO and other risk management officers of the risk management committee shall serve a 6-year term and may be reappointed in accordance with this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF2E4E8AEC9D7495D815A4CD270320BA9"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The CRO and other risk management officers of the risk management committee shall not—</text> <paragraph id="H8FCF04D16BDF460FB7A5EAABC08B27EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hold any other public office;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD97D3C692053458983C03585380EE24E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have any interest in an infrastructure project considered by the Board;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDC0AC121B8364DF1AADB117D3423ACB4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have any interest in an investment institution, commercial bank, or other entity seeking financial assistance for any infrastructure project from or investing in the Bank; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE9AC3C3F6384ECC904BE17BC14194C3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>have any such interest during the 2-year period beginning on the date such officer ceases to serve in such capacity.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H59D546E0A307452A972523A30BE7A94B"><enum>9.</enum><header>Audit Committee</header>
 <subsection id="HB473C246FFBA4E0FB45876C40B793E71"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Bank shall establish an audit committee consisting of 5 members, headed by the chief compliance officer of the Bank.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6CECBEB0148842259A443EF752F66860"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointments</header><text>A majority of the Board shall have the authority to appoint and reappoint the CCO of the Bank.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H8A6229CAAA4A40D4AA48096CD1346C53"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions; duties</header><text>The CCO shall have such functions, powers, and duties as may be prescribed by one or more of the following: This Act, the bylaws of the Bank, and the Board. The CCO shall report directly to the Board.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8A1543848CB64AD3A3A024CBA7F6C99E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Audit duties</header><text>In order to carry out the purposes of the Bank under this Act, the audit committee shall—</text> <paragraph id="H65D993A272D64FDFA1E8C294BAA7991E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide internal controls and internal auditing activities for the Bank;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF5C491F8D5F4DDCA2986246FE0F0A8F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintain responsibility for the accounting activities of the Bank;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCCD282407AAA43F78C87636B909E33AA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>issue financial reports of the Bank; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E6783B5872D4E3A87CF78D059A4152C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>complete reports with outside auditors and public accountants appointed by the Board.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE6C591487B194928B10D23164FE196E0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Other audit officers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall appoint, remove, fix the compensation, and define the duties of 4 other audit officers to serve on the audit committee.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBE18C3578FBA448E8F57B8846AEE10B9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>The CCO and other audit officers shall have demonstrated experience and expertise in one or more of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HAA6358A7A0E744BC86A9D8810F92A080"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Internal auditing.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H933185E2806B41A493E8455E1E0036DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Internal investigations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD91F9F2E146C4782B312B3330D55FAD3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Accounting practices.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9AC06556D9EC4D03945A7AE40C06B827"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Financing practices.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H54F0BDCCDF47450E83AD8FA668B420A9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A vacancy in the position of CCO and other audit officers of the audit committee shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0EAC6D2FFB794DCE8478E12E0FF3368A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The compensation of the CCO and other audit officers of the audit committee shall be determined by the Board.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H93E29F56FA724A1FB3359A45AC95AB59"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The CCO and other audit officers of the audit committee may be removed at the discretion of a majority of the Board.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6E006B7C3152461F829FA9B45EA38A20"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The CCO and other audit officers of the audit committee shall serve a 6-year term and may be reappointed in accordance with this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H144DAAED1A794CB78895368130E771C8"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The CCO and other audit officers of the audit committee shall not—</text> <paragraph id="HE4708C8A4A78494DBA1E3CF5BAD74FFE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>hold any other public office;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE86C0A1569CA4E7EA561E24C2B2B85E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have any interest in an infrastructure project considered by the Board;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC9B0909FCD84D5BBD0527BF77ADCE7A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have any interest in an investment institution, commercial bank, or other entity seeking financial assistance for any infrastructure project from or investing in the Bank; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D74289F14D7407E841BA507DCB3E7FD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>have any such interest during the 2-year period beginning on the date such officer ceases to serve in such capacity.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H00112C9B0AAB49AA800C0EFAF9F6835F"><enum>10.</enum><header>Personnel</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The chairperson of the Board, chief executive officer, chief risk officer, and chief compliance officer shall appoint, remove, fix the compensation of, and define the duties of such qualified personnel to serve under the Board, Executive Committee, risk management committee, or audit committee, as the case may be, as necessary and prescribed by one or more of the following: This Act, the bylaws of the Bank, and the Board.</text>
		</section><section id="H4A444B5C93B44975A4D166CE140EB532"><enum>11.</enum><header>Eligibility criteria for assistance from Bank</header>
 <subsection id="H947EE5E75AA5426595BE4A6B75C72D2C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any entity proposing a project for which the use or purpose is private and without public benefit shall not be eligible for financial assistance from the Bank under this Act. No financial assistance shall be available from the Bank unless the entity for such assistance has demonstrated to the satisfaction of the Board that the project for which such assistance is being sought meets the requirements of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HAF1B567B231A48B88FDB39C0E528FD89"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of project criteria</header>
 <paragraph id="H3372D9BCEEEE4D96B79D1022497DC304"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Consistent with the requirements of subsections (c) and (d), the Board shall approve—</text> <subparagraph id="HB47C4D632DE14194991DE6BF00D8AA71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>criteria for determining eligibility for financial assistance established by the Executive Committee under this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6F6C9630AA94A33845ECAD5B6B9DA20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>revisions to criteria for determining eligibility for financial assistance established by the Executive Committee under this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77623910B57F476088223A34AE8CD7FD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the weight given to factors to be taken into account established by the Executive Committee;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF203017D48834CE2926CBEE96C2CDF63"><enum>(D)</enum><text>disclosure and application procedures to be followed by entities to nominate projects for assistance established by the Executive Committee under this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92373513457842B6911B0452DAB4BDCE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>such other criteria as the Board may consider to be appropriate for the purposes of carrying out this Act.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD26F2883E1D45ED9AAD1AB5446B04BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Factors to be taken into account</header>
 <subparagraph id="H90A5036EA6FC4AF0ABF4440CD17F8603"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Executive Committee shall conduct an analysis that takes into account the economic, environmental, and social benefits, and costs of each project under consideration for financial assistance under this Act, prioritizing projects that contribute to economic growth, lead to job creation, and are of regional or national significance.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9A691399068494E92CD22A74E5D9087"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The criteria established pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) shall provide for the consideration of the following factors in considering eligibility for financial assistance under this Act:</text>
 <clause id="H34B60463EFA942C2A8540F32C781135B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The means by which development of the infrastructure project under consideration is being financed, including—</text>
 <subclause id="H05237619FFC641839E341A0B55199BBB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the terms and conditions and financial structure of the proposed financing;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H22AD274F441D481D88DB1BB9972201F4"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the credit worthiness and standing of the project sponsors, providers of equity, and cofinanciers;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6A64540E360F44C79BE2DF5566E2BBEC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the financial assumptions and projections on which the project is based; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HFCFCB97C61AF4CB599FC913D1773309C"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the extent to which the infrastructure project maximizes investment from other sources.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H7269278ED8A54AD2B99DACAC7E4B9CBF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The likelihood that the provision of assistance by the Bank will cause such development to proceed more promptly and with lower costs for financing than would be the case without such assistance.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB98AE22A3C254F458BA10B8B070ADC40"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The extent to which the provision of assistance by the Bank maximizes the level of private investment in the infrastructure project while providing a public benefit.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5914D0FBDAC4E058AF61C48BE3C80CF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Dedicated revenue sources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any financial assistance for an infrastructure project shall be repayable, in whole or in part, from dedicated revenue sources that also secure the infrastructure project obligations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1A5BF93A71F49F4B3C745D51A206B99"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Amount of financial assistance</header><text>The amount of financial assistance under this Act shall not exceed the lesser of 50 percent of the reasonably anticipated eligible infrastructure project costs.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H092EF0499EF741A1BE93FFF39ACC91C6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public input</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing proposed infrastructure project criteria and conducting reviews of infrastructure project criteria for the Board, the Executive Committee shall seek input from the public including views related to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEAA3D81780F44CACB1A6ED90E1FF5772"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the weight given to different factors to be taken into account;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF1477A4519249708C0D6397B9FA77A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>measuring whether projects are meeting approved criteria; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD95D6E8EC9E4457829E725516D42604"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other input considered by the Executive Committee and the public for the purposes of carrying out this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB34A442316AA4BC7A572B9272911CF15"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Factors for specific types of projects</header>
 <paragraph id="HAD3DFF814F2A4B598245BB87B0C048C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Transportation infrastructure projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any transportation infrastructure project, the Board shall consider the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H724988E43FB74069A79957599FA6529C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Job creation, including workforce development for women and minorities, responsible employment practices, and targeted job training and employment opportunities for low income workers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10EDA2BAA37644C0B2DB5D96FABF5D12"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Reduction in greenhouse gases.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H69454549226E4D2291594533844EA314"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Reduction in surface and air traffic congestion.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1989BA32B7C42C1AEB53B510B2FCA17"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Use of smart tolling, such as vehicle miles traveled and congestion pricing, for highway, road, and bridge projects.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2423B2B73887488E9DEFE17B3369FE28"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Increased access to transportation options.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1A8EAE36B034468B133D789440EEA3F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Increased safety of transportation systems for motorized and non-motorized users.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2BE9F04EC054784963A6C3ED568BD51"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Public health benefits, including the removal of lead coatings or other hazardous chemicals and materials.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE255BBD74E01489DB1249518B5BD24DA"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Reduction in risk of structural failure over the service life of the project.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA17F9C738C3E4711BCA7FD6D6F22A0AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Environmental infrastructure project</header><text>For any environmental infrastructure project, the Board shall consider the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H57305805400E46AEB446311E592D4EAF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Job creation, including workforce development for women and minorities, responsible employment practices, and targeted job training and employment opportunities for low income workers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AD5CE6F4F11440FA2230F6C25660B25"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Public health benefits, including the removal of lead coatings or other hazardous materials.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C00CACA56B645E8947A6C812B7659D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Pollution reductions.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1889E8AE1D914C999D37DD65E7B51769"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Reductions in greenhouse gas.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7953CEE37591437F9FC385F412FDAD69"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Increased coastal and inland flood mitigation and protection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B5E3E0D823C48BB97CF589ADAB08873"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reduction in risk of structural failure over the service life of the project.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AF8D3335B674F448FCAF9360A4C74B7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Energy infrastructure project</header><text>For any energy infrastructure project, the Board shall consider the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB5B0DE9790D14B7BB83862B776E8F421"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Job creation, including workforce development for women and minorities, responsible employment practices, and targeted job training and employment opportunities for low income workers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98C65899B7764B3BBAEE02D30AE3164B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Reduction in greenhouse gas.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA323A72E21784F7B8176C91A5D8F70E1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Expanded use of renewable energy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H246E75B1C620474FA05C3D6C0EDD4E1B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Development of a smart grid.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB3BBB78DE50468697830F75ED26187B"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Energy efficient building, housing, and school modernization, including renewable energy designated retrofits.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA6843438679465D86BEEEC6E7C80D0A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>In any case in which the project is also a public housing project—</text> <clause id="H4832F3DB41D24D899DB8A68F7C7372BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>improvement of the physical shape and layout;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H78ACE5020BBD440AACB1B058BEB5AEB3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>environmental improvement; and</text> </clause><clause id="H971C9207CA7A4182936E32F140A1ADA5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>mobility improvements for residents.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCED74D10DB4E446B873944E137336C72"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Public health benefits including the removal of lead coatings or other hazardous chemicals and materials.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EEB80B8FB10459EBB6FDA4B4A0139FA"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Reduction in risk of structural failure over the service life of the project.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F0B71E51B5C49629F01297366AA8A74"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Telecommunications</header><text>For any telecommunications project, the Board shall consider the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7A491D4B187C4DB19DAC2D2032B2630D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Job creation, including workforce development for women and minorities, responsible employment practices, and targeted job training and employment opportunities for low income workers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7C202234CF245789BF369FF2D1B2884"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The extent to which assistance expands or improves broadband and wireless services in rural and disadvantaged communities.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13B6839DB58C4F38895A7A6DF43D4525"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consideration of project proposals</header>
 <paragraph id="H96F69654BD6644A3B761F5452A785295"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Participation by other agency personnel</header><text>Consideration of a project under this section by the Executive Committee and the Board shall be conducted with personnel on detail to the Bank from relevant Federal agencies among individuals who are familiar with and experienced in the selection criteria for competitive infrastructure projects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E8653B178134661BB6361DFC97DDBCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A fee may be charged for the review of any project proposal in such amount as may be considered appropriate by the Executive Committee approved by the Board to cover the cost of such review.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7CD2300E16F40DF9056B3D385A145F5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Discretion of board</header><text>Consistent with other provisions of this Act, any determination of the Board to provide assistance to any infrastructure project, and the manner in which such assistance is provided, including the terms, conditions, fees, and charges shall be at the sole discretion of the Board.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2FFA6678263B4325AF283C1C24243DC8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>State and local permits required</header><text>The provision of assistance by the Board in accordance with this Act shall not be deemed to relieve any recipient of assistance or the related infrastructure project of any obligation to obtain required State and local permits and approvals.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H54685C43FA5A4D1F8DC95BE81A9887EE"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>An entity receiving assistance from the Board shall make annual reports to the Board on the use of any such assistance, compliance with the criteria set forth in this section, and a disclosure of all entities with a development, ownership, or operational interest in a infrastructure project assisted or proposed to be assisted under this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H2DE59167CBFA463A8C8D9875AC5C0D8D"><enum>12.</enum><header>Exemption from local taxation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">All bonds issued by the Bank, and the interest on or credits with respect to such bonds, shall not be subject to taxation by any State, county, municipality, or local taxing authority.</text>
		</section><section id="H7AD49547BCD9454CB11A7EEA2183DF3F"><enum>13.</enum><header>Status and applicability of certain Federal laws</header>
 <subsection id="HDF15758A037C4E74A02BD2CB683A0231"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Compliance with Davis-Bacon Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All laborers and mechanics employed by contractors and subcontractors on infrastructure projects funded directly by or assisted in whole or in part by and through the Bank pursuant to this Act shall be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on projects of a character similar in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of chapter 31 of part A of title 40, United States Code. With respect to the labor standards specified in this section, the Secretary of Labor shall have the authority and functions set forth in Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950 (64 Stat. 1267; 5 U.S.C. App.) and section 3145 of title 40, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H748A4FC530CC49EDA4FF7D4DBEAC9649"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No priority as a Federal claim</header><text>The priority established in favor of the United States by section 3713 of title 31, United States Code, shall not apply with respect to any indebtedness of the Bank.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H107ACD0086134FAE9330008626F91D7B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compliance with grant requirements</header><text>Recipients of financial assistance authorized under this Act that funds public transportation capital projects, as defined in section 5302 of title 49, United States Code, must comply with the grant requirements applicable to grants made under section 5309 of such title.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H207783EBBFB84D62814038E4D09164A6"><enum>14.</enum><header>Compliance with certain domestic content statutes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The financing provided for an infrastructure project shall be in accordance with the following statutory provisions of the United States Code under the jurisdiction of the Department of Transportation: section 24305 of title 49, United States Code (AMTRAK), section 313 of title 23, United States Code (FHWA), section 5323(j) of title 49, United States Code (FTA), section 24405 of title 49, United States Code (Intercity Rail Passenger Corporation), and sections 50101 and 50105 of title 49, United States Code (FAA).</text>
		</section><section id="H1D68D4C35B5446228DD6AD9D608C3193"><enum>15.</enum><header>Use of iron, steel, and manufactured goods in infrastructure projects</header>
 <subsection id="H81EF675202104CF9ABD3D5A88915C74D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Buy America</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the financing provided for by the Bank may be used for a public infrastructure project unless all of the iron, steel, and manufactured goods used for the construction, alteration, maintenance or repair of the project are produced in the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H068E5E68C8B14EAEA132CF0311B35B83"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply in any case or category of cases in which the Secretary of the Treasury finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H87F0BD0B71044E17A331329B137F3BDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>applying subsection (a) would be inconsistent with the public interest;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H55826EB7970B43E0B89C017D856454D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>iron, steel, and the relevant manufactured goods are not produced in the United States in sufficient and reasonably available quantities and of a satisfactory quality; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE271159B22074667BBB0A51A35AC5FF4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>inclusion of iron, steel, and manufactured goods produced in the United States will increase the cost of the overall infrastructure project by more than 25 percent.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC31FCD98AA61488BA69D9D3752E6CD0F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Publication of waivers</header><text>If the Secretary of the Treasury determines that it is necessary to waive the application of subsection (a) based on a finding under subsection (b), the Treasury Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a detailed written justification as to why the provision is being waived.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD368BE0BB32240529F24BEF11E2A38D2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application of section</header><text>This section shall be applied in a manner consistent with the United States obligations under international agreements.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA30C1E6422E34D668F1552DE1355B53F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall consult with the Board and may consult with the Secretary of Transportation and other Federal Secretaries and Administrators when applying this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE37702B3E2B246C9A92596B0D63F5CC7"><enum>16.</enum><header>Audits; reports to President and Congress</header>
 <subsection id="HC0EB77909231488998FA19362E46776E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Accounting</header><text>The books of account of the Bank shall be maintained in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles and shall be subject to an annual audit by independent public accountants appointed by the Board and of nationally recognized standing.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H202119643C8D453088DF4EB0A2A7C9DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <paragraph id="H1E2C340B03BA4A5481AB87F867F81D3E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Board</header><text>The Board shall submit to the President and Congress, within 90 days after the last day of each fiscal year, a complete and detailed report with respect to the preceding fiscal year, setting forth—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H35E4987235AB4BDFB9C22328375A2308"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of the Bank’s operations, for such preceding fiscal year;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H767B3528A29E492BABAA4EBB268025F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a schedule of the Bank’s obligations outstanding at the end of such preceding fiscal year, with a statement of the amounts issued and redeemed or paid during such preceding fiscal year; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED4B449B9CB146AEBD347475691969D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the status of infrastructure projects receiving funding or other assistance pursuant to this Act, including disclosure of all entities with a development, ownership, or operational interest in such projects.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6BC8E68EC424F3EA89AD15ABF279C98"><enum>(2)</enum><header>GAO</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report evaluating activities of the Bank for the fiscal years covered by the report that includes an assessment of the impact and benefits of each funded infrastructure project, including a review of how effectively each project accomplished the goals prioritized by the Bank’s project criteria.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H69EFE9AFAF2A4BC489D88D7EE965CD65"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Books and records</header>
 <paragraph id="HFF28D62FEB5F4D378E1BA176D0101F5B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Bank shall maintain adequate books and records to support the financial transactions of the Bank with a description of financial transactions and infrastructure projects receiving funding, and the amount of funding for each project maintained on a publicly accessible database.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8341A1576F24F3DBE4E0FD6B1EE2F25"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public comment period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bank shall post infrastructure financing agreements on the database providing 30 days for public comments before providing final financing for the infrastructure project.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6BE126C3D1044DF39903DF8F2174F72F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Audits by the secretary and GAO</header><text>The books and records of the Bank shall be maintained in accordance with recommended accounting practices and shall be open to inspection by the Secretary and the Comptroller General of the United States.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4138DFBB63F24819B70EAD69DE5B7780" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>17.</enum><header>American Infrastructure Bond</header>
 <subsection id="H8CBADBA3698647379E531BE302B42807"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an American Infrastructure Bond, the Bank shall pay (contemporaneously with each interest payment date under such bond) to the issuer of such bond (or to any person who makes such interest payments on behalf of the issuer) the applicable percentage of the interest payable under such bond on such date.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H250F7992390C4C5BB855CA512542FD68"><enum>(b)</enum><header>American Infrastructure Bond</header>
 <paragraph id="HCA7E00DD95CB4D52AEE38D93E2552DB3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>American Infrastructure Bond</quote> means any obligation (other than a private activity bond) if—</text> <subparagraph id="H6E31161EC47941D2A32F59A8C803BD58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the interest on such obligation would (but for this section) be excludable from gross income under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/103">section 103</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD2DE6314C8F4EC980194B3BF9FF78CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such obligation would have been a qualified bond under section 54AA of such Code (determined without regard to subparagraphs (B) and (C) of subsection (d)(1) and subsection (g)(2)(B) thereof);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H128CF62E7B9F4A468EBBFB2D6DC502E2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such obligation is approved under the American Infrastructure Bond program; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DBCFC32BB534F09826ACA5769ED3C53"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the issuer makes an irrevocable election to have this section apply.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E88011365BF4B94B43948ADDC3E9B2A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable rules</header><text>For purposes of applying paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H4B5086AABA7943928FE1D546C518710B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for purposes of section 149(b) of such Code, an American Infrastructure Bond shall not be treated as federally guaranteed by reason of the subsidy provided under subsection (a);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B25C843114F4A44BFE0132BF1417340"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for purposes of section 148 of such Code, the yield on an American Infrastructure Bond shall be determined without regard to the subsidy provided under subsection (a); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F0035F6D8D942C0B0D808F8BCE34F2B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a bond shall not be treated as an American Infrastructure Bond if the issue price has more than a de minimis amount (determined under rules similar to the rules of section 1273(a)(3) of such Code) of premium over the stated principal amount of the bond.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6AF999856623484B9CA4537C17A5F48C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Interest on bonds included in gross income</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, interest on any American Infrastructure Bond shall be includible in gross income.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8DC8DB47A78F4B668DB5B2E0756397D2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H1682C25480114804A7BEA9EECE30F41C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interest payment date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>interest payment date</quote> means any date on which the holder of record of the American Infrastructure Bond is entitled to a payment of interest under such bond.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC370F05C59D5458193940863214AD6C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The applicable percentage with respect to the interest subsidy provided for any bond under the American Infrastructure Bond program shall be a percentage recommended by the Executive Committee, reviewed by the risk management committee, and approved by the Board.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9F3D4B47A6CE43B980008193227D5CE5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>American Infrastructure Bond program</header>
 <paragraph id="HE37313269CF54AA0BE3F12A5715B4057"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Board, in consultation with the Executive Committee, risk management committee, and the Secretary of the Treasury, shall establish an American Infrastructure Bond program, under which the Board may—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H320C1A87707A4244983A81F089C6B3C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>approve bond issuances for purposes of this section, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB230254F7744D49AD59C6B94CAA37D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assign an applicable percentage with respect to any bond so approved.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FAEC339173E442BA677B247B496ACE7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Issuers may apply for the approval of a bond issuance for purposes of this section, and any such application shall contain such information as the Executive Committee and the risk management committee may require in order to accept or reject an application and to assign an applicable percentage to such bond.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA395B0C9A9CA421094FBCF0E49743F0C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>Approval of an application and the applicable percentage subsidy assigned under the program shall be based on the ability of each project to meet the criteria established under section 8(d).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HF8C4643BF7F449979068E31706935DDD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitations</header>
 <subparagraph id="H65AE4403D54247E7AE5951536068F2CE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Per bond subsidy</header><text>The applicable percentage with respect to any bond may not exceed 40 percent.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DCCE5DA46B54115865C8C43A5AFA122"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Aggregate subsidy limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any calendar year, the aggregate amount of interest subsidies provided under this section with respect to all American Infrastructure Bonds shall not exceed an amount equal to 28 percent of interest payable under all such bonds.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H31ACCC856B1A4D7897DDA680BE51B224"><enum>18.</enum><header>National Infrastructure Development Bank Trust Fund</header>
 <subsection id="H823C529A162E4247A43067300E47F7BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the <quote>National Infrastructure Development Bank Trust Fund</quote> consisting of such amounts as may be appropriated to such trust fund as provided in this section.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H17EB90DFC3854B14A54383F3C41C6525"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer to trust fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are hereby appropriated to the National Infrastructure Development Bank Trust Fund such amount as the Secretary of the Treasury estimates is equivalent to the tax receipts attributable to interest payable under American Infrastructure Bonds.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8648812E35B8412AAD56F774A8F3E5D3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expenditures from trust fund</header><text>Amounts in the National Infrastructure Development Bank Trust Fund shall be available, as provided in appropriation Acts, only for purposes of the Secretary making transfers to the National Infrastructure Development Bank for infrastructure project assistance provided by the Bank under this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H6807FEA0AA6D456EBB997B1F04EAFF67"><enum>19.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017, 2018, 2019, 2020, and 2021 to capitalize the Bank and to remain available until expended, of which not more than $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 and 2018, and not more than $50,000,000 for each fiscal year thereafter, may be used for administrative costs of the Bank.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


