<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB6D0FA54D0AA419E823469F7E0D6F740" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3899 IH: To amend title 28, United States Code, to redefine the eastern and middle judicial districts of North Carolina.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3899</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171002">October 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001065">Mr. Holding</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 28, United States Code, to redefine the eastern and middle judicial districts of
			 North Carolina.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H18B63870583C4BA48EA5330B487B0138" style="OLC">
		<section id="HC5D2430D3328488E8410195D9D9CA7CF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Judicial districts of North Carolina</header>
 <subsection id="H3A8F4FC56E394A21957B277D19E62C82"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 113 of title 28, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HCFF749416AA6458794BC9A2E96AD3B1D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>and Wilson and</quote> and inserting <quote>Wilson, those portions of Hoke, Moore, Scotland, and Richmond counties encompassing the Fort Bragg Military Reservation and Camp Mackall, and</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H734914AD2AFB407E85E91FBC11D20D3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6D4C405591343C89141D32D2B8E4747" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HF808856DF0B64BB3B6045D52024CC06E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Middle district</header><text>The Middle District comprises the counties of Alamance, Cabarrus, Caswell, Chatham, Davidson, Davie, Durham (excluding that portion of Durham County encompassing the Federal Correctional Institution, Butner, North Carolina), Forsyth, Guilford, Hoke (excluding that portion of Hoke County encompassing the Fort Bragg Military Reservation and Camp Mackall), Lee, Montgomery, Moore (excluding that portion of Moore County encompassing the Fort Bragg Military Reservation and Camp Mackall), Orange, Person, Randolph, Richmond (excluding that portion of Richmond County encompassing the Fort Bragg Military Reservation and Camp Mackall), Rockingham, Rowan, Scotland (excluding that portion of Scotland County encompassing the Fort Bragg Military Reservation and Camp Mackall), Stanly, Stokes, Surry, and Yadkin.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA1F4B8954CB453FA4E8A88350B7F0AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall not apply to any action commenced or pending in any judicial district of North Carolina before the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


