<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7ECFB935473D4FE4AB40AEFD7087C50C" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 1238 ENR: Securing our Agriculture and Food Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IB</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Fifteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress><session display="yes">At the First Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Tuesday, the third day of January, two thousand and seventeen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1238</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to make the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security for Health Affairs responsible for coordinating the efforts of the Department of Homeland Security related to food, agriculture, and veterinary defense against terrorism, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HD1C854D28E2948E893E20228908DC3D4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H848563E2DE144080B3AAE8D8E6493213" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing our Agriculture and Food Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H4A995FBC279D4302AFBBF7C1ED32EE46"><enum>2.</enum><header>Coordination of food, agriculture, and veterinary defense against terrorism</header> <subsection id="HCBACAE7ABA7F418EB0A9D8ADD8BAD073"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title V of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/311">6 U.S.C. 311</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0401C2DA4D84A56B4B467914D7FC457" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA682413B3E9B4B30A6FD1B90671486A9"><enum>528.</enum><header>Coordination of Department of Homeland Security efforts related to food, agriculture, and veterinary defense against terrorism</header> 
<subsection id="HE976B8163B6D420D9AE5A7DB1BC84D8A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Health Affairs, shall carry out a program to coordinate the Department’s efforts related to defending the food, agriculture, and veterinary systems of the United States against terrorism and other high-consequence events that pose a high risk to homeland security.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HC66F4ED191AC455A8564514ED6E676D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program elements</header><text>The coordination program required by subsection (a) shall include, at a minimum, the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4FA41E9EDE6E4919B8DEE752898ADF1D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Providing oversight and management of the Department’s responsibilities pursuant to Homeland Security Presidential Directive 9–Defense of United States Agriculture and Food.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7300FF31A1A40B9AD74FAD3225F469C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Providing oversight and integration of the Department’s activities related to veterinary public health, food defense, and agricultural security.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F29147B7ACE4D3FABAB323A8D1EB50E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Leading the Department’s policy initiatives relating to food, animal, and agricultural incidents, and the impact of such incidents on animal and public health.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H247E9598B1494199ABD2BC02C244378F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Leading the Department’s policy initiatives relating to overall domestic preparedness for and collective response to agricultural terrorism.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF3DF68D7D20C48FD80865B5366BDC974"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coordinating with other Department components, including U.S. Customs and Border Protection, as appropriate, on activities related to food and agriculture security and screening procedures for domestic and imported products.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H0578E7E5EA374C379A4CADFEE5622279"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Coordinating with appropriate Federal departments and agencies.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC0259DCBC33147579EC4F62BB2339AD5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Other activities as determined necessary by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H31570B4F90C64A1FBFB753092EC619AE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed as altering or superseding the authority of the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD84BCA62EC97495A8A677E6C0B169ED1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4AD621F6AC0A48D69E441325F991A9D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the items relating to sections 523, 524, 525, 526, and 527; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6D1519C1F1D48629EC1E62FCA1AAA4B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after the item relating to section 522 the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB43B307B9A4549D88BD1114E2ABDD860" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 523. Guidance and recommendations.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 524. Voluntary private sector preparedness accreditation and certification program.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 525. Acceptance of gifts.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 526. Integrated public alert and warning system modernization.</toc-entry> <toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 527. National planning and education.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 528. Coordination of Department of Homeland Security efforts related to food, agriculture, and veterinary defense against terrorism.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> </section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

