<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBF07A1D0E7084DD58CE733B43FF11F7C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2576 IH: Incentivize Growth Now In Tomorrow’s Entrepreneurs Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2576</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170519">May 19, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the tax treatment of small business
			 start-up savings accounts.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HEA32EDF8F49F4C2FAF4480A5DEE78E5C" style="OLC">
 <section id="HEF5E12A2B60F495E8C01692AA4DDED47" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Incentivize Growth Now In Tomorrow’s Entrepreneurs Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0DA907B9402D4344B1ACE31F9396360F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Small Business Start-Up Savings Accounts</header> <subsection id="HA0EF4026FC844793B177240E5545B4DF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter F of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new part:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30A6393620D14229813EC0CA244AC814" style="OLC">
					<part id="HD865F7BB14E24061A1CD8A3D238160A5"><enum>IX</enum><header>Small Business Start-Up Savings Accounts</header>
						<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H30A6393620D14229813EC0CA244AC814" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="HA4382C182411489D9B348816631B6179" level="section">Sec. 530A. Small Business Start-Up Savings Accounts.</toc-entry></toc>
						<section id="HA4382C182411489D9B348816631B6179"><enum>530A.</enum><header>Small Business Start-up Savings Accounts</header>
 <subsection id="H0BDD3B384D434733AC4332FEC7F392E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General Rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A small business start-up savings account shall be exempt from taxation under this subtitle. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, the small business start-up savings account shall be subject to the taxes imposed by section 511 (relating to imposition of tax on unrelated business income of charitable organizations).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9A026B8325AE4A30981EA554DF1CBB32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Small Business Start-Up Savings Account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>small business start-up savings account</term> means a trust created or organized in the United States exclusively for the purpose of making qualified start-up expenditures of the individual who is the designated beneficiary of the trust (and designated as a small business start-up savings account at the time created or organized), but only if the written governing instrument creating the trust meets the following requirements:</text>
 <paragraph id="H72E439F22B5E4B8E85838E057EF1BE86"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Except in the case of a rollover contribution described in subsection (d)(4), no contribution will be accepted unless it is in cash, and contributions will not be accepted if such contribution would result in aggregate contributions for the taxable year not exceeding the lesser of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8D480E576AE24A7BB85AF5E2930A748C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$10,000, or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CD6109D958440459EA4DE283469A5F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an amount equal to the compensation (as defined in section 219(f)(1)) includible in the individual’s gross income for such taxable year.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9946D279BB34F6BB6AAB908BB973743"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The trustee is a bank (as defined in section 408(n)) or such other person who demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the manner in which such other person will administer the trust will be consistent with the requirements of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8728DF2110E849A58BF5859FA278877E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>No part of the trust funds will be invested in life insurance contracts.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BF273AC0B2A4A1BB8D5A2ABF5C46384"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The assets of the trust will not be commingled with other property except in a common trust fund or common investment fund.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCE0DFBC9A6AA43A1A8D9168CC86534A5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified Start-Up Expenditures</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H74949FF6B98E45F89A108EF0AA8009B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified start-up expenditures</term> has the meaning given such term by section 195.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H391343E8F64948D9B804D7BA810E90D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for corporation or partnership interests</header><text>Such term includes the taxpayer’s allocable share of qualified start-up expenditures of an entity in which the taxpayer directly holds stock or a capital or profits interest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F2DF6CC8C074E95A9BDD85FD1C18B08"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Such term shall not apply to any expenditures paid or incurred in a taxable year in connection with a trade or business if there is any day during the taxable year on which the number of full-time employees of the trade or business exceeds 50.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFBFCB963DA024E589C72273B3F395E6B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tax treatment of distributions</header>
 <paragraph id="HB551135FAAAD4AD690D66A085735483F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any distribution shall be includible in the gross income of the distributee in the manner as provided in section 72.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H156BF1C8D1C54FFE9FF2BAC52CB086E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distributions for qualified start-up expenditures</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2D68B278539E41F3BA3C27AD4B1A00EA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No amount shall be includible in gross income under paragraph (1) if the qualified start-up expenditures of the individual during the taxable year are not less than the aggregate distributions during the taxable year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD7269E0599842FB8232C8BF2563B4FE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Distributions in excess of expenses</header><text>If such aggregate distributions exceed such expenses during the taxable year, the amount otherwise includible in gross income under paragraph (1) shall be reduced by the amount which bears the same ratio to the amount which would be includible in gross income under paragraph (1) (without regard to this subparagraph) as the qualified start-up expenditures bear to such aggregate distributions.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC24F6F836C034F49A44C5E3918FB5238"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Disallowance of excluded amounts as deduction, credit, or exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No deduction, credit, or exclusion shall be allowed to the taxpayer under any other section of this chapter for any qualified start-up expenditure to the extent taken into account in determining the amount of the exclusion under this paragraph.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H812BDFCC0CC346E6A9CA384725036486"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Excess contributions returned before due date of return</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB297FE49A02E48C08991E00320C968F5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any excess contribution is contributed for a taxable year to any small business start-up savings account of an individual, paragraph (1) shall not apply to distributions from the small business start-up savings accounts of such individual (to the extent such distributions do not exceed the aggregate excess contributions to all such accounts of such individual for such year) if—</text>
 <clause id="H228214147A834577B9AB30A5860DC1FB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such distribution is received by the individual on or before the last day prescribed by law (including extensions of time) for filing such individual’s return for such taxable year, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7077C8D4500A4DAE92630AC4B4738BDC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such distribution is accompanied by the amount of net income attributable to such excess contribution.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39233F3059CB4606BD4017703A6BD1EF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Excess contribution</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>excess contribution</term> means any contribution (other than a rollover contribution described in paragraph (4)) which when added to all previous contributions for the taxable year exceeds the amount allowable as a contribution under subsection (b)(1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC04CA03BFE57487081816A5A49F31FBD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rollover contribution</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any amount paid or distributed from a small business start-up savings account to the account beneficiary to the extent the amount received is paid into a small business start-up savings account for the benefit of such beneficiary not later than the 60th day after the day on which the beneficiary receives the payment or distribution. For purposes of this paragraph, rules similar to the rules of section 408(d)(3)(D) shall apply.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5202C273F364C4888009D394A8B47BF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Transfer of account incident to divorce</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The transfer of an individual’s interest in a small business start-up savings account to an individual’s spouse or former spouse under a divorce or separation instrument described in subparagraph (A) of section 71(b)(2) shall not be considered a taxable transfer made by such individual notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, and such interest shall, after such transfer, be treated as a small business start-up savings account with respect to which such spouse is the account beneficiary.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H6A4565F604C34B1C8570933E77CE7B75"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Treatment after death of account beneficiary</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9EA646ABD983485097E8019EFBD0CC07"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Treatment if designated beneficiary is spouse</header><text>If the account beneficiary’s surviving spouse acquires such beneficiary’s interest in a small business start-up savings account by reason of being the designated beneficiary of such account at the death of the account beneficiary, such account shall be treated as if the spouse were the account beneficiary.</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1035636788DB4873AEDDC23D5B78EDEF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other cases</header>
 <clause id="HA97FD6168B0B4CCFBE89994A17A1B3CB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If, by reason of the death of the account beneficiary, any person acquires the account beneficiary’s interest in a small business start-up savings account in a case to which subparagraph (A) does not apply—</text>
 <subclause id="H3EF89E3504E047DAB95156D5524B1CD8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such account shall cease to be a small business start-up savings account as of the date of death, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD784FFC32CA94023B111A613BFB987C9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an amount equal to the fair market value of the assets in such account on such date shall be includible if such person is not the estate of such beneficiary, in such person’s gross income for the taxable year which includes such date, or if such person is the estate of such beneficiary, in such beneficiary’s gross income for the last taxable year of such beneficiary.</text>
											</subclause></clause><clause id="H101A0CFC5B1640D1998702245ABAD0C8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <subclause id="H355D8212D8A444F2B68B33CE674C5B1D"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Reduction of inclusion for predeath expenses</header><text>The amount includible in gross income under clause (i) by any person (other than the estate) shall be reduced by the amount of qualified start-up expenditures which were incurred by the decedent before the date of the decedent’s death and paid by such person within 1 year after such date.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1B80C6677292416484B4DD009C67D581"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Deduction for estate taxes</header><text>An appropriate deduction shall be allowed under section 691(c) to any person (other than the decedent or the decedent’s spouse) with respect to amounts included in gross income under clause (i) by such person.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE9DF187AB5E46758A14004C4C885201"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Community property laws</header><text>This section shall be applied without regard to any community property laws.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H0725E993FEB84CE4907217B88832A24E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Custodial accounts</header><text>For purposes of this section, a custodial account shall be treated as a trust if the assets of such account are held by a bank (as defined in subsection (n)) or another person who demonstrates, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, that the manner in which he will administer the account will be consistent with the requirements of this section, and if the custodial account would, except for the fact that it is not a trust, constitute a small business start-up account described in subsection (a). For purposes of this title, in the case of a custodial account treated as a trust by reason of the preceding sentence, the custodian of such account shall be treated as the trustee thereof.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H40108ED6974A41A1AF7C8A412B9D121E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Adjustment for inflation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a taxable year beginning after December 31, 2017, the dollar amount in subsection (b)(1) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC4D964E81A4E4D28A1241BCA024FD24A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H61421ED914104FCA985F0A282ACCB464"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> for <quote>calendar year 1992</quote> in subparagraph (B) thereof.</text>
								</paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">If any amount as increased under the preceding sentence is not a multiple of $100, such amount
 shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $100.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="HC6A7C6A0EDBA450FA25FCB3102C1611B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>The trustee of a small business start-up savings account shall make such reports regarding such account to the Secretary and to the individual for whom the account is, or is to be, maintained with respect to contributions (and the years to which they relate), distributions, aggregating $10 or more in any calendar year, and such other matters as the Secretary may require. The reports required by this subsection—</text>
 <paragraph id="H63F916B88E054C89B29FFCB3032C9649"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be filed at such time and in such manner as the Secretary prescribes, and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H075AE26649CC4108A1357853DEB9F426"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be furnished to individuals—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEA351431D89A45BCB3A6A87AA18B97AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than January 31 of the calendar year following the calendar year to which such reports relate, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E6B22234EE84BA0BAB473A375588AC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in such manner as the Secretary prescribes.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3A12C331A38441EF86F8332E8BEE536D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary to carry out this section, including for purposes of subsection (c)(2) the making reports by regarding qualified start-up expenditures of an entity in which the taxpayer directly holds stock or a capital or profits interest.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H6BB664BE53D2474CA752C3E450253D38"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tax on prohibited transactions</header>
 <paragraph id="H78485825493E4F8CB7186CDB8CCE3CE3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (1) of section 4975(e) of such Code (relating to prohibited transactions) is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (F), by redesignating subparagraph (G) as subparagraph (H), and by inserting after subparagraph (F) the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HD9E184444EB14E1399D08E6EE28F196D" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H697B32326F9F426DB3C0AC4682AD0EB6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a small business start-up savings account described in section 530A, or</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FA6D8B1CDC845049186C1A8CCF43233"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>Subsection (c) of section 4975 of such Code is amended by adding at the end of subsection (c) the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H066EB25531F4467090DF7638D0982C8B" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HD2E8CA8237E9446F98FD83270E0B5C3B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Special rule for small business start-up savings accounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual for whose benefit a small business start-up savings account is established and any contributor to such account shall be exempt from the tax imposed by this section with respect to any transaction concerning such account (which would otherwise be taxable under this section) if section 530A(d)(1) applies with respect to such transaction or if such transaction is a qualified start-up expenditure (as defined in section 530A(c)).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H005090BCFE074E4A91935A628C53DC0E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Failure To Provide Reports on Small Business Start-Up Savings Accounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of section 6693(a) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (D), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (E) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB24A0BC9F285427884E17CFE2728666F" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HA32BEEDE004343C18495AA5A90871611"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 530A(h) (relating to small business start-up savings accounts).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HD9169DC422684441B7E03AA6EDF9BF3D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Excess contributions</header> <paragraph id="HCE77FD4B1C534A2DA52B354B954F33F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Tax imposed</header><text>Section 4973(a) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of paragraph (5), by inserting <quote>or</quote> at the end of paragraph (6), and by inserting after paragraph (6) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEFC9BF0FC26E4F86BFE4CE6B962626FB" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HE371FDF0217247698D57C6EB39A79ABA"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a small business start-up savings account (within the meaning of section 530A(b)),</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H44C7A91EFE154D8CA9F7069F6B9EB397"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Excess Contributions to Small Business Start-Up Savings accounts defined</header><text>Section 4973 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H5F89D475546948D795684AC299D3FAC9" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H9FE4ACE81AAA4190B204E9CE372A06EC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Excess Contributions to Small Business Start-Up Savings accounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, in the case of contributions to a small business start-up savings account (within the meaning of section 530A(b)), the term <term>excess contributions</term> means the sum of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H20EFD429A28142ABB54EB3EE2B3CAECF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the excess (if any) of—</text> <subparagraph id="HB90B9260310145EBB2CC581EAE3E07B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount contributed for the taxable year to such accounts (other than a rollover contribution described in section 530A(d)(4)), over</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6625B87242C44C928C4D4C4EA7C285CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount allowable as a contribution under section 530A(b)(1), and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H69FE4683AF6C4EBCB1AE2D40FFBB0E61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount determined under this subsection for the preceding taxable year, reduced by the sum of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFA93D047A0A74E279FC3CA609B86FFA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the distributions out of the accounts for the taxable year, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01D786ECF68545FB9ED5608628D3574E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the excess (if any) of the maximum amount allowable as a contribution under sections 530A(b)(1) for the taxable year over the amount contributed to the accounts for the taxable year.</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">For purposes of this subsection, any contribution which is distributed from a small business
			 start-up savings account in a distribution described in section 530A(d)(3)
			 shall be treated as an amount not contributed.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H08962AFA9ECC43B99315DD0BD310F1ED"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for subchapter F of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8DF97F113AE4401BBE3E6428385753D9" style="OLC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H30A6393620D14229813EC0CA244AC814" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="HD865F7BB14E24061A1CD8A3D238160A5" level="part">Part IX. Small Business Start-Up Savings Accounts</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2668B57E71914D12801C6AF4600A75E2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2016.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

