<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H05C3E50D48764D59AF1ABE622D6F2BD6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2243 IH: HEARTS Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2243</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170428">April 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000174">Mr. Sam Johnson of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for the eligibility of certain former members of
			 the Armed Forces who are medically retired and who are entitled to
			 hospital insurance benefits under Medicare part A by reason of previous
			 entitlement to social security disability insurance benefits to enroll in
			 the TRICARE program regardless of whether such members decline enrollment
			 under Medicare part B, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H0F1898E3E1E64C888F4325E80F940042" style="OLC">
 <section id="H13776E07083C40268FFA615F778CE470" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Equity and Access for Returning Troops and Servicemembers Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>HEARTS Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="HCF162E1A36CE41B2971FA8FE63F07E7C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modification of requirement for certain former members of the Armed Forces to enroll in Medicare Part B to be eligible for TRICARE for Life</header> <subsection id="HDD1B66BF28E544EB99F0817FE740A530"><enum>(a)</enum><header>TRICARE eligibility</header> <paragraph id="H7F2C95C3EDD04C31BFE30A34E72BA693"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (d) of section 1086 of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7638BD7EBFB0480990C200A0D4B360B2" style="USC">
						<paragraph id="H44101322462845EFB798D3B88CD9119D" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H55DE6C829FF14E3EB11514F9DD7AB4C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement in paragraph (2)(A) to enroll in the supplementary medical insurance program under part B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395j">42 U.S.C. 1395j</external-xref> et seq.) shall not apply to a person described in subparagraph (B) during any month in which such person is not entitled to a benefit described in subparagraph (A) of section 226(b)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/426">42 U.S.C. 426(b)(2)</external-xref>) if such person has received the counseling and information under subparagraph (C).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE30E818706A34F6D8DF680505BC951CD" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A person described in this subparagraph is a person—</text> <clause id="H6FA113747B144ECA96B703B55D471C8C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who is under 65 years of age;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HCAB79509099A4A35802BAD868E072863"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who is entitled to hospital insurance benefits under part A of title XVIII of the Social Security Act pursuant to subparagraph (A) or (C) of section 226(b)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/426">42 U.S.C. 426(b)(2)</external-xref>);</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H66001534F36740688D07CC921B99600E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whose entitlement to a benefit described in subparagraph (A) of such section has terminated due to performance of substantial gainful activity; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3B62E31B2D6445C9896A9820896AB767"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>who is retired under chapter 61 of this title.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83D5CCB55D3D4C278229E8D78B129D0A" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall coordinate with the Secretary of Health and Human Services to notify persons described in subparagraph (B) of, and provide information and counseling regarding, the effects of not enrolling in the supplementary medical insurance program under part B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395j">42 U.S.C. 1395j</external-xref> et seq.), as described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A151D3508D94617A3B0DA0C3E6F1E50"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (2)(A) of such subsection is amended by striking <quote>is enrolled</quote> and inserting <quote>except as provided by paragraph (6), is enrolled</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H43EF62F1DC27480B8C6F3F21FB1BD3B4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Identification of persons</header><text>Section 1110a of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC19992338AF43C18118C13C4EEC3C96" style="USC">
 <subsection id="H2E413D0C7B13467A9177176039D240A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certain individuals not required To enroll in Medicare Part B</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall coordinate with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Commissioner of Social Security to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7158491BFC0044EC8F048A1CF2919C52"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify persons described in subparagraph (B) of section 1086(d)(6) of this title; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2EFF8A01052B41378B038AA21D306DF6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide information and counseling pursuant to subparagraph (D) of such section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36C91C4FDB8949198C517C393AFC9FC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Non-Application of Medicare part B late enrollment penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1839(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395r">42 U.S.C. 1395r(b)</external-xref>) is amended, in the second sentence, by inserting <quote>or months for which the individual can demonstrate that the individual is an individual described in paragraph (6)(B) of section 1086(d) of title 10, United States Code, who is enrolled in the TRICARE program pursuant to such section</quote> after <quote>an individual described in section 1837(k)(3)</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA0743DCC9FF3491BAC80C18B2C70319D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Commissioner of Social Security shall jointly submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate, the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on the implementation of section 1086(d)(6) of title 10, United States Code, as added by subsection (a). Such report shall include, with respect to the period covered by the report—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBD4D8FCF53844414BFE1160856CD24C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of individuals enrolled in TRICARE for Life who are not enrolled in the supplementary medical insurance program under part B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395j">42 U.S.C. 1395j</external-xref> et seq.) by reason of such section 1086(d)(6); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H41EDEB9DB7884B20959C3663D2B0E505"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of individuals who—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H92D45CE1759740658198970A2152C60E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are retired from the Armed Forces under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/61">chapter 61</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0484A48388604A70AFC1EE3514E7FE45"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are entitled to hospital insurance benefits under part A of title XVIII of the Social Security Act pursuant to receiving benefits for 24 months as described in subparagraph (A) or (C) of section 226(b)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/426">42 U.S.C. 426(b)(2)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C1C9533FF204FA59E59110C99AE64DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>because of such entitlement, are no longer enrolled in TRICARE Standard, TRICARE Prime, TRICARE Extra, or TRICARE Select under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/55">chapter 55</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9CAB2056CB6F49F2A86B4EAF0DEEC9B0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to a person who, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act, is a person described in section 1086(d)(6)(B) of title 10, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


