<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H900DB7F9440844069DBFE046CC0462EE" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3977 IH: Infrastructure Bank for America Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3977</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171005">October 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000464">Mr. Faso</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Infrastructure Bank for America to serve as a lender for infrastructure projects,
			 both directly and through State and local governments, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H65340E4E32CF49DF9D55A717FA5E5E79" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB454B4BFD0014FA9B1B886AFE619FD91" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Infrastructure Bank for America Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H68884BA0388E41E190A9F722F42038DC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of the Infrastructure Bank for America</header> <subsection id="H38DABC8B55054FA6AD96AB792F9F519E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The formation agent shall, in accordance with such rules and regulations as the Secretary of the Treasury may prescribe, make and file with the Secretary at the earliest practicable date after the date of the enactment of this Act, an organization certificate which shall contain such information as the Secretary may require. Upon the making and filing of such organization certificate with the Secretary, such formation agent shall become a body corporate to be known as the <quote>Infrastructure Bank Holding Company</quote> (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>Holding Company</quote>), which shall be the parent company of the <quote>Infrastructure Bank for America</quote> (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>Bank</quote>), which is hereby established and which shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3D7299F4C24845B399B697768097B0E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serve as a lender for infrastructure projects, both directly and indirectly through State and local governments and State infrastructure banks, as provided under this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED819ABA5DEC46D3A38F08E4AF7E20E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintain its principal office in New York City or the District of Columbia or the metropolitan area thereof;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H778C634EB4F144D0ADE0B4A092C4210A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be deemed, for purposes of jurisdiction and venue in civil actions to be a Delaware corporation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H840625D6D8B643F5BE13D7F635460952"><enum>(4)</enum><text>have all powers, not inconsistent with the provisions of this Act, as are customary and usual in corporations generally.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1127EEF63665430EA472B79028BAB3E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regional offices</header><text>The Bank shall establish regional offices, for the purpose of focusing on projects in different areas of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5C68193032CD48ACBAFDAA88FF8EAFAE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Board of directors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bank shall have a board of directors, which shall—</text> <paragraph id="HB2DA4B25DA884062855F2A692FD684A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>initially consist of 7 members, or such other number as the Bank determines appropriate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H19AD20ED00DB4C68A93A128290BFB72E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be elected by the Bank’s shareholders;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H163F4E41837C4960AF57CE7CF10BF3E4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>within the limitations of law and regulation, determine the general policies which shall govern the operations of the Bank, and have power to adopt, amend, and repeal bylaws governing the performance of the powers and duties granted to or imposed upon the Bank by law; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24FF118E718A4DEF80A8106F5B3F99AC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>select and effect the appointment of qualified persons to fill the office of the Chief Executive Officer and, along with the Chief Executive Officer, such other offices as may be provided for in the bylaws.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB66E2BE5F98A4F83A51F3843CC1EB501"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment of shareholders of the formation agent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Holding Company shall, upon establishment, issue equity securities of the Holding Company to each shareholder of the formation agent, in an amount that the Board of Directors determines has a value equal to the value of equity securities of the formation agent held by such shareholder upon the establishment of the Holding Company.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0C9AD18F643F4880890EEE4B56E1285D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Earnings and reserves not Government funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The earnings and reserves of the Holding Company and the Bank shall be the sole property of the Holding Company and the Bank and shall not be construed to be Government or public funds or appropriated money.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HA6E7BE19376B44D3B803500BBA4A75A6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Functions of the Bank</header>
 <subsection id="H1706155ABB714CFFBF2686C200C5765B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bank shall provide—</text> <paragraph id="HB3130C4574D44BF8BBDCBF193835602F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">direct loans and loan guarantees to private entities for the construction or maintenance of revenue-producing infrastructure projects; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB51FD0DB05E45629B2CCBB8DB1B8DE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>indirect loans and loan guarantees to State and local governments and State infrastructure banks, for the construction or maintenance of infrastructure projects.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H810275004F574E749C5E30DE6F801EA1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Support for rural projects</header><text>At least 7 percent of the dollar amount of loans and loan guarantees provided by the Bank shall be with respect to infrastructure projects in rural areas.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H525A99280ADD4BB2800057D44F5C5BB3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No commercial or investment banking activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bank shall not accept customer deposits nor engage in financial or investment banking activities, such as trust management or underwriting securities.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H82791D252CDD4F4D85E693E095C692CC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Pledge and credit facilities</header>
 <paragraph id="H3F85FAD76A0A42A989C42AA5CA05642C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pledge</header><text>The Bank shall have the authority to pledge its loans to the discount window of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and as advances to any Federal Home Loan Bank.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H879D4DF05A5B469E92DC6C3FB0B211C6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Line of credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide a line of credit to the Bank in a similar manner to the facility available to the Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Banks.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4C61BB84051246338F60420E7E4997DF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Holding Company securities</header>
			<subsection id="H98BD0B49463F4B13BC9E3A8E21FE6B0D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Equity securities</header>
 <paragraph id="H567A490C0D3749499F11AD7FA44476F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Holding Company shall issue such equity securities as the Holding Company determines appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF2DD52ECAB049E78B7152180E4F4A00"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dividends</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Holding Company may make such dividend payments on the equity securities of the Holding Company as the Holding Company determines appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7BAF491BE2C047B88CA194ED6420B84F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Initial issuance amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Holding Company shall have the goal of raising $100,000,000,000 in the initial issuance of equity securities, the purpose of which is to fund the Bank.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H61F01D6C1B864ABDADC6ECE0C912B0C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bonds</header>
 <paragraph id="HA74EDB46C67144A88E6DD64D7A1BD1C3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Standard bonds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Holding Company shall issue standard bonds, with maturities up to 30 years, or longer as needed.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HE3B2A38104BE4421A3F8F02684652BDB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Repatriated cash bonds</header>
 <subparagraph id="H50E19F90FA364DD4B7D35F96906E9046"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Holding Company shall issue special bonds, named <quote>Repatriation Bonds</quote>, with maturities up to 30 years or longer as needed, that are only purchasable using dividends to which <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/965">section 965(g)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 applied.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0D38DCAE8B94A06B7F7B51984F0C427"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of repatriated cash to purchase securities</header><text>For treatment of dividends used to purchased special bonds under this paragraph, see <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/965">section 965(g)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC570344F8EE425C84DA81318FAB025E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>5-year limitation</header><text>The Holding Company may not issue any new Repatriation Bonds after the end of the 5-year period beginning on the date the Bank is established.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H83F6B9233F6146728F79DB7F425A2687"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other bonds</header><text>The Holding Company may issue such other bonds, notes, and marketable securities with maturities and interest rates as the Holding Company determines appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA3C5079B3D349B0B20EB8D0E691657A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Initial issuance amount</header><text>The Holding Company shall have the goal of making initial bond sales in an aggregate amount of $1,000,000,000,000 or more.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H5D9A5FF13EA34142B2465716D94472E4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Treasury oversight and authority to purchase bonds</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0453815C13A44341BDFFC8FFA9EDF374"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Approval required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before issuing any bonds, the Holding Company shall submit a proposal for such bond issuance to the Secretary, and the Holding Company may only issue such bonds if the Secretary approves the proposal.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E7C8196EAC84982B8408583D040B58C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority to purchase bonds</header>
 <clause id="H8C22951B468540F3B9E485AF4CE94DB6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may purchase bonds issued under this subsection.</text> </clause><clause id="H12BC901A980D459EB36BA044A6279B45"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The aggregate amount of outstanding bonds purchased by the Secretary under this subsection may not exceed 5 percent of the total amount of the Holding Company’s outstanding bonds.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H763A98F1B8CA440A96FE54A8BE57A5CA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Leverage limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Holding Company and the Bank shall seek to maintain risk based capital at no less than 10 percent.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H02A5C04A1AA844F190D5E4B6AF219DDB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Oversight and regulation</header>
 <subsection id="H67DEC275626F4DE89CE9F004C71CCE34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall have oversight and supervisory authority over the Infrastructure Bank Holding Company and the Bank in order to ensure the safe and sound operations of the Infrastructure Bank Holding Company and the Bank.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAE690E61C33E4A0284DE76CA0075EC85"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Secretary of the Treasury</header><text>The Secretary shall establish an office, which shall report to the Assistant Secretary of the Treasury for Financial Institutions, which shall have oversight and supervisory authority over the issuance of bonds by the Infrastructure Bank Holding Company and the Bank in order to ensure the safe and sound financing of the Infrastructure Bank Holding Company and the Bank.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE86C54E7D84F4DB9A175F82E68651BFB"><enum>6.</enum><header>Infrastructure Guarantee Fund</header>
 <subsection id="H9DEB99D7255D49E98A16802B368148F7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bank shall establish an Infrastructure Guarantee Fund, which shall be available for State and local governments and other persons who wish to deposit funds to be used with respect to specific loans or loan guarantees made by the Bank, in the event of any non-payment by the recipient of such loan or loan guarantee.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDA7A7DCE24144161A974DEB1D28445CA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Return of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any funds described under subsection (a) that are remaining at the time such loans or guaranteed loans are repaid shall be returned to the State or local government or other person who deposited the funds.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H692D7E3746CF4083B060606A2FFF5082"><enum>7.</enum><header>Holding Company and Bank exemption from taxation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Holding Company and the Bank, including its franchise, its capital, reserves, and surplus, its advances, and its income shall be exempt from all taxation now or hereafter imposed by the United States, by any territory, dependency, or possession thereof, or by any State, county, municipal, or local taxing authority, except that any real property of the Holding Company and the Bank shall be subject to State, territorial, county, municipal, or local taxation to the same extent according to its value as other real property is taxed.</text>
		</section><section id="H299D5135379149DA9F0FA48DBD0E9BEF" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>8.</enum><header>Extension and modification of dividends received deduction for repatriated foreign earnings used to
			 purchase Holding Company bonds</header>
 <subsection id="H2EE4203668E44CE7846026877644D746"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/965">Section 965</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15520C92113B4F0483F8CDDB5A661A6A" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HB90365DBF6E74822829CFC0C2D5E3379"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Temporary extension and modification</header>
 <paragraph id="HD38A5B95F87C434C8F3ED24DC1EEE82A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an election under this subsection, subsection (f)(1) shall be applied by substituting <quote>the date of the enactment of subsection (g)</quote> for <quote>the date of the enactment of this section</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H704B3DCBDB494D09AA6F82AD72608BF1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Percentage deductible</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an election under this subsection, subsection (a)(1) shall be applied by substituting <quote>100 percent</quote> for <quote>85 percent</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE306F7F67054197A3333ABD0E2867C9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirement to invest in bonds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an election under this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H9C8178A67B5249C6ACDB842B3C39476E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subsection (b)(4) shall not apply, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFED642FC89BA4C87AABAE8A2E9892E2B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subsection (a) shall only apply to so much of the portion dividends received by a United States shareholder during the taxable year as does not exceed the amount paid by the shareholder during such taxable year for bonds issued under section 4(b)(2) of the Infrastructure Bank for America Act of 2017.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H546AE65A3E0E4A86ADD818B29FAA63A6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <subparagraph id="H701416E575A947418682B9C89D9906D2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Recapture in case of bonds sold during recapture period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, by regulations, provide for recapturing the applicable percentage of the benefit under any deduction allowable by this subsection if before the end of the 10-year period beginning on the date of the purchase of the bond to which this subsection applies the taxpayer disposes of such bond.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC47DD18B9690406B86C65851B6255830"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the applicable percentage shall be determined under the following table:</text>
								<table align-to-level="section" blank-lines-before="1" colsep="0" frame="none" line-rules="no-gen" rowsep="0" rule-weights="0.0.0.0.0.0" subformat="S6211" table-template-name="Flush/hang, 1 text, 1 num, bold hds" table-type="Leaderwork"><tgroup cols="2" rowsep="0" thead-tbody-ldg-size="10.10.12"><colspec coldef="txt" colname="column1" colwidth="258pts" min-data-value="225"></colspec><colspec coldef="fig" colname="column2" colwidth="176.06pt" min-data-value="12"></colspec><thead><row><entry align="left" colname="column1" morerows="0" namest="column1" rowsep="0"><bold>In the case of a disposition</bold></entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" morerows="0" namest="column2" rowsep="0"></entry></row><row><entry align="left" colname="column1" morerows="0" namest="column1" rowsep="0"><bold>  in the following year of </bold></entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" morerows="0" namest="column2" rowsep="0"><bold>The applicable </bold></entry></row><row><entry align="left" colname="column1" morerows="0" namest="column1" rowsep="0"><bold> such 10-year period:</bold></entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" morerows="0" namest="column2" rowsep="0"><bold> percentage shall be:</bold></entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">First year</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0"> 100 percent</entry></row><row><entry colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Second year</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">90 percent</entry></row><row><entry colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Third year</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">80 percent</entry></row><row><entry colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Fourth year</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">70 percent</entry></row><row><entry colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Fifth year</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">60 percent</entry></row><row><entry colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Sixth year</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">50 percent</entry></row><row><entry colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Seventh year</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">40 percent</entry></row><row><entry colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Eighth year</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">30 percent</entry></row><row><entry colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Ninth year</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">20 percent</entry></row><row><entry colname="column1" leader-modify="force-ldr" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">Tenth year</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" rowsep="0">10 percent.</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H13867495BCF24167AF181A7577E5D16D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header>
 <paragraph id="HBB9D0306708E4AF4908E3EB5D40C3ED0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 965 of such Code is amended by striking <quote>June 30, 2003</quote> each place it occurs and inserting <quote>June 30, 2016</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD516ECA9632D48ED84EF3978B5401699"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Subparagraph (B) of section 965(b)(3) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>October 3, 2004</quote> and inserting <quote>September 1, 2017</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0682335502934D528B23FA4C9B21A927"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years ending on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H98D7FC479A1546F499B3ED2A790AC7EA"><enum>9.</enum><header>Infrastructure Bank Holding Company credit</header>
 <subsection id="HD7E01F5F176743E5AF2C9735D31C37FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F8B97103238424F973DD9155461CCBE" style="OLC">
					<section id="HEE24301597E244118E189F51D8B230EF"><enum>45S.</enum><header>Infrastructure Bank Holding Company credit</header>
 <subsection id="H81F8727C743E4846ADA1E94F86E3D319"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 38, in the case of a taxpayer who holds a qualified Holding Company equity investment on a credit allowance date of such investment which occurs during the taxable year, the Infrastructure Bank Holding Company credit determined under this section for such taxable year is an amount equal to 16 percent of the amount paid to the Holding Company for such investment at its original issue.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDE5DED766C1C4D73AEF08B332235764A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit allowance date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, credit allowance date with respect to any qualified Holding Company equity investment is—</text>
 <paragraph id="H996376EFD8444CB2ABF0F7A11569B0BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date on which such investment is initially made, and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H070C5A89C11945B684D2889966D6482F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each of the 4 anniversary dates of such date thereafter.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB72D3513FF644C728D515F0F5423BB77"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified Holding Company equity investment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified Holding Company equity investment</term> means any equity investment originally issued by the Holding Company to the taxpayer under section 4(a)(1) of the Infrastructure Bank for America Act of 2017 not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of such Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7590272FD6644DBDB66350EB9096FBB4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Holding Company</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>Holding Company</term> means the Infrastructure Bank Holding Company established under the Infrastructure Bank for America Act of 2017.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H25D5FB076A89450DB1D2187C6C06BA21"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Basis reduction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The basis of any qualified Holding Company equity investment shall be reduced by the amount of any credit determined under this section with respect to such investment.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HE8AFE850BAD743F299BB76B6D0BA3032"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H1DBD6366BBB54D6A9B8C0117B4E012E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 38(b) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (35), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (36) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H31EB961615FB42B1B9BB27FB0B7FF823" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H14610D24AEE24B6DA4CFC58EBED3E45F"><enum>(37)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Infrastructure Bank Holding Company credit determined under section 45S.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0678CA685A04F308C415DB4B979EABE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 1016(a) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (36), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (37) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F8D58501821433CAF22D614853DA7B1" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HE21FA3F9517F4816A885911A15601A3C"><enum>(38)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent provided in section 45S(e).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8138B773505D461AB1EB8BFBD2EB10B2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years ending after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HC202CE3731044F74B79134DA072A5A77"><enum>10.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HB1E5CA7E5E8C4C049671370F90C1650B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bank</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Bank</term> means the Infrastructure Bank for America established under section 2.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4EE8EE3F081847FA801AD61A96E3327B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Formation agent</header><text>The term <term>formation agent</term> means an entity selected by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H70AE6FD293C348B192B3A97CF309C51C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Infrastructure Bank Holding Company</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Infrastructure Bank Holding Company</term> means the company—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBE3F0332DCEF4B699147CF30463686DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by that name incorporated by the formation agent; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE4F994050394708849A442948F6E2FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>acting as the parent company of the Bank after the establishment of the Bank.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DD2B566007B45F29E00EAA116B74394"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Revenue-producing infrastructure project</header><text>The term <term>revenue-producing infrastructure project</term> means an infrastructure project that, when complete, generates revenue from user fees.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFE09F6BD349F467D91C9B63C6DD1A807"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Risk based capital</header><text>The term <term>risk based capital</term> shall have the meaning given that term by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D5E675F24FC4FD5BF3BF4A03E5C9ED5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rural</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rural</term> means a county that is neither in a metropolitan statistical area nor in a micropolitan statistical area that is adjacent to a metropolitan statistical area, as those terms are defined by the U.S. Office of Management and Budget and as they are applied under currently applicable Urban Influence Codes, established by the United States Department of Agriculture's Economic Research Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H342F1D7FE39149C08C940D71B79BD546"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Treasury.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H40131D167C43461C917632BC478EAA91"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, each territory or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian tribe.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE74991B19C54E72A12843A413ADAE91"><enum>(9)</enum><header>State infrastructure bank</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State infrastructure bank</term> means a State infrastructure bank or multistate infrastructure bank established pursuant to—</text> <subparagraph id="H7EC6159705D5469E84BD01ECFA8D6339"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 350 of the National Highway System Designation Act of 1995;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63D0EE73AC104D5DABA44B43E2CDC3AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 1511(l) of the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06F470C16AE54D1CB4DE63919B082038"><enum>(C)</enum><text>section 610 of title 23, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CC89BCF309243D5979C199A94925297"><enum>(10)</enum><header>State or local government</header><text>The term <term>State or local government</term> means a State or local government or any agency or instrumentality of a State or local government.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

