<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0B8DA9B40FB749408AB7B61B699E1323" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3787 IH: Small Entity Regulatory Relief Opportunity Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3787</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170914">September 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to provide for streamlined procedures for waiver petitions
			 seeking relief for small entities from regulations issued by the Federal
			 Communications Commission, to require the Commission to defer the
			 application of new regulations to small entities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HD0B523B188624E17A82989098978BD3F" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA23A468C90214E419152DC5F0C43F579" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small Entity Regulatory Relief Opportunity Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7A477A695C7D4D0CB4C23EBF6CE8B260"><enum>2.</enum><header>Regulatory relief for small entities</header> <subsection id="HFED14EA49E4741F4A4B5918F6EEC3E5D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title I of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6FB0E8D83E142D4A0B477AE02D0991D" style="OLC">
					<section id="HF1F8E60816C445C48B8B1D99E54C8955"><enum>13.</enum><header>Regulatory relief for small entities</header>
						<subsection id="H514122B640E7406FADD9950213128E97"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Streamlined procedures for waiver petitions</header>
 <paragraph id="HA201661884844A09A2086D1E5707B4A6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Commission shall complete a rulemaking to establish streamlined procedures applicable to the filing, consideration, and resolution of any petition—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H066CE5269DE1403597E3B5D01023D692"><enum>(A)</enum><text>seeking a waiver of a regulation issued by the Commission under this Act;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7D27AA19B154AC78DF730FB73D61096"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in which the relief sought is limited to small entities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2D37E48972549DF88AF689AA49793A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that is filed—</text> <clause id="H803867827FDA4636A0C69F9D26E361FF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by a small entity on its own behalf or jointly with other small entities; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H30A6844CE9904C90A207FB3ED2D20469"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by a representative organization on behalf of one or more classes of small entities.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4579A2D7B88F4AF597676FC49BA0EEF9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>The objectives of the streamlined procedures established under paragraph (1) shall be—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA2CE6455D06243329E18897DF44B9C0F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to expedite the consideration and resolution of petitions described in such paragraph; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D35578A6DF64285B8917D2781F0918E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a petition described in such paragraph that is filed by a small entity on its own behalf or jointly with other small entities, to reduce the costs and procedural obligations associated with filing such petition.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H85F3BE60565647E9A334D64E46803BB9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deferred application of regulations</header>
 <paragraph id="H0D92D9668BFE41E79297682BB011703F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), in the case of a regulation issued by the Commission under this Act, the Commission shall defer application to small entities of such regulation for not less than 1 year after the latest date on which such regulation becomes effective for an entity that is not a small entity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F2D1A8C84824E4EB2A19E99A694DF32"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply if the statutory provision under which the regulation is issued expressly states that the Commission may not exercise the authority granted under such paragraph to defer the application of such regulation to small entities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA665928F48DD402B899EF81275044EED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may decline to grant some or all small entities a deferral under paragraph (1), or may grant some or all small entities a deferral under such paragraph for less than 1 year, if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H50351194AB2A463E8CAF6AACA5F52186"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Commission finds (and incorporates the finding and a statement of reasons therefore in the order or other decision document in which the regulation is adopted) that—</text>
 <clause id="HB068902587B149A08BB0B388CF20C717"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the regulation is principally intended—</text> <subclause id="H93F025DFB517413EBEF74F46977BBF76"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to reduce waste, fraud, and abuse by a small entity; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H42F70183781541F796E5ADDF3E382825"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to protect public safety; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H34D7473F6C1643BD995074442693E1BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no deferral or deferral for less than 1 year would be in the public interest; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDED461F901B34A26915AEED2EF922454"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a showing has been made by the small entities that would benefit from the deferral otherwise required by paragraph (1) that the benefits to such small entities of such deferral are outweighed by the benefits to such small entities of no deferral or deferral for less than 1 year.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB092D3CA8A584890B4D2301C6D3F7FF6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regulations subject to information collection approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a regulation requiring a collection of information that is subject to approval under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, the deferral period under this subsection shall begin on the latest date following such approval on which such regulation becomes effective for an entity that is not a small entity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3CA8DAB8AB4C40B884696DADBEB38D53"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Entities that cease to be small entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity that is eligible under this subsection for deferred application of a regulation on the date on which the deferral commences shall continue to be entitled to the full term of the deferral notwithstanding that such entity ceases to be a small entity, whether through a change in the definition of the term <quote>small entity</quote> or otherwise.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H12D75DFA25C04D1281A807E67E577BB5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Small entity defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>small entity</quote> means any entity that meets either of the following requirements:</text> <paragraph id="HE4F5A52ED66141B1BA1178D594972B35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The entity is a small entity (as defined in section 601 of title 5, United States Code).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H78D701C32AD5471EB8230C4CCFD0BFEE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a regulation applicable to a particular subscription service, the entity provides such subscription service to 2 percent or fewer of the consumers receiving such subscription service in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2B1A7181882345438241F5AFF9A1C655"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Triennial regulatory review</header><text>Section 257 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/257">47 U.S.C. 257</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H77EA89489D534A1FBC89ACDCF36977C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Market entry barriers proceeding</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Elimination of market entry barriers and unnecessary regulation of small entities</header-in-text></quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BAC6A6D852043D889606CD1BF939A39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE97AAE978D64598A6DA13F24751C6FA" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H83D3F78B98564B07B65ECD90426A2264"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Review of application of regulations to small entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of the periodic review conducted under subsection (c), the Commission shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5174884F92BF47E4ADD4C8CEBD545353"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review all regulations issued under this Act in effect at the time of the review that apply to the operations or activities of any provider of any service subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission under this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3759E7245F3C43469C6E78653C720249"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether there is good cause for the Commission to grant relief to some or all small entities (as defined in section 13) from any such regulation, in whole or in part; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA4371860F90D43CA91DF932B1F9C3A5B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if the determination under paragraph (2) is affirmative, grant such relief by modifying such regulation as such regulation applies to some or all small entities.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


