<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE0850577F4BB4FA9AA8D2E2778F4D71B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2697 IH: Transparency in Military Lending Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2697</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to require additional disclosures by creditors when lending
			 to members of the Armed Forces and their dependents, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC465A15142D0492185F49AEDCDFE6027" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3C0FB75A79BA477FA21ADCD121E4B06F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transparency in Military Lending Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5EE95FB8C65241B597E6D81181549586"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transparency in lending to members of the Armed Forces and their dependents</header> <subsection id="HDAC4BFA6EE0246AF81AECDDF8A78FD08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transparency and disclosures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 987(c) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3047BD401E94D57ADA55FF0D474BC90" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H1CBD11ACF3B34209B00480883468C4DC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional disclosures</header>
 <subparagraph id="H46238EAE75014636B544EAF9C71CF8C9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any extension of consumer credit described in paragraph (1), a creditor shall provide to the member or dependent each of the following pieces of information, orally and in writing:</text>
 <clause id="HBCD1E0520A93431D937A341DC0840238"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A statement that the Department of Defense and each service branch offers a variety of financial counseling services.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H05C45BA8048147D294E131D984AE8B13"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A statement that other, lower interest rate loans, including potentially 0 percent interest loans, may be available through other financial institutions and military relief societies.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7AA319B60E4C4506ABC7B3456BA742EB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Contact information for the nearest Department of Defense financial counseling office.</text> </clause><clause id="H2BD44E5793FE46C78C537D5CE9C84266"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A statement of the actual cost of the extension of credit, prepared as an amortization table showing what the cost to the member or dependent will be if the extension of credit is paid off at different points over time.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80F5A24B8E9346B1BD8DD4A8733F8526"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Format of disclosures</header><text>The written disclosures required under clauses (i), (ii), and (iii) of subparagraph (A) shall be provided on single sheet of paper and be in a bold, 14-point font.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H862006C3D7894668811CB233A70D1B31"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Signed acknowledgment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any extension of consumer credit described under paragraph (1), a creditor may not issue the credit unless the member or dependent signs a separate acknowledgment next to each piece of information described in paragraph (3)(A) acknowledging that the member or dependent has read each piece of information.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H375290F68A864163905316186DA8A073"><enum>(D)</enum><header>List of financial counseling offices</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall prepare a list of Department of Defense financial counseling offices and make the list available to creditors and the public.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE51954144164902B0D4DB8D68E2C969"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Transparency for payday loans and vehicle loans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <quote>consumer credit</quote> shall include <quote>payday loans</quote> and <quote>vehicle title loans</quote> as those terms were defined in section 232.3 of title 32, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on July 1, 2015.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


