<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6E1A5B9F553F4D848D39FB42135F7F72" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2036 IH: To prohibit any reduction in the amount of the per diem allowance to which members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Marine Corps or civilian employees of the Department of Defense are entitled based on the duration of temporary duty assignments or official travel, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2036</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit any reduction in the amount of the per diem allowance to which members of the Army,
			 Navy, Air Force, and Marine Corps or civilian employees of the Department
			 of Defense are entitled based on the duration of temporary duty
			 assignments or official travel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9A01E02D017C4520B0CE2CCC4D9FB833" style="OLC">
		<section id="HC21E69C5FF1A47AF94D207E196193461" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition on per diem allowance reductions based on the duration of temporary duty assignment or
			 civilian travel </header>
 <subsection id="H1BE6751D44F54826A2F577E729C104AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 474(d)(3) of title 37, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>The Secretary of a military department shall not alter the amount of the per diem allowance, or the maximum amount of reimbursement, for a locality based on the duration of the temporary duty assignment in the locality of a member of the armed forces under the jurisdiction of the Secretary.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB8EFCAF73A4B4387BED3F829220684CE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civilian employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5702(a)(2) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>The Secretary of Defense shall not alter the amount of the per diem allowance, or the maximum amount of reimbursement, for a locality based on the duration of the travel in the locality of an employee of the Department.</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HBD81C7E728C640EEB2BB8A32F56AA52B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Repeals</header>
 <paragraph id="H21116638387C437A9DC93AF1FFF679FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Existing policy and regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The policy, and any regulations issued pursuant to such policy, implemented by the Secretary of the Department of Defense on November 1, 2014, with respect to reductions in per diem allowances based on duration of temporary duty assignment or civilian travel shall have no force or effect.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB25AB645A41C494BBAEAD18D19A8D84F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Attempted statutory fix</header><text>Section 672 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/37/474">37 U.S.C. 474</external-xref> note; 130 Stat. 2178) is repealed.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


