<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6EA75A9F47D44871B44750F49E43699D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 555 IH: Amateur Radio Parity Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 555</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170113">January 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000791">Mr. Walden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Federal Communications Commission to amend its rules so as to prohibit the
			 application to amateur stations of certain private land use restrictions,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB9A88B65381748AB9426B6103478F2A7" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA96CF6AFBB6B44408452F39DCBDEF63D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Amateur Radio Parity Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8C911ADECF0743B6B24237723ED450BC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H021BB2003E14473F87CB4B6725F8E1B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">More than 730,000 radio amateurs in the United States are licensed by the Federal Communications Commission in the amateur radio services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A329F28D2224D218E6825E544A2ED09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Amateur radio, at no cost to taxpayers, provides a fertile ground for technical self-training in modern telecommunications, electronics technology, and emergency communications techniques and protocols.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8EBD036AD754D80B1EAD0403FAF14E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>There is a strong Federal interest in the effective performance of amateur stations established at the residences of licensees. Such stations have been shown to be frequently and increasingly precluded by unreasonable private land use restrictions, including restrictive covenants.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H830F2C7DB54C4124B2B6F8568321F796"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Federal Communications Commission regulations have for three decades prohibited the application to stations in the amateur service of State and local regulations that preclude or fail to reasonably accommodate amateur service communications, or that do not constitute the minimum practicable regulation to accomplish a legitimate State or local purpose. Commission policy has been and is to require States and localities to permit erection of a station antenna structure at heights and dimensions sufficient to accommodate amateur service communications.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3F7454E87F934F3A92C4CCDD12C29B26"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Commission has sought guidance and direction from Congress with respect to the application of the Commission’s limited preemption policy regarding amateur service communications to private land use restrictions, including restrictive covenants.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H67A243470F1A49B182C188D873D0A54A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>There are aesthetic and common property considerations that are uniquely applicable to private land use regulations and the community associations obligated to enforce covenants, conditions, and restrictions in deed-restricted communities. These considerations are dissimilar to those applicable to State law and local ordinances regulating the same residential amateur radio facilities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB6E7676575BC475DA51EDA1D1A67F97F"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In recognition of these considerations, a separate Federal policy than exists at section 97.15(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, is warranted concerning amateur service communications in deed-restricted communities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H124071010B6741BF8D8BE301A3A4D1C9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Community associations should fairly administer private land use regulations in the interest of their communities, while nevertheless permitting the installation and maintenance of effective outdoor amateur radio antennas. There exist antenna designs and installations that can be consistent with the aesthetics and physical characteristics of land and structures in community associations while accommodating communications in the amateur radio services.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HD197431BCF474C9ABBB10D90B1243B4D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Application of private land use restrictions to amateur stations</header>
 <subsection id="HE767869EA510477B9957FEE2D79E8DF0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment of FCC rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Communications Commission shall amend section 97.15 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, by adding a new paragraph that prohibits the application to amateur stations of any private land use restriction, including a restrictive covenant, that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H984DE18D11F846BE94F86F9269B6CE3D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on its face or as applied, precludes communications in an amateur radio service;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA4A58DD3CF941E9B43BE4235BDBDC59"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fails to permit a licensee in an amateur radio service to install and maintain an effective outdoor antenna on property under the exclusive use or control of the licensee; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D68398C0553481B9228A0CFBE67CE56"><enum>(3)</enum><text>does not constitute the minimum practicable restriction on such communications to accomplish the lawful purposes of a community association seeking to enforce such restriction.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF78CBC9A527F4402B889048FBB3604B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text>In amending its rules as required by subsection (a), the Commission shall—</text> <paragraph id="HEA499E6D98C94D66BCDCCF1D04F4E818"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require any licensee in an amateur radio service to notify and obtain prior approval from a community association concerning installation of an outdoor antenna;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H883B1ACEA3B74B758283C4B53C37DBDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permit a community association to prohibit installation of any antenna or antenna support structure by a licensee in an amateur radio service on common property not under the exclusive use or control of the licensee; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A1075568C85402BAB249889624F3ECF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>subject to the standards specified in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a), permit a community association to establish reasonable written rules concerning height, location, size, and aesthetic impact of, and installation requirements for, outdoor antennas and support structures for the purpose of conducting communications in the amateur radio services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF200ABB2662145CD9D8E3EDF7F9B7E5C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Affirmation of limited preemption of State and local land use regulation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Communications Commission may not change section 97.15(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, which shall remain applicable to State and local land use regulation of amateur service communications.</text>
 </section><section id="HA501D8706CF74673B4FB72F60D489937"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HE34C931C018F47F7A1EEA54AFF558616"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community association</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>community association</quote> means any non-profit mandatory membership organization composed of owners of real estate described in a declaration of covenants or created pursuant to a covenant or other applicable law with respect to which a person, by virtue of the person’s ownership of or interest in a unit or parcel, is obligated to pay for a share of real estate taxes, insurance premiums, maintenance, improvement, services, or other expenses related to common elements, other units, or any other real estate other than the unit or parcel described in the declaration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24723E0359F542169FED49829549ADCF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms defined in regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>amateur radio services</quote>, <quote>amateur service</quote>, and <quote>amateur station</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 97.3 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

