<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H26BD7316A43F4E19AC1C0EE8C691A334" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4735 IH: Gold King Mine Spill Accountability Act of 2018</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2018-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4735</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20180103">January 3, 2018</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide compensation to persons injured by the Gold King Mine spill and fund certain long-term
			 water quality monitoring programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3D7BFA73134C4A32903B8C926BD7F9F4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4B0BE6C26A524DDFBCA2714B6859D418" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gold King Mine Spill Accountability Act of 2018</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8F572D6C1A184F3CBFD793782A91E3FB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H9D613E288901443EB3E301B5A340502D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On August 5, 2015, the Environmental Protection Agency caused a blowout at the Gold King Mine in Colorado that released approximately 3 million gallons of heavy-metal-laced mine wastewater into the Animas and San Juan Rivers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB3EA6ABB5AB14AA6994F42A4AC71A53A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In October of 2015, the Bureau of Reclamation issued a report that detailed how the Environmental Protection Agency <quote>incorrectly concluded</quote> that the water level inside the Gold King mine was only partially full of wastewater and used this conclusion to develop a <quote>plan to open the mine in a manner that appeared to guard against blowout, but instead led directly to that failure</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCFEEA18CE6364DB0BEA9BD97C6C5CC52"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On January 13, 2017, the Environmental Protection Agency concluded that the agency was not legally able to pay compensation for the claims relating to the Gold King Mine spill brought under the Federal Tort Claims Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71BA3BF0485A458CA6B42B7CFB90EAB4"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On August 4, 2017, Environmental Protection Agency Administrator Scott Pruitt announced that the agency will reconsider claims relating to the Gold King Mine spill.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HE41153C65D944879A58E789A3D5889CB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Compensation for victims of Gold King Mine spill</header>
			<subsection id="H39E6F4BDEBAB4AAF85F3EB50D4194A90"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal tort claims</header>
 <paragraph id="HABC4F2E87B884F09A99EDE517F7FEA23"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to <internal-xref idref="H1EC1728061354F8B99033399FAEF246F" legis-path="3.(a)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref>, each injured person shall be entitled to receive from the United States compensation for a claim filed, or civil action brought, under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Tort Claims Act</quote>), arising out of or relating to an injury resulting from the Gold King Mine spill.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1EC1728061354F8B99033399FAEF246F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonapplicability of limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 2672 of title 28, United States Code, the Administrator may provide compensation for a claim under this section in an amount greater than $25,000 without prior written approval of the Attorney General (or a designee), as the Administrator determines to be appropriate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H417C0D4E17ED49F0BA7BE25C155AAAB6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Office of Gold King Mine Spill Claims</header>
 <paragraph id="H971A58F7771A453DA7AB3466F6A2E773"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the Environmental Protection Agency an Office of Gold King Mine Spill Claims, in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H27E6EAD0B657461EB3428420FB86CC9F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Office shall receive, process, and pay claims in accordance with this section.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6E09BA2314648CC870E97402D63ECF1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment</header><text>The establishment of the Office by this subsection shall not diminish the ability of the Administrator to carry out the responsibilities of the Environmental Protection Agency under any other provision of law.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H214236AAAC2244C682B3D6CE19D0D7C2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Detailees</header><text>Upon the request of the Administrator, the head of any Federal department or agency may detail, on a reimbursable basis, any personnel of that department or agency to the Office to assist in carrying out this section.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB828F32127A44091A91E2FA614080292"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Allowable damages</header>
 <paragraph id="HC08ABA2E32594E488728AFB592CDC2E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Property loss</header><text>A claim that is paid for loss of property under this section may include damages resulting from the Gold King Mine spill for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2C970647FB3F46578E6B1DCF03BDBDF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any cost resulting from lost tribal subsistence from hunting, fishing, firewood gathering, timbering, grazing, or agricultural activities, or from lost use for traditional or ceremonial uses, conducted on land or using water damaged by the Gold King Mine spill;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC42A1735EC0D45ED971137021EEB28D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any cost of reforestation or revegetation on tribal or non-Federal land, to the extent that the cost of reforestation or revegetation is not covered by any other Federal program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68CB987B3779465BA69863F0156B3E84"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any costs borne by any injured person to determine the extent of—</text> <clause id="H689390289F4E421082E57A4F4EE7A7CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the damages to agricultural land; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDB2DA62E64BE402AAD2AEC4DE48DD21C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other damages covered by this section;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35D6F54995844E9AAF0C9EEDE12C6903"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any costs borne by an injured person to pay for water supplies or equipment to treat water during the period for which a water supply of the injured person was compromised by the Gold King Mine spill; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1324C0F715D64A4192663B1BDB025397"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other loss that the Administrator determines to be appropriate for inclusion as loss of property.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9C5925194674E8DACB38764A7585865"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Business loss</header><text>A claim that is paid for a business loss under this section may include damages resulting from the Gold King Mine spill for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0D3E6E8CABAD4E6CA030C81136C66461"><enum>(A)</enum><text>damage to tangible assets or inventory;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E161D967C6442DF82CB989B051E1F5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>business interruption losses;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27D545EDF72441549ED699B56F2E6CC9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>overhead costs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE459C04B6DC94915AD8890642EA8FF67"><enum>(D)</enum><text>employee wages for work not performed; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF85912CE85D94A5E9FE382518C1F6DE3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other loss that the Administrator determines to be appropriate for inclusion as a business loss.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8128EA28BF0842B0BDC16CFD95780437"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Financial loss</header><text>A claim that is paid for a financial loss under this section may include damages resulting from the Gold King Mine spill for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF8030EF308D84F4F844D35C408FC220E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an insurance deductible;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC916B16EDD9A44A6B44FF78C8B629AA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>lost wages or personal income;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DE1526A3433470998A533ECF26CC597"><enum>(C)</enum><text>emergency staffing expenses;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H501617F2448D4DA5B68BC075AFB72CAC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>debris removal and other cleanup costs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C59F022D0F1452085ECFF59C78BCA53"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other loss that the Administrator determines to be appropriate for inclusion as a financial loss.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6590632C705F4B518FF7DA21B0415F25"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Non-limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The losses described in paragraphs (1) through (3) do not limit any compensation that is otherwise available under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H86C07C48A416404AB58E6F0CE1E3A11A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Compensation</header>
 <paragraph id="H67F5052548E447CF8A3EB613946D960F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any claim for damages compensated under this section during a fiscal year shall be paid from unobligated funds appropriated to the Environmental Protection Agency for that fiscal year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF18F43A1BE3486BAB683B22B742AA33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rollover</header><text>To the extent that a claim exceeds the amount of unobligated funds available in that fiscal year, the remainder of the claim shall be paid from unobligated funds in the first subsequent fiscal year in which sufficient unobligated funds are available to satisfy such remainder.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H428B8ED1AD084695950EAF789BC1E542"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H657C312F915C41F69917E5470557859D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Injured person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>injured person</term> means a person who suffered injury resulting from the Gold King Mine spill.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB83788C918AD4B6B88A6D4469DF70199"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Injury</header><text>The term <term>injury</term> includes any injury for which compensation may be provided under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, that is caused by a negligent or wrongful act or omission of a Federal officer, employee, contractor, or subcontractor while acting within the scope of office, employment, or contract, under circumstances in which the Federal officer, employee, contractor, or subcontractor, if a private person, would be liable to the claimant in accordance with the law of the jurisdiction in which the act or omission occurred.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H55D33EEEE6BE40C494AD524D357DC066"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means a person who is eligible to bring a claim under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, and may include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC8005F3B094B43178C2505C8BD421262"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51BDBD61613444BAAAE987E7F8A2659D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an Indian tribe, tribal corporation, or other tribal organization;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H01CDE811BC9F4A5A9EDE3A9AF8C8D9D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a non-Federal entity, including a corporation, business, partnership, company, association, insurer, ditch company, water district, and water company;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC66A6BEB6C4B409CB254A6997125E497"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a State or political subdivision of a State, including a county, township, city, school district, and special district;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B6FE0D0E7C948BEA4DEDEA215D1DEAC"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Animas-La Plata Operation, Maintenance, and Replacement Association; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8097D903E7FD4BDF99F892406BA8FFA3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a legal representative of an individual or entity described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (E).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H54E4E87B80124B6B8A3BA4C90F72EAEC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Gold King Mine spill response program</header>
 <subsection id="HBCE4F3870C764B2BBE50881C31D3F019"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the requirements of subsection (b), the Administrator shall fund the implementation of the long-term monitoring program developed by the Long-Term Impact Review Team of the State of New Mexico for the water quality of the Animas and San Juan Rivers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H78D2B40D9784454DB4BC2729B75AC1D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to be funded by the Administrator under subsection (a), the long-term monitoring program shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9FC356A3A9A04E6EBDD080F7EB0330C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide full disclosure to the public of applicable water quality and sediment data;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A48AF08EE114123A95C6D976D737655"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enable clear and meaningful comparison between those data and all relevant water quality standards; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF222978AD12045A5A56795654C8BFF6B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>meet such other conditions as the Administrator may require to administer the program.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB658C80E2ED24B7F8F0898537C16248C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibition of rule making</header> <subsection id="H9DB63984CA2E4DED9BD6F877155FA213"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided under subsection (b), the Administrator may not finalize a rule or engage in a rule making (as such terms are defined in section 551 of title 5, United States Code) until all claims processed under section 3 have been paid in full, as applicable.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9DF97463A2864C568B03705135FCCF50"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prohibition under subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to—</text> <paragraph id="HEC31348C60284B7DB8BF4EEDE5AC8210"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such rules as may be required in order to implement this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H360137A43D424144967537DF15DBC6E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any rule that the Administrator determines necessary to address an imminent threat to public health or safety, or other emergency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H24A03E7E53554A4B929A323A96E9C8B1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H362CD7B7EF7A4A55811F5A5F46D5E668"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DE576DBA79F4508852F795537F4BB5C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gold King Mine spill</header><text>The term <term>Gold King Mine spill</term> means the discharge on August 5, 2015, of approximately 3,000,000 gallons of contaminated water from the Gold King Mine north of Silverton, Colorado, into Cement Creek that occurred while contractors of the Environmental Protection Agency were conducting an investigation of the Gold King Mine.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


