<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H65BCAF6283704B4BB57FD414B8A3EB31" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2264 IH: Make It In America Manufacturing Communities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2264</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170501">May 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve the competitiveness of United States manufacturing by designating and supporting
			 manufacturing communities.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB476B3BB15224D1AB60AEAACA017FE66" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE10235EFFF664E4B9A69C5B12A98D65B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Make It In America Manufacturing Communities Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD378F42D99AB44ADB01564553FCCEA94"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7AB338F5AE5343F897082D265CAEAD81"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Manufacturing community support program</header><text>The term <term>Manufacturing Community Support Program</term> means the program established under section 3(a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB96336861130440AB639B9423B3BD0EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Participating agency</header><text>The term <term>participating agency</term> means a Federal agency that elects to participate in the Manufacturing Community Support Program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E26457B713E4DDAB96925B4EB398EC8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Participating program</header><text>The term <term>participating program</term> means a program identified by a participating agency under section 3(c)(1)(C).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1ECC762E4FFE4EAA943EB5FEAED14303"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H345CCD20CDB74D8B9F2715B0811B1F60"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Program to designate and support manufacturing communities</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H295FD98F3A9A4439B1EC88E70DB87D1B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a program to improve the competitiveness of United States manufacturing—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD75D3135832E4E66966CCB61CD90FF4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by designating consortiums as manufacturing communities under subsection (b); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E530F84C01A4F7AACDDB19FA2103DB6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by supporting manufacturing communities, as so designated, under subsection (c).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5DCEF74F404D40448C16CAEC46868406"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation of manufacturing communities</header>
 <paragraph id="H8543D865D04140E5922B4A9C61E38913"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (7), for purposes of the Manufacturing Community Support Program, the Secretary shall designate eligible consortiums as manufacturing communities through a competitive process.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H70731C083570430DB367B83F4EF197D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible consortiums</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1300148EA9BF47D4938B10ADBE1BA280"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible consortium is a consortium that—</text> <clause id="HDA0B17905E6D41628A9385C34E22E80B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>represents a region defined by the consortium in accordance with subparagraph (B);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3C879313C5F4440588A77A996878FB38"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes at least one—</text> <subclause id="HC326DFE1FB2E49DC81EDEB685245D963"><enum>(I)</enum><text>institution of higher education;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3E944C502CA4432EABB2F05B266BAA7B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a private sector entity; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H3E6CA4F31FF444E79A6013C6095CC1D0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a government entity;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H74C3652ACACA477197985B0172FAB5D1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>may include one or more—</text> <subclause id="HF504409F460D4F9390ADF3908A65DF34"><enum>(I)</enum><text>private sector partners;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HECDCA18F706749E5A6DA3C7E6008F0FC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>institutions of higher education;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H4FA3ABA26C5E43EABBC54ADD915DC37C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>government entities;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4246109F1A314A578F7BED055B07C340"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>economic development and other community and labor groups;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HEF1D7428A8374A9CBB2D8A383DC7CF97"><enum>(V)</enum><text>financial institutions; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0E94C523D9B340C2BA401EED5A69CE8D"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>utilities;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H98E79C4451CB4979A63453A454E60661"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>has, as a lead applicant—</text>
 <subclause id="H2339A92D36C34B2A91E6BC8DCC002A27"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a district organization (as defined in section 300.3 of title 13, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulation);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC44A059E4D40462A8A378AFDF4B84182"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an Indian tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>)) or a consortium of Indian tribes;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H52A2E9AD8CF74A6D88971603625AA5EA"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a State or a political subdivision of a State, including a special purpose unit of a State or local government engaged in economic or infrastructure development activities, or a consortium of political subdivisions;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H97E5924BEB8F4397A62602266A2EAFF8"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>an institution of higher education or a consortium of institutions of higher education; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H0378403126A048F791B1AD074FEE3F82"><enum>(V)</enum><text>a public or private nonprofit organization or association that has an application that is supported by a State, a political subdivision of a State, or a native community.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DF5235CE8544B448B14BE7D8B15565B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Regions</header><text>Subject to approval by the Secretary, a consortium may define the region that it represents if the region—</text>
 <clause id="H14B48B657FD441CCACF0EF4B48073808"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is large enough to contain critical elements of the key technologies or supply chain prioritized by the consortium; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6A4EB3D1A0B241A888589A044F6384C7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is small enough to enable close collaboration among members of the consortium.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H156AE7EA4D5B488E81F913EE70D8CA75"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Each designation under paragraph (1) shall be for a period of two years.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H81906F6588BD459AA73B5D70AFE5C119"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Renewal</header>
 <subparagraph id="HBAFF4597E4CE498DAD7E68BB7D51CE94"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon receipt of an application submitted under subparagraph (B), the Secretary may renew a designation made under paragraph (1) for up to two additional two-year periods. Any designation as a manufacturing community or renewal of such designation that is in effect before the date of the enactment of this Act shall count toward the limit set forth in this subparagraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98D6C98FC2A44BBD901A57D11C2BA6C5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application for renewal</header><text>An eligible consortium seeking a renewal under subparagraph (A) shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C44219ADE8B416FB8846B6EB9979EA3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Modifications authorized</header><text>The Secretary may renew a designation under subparagraph (A) for an eligible consortium that—</text> <clause id="H9DC4D703E12C427CAEEFC46E7A76F7E1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has changed its composition, either by adding or removing members; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD0CA61DEA5314237A2DEE1D897442487"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as part of its application under subparagraph (B), submits a revision to the plan submitted under paragraph (5)(B)(iv) or the strategy submitted under paragraph (5)(B)(v).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H456002AF6B5D4555BD3514546242E966"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Evaluation for renewal</header><text>In determining whether to renew a designation of an eligible consortium under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall assess the eligible consortium based upon—</text>
 <clause id="HA393FFAD1D9D416DA258EF7B58B39121"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the performance of the consortium against the terms of the consortium’s most recent designation under paragraph (1) and any post-designation awards the consortium may have received;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H200C27A63B724E52876DD2C5391D95D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the progress the consortium has made with respect to project-specific metrics the consortium proposed in the consortium’s application for the most recent designation under paragraph (1), particularly with respect to those metrics that were designed to help communities track their own progress;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB78CFA7636E94CEB9DDDE45FF6DF1307"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whether any changes to the composition of the eligible consortium or revisions to the plan or strategy described in subparagraph (C)(ii) would improve the competitiveness of United States manufacturing; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE629DE3DFF26434E93F8F7EC61E22258"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>such other criteria as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H31C5297F3D064A95BC370D3C5E613648"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Application for designation</header> <subparagraph id="HFA60E84FBC784111A51F663BD5A669FC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible consortium seeking a designation under paragraph (1) shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBA87D79396D4CAF91FBE1F32BD2D342"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each application submitted to the Secretary under subparagraph (A) include—</text> <clause id="H64ED378547C04E3A87832ADE661A96E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the regional boundaries of the consortium;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7DEFB179C5E947749676C561CE9A0275"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of the manufacturing concentration of the consortium, including an assessment of how the manufacturing concentration of the consortium competitively ranks nationally according to measures relating to employment, sales, location quotients for an industry’s level of concentration, or such other measures as the Secretary considers appropriate;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9D586404B3B0491C84DC6B686D296552"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an integrated assessment of the local industrial ecosystem of the region of the consortium, which may include assessment of workforce and training, such as that involving women and underrepresented minorities, supplier network, research and innovation, infrastructure or site development, trade and international investment, operational improvements, and capital access components needed for manufacturing activities in such region;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8BA807418CAA46A7BBAE08C3DED92EAC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an evidence-based plan for developing components of such ecosystem (selected by the consortium)—</text> <subclause id="HAAACAA2C10824478A03D1F900DACAA88"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by making specific investments to address gaps in such ecosystem; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF97310862C2A4B5A90E3FF4C83753272"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by making the manufacturing of the region of the consortium uniquely competitive;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H310F80DE767940188D6A34957E1AA73E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a description of the investments the consortium proposes and the implementation strategy the consortium intends to use to address gaps in such ecosystem;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3CD1A42B278E4CA7A6387E06DA5617A2"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a description of the outcome-based metrics, benchmarks, and milestones that the consortium will track and the evaluation methods the consortium will use while designated as a manufacturing community to gauge performance of the strategy of the consortium to improve the manufacturing in the region of the consortium; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H05AEEA5B59BF42F48BC6A7E7E5919CA7"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>such other matters as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H004D40244D914993A400150DB33DA85D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Evaluation of applications</header><text>The Secretary shall evaluate each application received under paragraph (5) to determine—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD87E6251834C429D800AD9846545C938"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether the applicant demonstrates a significant level of regional cooperation in their proposal; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDD115AFD0D34D7BA578B596C7104C94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how the manufacturing concentration of the applicant competitively ranks nationally according to measures described in paragraph (5)(B)(ii).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5059E34D61D4C709EC050481E865C00"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Certain communities previously recognized</header><text>Each consortium that was designated as a manufacturing community by the Secretary in carrying out the Investing in Manufacturing Communities Partnership initiative of the Department of Commerce before the date of the enactment of this Act shall be deemed a manufacturing community designated under this subsection if such consortium is still designated as a manufacturing community by the Secretary as part of such initiative.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDB6D8A0E252944D68DB7AF2E84BDA72A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Support for designated manufacturing communities</header>
				<paragraph id="H693021AD70F84741AA2CEC57D9BC3FF9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Preferential consideration</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE3E6EAFA49DE4E20A561C1391B8F8B62"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (D), if a member of a consortium designated as a manufacturing community under subsection (b) seeks financial or technical assistance under a participating program of a participating agency, the head of such agency may give preferential consideration to such member with respect to the awarding of such financial or technical assistance if—</text>
 <clause id="H26279B5680014F6FB26B6C61C5D04088"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such head considers the award of the financial or technical assistance consistent with the economic development strategy of the consortium; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5DF42F1FE0CE4F59A1392FDBC029F1DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the member otherwise meets all applicable requirements for the financial or technical assistance.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67B27393892E487DBAB74F192200C2FD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Participating agencies</header><text>The Secretary shall invite other Federal agencies to become participating agencies of the Manufacturing Community Support Program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H817B0B75B67645808BB1E80EDCD28358"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Participating programs</header><text>The head of each participating agency shall identify all programs administered by such participating agency that are applicable to the Manufacturing Community Support Program.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF80ECD7444BE4D1BA7CA603203DC678A"><enum>(D)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Multiple members of the same consortium seeking the same financial or technical assistance</header>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99ACD70D00A9436EBB18502267997BFC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a participating agency receives applications for the same financial or technical assistance from more than one member of the same consortium designated as a manufacturing community under subsection (b), the head of such agency may determine how preference will be given under subparagraph (A), including by requiring the consortium to select which of the members should be given preference.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEAE89828DD0841BEB13323191154254A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>If the head of a participating agency determines that more than one member of a consortium should be given preference for financial or technical assistance under subparagraph (A), he or she may require such members to demonstrate coordination with each other in developing their applications for the financial or technical assistance.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DCF3925F9154B7A949EC8A7D807B44D"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of each participating agency shall submit a report to the Secretary that specifies how the head will give preferential consideration under subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C0D1699B8DB4E1897A9D684E9159F60"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary may make a Federal point of contact available to each consortium designated as a manufacturing community under subsection (b) to help the members of the consortium access Federal funds and technical assistance.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HFC2E17E80D044BBAA3D2149E4998D586"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Financial and technical assistance</header>
 <subparagraph id="H01732DCA268249F8A3F2185818F28FF7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under the Manufacturing Community Support Program, the head of a participating agency may award financial or technical assistance to a member of a consortium designated as a manufacturing community under subsection (b) as he or she considers appropriate for purposes of such program and consistent with the economic development strategy of the consortium.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29A6EE7C676C41BAA6825D32FA791172"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of funds</header>
 <clause id="HF235D8ED9056427F8EFA3B21D3E5DD93"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A recipient of financial or technical assistance under subparagraph (A) may use such financial or technical assistance to support an investment in an ecosystem that will improve the competitiveness of United States manufacturing.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDED68F5DBAED48BCB1AC516C3AF7461F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Investments supported</header><text>Investments supported under this subparagraph may include—</text> <subclause id="H305D73F32F554F1A849E8D88E5C9585F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>infrastructure;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0DE45771588B4F7091EE9651717D178C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>access to capital;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H893DDB5CAE4343B6AEF68D18BC1ACC03"><enum>(III)</enum><text>promotion of exports and foreign direct investment;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H322319E44EAD4875B4A6207C2F6211A8"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>equipment or facility upgrades;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HEC2C13AC89564A24B22067E32E4FEF07"><enum>(V)</enum><text>workforce training, retraining, or recruitment and retention, including that of women and underrepresented minorities;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H49991903D358476E986975AA07A0914A"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>energy or process efficiency;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HE158F603CE1A45A2AE37BE837937ACAB"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>business incubators;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H42452D7C6AA842BD82856066CFE1B659"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>site preparation;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HD2C6015F6DA3415FB1448A35D1B805DD"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>advanced research;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD360AE7269E547DF9D50D50E49D4A679"><enum>(X)</enum><text>supply chain development; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HE2026D725861438299B295DC08E91BEC"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>small business assistance.</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H40D9135B54BA4D11B54ED691C55D8D1A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coordination</header>
 <subparagraph id="H18DF46A2B8B64BCCB0270D62322435C3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Coordination by Secretary of Commerce</header><text>The Secretary shall coordinate with the heads of the participating agencies to identify programs under paragraph (1)(C).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C1B1AD4798E43859BAD11230C09421F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inter-agency coordination</header><text>The heads of the participating agencies shall coordinate with each other—</text> <clause id="H53D894C57CD545EBBB3EB1716CB8B6BB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to leverage complementary activities, including from non-Federal sources, such as philanthropies; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H972483B8B2AF4ECBB92619007627CB7D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to avoid duplication of efforts.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7962C4FC7BEB46E380A88C6AC543EDD9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Receipt of transferred funds</header><text>The Secretary may accept amounts transferred to the Secretary from the head of another participating agency to carry out this section.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


