<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE7107295F0C745659BF5D533E7510905" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2732 IH: North Korea Travel Control Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2732</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit travel-related transactions to, from, and within North Korea by persons subject to the
			 jurisdiction of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC3B0D87984074AFC89BBDAABD75DAB35" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA89D0AE350444E37B0538478BC0E64DF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>North Korea Travel Control Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H10F0D82F6FCB4F84905DDA0E8A9C7D03"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H85D716EA0C4E43A1A882EC144A5074CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In recent years, there has been an increase in tourist travel to North Korea by citizens of Western countries, including the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD41D267BCF543A0A9CD1644732B7AE8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In the last ten years, at least 17 United States citizens have been detained in North Korea, and at least four citizens remain imprisoned in North Korea as of May 2017. These Americans traveled to North Korea for a variety of reasons, including tourism travel, lured in part by its secrecy and decades of closure to the West.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB08DA0191C654BDFB908A25904B20DA1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Government of North Korea has repeatedly detained United States citizens to be used as bargaining chips in negotiations over a variety of issues, including North Korea’s illegal nuclear weapons program and ballistic missile development, and as a way to extract diplomatic concessions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H27CCF2D4324D4B68B91C691889F49E75"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The United States has undertaken great diplomatic efforts to secure the release of Americans detained in North Korea, including through visits by former United States Presidents and cabinet level officials.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5125405E26674046974D92745C6950CD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Department of State strongly discourages travel to North Korea, stating in a travel warning that United States citizens are at <quote>serious risk of arrest and long-term detention under North Korea’s system of law enforcement</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE316AD9838F04B3986D6EC4258EBF0FC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Travel to North Korea is a source of foreign capital for the most self-isolated nation in the world, helping to perpetuate an authoritarian regime which brutally represses dissent.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H93236B9ED266435BBA7AD9B37B45B46B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Regulations prohibiting travel-related transactions to, from, and within North Korea by persons
			 subject to the jurisdiction of the United States</header>
 <subsection id="H8DA7D1363F744DCF86EEFB2B6C59D9A3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall issue regulations prohibiting transactions related to travel to, from, or within North Korea by any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States unless authorized either by a general license issued by the Secretary of the Treasury or on a case-by-case basis by a specific license issued by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H554871EA81BF4359AC6D4E2D9FA6CEAC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on travel for tourist activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of the Treasury may not issue a general license or a specific license for travel-related transactions for travel to, from, or within North Korea by any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States if the primary purpose of such travel is to engage in tourist activities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB9129339E25E4E9DBF37DE2D91E330F8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The penalties provided for in section 206(b) of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705(b)</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations promulgated under this section to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of that Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H2F9F68CA2FE9415F94E93FA281847C83"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States</header><text>In this section, the term <term>person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States</term> has the meaning given such term in section 515.329 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9BD0E1DC28924485B4B72255F19FFD4A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall cease to be effective beginning on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


