<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H408C62118E0C4DCF82906206E8E711C1" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1252 RH: DHS Acquisition Authorities Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 27</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1252</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–47]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170228">February 28, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HHM00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>March 20, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 28, 2017</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide for certain acquisition authorities for the
			 Under Secretary of Management of the Department of Homeland Security, and
			 for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HB8253FBA7700460DA804B42FE181739E" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB1CBAD73F9A64F6EBE6149BCB96E452B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DHS Acquisition Authorities Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA5681B44ED5E45CC8CF2F90A3FBD23F2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Acquisition authorities for Under Secretary for Management of the Department of Homeland Security</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 701 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/341">6 U.S.C. 341</external-xref>) is amended by—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC06ECF43E75F4A83BFD0944688D817A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">redesignating subsections (d) and (e) as subsections (e) and (f); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H462728A2F2AA4BEFA36D7F56FF2182CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>inserting after subsection (c) the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71C9E737D88843F59E0D92CDAE2854FC" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H0EBD622B080C4A99AB95C9835C28AFF3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Acquisition and related responsibilities</header>
 <paragraph id="H968E593DD7EA417589D7A0D0D9AFD827"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 1702(b) of title 41, United States Code, the Under Secretary for Management is the Chief Acquisition Officer of the Department. As Chief Acquisition Officer, the Under Secretary shall have the authorities and perform the functions specified in section 1702(b) of such title, and perform all other functions and responsibilities delegated by the Secretary or described in this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3317314019D348D790092BC5D644A365"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Functions and responsibilities</header><text>In addition to the authorities and functions specified in section 1702(b) of title 41, United States Code, the functions and responsibilities of the Under Secretary for Management related to acquisition (as such term is defined in section 710) include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB1ACD811F5094578A933A0D5466FFB40"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Advising the Secretary regarding acquisition management activities, taking into account risks of failure to achieve cost, schedule, or performance parameters, to ensure that the Department achieves its mission through the adoption of widely accepted program management best practices (as such term is defined in section 710) and standards and, where appropriate, acquisition innovation best practices.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB165DC75AB2D434393498C00917993D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Leading the Department’s acquisition oversight body, the Acquisition Review Board, and exercising the acquisition decision authority (as such term is defined in section 710) to approve, pause, modify (including the rescission of approvals of program milestones), or cancel major acquisition programs (as such term is defined in section 710), unless the Under Secretary delegates such authority to a Component Acquisition Executive (as such term is defined in section 710) pursuant to paragraph (3).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBB0949768C84E5486A48AA0BE8E92F2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Establishing policies for acquisition that implement an approach that takes into account risks of failure to achieve cost, schedule, or performance parameters that all components of the Department shall comply with, including outlining relevant authorities for program managers to effectively manage acquisition programs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69134F1626014157B5778A90FB12ADC1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Ensuring that each major acquisition program has a Department-approved acquisition program baseline (as such term is defined in section 710), pursuant to the Department’s acquisition management policy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0BE4C19F20C4FDE8875136FC8085D68"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Ensuring that the heads of components and Component Acquisition Executives comply with Federal law, the Federal Acquisition Regulation, and Department acquisition management directives.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83B3C91FAF2B46809EF27A8B8ACB09FB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Ensuring that grants and financial assistance are provided only to individuals and organizations that are not suspended or debarred.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7428B222E6B4DB8BDED57CDC996224A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Distributing guidance throughout the Department to ensure that contractors involved in acquisitions, particularly contractors that access the Department’s information systems and technologies, adhere to relevant Department policies related to physical and information security as identified by the Under Secretary for Management.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C6ECB0C7F7A43A2879787FBAFAFACEF"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Overseeing the Component Acquisition Executive organizational structure to ensure Component Acquisition Executives have sufficient capabilities and comply with Department acquisition policies.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A01CB4D80414EA0B4EB51311431BDE2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Delegation of acquisition decision authority</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF6B385CA3C894260A31B6D3FB63B1110"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Level 3 acquisitions</header><text>The Under Secretary for Management may delegate acquisition decision authority in writing to the relevant Component Acquisition Executive for an acquisition program that has a life cycle cost estimate of less than $300,000,000.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDE1E5A7CC4E4B168A86BE89AEB499F5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Level 2 acquisitions</header><text>The Under Secretary for Management may delegate acquisition decision authority in writing to the relevant Component Acquisition Executive for a major acquisition program that has a life cycle cost estimate of at least $300,000,000 but not more than $1,000,000,000 if all of the following requirements are met:</text>
 <clause id="H4987A6F1F5DE43DBBB53FCFC374E01C3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The component concerned possesses working policies, processes, and procedures that are consistent with Department-level acquisition policy.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD40E077A6E6548648F700E6706C27135"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Component Acquisition Executive concerned has adequate, experienced, and dedicated professional employees with program management training, as applicable, commensurate with the size of the acquisition programs and related activities delegated to such Component Acquisition Executive by the Under Secretary for Management.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7706DC09320F4BBAA5E66A1450A62135"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Each major acquisition program concerned has written documentation showing that it has a Department-approved acquisition program baseline and it is meeting agreed-upon cost, schedule, and performance thresholds.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA383AE8F6A1443DE8E3A3ED5BC0B6D24"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relationship to Under Secretary for Science and Technology</header>
 <subparagraph id="HDA188D8F742D42F8B669F0554BA842E3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall diminish the authority granted to the Under Secretary for Science and Technology under this Act. The Under Secretary for Management and the Under Secretary for Science and Technology shall cooperate in matters related to the coordination of acquisitions across the Department so that investments of the Directorate of Science and Technology are able to support current and future requirements of the components of the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A7BD1596A1D49149959D268235D128A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Operational testing and evaluation</header><text>The Under Secretary for Science and Technology shall—</text> <clause id="HC5EADC99E9164400ADED22B58EE2B2AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensure, in coordination with relevant component heads, that major acquisition programs—</text>
 <subclause id="H6D00940413C2450A9DDC1555581EF861"><enum>(I)</enum><text>complete operational testing and evaluation of technologies and systems;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H79F5AC7221A94EF9B49A2D27E1D27299"><enum>(II)</enum><text>use independent verification and validation of operational test and evaluation implementation and results; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HAA5C32A195CE465EB25F1C0F83939885"><enum>(III)</enum><text>document whether such programs meet all performance requirements included in their acquisition program baselines;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H95955D4671A64BCE8E07A930407E1854"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure that such operational testing and evaluation includes all system components and incorporates operators into the testing to ensure that systems perform as intended in the appropriate operational setting; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H84C8DB52FE264141A453FB4CF4F43DC5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>determine if testing conducted by other Federal agencies and private entities is relevant and sufficient in determining whether systems perform as intended in the operational setting.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HF72240552BDA4C24A42CB643FFC21B26"><enum>3.</enum><header>Acquisition authorities for Chief Financial Officer of the Department of Homeland Security</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of section 702(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/342">6 U.S.C. 342(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
			<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F91B3F1F3CC49D3930DAB50FFD9D18A" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H424773496B09437A9C1FF70CBFA9ECBD"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Oversee the costs of acquisition programs and related activities to ensure that actual and planned costs are in accordance with budget estimates and are affordable, or can be adequately funded, over the life cycle of such programs and activities.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HB10E3774B0164CDEB7AEA7CF3B2964CC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Acquisition authorities for Chief Information Officer of the Department of Homeland Security</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 703 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/343">6 U.S.C. 343</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF92C4F07924545439F42FC98C810895C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (b) as subsection (c); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HABA85D8EFDA14DF8B08B4458066FF394"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6FAE13AA2DE746B680E84593C2B2FD19" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H9F4DB9754C8F422FB98A134EF6456D58"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Acquisition responsibilities</header><text>Notwithstanding section 11315 of title 40, United States Code, the acquisition responsibilities of the Chief Information Officer, in consultation with the Under Secretary for Management, shall include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HEE1DF87012EB4AD4A256F582FB15700F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Oversee the management of the Homeland Security Enterprise Architecture and ensure that, before each acquisition decision event (as such term is defined in section 710), approved information technology acquisitions comply with departmental information technology management processes, technical requirements, and the Homeland Security Enterprise Architecture, and in any case in which information technology acquisitions do not comply with the Department’s management directives, make recommendations to the Acquisition Review Board regarding such noncompliance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFBE38483720A4C4DAA1E8B1058958A83"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Be responsible for providing recommendations to the Acquisition Review Board regarding information technology programs, and be responsible for developing information technology acquisition strategic guidance.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HD7C263BEF1B448168AF63E5C58734FFC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Acquisition authorities for Program Accountability and Risk Management (PARM)</header>
 <subsection id="H5A1598634B1D458EA17197EBB1F4A8FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title VII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/341">6 U.S.C. 341</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA1523741BF94EBFA5693E708C2F125E" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
					<section id="HFD3A3E5F34A143138931F12D88DEAB21"><enum>710.</enum><header>Acquisition authorities for Program Accountability and Risk Management</header>
 <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8E8EBB6DF9E487298FD64CF174458B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of Office</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within the Management Directorate, there shall be a Program Accountability and Risk Management office to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H49310253DF264426A4BE50DC03F9200F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide consistent accountability, standardization, and transparency of major acquisition programs of the Department; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H48E73FC6E25F4668887D82944F09809D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>serve as the central oversight function for all Department acquisition programs.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H96464FEB154643899C9AE5C5DF24216C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities of Executive Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Program Accountability and Risk Management office shall be led by an Executive Director to oversee the requirement under subsection (a). The Executive Director shall report directly to the Under Secretary for Management, and shall carry out the following responsibilities:</text>
 <paragraph id="H371D2C8743C342D1B105B9D6274EB305"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Monitor regularly the performance of Department acquisition programs between acquisition decision events to identify problems with cost, performance, or schedule that components may need to address to prevent cost overruns, performance issues, or schedule delays.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0E819BFB06B4CE4B593EBD2D739A835"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assist the Under Secretary for Management in managing the Department’s acquisition programs and related activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56E27F4221B8465A89FBFA183B183010"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Conduct oversight of individual acquisition programs to implement Department acquisition program policy, procedures, and guidance with a priority on ensuring the data the office collects and maintains from Department components is accurate and reliable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFAD2A5B3F453469C807727D7A6351B0F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Serve as the focal point and coordinator for the acquisition life cycle review process and as the executive secretariat for the Acquisition Review Board.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF0000525E2144098F7323D3F65D5AF7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Advise the persons having acquisition decision authority in making acquisition decisions consistent with all applicable laws and in establishing clear lines of authority, accountability, and responsibility for acquisition decisionmaking within the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H282654C5E0E84F05ABC23CAFEB394A21"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Engage in the strategic planning and performance evaluation process required under section 306 of title 5, United States Code, and sections 1105(a)(28), 1115, 1116, and 9703 of title 31, United States Code, by supporting the Chief Procurement Officer in developing strategies and specific plans for hiring, training, and professional development in order to rectify any deficiency within the Department’s acquisition workforce.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1EFA1ABB2FCF4F32B9AAB791A10A6609"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Develop standardized certification standards in consultation with the Component Acquisition Executives for all acquisition program managers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H15D1205E05EB4E5E9E15D500380CEB2B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In the event that an acquisition program manager’s certification or actions need review for purposes of promotion or removal, provide input, in consultation with the relevant Component Acquisition Executive, into the relevant acquisition program manager’s performance evaluation, and report positive or negative experiences to the relevant certifying authority.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H044BDBE813F741B29DC3051BF47D8A4A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Provide technical support and assistance to Department acquisitions and acquisition personnel in conjunction with the Chief Procurement Officer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9EF5CB922A4F4580BD46ECA721FF1287"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prepare the Department’s Comprehensive Acquisition Status Report, as required by title I of division D of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref>), and make such report available to the congressional homeland security committees.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA009395081C747298F857AD57D068EE0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities of components</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each head of a component shall comply with Federal law, the Federal Acquisition Regulation, and Department acquisition management directives established by the Under Secretary for Management. For each major acquisition program, each head of a component shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0DCA6D1ECD174A74B4B104B4460C8169"><enum>(1)</enum><text>define baseline requirements and document changes to such requirements, as appropriate;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BA0D1332F33422499736D65A039D5F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish a complete life cycle cost estimate with supporting documentation, including an acquisition program baseline;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H298F66B7B7AA45D29C968AA85C9BEBD4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>verify each life cycle cost estimate against independent cost estimates, and reconcile any differences;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H947B47D046154DEFA4888067AA9A3E52"><enum>(4)</enum><text>complete a cost-benefit analysis with supporting documentation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC30433D9512B4D3897A4239C52B22440"><enum>(5)</enum><text>develop and maintain a schedule that is consistent with scheduling best practices as identified by the Comptroller General of the United States, including, in appropriate cases, an integrated master schedule; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H98D42F71FC0849388BFF64B456AABE5B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>ensure that all acquisition program information provided by the component is complete, accurate, timely, and valid.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H776D15DA3A9E456785EAB72F67197D74"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H63050C3944B24EE0BD186114E2926E4D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Acquisition</header><text>The term <quote>acquisition</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 131 of title 41, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC5A39A5F50743E2B236326C2D6C2655"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Acquisition decision authority</header><text>The term <quote>acquisition decision authority</quote> means the authority, held by the Secretary acting through the Deputy Secretary or Under Secretary for Management to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5E11FFE68D5743B1B65AA7A88F317C2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure compliance with Federal law, the Federal Acquisition Regulation, and Department acquisition management directives;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H482DC667ADAA4F32AADBF253C8466C43"><enum>(B)</enum><text>review (including approving, pausing, modifying, or canceling) an acquisition program through the life cycle of such program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA944A9C06D3C49E3940CF67632792D07"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that acquisition program managers have the resources necessary to successfully execute an approved acquisition program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0559074F7F94453B0D8656EB6970047"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensure good acquisition program management of cost, schedule, risk, and system performance of the acquisition program at issue, including assessing acquisition program baseline breaches and directing any corrective action for such breaches; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H626A312CEF714175B4118B9AFECEB683"><enum>(E)</enum><text>ensure that acquisition program managers, on an ongoing basis, monitor cost, schedule, and performance against established baselines and use tools to assess risks to an acquisition program at all phases of the life cycle of such program to avoid and mitigate acquisition program baseline breaches.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC9C42EAF17A4C058E831F0C63EF9666"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Acquisition decision event</header><text>The term <quote>acquisition decision event</quote>, with respect to an acquisition program, means a predetermined point within each of the acquisition phases at which the acquisition decision authority determines whether such acquisition program shall proceed to the next acquisition phase.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A60AAF52B72427DA8EE70C2C83A4FCE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Acquisition program</header><text>The term <quote>acquisition program</quote> means the process by which the Department acquires, with any appropriated amounts, by contract for purchase or lease, property or services (including construction) that support the missions and goals of the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2367718DEA2F44988206BA3567046EF3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Acquisition program baseline</header><text>The term <quote>acquisition program baseline</quote>, with respect to an acquisition program, means a summary of the cost, schedule, and performance parameters, expressed in standard, measurable, quantitative terms, which must be met in order to accomplish the goals of such program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H839E0D5AFD4C46AB902F76FDA4C06B74"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>The term <quote>best practices</quote>, with respect to acquisition, means a knowledge-based approach to capability development that includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H042DBBFDE0E94CDD95D85FE2C903347F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifying and validating needs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F185B02CB574762B398D2BB9CC4537D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assessing alternatives to select the most appropriate solution;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0475075D831D46228C90B77E00C1AA94"><enum>(C)</enum><text>clearly establishing well-defined requirements;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C5A5F38D7114F7DBD3B01B6FB150275"><enum>(D)</enum><text>developing realistic cost assessments and schedules;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE5A14D3A71B43C9911F73EE3BD1DE45"><enum>(E)</enum><text>securing stable funding that matches resources to requirements;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53CB4261AC4646B2B2FC81218661C40C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>demonstrating technology, design, and manufacturing maturity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEB47AC57E7F4F19856942F97818B9D8"><enum>(G)</enum><text>using milestones and exit criteria or specific accomplishments that demonstrate progress;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9033CE90CF245AE8665C03B381C13CD"><enum>(H)</enum><text>adopting and executing standardized processes with known success across programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF1A31D0C91A4CBB86599D165B84F418"><enum>(I)</enum><text>establishing an adequate workforce that is qualified and sufficient to perform necessary functions; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H556AD216843A48EBA8418619DE33708B"><enum>(J)</enum><text>integrating the capabilities described in subparagraphs (A) through (I) into the Department’s mission and business operations.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H98F583BDB9D24ADB936B8A3E1B2420DF"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Breach</header><text>The term <quote>breach</quote>, with respect to a major acquisition program, means a failure to meet any cost, schedule, or performance threshold specified in the most recently approved acquisition program baseline.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE22D30024B504D329740482E899F8D76"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Congressional homeland security committees</header><text>The term <quote>congressional homeland security committees</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H0D26246B14C24FB0AF0B8E00611D1136"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A65F6239BB746AFBA7C3B9B34D46F32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and of the Senate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BA99088C9DD408EB8DA017966525B3C"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Component Acquisition Executive</header><text>The term <quote>Component Acquisition Executive</quote> means the senior acquisition official within a component who is designated in writing by the Under Secretary for Management, in consultation with the component head, with authority and responsibility for leading a process and staff to provide acquisition and program management oversight, policy, and guidance to ensure that statutory, regulatory, and higher level policy requirements are fulfilled, including compliance with Federal law, the Federal Acquisition Regulation, and Department acquisition management directives established by the Under Secretary for Management.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC672D67C8B984891BAB63591F3FFF21C"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Major acquisition program</header><text>The term <quote>major acquisition program</quote> means a Department acquisition program that is estimated by the Secretary to require an eventual total expenditure of at least $300,000,000 (based on fiscal year 2017 constant dollars) over its life cycle cost.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7ED517F1758F4E828C9728AF1FAB8AF6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 709 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEFE6B618B742464DB51781FD61D25C8B" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
					<toc changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" regeneration="no-regeneration" reported-display-style="italic">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 710. Acquisition authorities for Program Accountability and Risk Management.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>March 20, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


