<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA2BE47315AE04881B99B6622BA7749D6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3492 IH: To amend title 38, United States Code, to expand educational assistance to veterans who pursue certain apprenticeship programs, to establish a pilot program for veterans to pursue certification programs in computer numerically controlled machining, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3492</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170727">July 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to expand educational assistance to veterans who pursue
			 certain apprenticeship programs, to establish a pilot program for veterans
			 to pursue certification programs in computer numerically controlled
			 machining, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9FA49A6E195E4D48A230951F9D42D395" style="OLC">
 <section commented="no" id="HE9BAC186E9344EFC9D12448B9803E77F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HB6DE4057A1474975A44FD6198CFE9EB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Apprenticeships can help veterans bridge the gap between service in the Armed Forces and civilian employment by—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H8AA9EF41FF2347ABB54CE754CE65A462"><enum>(A)</enum><text>receiving on-the-job training under the direct supervision of a professional and classroom instruction;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDD49B288F39247CA89ABFD7EEDD415B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>implementing skills the veterans acquired while in the Armed Forces;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1766AD8439D148EDA4FB7DC60BE8B061"><enum>(C)</enum><text>providing practical work experience to the veterans; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HECC9744043B048418577BC1C84011A6F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>forming professional connections to fellow members of skilled occupations.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0E68B5621829453A9AB8AEE1D02A6FD1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor, in fiscal year 2016—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H871086D28B4E4CED933B382AC010D261"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more than 21,000 apprenticeship programs across the United States are registered with the Administration;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H387E2001CF2145E19ED2A4D0CF525DFE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">approximately 1,700 new apprenticeship programs were established in the United States;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H413305B9AEC64713804A555FB7B26625"><enum>(C)</enum><text>more than 206,000 individuals across the United States entered an apprenticeship program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEE0F62EF4B234D8DB8EEC0542BF23A28"><enum>(D)</enum><text>more than 505,000 apprentices sought to acquire skills to earn the wages necessary for financial security; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4AB13F7809CE4370B8576A5E3888A71C"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">approximately 49,000 individuals graduated from apprenticeship programs.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H4F63DEFFDD6645F2B280E7C42AB30C3F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Educational assistance for veterans who pursue certain apprenticeship programs</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3313(g)(3) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H598B58D2C6A8454C823A45860CA42639" style="USC">
 <subparagraph id="H382DC67B4F4D4D7EBD7C9708F3810BB5"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual pursuing a program of apprenticeship (that is registered with the Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor) on more than a half-time but less than full-time basis, an annual stipend for tuition and fees not to exceed the lesser of—</text>
 <clause id="H1F86889FA57342E9B481D3C66195791C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the actual net cost for tuition and fees for the program of apprenticeship after the application of any waiver of, or reduction in, tuition and fees; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF6960AFD84844A0AA74480F0995EBEF8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>25 percent of the amount calculated under subsection (c)(1)(A)(ii).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA1A7053CE004C3D8ECE791B166B8FFC"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual pursuing a program of apprenticeship (that is registered with the Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor and for which the individual provides proof of current registration to the Secretary) that is not sponsored by the employer of the individual, an annual stipend for tuition and fees not to exceed the lesser of—</text>
 <clause id="HC5C39379F3454AF29D044DBCDEF602BD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the actual net cost for tuition and fees for the program of apprenticeship after the application of any waiver of, or reduction in, tuition and fees; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3231B1E54B2247A9B8C4219B2903DB77"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>25 percent of the amount calculated under subsection (c)(1)(A)(ii).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section id="HC048311164DE4020B95909CB0E5CC73F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that apprenticeship programs that are not sponsored by employers of participants in such programs should supply professional development resources and interview training to the participants.</text>
		</section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC5B04EDE9A5F4A3EA1D87ACDF0B76014"><enum>4.</enum><header>Pilot program for veterans who pursue computer numerically controlled machining certifications</header>
 <subsection id="H6FAF6D8D7C2B4410993F29ABA1EA2C9B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a pilot program under which the Secretary shall provide eligible veterans with the opportunity to enroll in certification programs in computer numerically controlled machining.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H69CC8C2542B74E8CAAC6AA2D23ED163D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>For purposes of the pilot program under this section, an eligible veteran is a veteran who is entitled to educational assistance under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H3571D115342E4B77BDAF7386E388D4EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contracts</header>
 <paragraph id="HA85874F207A741959D6888C38C7BF2B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of carrying out subsection (a), by not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall seek to enter into contracts with multiple qualified providers of certification programs in computer numerically controlled machining for the provision of such programs to eligible veterans under the pilot program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB82577711F4047A2A23F783B2C89CB30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment of contractors</header><text>A contract under this subsection shall provide that the Secretary shall pay to a provider—</text> <subparagraph id="HE4E23628EA5746D58F5FD0A57F41FAA9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>25 percent of the cost of providing the certification program upon the enrollment of an eligible veteran in the program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E1730CF956D4F7E902578F0453E514E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>25 percent of such cost upon the completion of the program by the veteran; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18A98B6755524A639DB9AD505784D2C3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>50 percent of such cost upon the employment of the veteran following completion of the program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCCA1C41800E4A5CB967FFFB1F5E2296"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified providers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the pilot program, a provider of a certification program in computer numerically controlled machining is qualified if the provider has been operational for at least two years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8CFBF658FAA40ADB93070593D0432E9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tuition reimbursement</header><text>In entering into contracts to carry out the pilot program, the Secretary shall give preference to a qualified provider that offers tuition reimbursement for any student who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H33024D3D5BDB48BDB646C132763CA618"><enum>(A)</enum><text>completes a certification program offered by the provider; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91DAB39B9A5448DAAB5ED27FAF47E4C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not find full-time meaningful employment within the 180-day period beginning on the date the student completes the program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HA857BEB0EEB044C891EC58BCA159395E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Housing stipend</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall pay to each eligible veteran who is enrolled in a certification program in computer numerically controlled machining under the pilot program on a full-time basis a monthly housing stipend equal to the product of—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HD2E995A188EB4FFBBA2D3225479B2467"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H825D927D40C74DA6A9A1D225AB3B8BED"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a veteran pursuing resident training, the monthly amount of the basic allowance for housing payable under section 403 of title 37, United States Code, for a member with dependents in pay grade E–5 who resides in the military housing area that encompasses all or the majority of the ZIP code area in which the campus at which the veteran attends training or classes is located; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBA0F79C63D014993827E2CA780F7F1F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a veteran pursuing a certification program through distance learning, a monthly amount equal to 50 percent of the amount payable under subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H70CCB0A16BA14072A929FF49013C91FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the lesser of—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H319F5FFB5E76475AB9C26C7E0622C0DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1.0; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H98DE9744AE324D839AAEB439A7E3DCDC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of course hours carried by the individual in pursuit of the certification program involved, divided by the minimum number of course hours required for full-time pursuit of such certification program, rounded to the nearest tenth.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75D96A3EFFE64D65848F2DA2086AABB0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Certification program in computer numerically controlled machining defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>certification program in computer numerically controlled machining</term> means a training program that—</text> <paragraph id="H3986BDDD9B3E4AC1A2B1EB8018D793E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is offered by an entity—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HBD5D5138ABDB4AFA931A5EF11B772FB0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>other than an institution of higher learning; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3451D3577B2E4EDC844DF2F85044D521"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is a professional organization;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H47FA3F15F33B4F3490AC81BC45A026DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not lead to a degree; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2810A50540CC456791388A65D0414E4C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">leads to a National Institute for Metalworking Skills credential or certification in computer numerically controlled machining.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H188E18E0734448FBBF6AFECFA9065A4A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <paragraph id="HCAEC35D824A24C6394AF8982FC9D1208"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the pilot program under this section.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HB7BA499172F041AC8C726624C62F71E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comptroller General</header>
 <subparagraph id="HACE7348408234A78B685899DA929D274"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text>Not later than three years after the date on which the Secretary first enters into a contract under this section, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of the interim assessment of the Comptroller General. Such report shall include the recommendations of the Comptroller General for improving the pilot program and an assessment of each of the following:</text>
 <clause id="H7B8D24128A1E48C2BEE64E45140DE07B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The manufacturing and training experience of the directors and instructors of the providers of certification programs in computer numerically controlled machining under the pilot program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDAA96526CE544453B9974F46362B3A9E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the providers followed training curricula commonly used in the industry (including curricula from the National Institute for Metalworking Skills) for the certification programs.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H956348CFE3A142C2A4E012EA8AE8D3F4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the providers use open source curricula for the certification programs.</text> </clause><clause id="H80FBA5D7F0454B8B96AC5A1D51114C8D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The admittance rate into the pilot program.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5821A428D9224661BD588216DB576214"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The job placement rate for veterans who completed a certification program under the pilot program.</text> </clause><clause id="H633957C4ED0B428BA382B5FD397F2924"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The average salary of veterans who completed a certification program under the pilot program and were subsequently employed.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC885B2A960A84913894E0EA68B968EAB"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The average age of veterans who participated in the pilot program.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BD58006E31D476693E3EC251703FE99"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than five years after the date on which the Secretary first enters into a contract under this section, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a final report on the pilot program. Such report shall include the recommendation of the Comptroller General with respect to whether the program should be extended and an assessment of each of the following:</text>
 <clause id="H54E91ACEF62A447FB16C9923D042C02C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Each item described in clauses (i) through (vii) of subparagraph (A).</text> </clause><clause id="H62F79F208B744D5C9F485FAC6612F2DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The percentage of veterans who completed a certification program under the pilot program who were subsequently employed for a period of six months or longer.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA6505FD438D94697AAD09C21B38F4BF8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs $5,000,000 for each fiscal year during which the Secretary carries out a pilot program under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2AF67E66A03041C8BE218A6A6E50F9BC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The authority to carry out a pilot program under this section shall terminate on the date that is five years after the date on which the Secretary first enters into a contract under this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H4756291F6C33417596BE17C210FE3B19"><enum>5.</enum><header>Comptroller General review of the career technical training track of the Transition Assistance
 Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review of the career technical training track of the Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs (specifically with regard to the effectiveness of educating participants about apprenticeship opportunities) and submit to Congress a report on the results of the review and any recommendations of the Comptroller General for improving the program.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


