<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB1CC3C3B44A24F7BB8A9B3F683A0B16F" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1491 : Santa Ynez Band of Chumash Indians Land Affirmation Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1491</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20171129">November 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIA00">Committee on Indian Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To reaffirm the action of the Secretary of the Interior to take land into trust for the benefit of
			 the Santa Ynez Band of Chumash Mission Indians, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H6324860F65F24D84BBBBABDAC2167791" style="OLC">
 <section id="H18D25CC5AB0A4A8E871355EA6D3485C9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Santa Ynez Band of Chumash Indians Land Affirmation Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H177A13FEBD894D70B45734A3B6139270"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA91BCBED68A94A52BE4A0C8C8DE79FEA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On October 13, 2017, the General Council of the Santa Ynez Band of Chumash Indians voted to approve the Memorandum of Agreement between the County of Santa Barbara and the Santa Ynez Band of Chumash Indians regarding the approximately 1,427.28 acres of land, commonly known as Camp 4, and authorized the Tribal Chairman to sign the Memorandum of Agreement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE40C04CBA1B741818DDFED59D70CD1E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On October 31, 2017, the Board of Supervisors for the County of Santa Barbara approved the Memorandum of Agreement on Camp 4 and authorized the Chair to sign the Memorandum of Agreement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC0B57A3304B431E971E44AADAD9098A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Interior approved the Memorandum of Agreement pursuant to section 2103 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/81">25 U.S.C. 81</external-xref>).</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H50DAEF12DBCB44568419B3EDEBD09750"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reaffirmation of status and actions</header>
 <subsection id="HF4F8A33D024D45F4BC0A63448B642A9F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Ratification of trust status</header><text>The action taken by the Secretary on January 20, 2017, to place approximately 1,427.28 acres of land located in Santa Barbara County, California, into trust for the benefit of the Santa Ynez Band of Chumash Indians is hereby ratified and confirmed as if that action had been taken under a Federal law specifically authorizing or directing that action.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC546D795E3094F0594D1FEF23FFC5DF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ratification of actions of the Secretary</header><text>The actions taken by the Secretary to assume jurisdiction over the appeals relating to the fee-to-trust acquisition of approximately 1,427.28 acres in Santa Barbara County, California, on January 30, 2015, is hereby ratified and confirmed as if that action had been taken under a Federal law specifically authorizing or directing that action.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE6EF4AE203B346B6B42CA6E55532B0DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ratification of actions of the Secretary</header><text>The actions taken by the Secretary to dismiss the appeals relating to the fee-to-trust acquisition of approximately 1,427.28 acres in Santa Barbara County, California, on January 19, 2017, is hereby ratified and confirmed as if that action had been taken under a Federal law specifically authorizing or directing that action.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HCC866FA85BE74AEE85E241B0202D01D5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header>
 <paragraph id="H52E843CC7A714A31A695763E89F78336"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The land placed into trust for the benefit of the Santa Ynez Band of Chumash Indians by the Secretary of the Interior on January 20, 2017, shall be a part of the Santa Ynez Indian Reservation and administered in accordance with the laws and regulations generally applicable to the land held in trust by the United States for an Indian tribe.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H015FF1FEB9F2410DBFE1B04D8BBBFC59"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>For purposes of certain California State laws (including the California Land Conservation Act of 1965, Government Code Section 51200, et seq.), placing the land described in subsection (b) into trust shall remove any restrictions on the property pursuant to California Government Code Section 51295 or any other provision of such Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H705D052BC95D48F583E43EE342EDD061"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Legal description of lands transferred</header><text>The lands to be transferred pursuant to this Act are described as follows:</text><list level="paragraph"><list-item>Legal Land Description/Site Location:Real property in the unincorporated area of the County of Santa Barbara, State of California, described as follows: PARCEL 1: (APN: 141-121-51 AND PORTION OF APN 141-140-10)LOTS 9 THROUGH 18, INCLUSIVE, OF TRACT 18, IN THE COUNTY OF SANTA BARBARA, STATE OF CALIFORNIA, AS SHOWN ON THE MAP SHOWING THE SUBDIVISIONS OF THE CANADA DE LOS PINOS OR COLLEGE RANCHO, FILED IN RACK 3, AS MAP 4 IN THE OFFICE OF THE COUNTY RECORDER OF SAID COUNTY. THIS LEGAL IS MADE PURSUANT TO THAT CERTAIN CERTIFICATE OF COMPLIANCE RECORDED DECEMBER 5, 2001 AS INSTRUMENT NO. 01-105580 OF OFFICIAL RECORDS. PARCEL 2: (PORTION OF APN: 141-140-10)LOTS 1 THROUGH 12, INCLUSIVE, OF TRACT 24, IN THE COUNTY OF SANTA BARBARA, STATE OF CALIFORNIA, AS SHOWN ON THE MAP SHOWING THE SUBDIVISIONS OF THE CANADA DE LOS PINOS OR COLLEGE RANCHO, FILED IN RACK 3, AS MAP 4 IN THE OFFICE OF THE COUNTY RECORDER OF SAID COUNTY.THIS LEGAL IS MADE PURSUANT TO THAT CERTAIN CERTIFICATE OF COMPLIANCE RECORDED DECEMBER 5, 2001 AS INSTRUMENT NO. 01-105581 OF OFFICIAL RECORDS. PARCEL 3: (PORTIONS OF APNS: 141-230-23 AND 141-140-10)LOTS 19 AND 20 OF TRACT 18 AND THAT PORTION OF LOTS 1, 2, 7, 8, 9, 10, AND 15 THROUGH 20, INCLUSIVE, OF TRACT 16, IN THE COUNTY OF SANTA BARBARA, STATE OF CALIFORNIA, AS SHOWN ON THE MAP SHOWING THE SUBDIVISIONS OF THE CANADA DE LOS PINOS OR COLLEGE RANCHO, FILED IN RACK 3, AS MAP 4 IN THE OFFICE OF THE COUNTY RECORDER OF SAID COUNTY, THAT LIES NORTHEASTERLY OF THE NORTHEASTERLY LINE OF THE LAND GRANTED TO THE STATE OF CALIFORNIA BY AN EXECUTOR’S DEED RECORDED APRIL 2, 1968 IN BOOK 2227, PAGE 136 OF OFFICIAL RECORDS OF SAID COUNTY.THIS LEGAL IS MADE PURSUANT TO THAT CERTAIN CERTIFICATE OF COMPLIANCE RECORDED DECEMBER 5, 2001 AS INSTRUMENT NO. 01-105582 OF OFFICIAL RECORDS. PARCEL 4: (APN: 141-240-02 AND PORTION OF APN: 141-140-10)LOTS 1 THROUGH 12, INCLUSIVE, OF TRACT 25, IN THE COUNTY OF SANTA BARBARA, STATE OF CALIFORNIA, AS SHOWN ON THE MAP SHOWING THE SUBDIVISIONS OF THE CANADA DE LOS PINOS OR COLLEGE RANCHO, FILED IN RACK 3, AS MAP 4 IN THE OFFICE OF THE COUNTY RECORDER OF SAID COUNTY.THIS LEGAL IS MADE PURSUANT TO THAT CERTAIN CERTIFICATE OF COMPLIANCE RECORDED DECEMBER 5, 2001 AS INSTRUMENT NO. 01-105583 OF OFFICIAL RECORDS. PARCEL 5: (PORTION OF APN: 141-230-23)THAT PORTION OF LOTS 3 AND 6 OF TRACT 16, IN THE COUNTY OF SANTA BARBARA, STATE OF CALIFORNIA, AS SHOWN ON THE MAP SHOWING THE SUBDIVISIONS OF THE CANADA DE LOS PINOS OR COLLEGE RANCHO, FILED IN RACK 3, AS MAP 4 IN THE OFFICE OF THE COUNTY RECORDER OF SAID COUNTY, THAT LIES NORTHEASTERLY OF THE NORTHEASTERLY LINE OF THE LAND GRANTED TO THE STATE OF CALIFORNIA BY AN EXECUTOR’S DEED RECORDED APRIL 2, 1968 IN BOOK 2227, PAGE 136 OF OFFICIAL RECORDS OF SAID COUNTY.THIS LEGAL IS MADE PURSUANT TO THAT CERTAIN CERTIFICATE OF COMPLIANCE RECORDED DECEMBER 5, 2001 AS INSTRUMENT NO. 01-105584 OF OFFICIAL RECORDS.</list-item></list> </subsection><subsection id="HAED30710CB9A4A5EA0BFF8729CD31AB0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2E409A701B234307B933DAE513B10B0B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enlarge, impair, or otherwise affect any right or claim of the Tribe to any land or interest in land that is in existence before the date of the enactment of this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H812FBC82EF8B4011A68D414374D78CFF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affect any water right of the Tribe in existence before the date of the enactment of this Act; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE67FBEC4306406281F3D7659193448E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>terminate or limit any access in any way to any right-of-way or right-of-use issued, granted, or permitted before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2CC1054844FB465EA73FA4B747314017"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Restricted use of transferred lands</header><text>The Tribe may not conduct, on the land described in subsection (b) taken into trust for the Tribe pursuant to this Act, gaming activities—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4A50B524F54F4A2997F2B4E6E28EE121"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as a matter of claimed inherent authority; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9597D7BF684A4F10A3BC922922B08066"><enum>(2)</enum><text>under any Federal law, including the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2701">25 U.S.C. 2701</external-xref> et seq.) and regulations promulgated by the Secretary or the National Indian Gaming Commission under that Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9E05F1FB06B94E3FBD82A588114338B7"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For the purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H0976403A0B174EC6A7C906E1D703D3F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H747C8496561F4A5BA23BDF09B723A13B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tribe</header><text>The term <quote>Tribe</quote> means the Santa Ynez Band of Chumash Mission Indians.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20171128">Passed the House of Representatives November 28, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

