<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC111F06038A24804BCCFF0AC2E5BFD5D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3987 IH: Protecting Americans from Gun Violence Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3987</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171005">October 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reduce gun violence, fund gun violence research and victim assistance, and enhance the tracking
			 of lost and stolen firearms, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF806120D7B044DA9A80868854D3CD106" style="OLC">
 <section id="H66ADC56104FE4B67A9A102993EC4DFEB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Americans from Gun Violence Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0101A54D3FA0427885E692FCA600E4F3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Collection of fee for use of the national instant criminal background check system in transferring a firearm</header> <subsection id="HD5FFF26747F94583B9C36A3B7F5D7994"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 923 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB6EFB585F5394E6F8ACCDC14580863CB" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HC5E570AE230C4577A2F993C8D9890B6E"><enum>(m)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7F6CA13571D047C1A3D1BD64DE4A610F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>When, pursuant to section 922(t) of this title, a licensee under this chapter is first required to contact the national instant criminal background check system established under section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act about a person with respect to a transaction involving one or more firearms, but before contacting the system, the licensee shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H13896D1628E643F8B0C18FAC59BE81D5" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>charge and collect from the person a fee in an amount equal to $1, regardless of the number of firearms involved in the transaction;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E6E225C12E64CD78634B51A5DF49754" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide the person with a timestamped receipt acknowledging receipt of the fee from the person; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FFFAA8B3A0E4BE1995D4B3B5A58D484" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>maintain a written or electronic record of the transaction and the timestamped receipt for 3 years.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CD3C795E5BA429B8B88A1CA7E7D8CFC" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the end of the calendar quarter in which a licensee collects a fee under paragraph (1), the licensee shall transmit the amount of the fee to the Attorney General, who shall remit the amount to the Secretary of the Treasury.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6990B987D5A7468C9C3FE8F99DF3418B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Section 924 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE8BCC075462C48AAA935C10998BEF8C4" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H72D97E56FDE14F86AB5FBAD77656A6A1"><enum>(q)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HED978B54EF8A4C5BBC60ABB8F280D07C"><enum>(1)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF8F52665BBF2409299C4F33D8226D56D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>With respect to each violation of section 923(m) by a licensed manufacturer, licensed importer, or licensed dealer, the Attorney General shall, after notice and opportunity for hearing, impose a civil penalty of $2,500 on the licensee.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBF25D2E45AA4624A843B667D7323435" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An action of the Attorney General under this paragraph may be reviewed only as provided under section 923(f).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H93C5CFBEF7EB4491B3326F2A3F26CF31" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The imposition of a civil penalty under paragraph (1) shall not preclude any administrative remedy that is otherwise available to the Attorney General.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0DCB06CE978846009D2EA87D8585CAC6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HAB8FD1D79DAF4AEB9C648810733293C9"><enum>3.</enum><header>CDC research on gun violence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 391 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280b">42 U.S.C. 280b</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE9EA83DBC45B488D83D052F157595877" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H1CC95051CAC1418085C6ABAEA0753A0E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Gun violence research</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall conduct or support research described in such subsection relating to gun violence.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HBEE663DB84E2415595D8C42841BE55AA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Dedication of revenues</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Of the amounts received by the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to the amendment made by section 2(a) for fiscal year 2018 or any succeeding fiscal year:</text>
 <paragraph id="H549D3C4C4714425CA0C890D7CEB14D00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The first $10,000,000 shall be available, without further appropriation, to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to carry out section 391(c) of the Public Health Service Act, as added by section 3.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD20EE04914E0451DB546F2B6D955F885"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The next $5,000,000 shall be available, without further appropriation, to the Attorney General, for the operation and maintenance of the national instant criminal background check system established under section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H91864645B9F94A279CE46BDE51F466BF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The remainder shall be available, without further appropriation, to the Attorney General for such activities of the Office for Victim Assistance of the Federal Bureau of Investigation as the Attorney General deems appropriate.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HF0BF26496B5A4EE089A99F08A95C3FAE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reporting of lost or stolen firearms to local law enforcement authorities</header>
 <subsection id="HEB2AE5BD932242B7A924596129D18820"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 922 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC4AE14FC0A94662B4D26C4D4F61E9B3" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HC3BD0E83C3BB455B82D82D49CC75C8D8"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 48 hours after a person who owns a firearm that has been shipped or transported in, or has been possessed in or affecting, interstate or foreign commerce, discovers or should have discovered the theft or loss of the firearm, the person shall report the theft or loss to local law enforcement authorities. To the best of the person’s ability, the person shall provide the following information, if known:</text>
 <paragraph id="HFA71D53608454C72B6440631F81C5DC4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the firearm, including the make, model, manufacturer, caliber, and serial number of the firearm, and any other distinguishing number or identification mark on the firearm.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF6693F0415334476AD16CAD4E4E14101"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Whether the firearm is being reported lost or stolen.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2EBCE54EFE14A858366905DFB76768E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The date of the loss or theft.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H65804805A0214DAB8F43B64F3A445A0C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The person’s name and address.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE6A02234973B428688B5FA29BA5A6B5C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The location from which the firearm was lost or stolen.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC7D52918112C4F96A5BC5EDF1A0FBA0C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 924 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28F9020D21E54488B5E1A10ADE646FE3" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HE1A80EAB273945E99FFFF6D50C868A44"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Penalties for failure To report loss or theft of firearm</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever violates section 922(aa) shall be fined $10,000, imprisoned not more than 1 year, or both, with respect to each firearm involved in the violation.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HF117D24EA8F0434CAF1DCB2483FF472F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirement that local law enforcement authorities report lost or stolen firearms to the national
 crime information center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 7 days after a local law enforcement authority receives a report that a firearm is lost or stolen, the authority shall transmit the report to the National Crime Information Center maintained by the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


