<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H70D2E55A0E73436EADD3A0AF35F7370B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3547 IH: Jerusalem’s Enhanced and Secure Accommodations Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3547</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000184">Mrs. Noem</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000461">Mr. Flores</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of State to establish a permanent residence in Jerusalem, Israel, for
			 the United States Ambassador to Israel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HDE6AEF31B8704480858CB84D88750B94" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA1EF0489EE144DDC9FCAF2334E0064AA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Jerusalem’s Enhanced and Secure Accommodations Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H11ABCD3D50164AAB8EBF80FB9C9801D9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HCC2B7A0AAB0C4F6D8D4499FA1265F80B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States was among the first countries to recognize Israel as an independent nation on May 14, 1948, and over the decades, Israel has remained one of America’s strong allies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H479C78A440E148E2BFEAC004564553C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The first United States Ambassador to Israel was James Grover McDonald in March 1949.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HED827A57560448CC93A292B50815E3EB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States Embassy in Tel Aviv, Israel, opened in 1966 to maintain and promote diplomatic relations between the two countries.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6BE329EC747A47C3A14303904EDDA006"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The United States maintains a Consulate General in Jerusalem.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A923A9C68D0472888BA5C730DECE591"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The United States Embassy in Israel remains the only United States Embassy not located in a country’s capital city, even though the Jerusalem Embassy Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/45">Public Law 104–45</external-xref>) directed the United States Embassy to be relocated in Jerusalem by May 31, 1999, and the Foreign Relations Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/228">Public Law 107–228</external-xref>) urged the President to begin relocating the embassy <quote>immediately</quote>, every President since 1995 has signed a waiver in the interest of national security to delay the move of the embassy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HACFF5CDC140E4912B9403F8ADCF186C9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The United States Ambassador has a residence in Herzliya, near Tel Aviv; however, for decades, ambassadors have spent a significant amount of their time in Jerusalem. For convenience and security, many of them have established their own temporary residences and have held official business meetings and stayed in hotels in Jerusalem.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H17919EFE0A534CF598DDC838FC63448F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress—</text> <paragraph id="H49CE37786F5B4ABC83B0930C95A6F811"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reaffirms that Israel is a major strategic partner of the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A9E21F5927C4D80AEA7005EBA4522F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses support for individuals and organizations working to encourage cooperation between Israelis and Palestinians to bring an end to the conflict.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H20DD748485764969AD75C2825EB086AE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Permanent residence for United States ambassador to Israel</header>
 <subsection id="H14069F1259614CD69EDAE0AD9AB13A01"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State is authorized, notwithstanding any other provision of law, to establish in Jerusalem, Israel, a permanent residence for the United States ambassador to Israel.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8B61DF6A9D6B4FA0B1D5FCEA43581E3B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Location</header><text>The permanent residence described in subsection (a) may be located at the United States consulate in Jerusalem, Israel, or at a different location in Jerusalem, as the Secretary of State determines appropriate.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


