<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H85CCA6D6B3C14E7A9151F8C1CE1C4C89" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1124 IH: State and Local Pensions Accountability and Security Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1124</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170216">February 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Secretary of the Treasury and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System
			 from providing bailouts or other financial assistance to a pension plan of
			 a State or political subdivision thereof, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HAF50D27468DC445A9C67066260A21A06" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6DB0CCE783DB4EB18AC53E9FAAFED78B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>State and Local Pensions Accountability and Security Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA3C120EFC02D4E70B8B3D57100DB239D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on bailouts for State and local pension funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System may not provide any loan, grant, or other form of financial assistance—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8C57392395314418936130D726603722"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to a pension plan (as defined under section 3 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>)) established or maintained by the government of any State or political subdivision thereof, or by any agency or instrumentality of such a State or political subdivision; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1820D8ACA02B410EB1AD216EDAC1CC95"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the government of any State or political subdivision thereof, or by any agency or instrumentality of such a State or political subdivision, unless such government, agency, or instrumentality certifies that the financial assistance will not be used, directly or indirectly, to fund such a pension plan.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


