<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4C9A126D3060447F8B8A2BF078F95CD2" key="H" public-private="public">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1380 IH: Timber Innovation Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1380</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20170307">March 7, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. McMorris Rodgers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster of New Hampshire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000374">Mr. Abraham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001045">Mr. Harper</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To clarify research and development for wood products, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form> 
<legis-body id="H1229B0C2F2E04CE6AF7057F630771BFB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1DA43242CC5742DB9C3B60626AD9F881" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Timber Innovation Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H6CB0C0D16055427C8B222728ED1E9532"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H1F66919D8B4645A38B085BC8F0679064"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Innovative wood product</header><text>The term <term>innovative wood product</term> means a type of building component or system that uses large panelized wood construction, including mass timber.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H6162B8D2EC0A4B15AD2B3603B690041C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mass timber</header><text>The term <term>mass timber</term> includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H766392EDB5564DE28D06676B98A0169C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>cross-laminated timber;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCD39A28D9496464FB20F35B38F059760"><enum>(B)</enum><text>nail laminated timber;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H324084B40A1A4229912D9FD9BF71CB9E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>glue laminated timber;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB92242C274F4F0ABA2387488959884D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>laminated strand lumber; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D1D4CC04D564078BDA7ACBF0CF64EF4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>laminated veneer lumber.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C617972A02548179542BE9C040FC3E3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Research and Development deputy area and the State and Private Forestry deputy area of the Forest Service.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB0F59CC4D5FE4396B0FDCD537550A58E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tall wood building</header><text>The term <term>tall wood building</term> means a building designed to be—</text> <subparagraph id="H5713B2EC0A5740E0B369771BF5F856A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>constructed with mass timber; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF1787292A961463CBE34EEF81183754A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>more than 85 feet in height.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HF9FDE35060FA48E6B5B7B87E87AD167E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clarification of research and development program for wood building construction</header> <subsection id="HE46737E02B404D4082045B1EF1CC177D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct performance-driven research and development, education, and technical assistance for the purpose of facilitating the use of innovative wood products in wood building construction in the United States.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H65BB6BD84A57429988D863767C864F14"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H614FD6FCA57B4557A59CBD9BF9A58179"><enum>(1)</enum><text>after receipt of input and guidance from, and collaboration with, the wood products industry, conservation organizations, and institutions of higher education, conduct research and development, education, and technical assistance at the Forest Products Laboratory or through the State and Private Forestry deputy area that meets measurable performance goals for the achievement of the priorities described in subsection (c); and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7C116CF9794842378604361DDEDB32E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>after coordination and collaboration with the wood products industry and conservation organizations, make competitive grants to institutions of higher education to conduct research and development, education, and technical assistance that meets measurable performance goals for the achievement of the priorities described in subsection (c).</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBA1AACBE5E9E443A9CBA0A920E44887F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priorities</header><text>The research and development, education, and technical assistance conducted under subsection (a) shall give priority to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF32CB9800C5C487EAD5437A1667355E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ways to improve the commercialization of innovative wood products;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE254C9B04E34906BCF5209ECF2147A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>analyzing the safety of tall wood building materials;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3217F63021E04E7E8DB8D12EE62A9D17"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calculations by the Forest Products Laboratory of the life cycle environmental footprint, from extraction of raw materials through the manufacturing process, of tall wood building construction;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7353AD5D1B240D8BDACC5E25306C0AD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>analyzing methods to reduce the life cycle environmental footprint of tall wood building construction;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB9EBD4B5E887434A9B8DA28EFFFE0C69"><enum>(5)</enum><text>analyzing the potential implications of the use of innovative wood products in building construction on wildlife; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H1728AA02F74D4781A023F0E9ADDAF836"><enum>(6)</enum><text>one or more other research areas identified by the Secretary, in consultation with conservation organizations, institutions of higher education, and the wood products industry.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HBACED364E5CC4A11B92998800EF947B1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Timeframe</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the measurable performance goals for the research and development, education, and technical assistance conducted under subsection (a) shall be achievable within a 5-year timeframe.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H1F22153B5A074096AD92EFFA4826F23D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Tall wood building competition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subject to availability of appropriations, not less frequently than once during each fiscal year for the period of fiscal years 2017 through 2021, the Secretary shall carry out a competition for a tall wood building design, or other innovative wood product demonstration, in accordance with section 24 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3719">15 U.S.C. 3719</external-xref>).</text> </section>
<section id="H02CB38AB4CA94544A3A6ED771AB6C774"><enum>5.</enum><header>Wood innovation grant program</header> 
<subsection id="H0C09F642CD8245D3A9B29453F7779F90"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HB5E8EE01F1684C9891963DB95CC5A5A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8D5C253178C845FF8D3AE4A583A0B6E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA99009D1AED748ADB8A90E9F223F7187"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a public or private entity (including a center of excellence that consists of one or more partnerships between forestry, engineering, architecture, or business schools at one or more institutions of higher education); or</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA533E8FD1F064DF889534DF60F835BC5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a State, local, or tribal government.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H662E3CFB71BB466AACF2895904BE2D99"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H6D1B48A873B446C59BAEA13AD50CC95B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text>The Secretary, in carrying out the wood innovation grant program of the Secretary described in the notice of the Secretary entitled <quote>Request for Proposals: 2016 Wood Innovations Funding Opportunity</quote> (80 Fed. Reg. 63498 (October 20, 2015)), may make a wood innovation grant to one or more eligible entities each year for the purpose of advancing the use of innovative wood products.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H969E935D498E406698C7A5A82238BDA2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Incentivizing use of existing milling capacity</header><text>In selecting among proposals of eligible entities under subsection (b), the Secretary shall give priority to proposals that include the use or retrofitting (or both) of existing sawmill facilities located in counties in which the average annual unemployment rate exceeded the national average unemployment rate by more than 1 percent in the previous calendar year.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H341A800DB0DE48068AA1BF618AC7DD73"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><text>As a condition of receiving a grant under subsection (b), an eligible entity shall provide funds equal to the amount the eligible entity receives under the grant, to be derived from non-Federal sources.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

