<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8F2436EA6BB24521BEB73880A54A5B79" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3621 IH: Rechecking Eligibility of Applicants to the Lifeline Program to Prevent Losses Yearly Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3621</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000604">Mr. Russell</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require subscribers to services supported through the Lifeline program of the Federal
			 Communications Commission to reapply for such services on an annual basis.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H26672A43AB20447C9008184109E4C1B7" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3A76D6F5F992400284C3823D3CA6BFA2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rechecking Eligibility of Applicants to the Lifeline Program to Prevent Losses Yearly Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>REAPPLY Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE1C680E8FA294688BDE53D186EDDB592"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual reapplication for Lifeline services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Communications Commission shall amend subpart E of part 54 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, so as to prohibit a provider of a Lifeline service from seeking or receiving reimbursement for providing such service to a subscriber unless, on an annual basis—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD0072978AE3D43389C1D0E045540CED1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such subscriber submits an application for such service in the same manner, and subject to the same requirements, as in the case of an initial application for such service; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE781790D17DE4C7EB5D078F7C43BCA8F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the eligibility of such subscriber to receive such service is determined and certified in the same manner, and subject to the same requirements, as in the case of the initial such determination and certification.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


