<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD177FC40D18248429631DD51A7F6E96C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1164 IH: Taylor Force Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1164</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170216">February 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="Z000017">Mr. Zeldin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To condition assistance to the West Bank and Gaza on steps by the Palestinian Authority to end
			 violence and terrorism against Israeli citizens.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H65796ECD7A8442AD90EBC196C83F166D" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7D29EE2150634EF5B9BBB451818D97C0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taylor Force Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H288D2E2465754C359F800138FF74A277"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on assistance to the West Bank and Gaza</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Funds appropriated or otherwise made available for assistance under chapter 4 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2346">22 U.S.C. 2346</external-xref> et seq.; relating to the Economic Support Fund) and available for assistance for the West Bank and Gaza may only be made available for such purpose if the Secretary of State certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the Palestinian Authority—</text>
 <paragraph id="H671F9B4173E04324807DAA05DC82470D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is taking credible steps to end acts of violence against United States and Israeli citizens that are perpetrated by individuals under its jurisdictional control, such as the March 2016 attack that killed former United States Army officer Taylor Force, a veteran of the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63F7F9E3615D4939BD70EC4CE842B57A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is publicly condemning such acts of violence and is taking steps to investigate or is cooperating in investigations of such acts to bring the perpetrators to justice; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H97F27495EB1242DFADAE0A2FDBD88525"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has terminated payments for acts of terrorism against United States and Israeli citizens to any individual who has been imprisoned after being fairly tried and convicted for such acts of terrorism and to any individual who died committing such acts of terrorism, including to a family member of such individuals.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H903F7868A1084FF0AD577CDEC0480AFC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> <paragraph id="HCFB7054CACEE41ECAF804BF1D4E18AF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H560911F1671148548BE62AB00BC9A3A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


