<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD692F5E220B1497695E712B1C8597713" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3448 IH: Classified Information Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3448</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170727">July 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide for penalties for the unauthorized disclosure of
			 classified information to a person not authorized to receive such
			 information.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HFACC5821E6EA40ECB6473892E5C9AEDA" style="OLC">
 <section id="H868B9EF15598474DB72AF26534465B1A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Classified Information Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4008028FC11C41A3B73651E36DE8EDC1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on unauthorized disclosure of classified information</header> <subsection id="H87CF708C04864368AD3758ECA77808C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/37">Chapter 37</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0D0BF27335BB4D3EAA0F9603B1C8336D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 798A as section 798B; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7206FFC0D3B54A81BC03CF8A17310F7A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 798 the following new section 798A:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HC7802188539C45DA85292A403A7A25CC" style="OLC">
						<section id="H9F15C10BAAF94A4AB7C5C3926CDEE898"><enum>798A.</enum><header>Unauthorized disclosure of classified information</header>
 <subsection id="H803F54308B054CE0AC8F73D1D2B8B1D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Whoever knowingly and willfully discloses, or attempts to disclose, any classified information acquired as a result of such person’s authorized access to classified information to a person who is not authorized access to such classified information, knowing that the person is not authorized access to such classified information, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 3 years, or both.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEABAE2F82F39471AA6723F5C0B7DE7E5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Construction of prohibition</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to establish criminal liability for disclosure of classified information in accordance with applicable law to the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1B4600AC80894FE9A7210AB1AC27D2B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any justice or judge of a court of the United States established pursuant to article III of the Constitution of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H218D9D8231CD4B91A0BD726B551F7506"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Senate or the House of Representatives, or any committee or subcommittee thereof, or joint committee thereof, or any member of Congress.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A9ACCB52C3C482EA7758DE1DB441999"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A person or persons acting on behalf of a foreign power (including an international organization) if the disclosure—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCF9F37CDCD3E4CA780EE45584C134CE1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is made by an officer or employee of the United States who has been authorized to make the disclosure; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83A0614B4A094F5F936B2394F6CE54FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is within the scope of such officer’s or employee’s duties.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H860002F21E964BD39158EAF9DC9B1AA4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any other person authorized to receive the classified information.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C8EF2DE9E9049C3A0847E6F9BC99458"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H16FC3A4835944375B150A09C29869150"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>authorized</term>, in the case of access to classified information, means having authority or permission to have access to the classified information pursuant to the provisions of a statute, Executive order, regulation, or directive of the head of any department or agency who is empowered to classify information, an order of any United States court, or a provision of any Resolution of the Senate or Rule of the House of Representatives which governs release of classified information by such House of Congress.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5D53B6B79D6A4890A81F0CF89EF7915C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>classified information</term> means information or material properly classified and clearly marked or represented, or that the person knows or has reason to believe has been properly classified by appropriate authorities, pursuant to the provisions of a statute or Executive order, as requiring protection against unauthorized disclosure for reasons of national security.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C2C8E8DE65A4A67B6CD908B8CD2BBBA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of that chapter is amended by striking the item relating to section 798A and inserting the following new items:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H7C42091B81D94A259D7B5D0850556A04" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">798A. Unauthorized disclosure of classified information.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">798B. Temporary extension of section 794.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


