<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H347F1FB5E1D847ADA1A326585AFC257F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1340 IH: Interagency Cybersecurity Cooperation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1340</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170302">March 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Federal Communications Commission to establish an Interagency Communications
			 Security Committee, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H80CE26327E3D4D779F5150C7C680ED5D" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7B6AE16AC3E84A48AAA40D8A0DCCE80C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Interagency Cybersecurity Cooperation Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H26D93CA9B2E443BD8FCCC4A9A8427688"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interagency communications security committee</header> <subsection id="H01E1B1AC142D4E3BBB902F455E269FFB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Communications Commission shall establish an advisory committee to be known as the Interagency Communications Security Committee (in this section referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7CE75CE7896F455CA879F66FECCBB793"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Committee shall—</text> <paragraph id="H3C89E907793243099AC06CEE08A510C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review each communications security report submitted to the Committee under subsection (d) or (f);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8FA90AD3F9A4036A63211BAFE2E31D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommend investigation to relevant agencies into any such communications security report; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1E46D3E908E4C9CBAED2F9504DDC3DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>issue regular reports containing the results of any such investigation, the Committee’s findings following each communications security incident, and policy recommendations that may arise from each communications security incident to the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H790D9712CF7A45C19E21E60EA5946B2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The agencies represented on the Committee.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28A594F910A44B728FA0A07EA70065A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F031620BF484E1CA1AEF8C8958F8B01"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H055B60CF75D64E25B5AE4CE40815DE41"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9168C31D69D446F9D08F7461E96071D"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CBDB4FC81344414AE1B82065D560CE1"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Armed Services Committee of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49425370ED8042C2B0ABED479CADEA09"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Armed Services Committee of the Senate.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8FA8438ED3041A9BF0A40F28FE71403"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AACAF5B9D6646AE99FF76B2490E8EBA"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63B42B193DE84B6681C96450D6793428"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Foreign Affairs Committee of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33EC715CF2114857A840C5CA2156C2A2"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Foreign Relations Committee of the Senate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H97CB19BCA908431B996D6D8C4E94656F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Committee shall be composed of 8 members, who shall each possess the appropriate access to classified information commensurate with the sensitivity of the classified information such members shall access in the course of service on the Committee. The members of the Committee shall include only—</text>
 <paragraph id="H02BB092483A642C6968895471941E1A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>one appointee from the Commission, who shall not be a member of the Commission, to be appointed by the Chair of the Commission, who shall serve as Chair of the Committee;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF59FD24011149D2A87F5EE62B52797D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>one appointee from the Department of Defense, to be appointed by the Secretary of Defense;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B70515616F04BB8B201C1A53051464C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>one appointee from the Department of Homeland Security, to be appointed by the Secretary of Homeland Security;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB92D0E990C743ADAB653A8FC92CC033"><enum>(4)</enum><text>one appointee from the Department of Justice, to be appointed by the Attorney General of the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD24DF14DE723457BAFA9FDA1348124DA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>one appointee from the intelligence community, to be appointed by the Director of National Intelligence;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H212E166535CF4E80908930A3A6898871"><enum>(6)</enum><text>one appointee from the National Institute of Standards and Technology, to be appointed by the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF0214EF2F96746039AEC0D814584903B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>one appointee from the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, to be appointed by the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1277A97BB0854E31BED99BD32077BE6E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>one appointee from the Office of Management and Budget, to be appointed by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F1C89FE93724F51B2A819ECC92E6929"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public communications security reports</header><text>The Committee shall consider communications security reports from communications network providers.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF08B4233A88C4872B181F25A5F5F9070"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application of critical infrastructure information protections</header><text>For purposes of subtitle B of title II of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/131">6 U.S.C. 131</external-xref> et seq.)—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H4CC4BC3095CB4CF8B3512D961B0ACAB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">communications networks shall be treated as critical infrastructure and protected systems defined in sections 2(4) and 212(6), respectively, of the <short-title>Homeland Security Act of 2002</short-title> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101(4)</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/131">6 U.S.C. 131(6)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H931C1B2E19154434BAED17523E5481CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to critical infrastructure information relating to communications networks, the Federal Communications Commission (in addition to the Department of Homeland Security) shall be treated as a covered Federal agency defined in section 212(2) of such Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H757BA657B5794C508C03F4BAA31D14A7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Agency communications security reports</header><text>Not less frequently than every 3 months, the head of each agency shall submit to the Committee a report of each communications security incident for the previous 3 months.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H30238D27CD3545BAB1F0074B28754E09"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Continuation of committee</header><text>Section 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) does not apply to the Committee.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H52DD05A811A94420803A34046CE7F88A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H80FF1D1656B84F989AB8D767149C54BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C12E11F378E4E7FA8821EB575A382FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Communications network</header><text>In this section, the term <term>communications network</term> means a network for the provision of wireline or mobile telephone service, Internet access service, radio or television broadcasting, cable service, direct broadcast satellite service, or any other communications service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E9BE02BBECE45F2B46BD91BFF67FB09"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Communications security incident</header><text>The term <term>communications security incident</term> means any compromise, whether electronic or otherwise, of any telecommunications system that the agency has reason to believe—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8EC5763853404725A4722772F1FB3023"><enum>(A)</enum><text>resulted in Government-held or private information, including passwords and other similar means of access, being viewed or extracted; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5784BF8E7E844ADDAA2CE783618DA8EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>resulted in the presence of outside programming on an agency computer or other electronic device.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H67FDD3FFB4A245B3B1E3F5A04591F607"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Communications Security Report</header><text>The term <term>communications security report</term> means a description of a communications security incident or multiple communications security incidents referred to the Committee.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


