<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H26CAF8310B6F45008B590350C119122F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1279 IH: Helping Veterans Exposed to Burn Pits Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1279</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170301">March 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish
			 within the Department of Veterans Affairs a center of excellence in the
			 prevention, diagnosis, mitigation, treatment, and rehabilitation of health
			 conditions relating to exposure to burn pits.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H63F731175C8846E29D665000F18C0F79" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE049241B69384B8BB4C32D8C3001D240" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helping Veterans Exposed to Burn Pits Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H80DF489A097E4FECA99AAC3E71A6AA1F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of center of excellence in prevention, diagnosis, mitigation, treatment, and rehabilitation of health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures</header> <subsection id="H179C7EA7874B45858481797B0A654BEA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/73">chapter 73</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC1E9E173AAB4459AB28DAD5F958CD708" style="USC">
					<section id="HB9D96B4167B0492E950F15A0860C73AC"><enum>7330C.</enum><header>Center of excellence in prevention, diagnosis, mitigation, treatment, and rehabilitation of health
			 conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other environmental
			 exposures</header>
						<subsection id="HE8AEB9DF53344698A649366C0488B513"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H79E52D7F305149C2B3DEF46D0809E14D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish within the Department a center of excellence in the prevention, diagnosis, mitigation, treatment, and rehabilitation of health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures to carry out the responsibilities specified in subsection (d).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59E985FEE54448FC90DD3DB4BFEDFC7D" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish the center of excellence under paragraph (1) through the use of—</text> <subparagraph id="HC2D49153B5CA475E98503E79CA05B5E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the directives and policies of the Department in effect as of the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Helping Veterans Exposed to Burn Pits Act</short-title>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D96E60016A049408CF8C33A5BA59A06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the recommendations of the Comptroller General of the United States and Inspector General of the Department in effect as of such date; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFBA2DA457D94A9BAE504A974BB6C1C0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>guidance issued by the Secretary of Defense under section 313 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/239">Public Law 112–239</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1074">10 U.S.C. 1074</external-xref> note).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD23DDEF54F4F46758AB99FDFA4DE688C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection of site</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting the site for the center of excellence established under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider entities that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6890CB3023F140AFA11B449E8F30C13D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are equipped with the specialized equipment needed to study, diagnose, and treat health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CC648561CF049E1A6A89891586E8AF3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have a track record of publishing information relating to post-deployment health exposures among veterans who served in the Armed Forces in support of Operation Iraqi Freedom and Operation Enduring Freedom;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4D959A773E03468C8F2A364C3B2E922E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>have access to animal models and in vitro models of dust immunology and lung injury consistent with the injuries of members of the Armed Forces who served in support of Operation Iraqi Freedom and Operation Enduring Freedom; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B5DE72D758E41F79D6AED74D93D5C52"><enum>(4)</enum><text>have expertise in allergy, immunology, and pulmonary diseases.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H769AE37BBA434C88AE4472EA7B50AB62"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the center of excellence collaborates, to the maximum extent practicable, with the Secretary of Defense, institutions of higher education, and other appropriate public and private entities (including international entities) to carry out the responsibilities specified in subsection (d).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFD73C8B288154ECBA02942ED94F21419"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The center of excellence shall have the following responsibilities:</text> <paragraph id="H19B7D2644CA34BFBBD3077A506D238DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To provide for the development, testing, and dissemination within the Department of best practices for the treatment of health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CF8D1FB77A94B5B9D3F54386AED268C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To provide guidance for the health systems of the Department and the Department of Defense in determining the personnel required to provide quality health care for members of the Armed Forces and veterans with health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2D05DA3436F4EC796EF7CB4D7EAB726"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To establish, implement, and oversee a comprehensive program to train health professionals of the Department and the Department of Defense in the treatment of health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A414A67928A41038F775ACBB542E085"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To facilitate advancements in the study of the short-term and long-term effects of exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1987705C847E45029DCBE4990524CF65"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To disseminate within medical facilities of the Department best practices for training health professionals with respect to health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B353F7BF3AB415FA357F9CA180D9DB1"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To conduct basic science and translational research on health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures for the purposes of understanding the etiology of such conditions and developing preventive interventions and new treatments.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H408A16301329447680EE19412AD8678E"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To provide medical treatment to veterans diagnosed with medical conditions specific to exposure to burn pits and other environmental exposures.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4A6DDE8332D24151B3473646D0F739A2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of burn pits registry data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out its responsibilities under subsection (d), the center of excellence shall have access to and make use of the data accumulated by the burn pits registry established under section 201 of the Dignified Burial and Other Veterans' Benefits Improvement Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/260">Public Law 112–260</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/527">38 U.S.C. 527</external-xref> note).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H877CD4B8C6314D53A7735C29015390C4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H75B2C8E4C03642BDA2E4392ECA2ACA8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>burn pit</term> means an area of land located in Afghanistan or Iraq that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H19D066CD4B1E4C02A14581119C1A78C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is designated by the Secretary of Defense to be used for disposing solid waste by burning in the outdoor air; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADB50BD6C9C44DAD8CB5CE2E9E06998E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not contain a commercially manufactured incinerator or other equipment specifically designed and manufactured for the burning of solid waste.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1008C5F8D27E4404A2EEB42789B9E603"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>other environmental exposures</term> means exposure to environmental hazards, including burn pits, dust or sand, hazardous materials, and waste at any site in Afghanistan or Iraq that emits smoke containing pollutants present in the environment or smoke from fires or explosions.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H45A0F7CA11BF4A46A237ABF7869D2748"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Funding</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2B35AD5F84AF48FD98BB2AB52C4AE08A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $4,100,000 for each of the first five fiscal years beginning after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Helping Veterans Exposed to Burn Pits Act</short-title>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA1943B2CC214271A4670A01BE83810E" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary may award additional amounts on a competitive basis to the center of excellence from the medical and prosthetics research account of the Department for the purpose of conducting research under this section relating to clinical and scientific investigation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1D5D66941ECD48C4B5015B4615A4D9F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 73 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7330B the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HBD3DB0EB8440416AA4E03F1DEFD60096" style="USC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry idref="HB9D96B4167B0492E950F15A0860C73AC" level="section">7330C. Center of excellence in prevention, diagnosis, mitigation, treatment, and rehabilitation of
			 health conditions relating to exposure to burn pits and other
			 environmental exposures.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


