<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB6502A216A184410859EBDD0C4BDB9D0" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1215 : Protecting Access to Care Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1215</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20170629">June 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc> Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To improve patient access to health care services and provide improved medical care by reducing the
			 excessive burden the liability system places on the health care delivery
			 system.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H7C173E61F23B453DACACDFAA6B8E8095" style="OLC">
		<section id="H35A59FC230B14E3D8BE79F8FDDDE26E9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="HE8C22ABA96234AB3B80B497AC3C93589"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Access to Care Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H327080C11C9A452B9625EAA6FB4F6F47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H35A59FC230B14E3D8BE79F8FDDDE26E9" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H58E408903F7C4D0E93DBFFCF274D646C" level="section">Sec. 2. Encouraging speedy resolution of claims.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H625AD197110A492983B5A71D048A1B20" level="section">Sec. 3. Compensating patient injury.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HFD8CF829AB564EF18474DB7116D6E6AB" level="section">Sec. 4. Maximizing patient recovery.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H11802E5A83FE41959AC23CC8817890F4" level="section">Sec. 5. Authorization of payment of future damages to claimants in health care lawsuits.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8B244A5E4C8942009E4BCF98E9ED8D80" level="section">Sec. 6. Product liability for health care providers.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB1DFE5DA6BE940158F2CCD0EBB763E97" level="section">Sec. 7. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB2422C815F064979933289BAC433CC25" level="section">Sec. 8. Effect on other laws.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H9E986172AAB14D928FA3EDFA65F8B9E1" level="section">Sec. 9. Rules of construction.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H2DB0C11C81D8491C88F38781C01E7148" level="section">Sec. 10. Effective date.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H3AD82FC650F14F539EB558CE463CC533" level="section">Sec. 11. Limitation on expert witness testimony.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H89728FF12D894814AE978205EABD892B" level="section">Sec. 12. Communications following unanticipated outcome.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H260A2C30FEE440ACB33FA12CB49D4A6A" level="section">Sec. 13. Expert witness qualifications.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H02B398E056BC4A8992FEAA196B692953" level="section">Sec. 14. Affidavit of merit.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBCF8EBB4B8B24CC1B7C54FB587DB613A" level="section">Sec. 15. Notice of intent to commence lawsuit.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
			</subsection></section><section id="H58E408903F7C4D0E93DBFFCF274D646C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Encouraging speedy resolution of claims</header>
			<subsection id="HEA260293AC4948C4983D9D488668B85D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statute of limitations</header>
 <paragraph id="HA82CA11FC5884489AB69016AC7D541DE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the time for the commencement of a health care lawsuit shall be, whichever occurs first of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7276D4EBEAA942E88E2F589D03DDA5A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>3 years after the date of the occurrence of the breach or tort;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF484B9D68CCD4913A6BE77CC0E6282F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>3 years after the date the medical or health care treatment that is the subject of the claim is completed; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80112CF0D3F0498B8B1FCD38A46B1827"><enum>(C)</enum><text>1 year after the claimant discovers, or through the use of reasonable diligence should have discovered, the injury.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E74236A32DF45D1A97910E8E55E9733"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tolling</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In no event shall the time for commencement of a health care lawsuit exceed 3 years after the date of the occurrence of the breach or tort or 3 years after the date the medical or health care treatment that is the subject of the claim is completed (whichever occurs first) unless tolled for any of the following—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8395A3C866324D2FBD115E1CDB3C9189"><enum>(A)</enum><text>upon proof of fraud;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE778DA74A8F49B28AFCE9F06757D47E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>intentional concealment; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BCA1826BBC5476C81B8E86B4904A12A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the presence of a foreign body, which has no therapeutic or diagnostic purpose or effect, in the person of the injured person.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H00916B33C4724D38B7457D403F922432"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Actions by a minor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Actions by a minor shall be commenced within 3 years after the date of the occurrence of the breach or tort or 3 years after the date of the medical or health care treatment that is the subject of the claim is completed (whichever occurs first) except that actions by a minor under the full age of 6 years shall be commenced within 3 years after the date of the occurrence of the breach or tort, 3 years after the date of the medical or health care treatment that is the subject of the claim is completed, or 1 year after the injury is discovered, or through the use of reasonable diligence should have been discovered, or prior to the minor’s 8th birthday, whichever provides a longer period. Such time limitation shall be tolled for minors for any period during which a parent or guardian and a health care provider have committed fraud or collusion in the failure to bring an action on behalf of the injured minor.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H765013CA4A3949789EC789FAF8F2AC56"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State flexibility</header><text>No provision of subsection (a) shall be construed to preempt any state law (whether effective before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act) that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4C9E02A3504441DE874AEA5FDC2F9509"><enum>(1)</enum><text>specifies a time period of less than 3 years after the date of injury or less than 1 year after the claimant discovers, or through the use of reasonable diligence should have discovered, the injury, for the filing of a health care lawsuit;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H32BD57B8DBF34168BBB2BE8FC88157C5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that specifies a different time period for the filing of lawsuits by a minor;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A910691E17B4DEDA362F1A66F0ECC01"><enum>(3)</enum><text>that triggers the time period based on the date of the alleged negligence; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE948BF0FF5F94C1D958C0337C3803ADB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establishes a statute of repose for the filing of health care lawsuit.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H625AD197110A492983B5A71D048A1B20"><enum>3.</enum><header>Compensating patient injury</header> <subsection id="HB448ABC2B590407D9536CB63D9F1F275"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unlimited amount of damages for actual economic losses in health care lawsuits</header><text>In any health care lawsuit, nothing in this Act shall limit a claimant’s recovery of the full amount of the available economic damages, notwithstanding the limitation in subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2D131700C9A64E4CBAB4DCBE616F3EB5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional noneconomic damages</header><text>In any health care lawsuit, the amount of noneconomic damages, if available, shall not exceed $250,000, regardless of the number of parties against whom the action is brought or the number of separate claims or actions brought with respect to the same injury.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEB1A04C7B1094D6C9A3EA1DE34399E95"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No discount of award for noneconomic damages</header><text>For purposes of applying the limitation in subsection (b), future noneconomic damages shall not be discounted to present value. The jury shall not be informed about the maximum award for noneconomic damages. An award for noneconomic damages in excess of $250,000 shall be reduced either before the entry of judgment, or by amendment of the judgment after entry of judgment, and such reduction shall be made before accounting for any other reduction in damages required by law. If separate awards are rendered for past and future noneconomic damages and the combined awards exceed $250,000, the future noneconomic damages shall be reduced first.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD884D174816C435F84C17BEC582C17B6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fair share rule</header><text>In any health care lawsuit, each party shall be liable for that party’s several share of any damages only and not for the share of any other person. Each party shall be liable only for the amount of damages allocated to such party in direct proportion to such party’s percentage of responsibility. Whenever a judgment of liability is rendered as to any party, a separate judgment shall be rendered against each such party for the amount allocated to such party. For purposes of this section, the trier of fact shall determine the proportion of responsibility of each party for the claimant’s harm.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1BBEC7DC7D5E4548BE273E3292654910"><enum>(e)</enum><header>State flexibility</header><text>No provision of this section shall be construed to preempt any State law (whether effective before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act) that specifies a particular monetary amount of economic or noneconomic damages (or the total amount of damages) that may be awarded in a health care lawsuit, regardless of whether such monetary amount is greater or lesser than is provided for under this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HFD8CF829AB564EF18474DB7116D6E6AB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Maximizing patient recovery</header>
 <subsection id="HA5B06200265F4A73AF4A355CF49A92BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Court supervision of share of damages actually paid to claimants</header><text>In any health care lawsuit, the court shall supervise the arrangements for payment of damages to protect against conflicts of interest that may have the effect of reducing the amount of damages awarded that are actually paid to claimants. In particular, in any health care lawsuit in which the attorney for a party claims a financial stake in the outcome by virtue of a contingent fee, the court shall have the power to restrict the payment of a claimant’s damage recovery to such attorney, and to redirect such damages to the claimant based upon the interests of justice and principles of equity. In no event shall the total of all contingent fees for representing all claimants in a health care lawsuit exceed the following limits:</text>
 <paragraph id="H45068246E73E4251A12001787989CEAB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Forty percent of the first $50,000 recovered by the claimant(s).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA294526DB31D4DC0AF9036AA5A8EB2DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Thirty-three and one-third percent of the next $50,000 recovered by the claimant(s).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H41B711AECE1548F7B8841ACBE627B490"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Twenty-five percent of the next $500,000 recovered by the claimant(s).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B9C6D0E8C154A86BFD6C18D724699F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Fifteen percent of any amount by which the recovery by the claimant(s) is in excess of $600,000.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3BD9AFC3170948F6B05791C0CD857FD5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The limitations in this section shall apply whether the recovery is by judgment, settlement, mediation, arbitration, or any other form of alternative dispute resolution. In a health care lawsuit involving a minor or incompetent person, a court retains the authority to authorize or approve a fee that is less than the maximum permitted under this section. The requirement for court supervision in the first two sentences of subsection (a) applies only in civil actions.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5A65132AC4004330A34C12AB154DB661"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State flexibility</header><text>No provision of this section shall be construed to preempt any State law (whether effective before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act) that specifies a lesser percentage or lesser total value of damages which may be claimed by an attorney representing a claimant in a health care lawsuit.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H11802E5A83FE41959AC23CC8817890F4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of payment of future damages to claimants in health care lawsuits</header>
 <subsection id="H3CC242DF81E84BB288494A4BA85AA61C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any health care lawsuit, if an award of future damages, without reduction to present value, equaling or exceeding $50,000 is made against a party with sufficient insurance or other assets to fund a periodic payment of such a judgment, the court shall, at the request of any party, enter a judgment ordering that the future damages be paid by periodic payments, in accordance with the Uniform Periodic Payment of Judgments Act promulgated by the National Conference of Commissioners on Uniform State Laws.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H709473DE5E6E4D32B5651D1A54B7A3D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section applies to all actions which have not been first set for trial or retrial before the effective date of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H10D437DC4CF941439EA3F148F80062DB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State Flexibility</header><text>No provision of this section shall be construed to preempt any State law (whether effective before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act) that specifies periodic payments for future damages at any amount other than $50,000 or that mandates such payments absent the request of either party.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H8B244A5E4C8942009E4BCF98E9ED8D80"><enum>6.</enum><header>Product liability for health care providers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A health care provider who prescribes, or who dispenses pursuant to a prescription, a medical product approved, licensed, or cleared by the Food and Drug Administration shall not be named as a party to a product liability lawsuit involving such product and shall not be liable to a claimant in a class action lawsuit against the manufacturer, distributor, or seller of such product.</text>
 </section><section id="HB1DFE5DA6BE940158F2CCD0EBB763E97"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H0F9CF9961CB24D7C8B7733BFDB906728"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Alternative dispute resolution system; ADR</header><text>The term <quote>alternative dispute resolution system</quote> or <quote>ADR</quote> means a system that provides for the resolution of health care lawsuits in a manner other than through a civil action brought in a State or Federal court.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B9B6C3E54064984BE8BC17F16A4BF7E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Claimant</header><text>The term <quote>claimant</quote> means any person who brings a health care lawsuit, including a person who asserts or claims a right to legal or equitable contribution, indemnity, or subrogation, arising out of a health care liability claim or action, and any person on whose behalf such a claim is asserted or such an action is brought, whether deceased, incompetent, or a minor.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H531066A0418D4B74A0FCF4F4A13AE2D0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Collateral source benefits</header><text>The term <quote>collateral source benefits</quote> means any amount paid or reasonably likely to be paid in the future to or on behalf of the claimant, or any service, product, or other benefit provided or reasonably likely to be provided in the future to or on behalf of the claimant, as a result of the injury or wrongful death, pursuant to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEECDC127954B41EEA7D5201B700F66C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any State or Federal health, sickness, income-disability, accident, or workers’ compensation law;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AF855EFE78F4B0C9645EFBCF33B779C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any health, sickness, income-disability, or accident insurance that provides health benefits or income-disability coverage;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46923146C77641D08AB8D3B4E7575FBC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any contract or agreement of any group, organization, partnership, or corporation to provide, pay for, or reimburse the cost of medical, hospital, dental, or income-disability benefits; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H976561D02F6143BBBD51A907C58C82E4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other publicly or privately funded program.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87072A59D2044548800F6A5B1EB5C537"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Contingent fee</header><text>The term <quote>contingent fee</quote> includes all compensation to any person or persons which is payable only if a recovery is effected on behalf of one or more claimants.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2992F32DB4B24D158245A801B85C9E3B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Economic damages</header><text>The term <quote>economic damages</quote> means objectively verifiable monetary losses incurred as a result of the provision or use of (or failure to provide or use) health care services or medical products, such as past and future medical expenses, loss of past and future earnings, cost of obtaining domestic services, loss of employment, and loss of business or employment opportunities, unless otherwise defined under applicable state law. In no circumstances shall damages for health care services or medical products exceed the amount actually paid or incurred by or on behalf of the claimant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F53A10C126D4C6099D474CA6D96407E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Future damages</header><text>The term <quote>future damages</quote> means any damages that are incurred after the date of judgment, settlement, or other resolution (including mediation, or any other form of alternative dispute resolution).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1D690FB97B7441993C2B7B4C6ED29ED"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Health care lawsuit</header><text>The term <quote>health care lawsuit</quote> means any health care liability claim concerning the provision of goods or services for which coverage was provided in whole or in part via a Federal program, subsidy or tax benefit, or any health care liability action concerning the provision of goods or services for which coverage was provided in whole or in part via a Federal program, subsidy or tax benefit, brought in a State or Federal court or pursuant to an alternative dispute resolution system, against a health care provider regardless of the theory of liability on which the claim is based, or the number of claimants, plaintiffs, defendants, or other parties, or the number of claims or causes of action, in which the claimant alleges a health care liability claim. Such term does not include a claim or action which is based on criminal liability; which seeks civil fines or penalties paid to Federal, State, or local government; or which is grounded in antitrust.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC38DB24B637D4A46B85DAF63CF89453F"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Health care liability action</header><text>The term <quote>health care liability action</quote> means a civil action brought in a State or Federal court or pursuant to an alternative dispute resolution system, against a health care provider regardless of the theory of liability on which the claim is based, or the number of plaintiffs, defendants, or other parties, or the number of causes of action, in which the claimant alleges a health care liability claim.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF87F1CFA57CC45D1B1D0EB18072D0CCB"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Health care liability claim</header><text>The term <quote>health care liability claim</quote> means a demand by any person, whether or not pursuant to ADR, against a health care provider, including, but not limited to, third-party claims, cross-claims, counter-claims, or contribution claims, which are based upon the provision or use of (or the failure to provide or use) health care services or medical products, regardless of the theory of liability on which the claim is based, or the number of plaintiffs, defendants, or other parties, or the number of causes of action.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3B282EE955C465DBE4D2A0241596D9E"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Health care provider</header><text>The term <quote>health care provider</quote> means any person or entity required by State or Federal laws or regulations to be licensed, registered, or certified to provide health care services, and being either so licensed, registered, or certified, or exempted from such requirement by other statute or regulation, as well as any other individual or entity defined as a health care provider, health care professional, or health care institution under state law.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCDAA6A36EEBA454B9B3BFB813167315A"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Health care services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>health care services</quote> means the provision of any goods or services (including safety, professional, or administrative services directly related to health care) by a health care provider, or by any individual working under the supervision of a health care provider, that relates to the diagnosis, prevention, or treatment of any human disease or impairment, or the assessment or care of the health of human beings.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H179C2B8D31B34150B8FBD933CD3F366A"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Medical product</header><text>The term <quote>medical product</quote> means a drug, device, or biological product intended for humans, and the terms <quote>drug</quote>, <quote>device</quote>, and <quote>biological product</quote> have the meanings given such terms in sections 201(g)(1) and 201(h) of the Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321(g)(1)</external-xref> and (h)) and section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262(a)</external-xref>), respectively, including any component or raw material used therein, but excluding health care services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H714BCA8CE4334E5A99DCE55691311848"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Noneconomic damages</header><text>The term <quote>noneconomic damages</quote> means damages for physical and emotional pain, suffering, inconvenience, physical impairment, mental anguish, disfigurement, loss of enjoyment of life, loss of society and companionship, loss of consortium (other than loss of domestic service), hedonic damages, injury to reputation, and all other nonpecuniary losses of any kind or nature incurred as a result of the provision or use of (or failure to provide or use) health care services or medical products, unless otherwise defined under applicable state law.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9440739A71364E86BB0B7CDFCE85DC51"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Recovery</header><text>The term <quote>recovery</quote> means the net sum recovered after deducting any disbursements or costs incurred in connection with prosecution or settlement of the claim, including all costs paid or advanced by any person. Costs of health care incurred by the plaintiff and the attorneys’ office overhead costs or charges for legal services are not deductible disbursements or costs for such purpose.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H47F8DA32422C457ABF84B166E47A0780"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Representative</header><text>The term <quote>representative</quote> means a legal guardian, attorney, person designated to make decisions on behalf of a patient under a medical power of attorney, or any person recognized in law or custom as a patient’s agent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF367513649445108D5296593C983276"><enum>(16)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States, or any political subdivision thereof.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HB2422C815F064979933289BAC433CC25"><enum>8.</enum><header>Effect on other laws</header>
			<subsection id="HB8F80C23BE7F485D9DB64C89ED3A605C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Vaccine injury</header>
 <paragraph id="H71C0ACCA503D42BE9698F38CE68D604C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To the extent that title XXI of the Public Health Service Act establishes a Federal rule of law applicable to a civil action brought for a vaccine-related injury or death—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H015C4291A6EF407B96D4A9B3B9FC598E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this Act does not affect the application of the rule of law to such an action; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H004A73A37A4344C2AE82C51BCE2EBABB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any rule of law prescribed by this Act in conflict with a rule of law of such title XXI shall not apply to such action.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA892898A06F4BD39239CB8B9763E02F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If there is an aspect of a civil action brought for a vaccine-related injury or death to which a Federal rule of law under title XXI of the Public Health Service Act does not apply, then this Act or otherwise applicable law (as determined under this Act) will apply to such aspect of such action.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1BDB61E7025E40C781E5418F772F42E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other Federal law</header><text>Except as provided in this section, nothing in this Act shall be deemed to affect any defense available to a defendant in a health care lawsuit or action under any other provision of Federal law.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H9E986172AAB14D928FA3EDFA65F8B9E1"><enum>9.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header>
 <subsection id="H773D4A44C810487B801BC2EE10114999"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Health care lawsuits</header><text>Unless otherwise specified in this Act, the provisions governing health care lawsuits set forth in this Act preempt, subject to subsections (b) and (c), State law to the extent that State law prevents the application of any provisions of law established by or under this Act. The provisions governing health care lawsuits set forth in this Act supersede <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, to the extent that such chapter—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEA2A962F65CB4BB6B5F38DB460302AC2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provides for a greater amount of damages or contingent fees, a longer period in which a health care lawsuit may be commenced, or a reduced applicability or scope of periodic payment of future damages, than provided in this Act; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H42C6FEABB2044A9199F538B9D3260031"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibits the introduction of evidence regarding collateral source benefits, or mandates or permits subrogation or a lien on collateral source benefits.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H49CB6041B9984458ACDEF9B59823D3D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Protection of States’ rights and other laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any issue that is not governed by any provision of law established by or under this Act (including State standards of negligence) shall be governed by otherwise applicable State or Federal law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3F11DB7D65F54783A0156B2CF21A58D2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State Flexibility</header><text>No provision of this Act shall be construed to preempt any defense available to a party in a health care lawsuit under any other provision of State or Federal law.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H2DB0C11C81D8491C88F38781C01E7148"><enum>10.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall apply to any health care lawsuit brought in a Federal or State court, or subject to an alternative dispute resolution system, that is initiated on or after the date of the enactment of this Act, except that any health care lawsuit arising from an injury occurring prior to the date of the enactment of this Act shall be governed by the applicable statute of limitations provisions in effect at the time the cause of action accrued.</text>
		</section><section id="H3AD82FC650F14F539EB558CE463CC533"><enum>11.</enum><header>Limitation on expert witness testimony</header>
 <subsection id="H1E286C6FA5A94F6CB21C51E910A656D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person in a health care profession requiring licensure under the laws of a State shall be competent to testify in any court of law to establish the following facts—</text>
 <paragraph id="H34BBA677424045AFBBAD21FA6A74DB2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the recognized standard of acceptable professional practice and the specialty thereof, if any, that the defendant practices, which shall be the type of acceptable professional practice recognized in the defendant’s community or in a community similar to the defendant’s community that was in place at the time the alleged injury or wrongful action occurred;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0DA79F6511A54B4080D99DE0616AAD21"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the defendant acted with less than or failed to act with ordinary and reasonable care in accordance with the recognized standard; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H137DB778A03A4BD39049EA255E6D2395"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that as a proximate result of the defendant’s negligent act or omission, the claimant suffered injuries which would not otherwise have occurred,</text>
				</paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">unless the person was licensed to practice, in the State or a contiguous bordering State, a
			 profession or specialty which would make the person’s expert testimony
			 relevant to the issues in the case and had practiced this profession or
			 specialty in one of these States during the year preceding the date that
 the alleged injury or wrongful act occurred.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H7D1693112A4D440187AD422885EF8E82"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements set forth in subsection (a) shall also apply to expert witnesses testifying for the defendant as rebuttal witnesses.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HECC176FF82E5417AAD2C601C62802751"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court may waive the requirements in this subsection if it determines that the appropriate witnesses otherwise would not be available.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H89728FF12D894814AE978205EABD892B"><enum>12.</enum><header>Communications following unanticipated outcome</header>
 <subsection id="H92CC1C5448AB4F8DBB3E9A1B8F46EE52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Provider communications</header><text>In any health care liability action, any and all statements, affirmations, gestures, or conduct expressing apology, fault, sympathy, commiseration, condolence, compassion, or a general sense of benevolence which are made by a health care provider or an employee of a health care provider to the patient, a relative of the patient, or a representative of the patient and which relate to the discomfort, pain, suffering, injury, or death of the patient as the result of the unanticipated outcome of medical care shall be inadmissible for any purpose as evidence of an admission of liability or as evidence of an admission against interest.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF6CB41402DE149BC812624F5DDC50235"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State flexibility</header><text>No provision of this section shall be construed to preempt any State law (whether effective before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act) that makes additional communications inadmissible as evidence of an admission of liability or as evidence of an admission against interest.</text>
			</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H260A2C30FEE440ACB33FA12CB49D4A6A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>13.</enum><header>Expert witness qualifications</header>
 <subsection id="HAF97F33D0D684FB1A920AA0A18C4A94B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any health care lawsuit, an individual shall not give expert testimony on the appropriate standard of practice or care involved unless the individual is licensed as a health professional in one or more States and the individual meets the following criteria:</text>
 <paragraph id="H3EB24E63C6024BF59CC5C4613885C14B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If the party against whom or on whose behalf the testimony is to be offered is or claims to be a specialist, the expert witness shall specialize at the time of the occurrence that is the basis for the lawsuit in the same specialty or claimed specialty as the party against whom or on whose behalf the testimony is to be offered. If the party against whom or on whose behalf the testimony is to be offered is or claims to be a specialist who is board certified, the expert witness shall be a specialist who is board certified in that specialty or claimed specialty.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D90F165DE974B62B9FC636CF96C06C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>During the 1-year period immediately preceding the occurrence of the action that gave rise to the lawsuit, the expert witness shall have devoted a majority of the individual’s professional time to one or more of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H812D9B5F2087453D9DCD8C5E9ED7B819"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The active clinical practice of the same health profession as the defendant and, if the defendant is or claims to be a specialist, in the same specialty or claimed specialty.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6264C474B9D45858318B00EE3B24895"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The instruction of students in an accredited health professional school or accredited residency or clinical research program in the same health profession as the defendant and, if the defendant is or claims to be a specialist, in an accredited health professional school or accredited residency or clinical research program in the same specialty or claimed specialty.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5133FCE9545C4FC79FC2D92C970C4541"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If the defendant is a general practitioner, the expert witness shall have devoted a majority of the witness’s professional time in the 1-year period preceding the occurrence of the action giving rise to the lawsuit to one or more of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD2B2CCBBD4EB40C69E8B398C182BC3F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Active clinical practice as a general practitioner.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13ABF6FCFB1449528B8AA325755F6D5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Instruction of students in an accredited health professional school or accredited residency or clinical research program in the same health profession as the defendant.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H49A040C3FA014F8EAD3EA3C33D276B66"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Lawsuits against entities</header><text>If the defendant in a health care lawsuit is an entity that employs a person against whom or on whose behalf the testimony is offered, the provisions of subsection (a) apply as if the person were the party or defendant against whom or on whose behalf the testimony is offered.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBE3F2C8D6897455694AD76B6E4E483D4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Power of court</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall limit the power of the trial court in a health care lawsuit to disqualify an expert witness on grounds other than the qualifications set forth under this subsection.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H845AF8D8A82A49DEA1BC9C5309615EF9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>An expert witness in a health care lawsuit shall not be permitted to testify if the fee of the witness is in any way contingent on the outcome of the lawsuit.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H16B4181F347948B0A41D8A01794B1A78"><enum>(e)</enum><header>State flexibility</header><text>No provision of this section shall be construed to preempt any State law (whether effective before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act) that places additional qualification requirements upon any individual testifying as an expert witness.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H02B398E056BC4A8992FEAA196B692953"><enum>14.</enum><header>Affidavit of merit</header>
 <subsection id="H5F826BA5CAA94A0A820C5407B1FC1E8A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Required filing</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), the plaintiff in a health care lawsuit alleging negligence or, if the plaintiff is represented by an attorney, the plaintiff’s attorney shall file simultaneously with the health care lawsuit an affidavit of merit signed by a health professional who meets the requirements for an expert witness under section 14 of this Act. The affidavit of merit shall certify that the health professional has reviewed the notice and all medical records supplied to him or her by the plaintiff’s attorney concerning the allegations contained in the notice and shall contain a statement of each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H906014906352469EB54E9F3E84A7D532"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The applicable standard of practice or care.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B4D91F71E8C44A79F500371A0696540"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The health professional’s opinion that the applicable standard of practice or care was breached by the health professional or health facility receiving the notice.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD47A11ED0418484E86F58DBEEBE755C6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The actions that should have been taken or omitted by the health professional or health facility in order to have complied with the applicable standard of practice or care.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC670F0DA82CD479DBBA09FFA0A2164B3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The manner in which the breach of the standard of practice or care was the proximate cause of the injury alleged in the notice.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEADA4673E1944237BA065D884C05E2DD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A listing of the medical records reviewed.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF0B9FEFCBBF942C58ABC3B4BFECCABE0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Filing extension</header><text>Upon motion of a party for good cause shown, the court in which the complaint is filed may grant the plaintiff or, if the plaintiff is represented by an attorney, the plaintiff’s attorney an additional 28 days in which to file the affidavit required under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEB2F26EFC5A74259B9706A5538A63EA4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State flexibility</header><text>No provision of this section shall be construed to preempt any State law (whether effective before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act) that establishes additional requirements for the filing of an affidavit of merit or similar pre-litigation documentation.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HBCF8EBB4B8B24CC1B7C54FB587DB613A"><enum>15.</enum><header>Notice of intent to commence lawsuit</header>
 <subsection id="H25AF460F1EAE42C0BD77948AF0E97B17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Advance notice</header><text>A person shall not commence a health care lawsuit against a health care provider unless the person has given the health care provider 90 days written notice before the action is commenced.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H10B39AD3A2F64CBBBE09F131A22511B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>A health care lawsuit against a health care provider filed within 6 months of the statute of limitations expiring as to any claimant, or within 1 year of the statute of repose expiring as to any claimant, shall be exempt from compliance with this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6AF15050B2514B799A878502AC372608"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State flexibility</header><text>No provision of this section shall be construed to preempt any State law (whether effective before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act) that establishes a different time period for the filing of written notice.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170628">Passed the House of Representatives June 28, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


