<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H513D8675EC4C4F4283D017D3BC5E5776" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2784 IH: Good Neighbor Gun Dealer Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2784</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170606">June 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Attorney General to establish a <quote>Good Neighbor</quote> code of conduct for federally licensed firearms dealers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H77FCAA878D1A45CDBEA1754F8D2B882D" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1EFDEB7029CB456980A843E6D015BB04" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Good Neighbor Gun Dealer Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8FB3ADC6905E4D3EB52C9B06CDAF2496"><enum>2.</enum><header>Good Neighbor code of conduct for gun dealers</header> <subsection id="H92D252323B024848B8332AD56E0CB9C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall establish a voluntary code of conduct for licensed dealers (which shall be known as the <quote>Good Neighbor Code of Conduct</quote>) that shall urge licensed dealers, at a minimum, to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8913C4C3DC744F24A3F76065CF969F0B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>take such steps as the Attorney General specifies in the code of conduct to—</text> <subparagraph id="HF1A41C445A8E4E49A6581011D7798E59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prevent the dealer from selling a firearm to a straw purchaser, gun trafficker, criminal, or other individual prohibited by law from purchasing a firearm; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2DB974FC4B24F6995C59876FF5D8274"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintain a well-trained, responsible, law-abiding workforce;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E4027B083164952BB999CB2181520A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implement a safety plan to detect and deter firearm theft from the licensed dealer;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H42394A0106C54DEFA53AD240E4836EE4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>cooperate fully with all law enforcement investigations, and notify law enforcement of suspected straw purchasers of firearms; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1FE00EC9F9D94B37A36B6025D54AC0FD"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that a background check is completed before the sale of any firearm.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H056F830DE4F14BFB8995F6B1CC8B3625"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Within 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall cause to be published on the website of the Department of Justice the code of conduct established under subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HF195324CE04C446494E868926262E6B6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Good Neighbor certification for gun dealers</header>
 <subsection id="HE153432605FC41359CDE715DB6A87930"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Creation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall create a <quote>Good Neighbor</quote> certification for licensed dealers who agree to abide by the code of conduct established under section 2.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFC03AF72EFAE4DACB97847E7FBFE1E75"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to the Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall report to the Congress on the process for awarding the certification created under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE9AA332F4085449E9DCFF1114994F854"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Revocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General, in the sole discretion of the Attorney General, may revoke a certification granted under this section, for failure to abide by the code of conduct established under section 2.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7D58660D392D4F64BB1F7B59B5486198"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall cause to be published on the website of the Department of Justice a full list of licensed dealers to whom a Good Neighbor certification has been granted under this section, and shall provide that list to the Congress annually.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HAC98946013974A5FA7AB388687A78B7D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Disclosure of firearm trace data</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Attorney General may disclose firearms trace data to the public, to the extent that doing so will not undermine an investigation or, in the judgement of the Attorney General, otherwise compromise the efforts of law enforcement or public safety.</text>
 </section><section id="HF2EBA49F10F240649F5768EDB683FE44"><enum>5.</enum><header>Strategic plan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Within 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a strategic plan detailing the efforts to be made by the Attorney General to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7C35AF6F62B044CD9C9B4B632F85ACF8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve the accuracy, reliability and comprehensiveness of firearms trace data;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H127C445D98B94EFBB85B87E1BFAEAA80"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enhance the identification of licensed dealers who have transferred firearms that have been disproportionately used in the commission of crime; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H06E95AD86FF1461BA6C2260246A7BBA4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increase enforcement against violations of Federal law by licensed dealers.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H4EAC4ECF5F884D67BC77D07D4554ED24"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definition of licensed dealer</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>licensed dealer</term> has the meaning given in section 921(a)(11) of title 18, United States Code.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


