<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6C4C72B9A8FF40AFA3A8B14D61AA27DF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4454 IH: Chronic Wasting Disease Management Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4454</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171121">November 21, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support State and tribal efforts to develop and implement management strategies to address
			 chronic wasting disease among deer, elk, and moose populations, to support
			 applied research regarding the causes of chronic wasting disease and
			 methods to control the further spread of the disease, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H813DE8BBC3814845A636D57D8F26B6D6" style="OLC">
		<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC2D43FC2CB54AE299354B1FE305B8B8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="HE3BB7FB0E67B49CFADFA60ABA243FEBF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Chronic Wasting Disease Management Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HD9224352025D403695E048E32DF9B103"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="HFC2D43FC2CB54AE299354B1FE305B8B8" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H132FE03FBD244C1D82D05BEAF2661359" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H1653686878C3468087B656A05ACF9E29" level="section">Sec. 3. Findings.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8337CBFCAB9C44E59DD070C995EA3223" level="section">Sec. 4. Support for State efforts to manage and control chronic wasting disease.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H0D9E6D84464D45ACB0F96B1F00D19D6A" level="section">Sec. 5. Support for applied research regarding chronic wasting disease.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H23839C0F2220474DAEA5F63ED0BBA636" level="section">Sec. 6. Multi-agency cooperation with States to address chronic wasting disease.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="H132FE03FBD244C1D82D05BEAF2661359"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H80BF2BB347D64B00BB5422C6FF400EA5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chronic wasting disease</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>chronic wasting disease</term> means the animal disease afflicting among deer, elk, and moose populations that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5AFE7C73EFD04D5CB30A4009204C65DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a transmissible disease of the nervous system resulting in distinctive lesions in the brain; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4962EDCDF0EB404AB231CC3AC0FFBE2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>belongs to the group of diseases known as transmissible spongiform encephalopathies, which group includes scrapie, bovine spongiform encephalopathy, and Creutzfeldt-Jakob disease.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3A579E436844411B95272FC5BF73383"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible grant recipient</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>eligible grant recipient</quote> means a State department of wildlife, State department of agriculture, college or university, or related research center conducting scientific applied research regarding chronic wasting disease.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H892903DEE73F46D2AA956670F0AD543F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the <act-name parsable-cite="ISDA">Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3EACA298F6974572AD593DCBE493999D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service-Wildlife Services.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H1653686878C3468087B656A05ACF9E29"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H993EFD8913DA4662BE962B34AABC61BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Pursuant to State and Federal law, the States retain primary and policy-making authority with regard to wildlife management, and nothing in this Act interferes with or otherwise affects the primary authority of the States in managing wildlife generally, or managing, surveying, and monitoring the incidence of chronic wasting disease.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96B86A41A3BA488D90B2F07FC3131A4A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chronic wasting disease, the fatal neurological disease found in cervids, is a fundamental threat to the health and vibrancy of deer, elk, and moose populations, and the increased occurrence of chronic wasting disease in regionally diverse locations in recent months necessitates an escalation in applied research, surveillance, monitoring, and management activities focused on containing and managing this lethal disease.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0EA2A4B3B2A44D2AA67430B6A8FA7771"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As the States move to manage existing levels of chronic wasting disease and insulate noninfected wild and captive cervid populations from the disease, the Federal Government should endeavor to provide integrated and holistic financial and technical support to these States and the many State departments of wildlife, State departments of agriculture, colleges and universities, and related research centers conducting scientific applied research regarding chronic wasting disease.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB94D5FEBE04548798A02B3C1D39B8479"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary should provide consistent, coherent, and integrated support structures and programs for the benefit of State wildlife and agricultural administrators, as chronic wasting disease can move freely between captive and wild cervids across the broad array of Federal, State, tribal, and local land management jurisdictions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H654E0A1FAF9E46D29FAA22C4142E340D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary can provide consistent, coherent, and integrated support systems under existing legal authorities to States and the many State departments of wildlife, State departments of agriculture, colleges and universities, and related research centers conducting scientific applied research regarding chronic wasting disease.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H8337CBFCAB9C44E59DD070C995EA3223"><enum>4.</enum><header>Support for State efforts to manage and control chronic wasting disease</header>
 <subsection id="H448AD6044E8D4E2B8D8702BA937ABE42"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Availability of Assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall allocate funds made available under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (e)(1) directly to State and tribal agencies responsible for wildlife management to support State and tribal efforts to develop and implement management strategies to address chronic wasting disease.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H236D9977B0AA41CCA84A20A8A6E5C4C1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Petition process</header><text>A State or tribal agency shall petition the Secretary for a portion of the funds available under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCC22EE9682FC42C089B3160C20F86462"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding Priorities</header><text>In determining the amounts to be allocated to State and tribal agencies under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to States and tribal agencies based on the following criteria:</text>
 <paragraph id="H97BB9C705C2348108E535ED7AF67D286"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Relative scope of incidence of chronic wasting disease on lands of the State or Indian tribe, with priority given to those States and Indian tribes with the highest incidence of the disease.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H94555BA9E03745B7825D69BFC967964F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>State or tribal expenditures on chronic wasting disease management, monitoring, surveillance, and applied research, with priority given to those States and Indian tribes that have shown the greatest financial commitment to managing, monitoring, surveying, and researching chronic wasting disease.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5BD5F9931314C469540724C3174D43E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Comprehensive and integrated State or tribal policies and programs focused on chronic wasting disease management between involved State or tribal wildlife and agricultural agencies, with priority given to those States and Indian tribes that have integrated the programs and policies of all involved agencies related to chronic wasting disease management.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F42D61D897247E6ABC34ABA69AF9323"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Rapid response to new outbreaks of chronic wasting disease, whether occurring in areas in which chronic wasting disease is already found or areas with first infections, with the intent of containing the disease in any new area of infection.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H45EA464BDC394FA3AEE080137FE22A02"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rapid response fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall use funds made available under subsection (e)(1)(C) as a rapid response fund to support State and tribal efforts to control the spread of chronic wasting disease upon the detection of chronic wasting disease among deer, elk, or moose populations not previously infected.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7706CD61DAB84DC7B26AD29002F27597"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="H258BAAE769274F0D8577BA9A47800A82"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $35,000,000 to support State and tribal efforts to manage and control chronic wasting disease, of which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0A82F10B221A49C2B8D74F6E0DB9F100"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$20,000,000 shall be allocated to States under subsection (a);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD08CB3EA97354B9CBCAC116C4D52A5CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$5,000,000 shall be allocated to tribal agencies under subsection (a); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA737B2E1E4724247BF2B84AF9034107B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$10,000,000 shall be retained for the rapid response fund under subsection (d).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FA39E3B8B57459AA14164CB2CE1DB52"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Funds appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations in paragraph (1) shall remain available until expended.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H472E91846EB241048D91AACF87F5F3F2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on administrative costs</header><text>Not more than three percent of the amount appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations in paragraph (1) may be used to cover administrative expenses incurred by the Secretary.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0D9E6D84464D45ACB0F96B1F00D19D6A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Support for applied research regarding chronic wasting disease</header>
 <subsection id="HB455599EDC3547929958D30AA181975F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expansion of applied research Grants</header><text>The Secretary shall make grants to support efforts to expand and accelerate applied research on chronic wasting disease, including (but not limited to) research regarding the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H28183403CEE1497EA4478CA91DB5C453"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sustainable cervid harvest management practices to reduce chronic wasting disease occurrence and to prevent or limit spatial spread of chronic wasting disease.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE678AAD9A0D94433900E2F18DAAC2E2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Management experiments and strategies designed for long-term suppression of chronic wasting disease.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2242C03F30A14D43AD2EBA7DFB83EBBB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Harvest management practices and other practices that exacerbate chronic wasting disease occurrence, with an emphasis on retrospective analyses of available harvest management and chronic wasting disease trend data.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H227E007FD95C409CABD4C7204ABC5AF2"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Factors contributing to local emergence of chronic wasting disease, increased prevalence of chronic wasting disease, and distribution of chronic wasting disease, including mechanisms of disease transmission and effective barriers to transmission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E0317882A93496CA712EF8D428E8B40"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Methods and products to effectively detect infectious prions in, and decontaminate infectious prions from natural environments and inorganic surfaces.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0BC13A8020A74B2C9B7E1B481490E106"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="HF3436A19AE304EA8B254DD39DB1E5A58"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $10,000,000 to make grants under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBFCA1DB2B11448028846C210FF8AFDD1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Funds appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations in paragraph (1) shall remain available until expended.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA23C356942BF4295B75915B00692927D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on administrative costs</header><text>Not more than three percent of the amount appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations in paragraph (1) may be used to cover administrative expenses incurred by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H23839C0F2220474DAEA5F63ED0BBA636"><enum>6.</enum><header>Multi-agency cooperation with States to address chronic wasting disease</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Land management agencies of the Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior shall work cooperatively with States—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8283A04F1AAB44C6817A6A7F959C1F18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the conduct of applied research regarding chronic wasting disease; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H94075ADC2A9F4676BE9278CA618AE424"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the implementation of State chronic wasting disease response plans to reduce the spread and prevalence of chronic wasting disease.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


