<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF9A134579BBF4BF7A81BCAA60EBA7FE3" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4397 IH: California Wildfire Disaster Tax Relief Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4397</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171115">November 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000820">Mrs. Mimi Walters of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001165">Mr. McCarthy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000612">Mr. Denham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide tax relief with respect to California wildfires.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF9AA68136968403699670DB2C446FF71" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD6C94DC1BABA4562A386F4188CA5798D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>California Wildfire Disaster Tax Relief Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3C4694D4DBE64704BD63C77D601ABD93" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="H94B9FA5C9E1B4E01ABFE2C563E3C73D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>California wildfire disaster zone</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>California wildfire disaster zone</term> means that portion of the California wildfire disaster area determined by the President to warrant individual or individual and public assistance from the Federal Government under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act by reason of wildfires in California.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H517B731E35C64BE8B456D56B14470A81"><enum>(2)</enum><header>California wildfire disaster area</header><text>The term <term>California wildfire disaster area</term> means an area with respect to which a major disaster has been declared by the President before November 15, 2017, under section 401 of such Act by reason of wildfires in California.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB60E1A84E4F742249315843164C5E673" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Special disaster-related rules for use of retirement funds</header>
			<subsection id="HFDA51B2699464F4FB955EBC8DC492F4B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Tax-Favored withdrawals from retirement plans</header>
 <paragraph id="H145ECD3F9BAB43578D5B3FA7E739E20C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/72">Section 72(t)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall not apply to any qualified wildfire distribution.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H2868C4CFA0954D19BA4C2B9C190D79F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aggregate dollar limitation</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD93BEC1117144935B1AF35E14F7AE936"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the aggregate amount of distributions received by an individual which may be treated as qualified wildfire distributions for any taxable year shall not exceed the excess (if any) of—</text>
 <clause id="HE15B18ED4A8B419FA20617BACEA2B827"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$100,000, over</text> </clause><clause id="H48A356E7AE994AF99531B2D3562534CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the aggregate amounts treated as qualified wildfire distributions received by such individual for all prior taxable years.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E89E7E99D2B4314BEAD6E94D1C158B1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of plan distributions</header><text>If a distribution to an individual would (without regard to subparagraph (A)) be a qualified wildfire distribution, a plan shall not be treated as violating any requirement of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 merely because the plan treats such distribution as a qualified wildfire distribution, unless the aggregate amount of such distributions from all plans maintained by the employer (and any member of any controlled group which includes the employer) to such individual exceeds $100,000.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69B277E1E3A64BD79611F288C89DB13A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Controlled group</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (B), the term <term>controlled group</term> means any group treated as a single employer under subsection (b), (c), (m), or (o) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/414">section 414</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E037E7B21474AFEB671AE9099F714A5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Amount distributed may be repaid</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB5E77966BD094C78B5CFAB02A284E212"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any individual who receives a qualified wildfire distribution may, at any time during the 3-year period beginning on the day after the date on which such distribution was received, make one or more contributions in an aggregate amount not to exceed the amount of such distribution to an eligible retirement plan of which such individual is a beneficiary and to which a rollover contribution of such distribution could be made under section 402(c), 403(a)(4), 403(b)(8), 408(d)(3), or 457(e)(16), of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as the case may be.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7197766602A4C6E8D4F4267AEF36876"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of repayments of distributions from eligible retirement plans other than IRAs</header><text>For purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, if a contribution is made pursuant to subparagraph (A) with respect to a qualified wildfire distribution from an eligible retirement plan other than an individual retirement plan, then the taxpayer shall, to the extent of the amount of the contribution, be treated as having received the qualified wildfire distribution in an eligible rollover distribution (as defined in section 402(c)(4) of such Code) and as having transferred the amount to the eligible retirement plan in a direct trustee to trustee transfer within 60 days of the distribution.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H104CB32D50704C13A566C99DAEF16BCD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Treatment of repayments for distributions from IRAs</header><text>For purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, if a contribution is made pursuant to subparagraph (A) with respect to a qualified wildfire distribution from an individual retirement plan (as defined by section 7701(a)(37) of such Code), then, to the extent of the amount of the contribution, the qualified wildfire distribution shall be treated as a distribution described in section 408(d)(3) of such Code and as having been transferred to the eligible retirement plan in a direct trustee to trustee transfer within 60 days of the distribution.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF733102322C44FBEB51A5AC1F299658D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="HE12568D499E745D8A62105CBA54A25BB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Qualified wildfire distribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the term <term>qualified wildfire distribution</term> means any distribution from an eligible retirement plan made on or after October 8, 2017, and before January 1, 2019, to an individual whose principal place of abode on October 8, 2017, is located in the California wildfire disaster area and who has sustained an economic loss by reason of the wildfires to which the declaration of such area relates.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE2088E5DE4D4B66A49A065AF4084480"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible retirement plan</header><text>The term <term>eligible retirement plan</term> shall have the meaning given such term by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/402">section 402(c)(8)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB117B9CB2EEB49359C1989F80C4C7A59"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Income inclusion spread over 3-year period</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7ECBA03A5D8443C881E2F57937C39BFA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any qualified wildfire distribution, unless the taxpayer elects not to have this paragraph apply for any taxable year, any amount required to be included in gross income for such taxable year shall be so included ratably over the 3-taxable-year period beginning with such taxable year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50623450CE314A5998AFB9DBBA8D87CE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), rules similar to the rules of subparagraph (E) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/408A">section 408A(d)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall apply.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6F5C97ADB014B71B5D3E8BAE2240849"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <subparagraph id="H53AC1A218A7F4CF6A648763DFB73F530"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Exemption of distributions from trustee to trustee transfer and withholding rules</header><text>For purposes of sections 401(a)(31), 402(f), and 3405 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, qualified wildfire distributions shall not be treated as eligible rollover distributions.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H571FC78F857E44848F6674C9A7F57AA1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified wildfire distributions treated as meeting plan distribution requirements</header><text>For purposes the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, a qualified wildfire distribution shall be treated as meeting the requirements of sections 401(k)(2)(B)(i), 403(b)(7)(A)(ii), 403(b)(11), and 457(d)(1)(A) of such Code.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E029D01AE8F4C958DC7642556F299BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recontributions of withdrawals for home purchases</header>
				<paragraph id="H97743722F8F148AF988D7E91431C47EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Recontributions</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF598C7EF010C4D6F9C531D33018A841F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any individual who received a qualified distribution may, during the period beginning on October 8, 2017, and ending on April 30, 2018, make one or more contributions in an aggregate amount not to exceed the amount of such qualified distribution to an eligible retirement plan (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/402">section 402(c)(8)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) of which such individual is a beneficiary and to which a rollover contribution of such distribution could be made under section 402(c), 403(a)(4), 403(b)(8), or 408(d)(3), of such Code, as the case may be.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC1CF1BF756448148AD06A5CF0A242D8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of repayments</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of subparagraphs (B) and (C) of subsection (a)(3) shall apply for purposes of this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H12E128F64C684932AF00697F04A93381"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified distribution</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>qualified distribution</term> means any distribution—</text> <subparagraph id="H2F725AC596D941A08C833A983802F9EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>described in section 401(k)(2)(B)(i)(IV), 403(b)(7)(A)(ii) (but only to the extent such distribution relates to financial hardship), 403(b)(11)(B), or 72(t)(2)(F), of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C555668155E429FA58389529ABE4C8A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>received after March 31, 2017, and before November 15, 2017, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85D1103A6339400FAF128803D3E20DE9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which was to be used to purchase or construct a principal residence in the California wildfire disaster area but which was not so purchased or constructed on account of the wildfires to which the declaration of such area relates.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF493A1705CE248A6B33A9E5AB2AAAB13"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Loans from qualified plans</header>
 <paragraph id="HC89CBC3385824589B5DDABC1E22B6D1B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Increase in limit on loans not treated as distributions</header><text>In the case of any loan from a qualified employer plan (as defined under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/72">section 72(p)(4)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) to a qualified individual made during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on December 31, 2018—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H86D407853E624AF3A6BCD15B2A5A2B02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>clause (i) of section 72(p)(2)(A) of such Code shall be applied by substituting <quote>$100,000</quote> for <quote>$50,000</quote>, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95FE952DD652424A95779C45EC428171"><enum>(B)</enum><text>clause (ii) of such section shall be applied by substituting <quote>the present value of the nonforfeitable accrued benefit of the employee under the plan</quote> for <quote>one-half of the present value of the nonforfeitable accrued benefit of the employee under the plan</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H011E02861DB6480CADBC87285D555D8F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delay of repayment</header><text>In the case of a qualified individual with an outstanding loan on or after October 8, 2017, from a qualified employer plan (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/72">section 72(p)(4)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H106CCD80CF89459EB70EBDC04EEE07D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the due date pursuant to subparagraph (B) or (C) of section 72(p)(2) of such Code for any repayment with respect to such loan occurs during the period beginning on October 8, 2017, and ending on December 31, 2018, such due date shall be delayed for 1 year,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17F631449BF348A284D26C619BAE86DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any subsequent repayments with respect to any such loan shall be appropriately adjusted to reflect the delay in the due date under paragraph (1) and any interest accruing during such delay, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H072D86E7F1D34201915183E3B96F858A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in determining the 5-year period and the term of a loan under subparagraph (B) or (C) of section 72(p)(2) of such Code, the period described in subparagraph (A) shall be disregarded.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0BA607FD23E4BDCA0C4C5BDAFF62F8A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified individual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>qualified individual</term> means any individual whose principal place of abode on October 8, 2017, is located in the California wildfire disaster area and who has sustained an economic loss by reason of wildfires to which the declaration of such area relates.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14AC8CC8274A41ECB0C4C7AEFABB2872"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Provisions relating to plan amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H6F37C7281DA04410BFB24DE8D8CA05D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If this subsection applies to any amendment to any plan or annuity contract, such plan or contract shall be treated as being operated in accordance with the terms of the plan during the period described in paragraph (2)(B)(i).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H94789175762F4EE48E568E5D81A32ACF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amendments to which subsection applies</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF59C7220638941F58D30F577599C3415"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This subsection shall apply to any amendment to any plan or annuity contract which is made—</text> <clause id="HC42B0252A96E4AB9A0DD3BE4347F4ACF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pursuant to any provision of this section, or pursuant to any regulation issued by the Secretary or the Secretary of Labor under any provision of this section, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAA1F837291F345E79D3F9F4D496E39B7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on or before the last day of the first plan year beginning on or after January 1, 2019, or such later date as the Secretary may prescribe.</text>
						</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">In the case of a governmental plan (as defined in section 414(d) of the Internal Revenue Code of
			 1986), clause (ii) shall be applied by substituting the date which is 2
 years after the date otherwise applied under clause (ii).</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF4E2FDF92D746A7BD5F77218048F4B3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>This subsection shall not apply to any amendment unless—</text> <clause id="HFF1C60E3B17F4588A81C399CC948AE34"><enum>(i)</enum><text>during the period—</text>
 <subclause id="H2A5D23F921FE48C7A416D34261817644"><enum>(I)</enum><text>beginning on the date that this section or the regulation described in subparagraph (A)(i) takes effect (or in the case of a plan or contract amendment not required by this section or such regulation, the effective date specified by the plan), and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H097B676FCCE64037B4837D82D4DB147B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ending on the date described in subparagraph (A)(ii) (or, if earlier, the date the plan or contract amendment is adopted),</text>
 </subclause></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">the plan or contract is operated as if such plan or contract amendment were in effect, and</continuation-text><clause id="H64CB473976C74529BAE16708FCD3252D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such plan or contract amendment applies retroactively for such period.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E3E2DE0DB3B4177BBB6FE6E54A03446" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Employee retention credit for employers affected by California wildfires</header> <subsection id="H1E8CAADBF0194452A59A01AC0DEDAF70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/38">section 38</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, in the case of an eligible employer, the California wildfire employee retention credit shall be treated as a credit listed in subsection (b) of such section. For purposes of this subsection, the California wildfire employee retention credit for any taxable year is an amount equal to 40 percent of the qualified wages with respect to each eligible employee of such employer for such taxable year. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the amount of qualified wages which may be taken into account with respect to any individual shall not exceed $6,000.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0BC261FC30DA4C7C924F08FBAD775315"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H0230FEB66A6445C6B29BF235CB596A09"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible employer</header><text>The term <term>eligible employer</term> means any employer—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6A2E67B35E7D48E4A807296B12204CC8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which conducted an active trade or business on October 8, 2017, in the California wildfire disaster zone, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62ECF41A04A44A25A28D4DC464CA4E67"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to whom the trade or business described in subparagraph (A) is inoperable on any day after October 8, 2017, and before January 1, 2018, as a result of damage sustained by reason of the wildfires to which such declaration of such area relates.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA7392D94DBE403C98A100D8F2B0CA48"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible employee</header><text>The term <term>eligible employee</term> means with respect to an eligible employer an employee whose principal place of employment on October 8, 2017, with such eligible employer was in the California wildfire disaster zone.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H21F342040AA64D238535BE6ED0D31883"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified wages</header><text>The term <term>qualified wages</term> means wages (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/51">section 51(c)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, but without regard to section 3306(b)(2)(B) of such Code) paid or incurred by an eligible employer with respect to an eligible employee on any day after October 8, 2017, and before January 1, 2018, which occurs during the period—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBBA82DB97A2343FD89B2FA1354D88EB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>beginning on the date on which the trade or business described in paragraph (1) first became inoperable at the principal place of employment of the employee immediately before the wildfires to which the declaration of the California wildfire disaster area relates, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB659BFD49F784D4D8097A54636426D00"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ending on the date on which such trade or business has resumed significant operations at such principal place of employment.</text>
					</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Such term shall include wages paid without regard to whether the employee performs no services,
			 performs services at a different place of employment than such principal
			 place of employment, or performs services at such principal place of
 employment before significant operations have resumed.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEBA9A1E8488142ADB4D3DA451C6B5658"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certain rules To apply</header><text>For purposes of this section, rules similar to the rules of sections 51(i)(1) and 52, of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, shall apply.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H14C0FC8BE6544E748BFBBB4ECF89CD12"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Employee not taken into account more than once</header><text>An employee shall not be treated as an eligible employee for purposes of this section for any period with respect to any employer if such employer is allowed a credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/51">section 51</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to such employee for such period.</text>
			</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H659D15D7C1664270968393116D2158C5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Additional disaster-related tax relief provisions</header>
			<subsection id="H553D15EEBFAE4FE4B580382D5ABB6173"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Temporary suspension of limitations on charitable contributions</header>
 <paragraph id="HBB40F455437041F7A33E8D7D33E3EB3D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (2), subsection (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">section 170</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall not apply to qualified contributions and such contributions shall not be taken into account for purposes of applying subsections (b) and (d) of such section to other contributions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H26F6DD0E35A7480196015E82BB720AF7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of excess contributions</header><text>For purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">section 170</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986—</text> <subparagraph id="H9B2FC6B27E5445FD86C46FBA69B2DD9A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Individuals</header><text>In the case of an individual—</text>
 <clause id="HEE7BF6AC81ED478484DECBFEE14A856F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Any qualified contribution shall be allowed only to the extent that the aggregate of such contributions does not exceed the excess of the taxpayer’s contribution base (as defined in subparagraph (G) of section 170(b)(1) of such Code) over the amount of all other charitable contributions allowed under section 170(b)(1) of such Code.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE5D8AD2CD46E4F53849C71799D8AABF9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Carryover</header><text>If the aggregate amount of qualified contributions made in the contribution year (within the meaning of section 170(d)(1) of such Code) exceeds the limitation of clause (i), such excess shall be added to the excess described in the portion of subparagraph (A) of such section which precedes clause (i) thereof for purposes of applying such section.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47FA55DBF1CC41AB8ED155D1EDBC7882"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Corporations</header><text>In the case of a corporation—</text> <clause id="HC847167AFB6346BF8E24924585668B9B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Any qualified contribution shall be allowed only to the extent that the aggregate of such contributions does not exceed the excess of the taxpayer’s taxable income (as determined under paragraph (2) of section 170(b) of such Code) over the amount of all other charitable contributions allowed under such paragraph.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H78BDA570A5F641ADAE3183FD970EAE67"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Carryover</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of subparagraph (A)(ii) shall apply for purposes of this subparagraph.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79C9486F963144DAB4DD7B0699F6C8D9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception to overall limitation on itemized deductions</header><text>So much of any deduction allowed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">section 170</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 as does not exceed the qualified contributions paid during the taxable year shall not be treated as an itemized deduction for purposes of section 68 of such Code.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HA66D233661964334832C3F5ED3FE4E79"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualified contributions</header>
 <subparagraph id="HEA815F872BD2404FAC176DB405689C88"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>qualified contribution</term> means any charitable contribution (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">section 170(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) if—</text>
 <clause id="HC53941D0D3E340D5B690F48A1A4E4999"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such contribution—</text> <subclause id="HE762EA552FCA425CA3E62A32322B5FB6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is paid during the period beginning on October 8, 2017, and ending on December 31, 2017, in cash to an organization described in section 170(b)(1)(A) of such Code, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF8611EC96AB24241B8DDA0981A421AEB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is made for relief efforts in the California wildfire disaster area,</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HA20B0C4995DA401F98619A1B2F1F95A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the taxpayer obtains from such organization contemporaneous written acknowledgment (within the meaning of section 170(f)(8) of such Code) that such contribution was used (or is to be used) for relief efforts described in clause (i)(II), and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEE431ABEC8D4483380C071EE14D0FD41"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the taxpayer has elected the application of this subsection with respect to such contribution.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE61CBAFBCDEF42FD929825776FCC68A5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Such term shall not include a contribution by a donor if the contribution is—</text>
 <clause id="H2808D4A3F8DE4E58913BD57DE12B7DFA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/509">section 509(a)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, or</text> </clause><clause id="H1094A4EBAEFF463A91DBD89F9F6A02B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for the establishment of a new, or maintenance of an existing, donor advised fund (as defined in section 4966(d)(2) of such Code).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5485E46FCD354030B2B2D5E5A77F665B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application of election to partnerships and S corporations</header><text>In the case of a partnership or S corporation, the election under subparagraph (A)(iii) shall be made separately by each partner or shareholder.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H03EA05B2C09E4A5C926277B85EFA162C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special rules for qualified disaster-Related personal casualty losses</header>
 <paragraph id="H0E206DBDAFF74AB19871FED4CBB9AF8B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual has a net disaster loss for any taxable year—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H19B30F9C32E248F4A69ADA4B746AE8A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount determined under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/165">section 165(h)(2)(A)(ii)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be equal to the sum of—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H20ACDDE67BB247B0BDC4FE4F36569D66"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such net disaster loss, and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H506402661A344758B4EAAE0ECF6E611A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>so much of the excess referred to in the matter preceding clause (i) of section 165(h)(2)(A) of such Code (reduced by the amount in clause (i) of this subparagraph) as exceeds 10 percent of the adjusted gross income of the individual,</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55A156C62A234818A9135A6FCAC7D5D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 165(h)(1) of such Code shall be applied by substituting <quote>$500</quote> for <quote>$500 ($100 for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2009)</quote>,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7F69765AD304F72B7B55CA581AD8670"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the standard deduction determined under section 63(c) of such Code shall be increased by the net disaster loss, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33F1925CBF644061BD0DB61BFB63B24B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>section 56(b)(1)(E) of such Code shall not apply to so much of the standard deduction as is attributable to the increase under subparagraph (C) of this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D7B25DEFADF45829645A8BA8FB0ADE3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Net disaster loss</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>net disaster loss</term> means the excess of qualified disaster-related personal casualty losses over personal casualty gains (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/165">section 165(h)(3)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H787542FF04F5459FBAA192A9CDE3C5A4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified disaster-related personal casualty losses</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>qualified disaster-related personal casualty losses</term> means losses described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/165">section 165(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 which arise in the California wildfire disaster area on or after October 8, 2017, and which are attributable to the wildfires to which the declaration of such area relates.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC4C15D2D3FBA4D519A0FB769A775E58D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rule for determining earned income</header>
 <paragraph id="H3F931104437840C582075C66EC300DEA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a qualified individual, if the earned income of the taxpayer for the taxable year which includes the applicable date is less than the earned income of the taxpayer for the preceding taxable year, the credits allowed under sections 24(d) and 32 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 may, at the election of the taxpayer, be determined by substituting—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA2C9DEC400F34E529F1476A77B02F5F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such earned income for the preceding taxable year, for</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A3FA180843F442DA713A33A198F27A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such earned income for the taxable year which includes October 8, 2017.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6F94ADB38534225999240A583C5D55B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified individual</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>qualified individual</term> means any individual whose principal place of abode on October 8, 2017, was located—</text> <subparagraph id="H4B6B6C345416448FB5FFEAE0BFC2C78F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the California wildfire disaster zone, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF67B09DFFFFE4251B9DCF3AA8CEC3B4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the California wildfire disaster area (but outside the California wildfire disaster zone) and such individual was displaced from such principal place of abode by reason of the wildfires to which the declaration of such area relates.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C8EA53DEF284BD097ADBF66B0083346"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Earned income</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>earned income</term> has the meaning given such term under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/32">section 32(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEBA1AB06C195480283242FB338774254"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special rules</header> <subparagraph id="HBAFFE77A62104EAA8BBB3F0399C37604"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application to joint returns</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), in the case of a joint return for a taxable year which includes October 8, 2017—</text>
 <clause id="H3E6B32C1B3834C479FDFC6C8C86737D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such paragraph shall apply if either spouse is a qualified individual, and</text> </clause><clause id="H1FC75A9FD8204B40939DAC1AB1AC4A93"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the earned income of the taxpayer for the preceding taxable year shall be the sum of the earned income of each spouse for such preceding taxable year.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E6A2B7334A44B45B7D54153AE7E1B43"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Uniform application of election</header><text>Any election made under paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to both sections 24(d) and 32, of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12518ECAE6244F2DB4F0D91015285AD8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Errors treated as mathematical error</header><text>For purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6213">section 6213</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, an incorrect use on a return of earned income pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be treated as a mathematical or clerical error.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86388BB71CE94A9CB6E97E5BE23CC246"><enum>(D)</enum><header>No effect on determination of gross income, etc</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be applied without regard to any substitution under paragraph (1).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA816F712D3A84A6BA1674A64B5A85D98"><enum>6.</enum><header>Budgetary effects</header>
 <subsection id="HAC1ED625CB7042948AC3F7C1757E382F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Emergency designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act is designated as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 4(g) of the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/933">2 U.S.C. 933(g)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H532D76C2FACC41339FAC401A9D7040C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation in Senate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the Senate, this Act is designated as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 403(a) of S. Con. Res. 13 (111th Congress), the concurrent resolution on the budget for fiscal year 2010.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


