<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6AAD1B1F932A48A7B743DADE118C6B07" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1015 IH: Complete America’s Great Trails Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1015</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170213">February 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a credit against income tax for qualified
			 conservation contributions which include National Scenic Trails.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB80F10F66FFE41119B50580CCB00B4B7" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4DA6E0129F804E44ACBA38371E896642" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Complete America’s Great Trails Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H656B37BA57044DFE92FAE5043F9140B8"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Scenic Trail conservation credit</header> <subsection id="HA58570B70A8E4DF699DEE85E19A44E8F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart B of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7053C4778D2F4E3294166BB708F49E5A" style="OLC">
					<section id="H084B5CAB6AC64BA1BB994F58C2E8EE6A"><enum>30E.</enum><header>National Scenic Trail conservation credit</header>
 <subsection id="H17FD82B672E14B5196858F46BB0900DF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year an amount equal to the fair market value of any National Scenic Trail conservation contribution of the taxpayer for the taxable year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1FA82B282E5B4B4F9ACD400710E07828"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National Scenic Trail conservation contribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="HB1BA01878DF642EFBBDC5A4A5F6DB0CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>National Scenic Trail conservation contribution</term> means any qualified conservation contribution—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7F76FE85EF3144B782C235C9F08E2A8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the extent the qualified real property interest with respect to such contribution includes a National Scenic Trail (or portion thereof) and its trail corridor, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A8C855F8F4940AB9C27CE0A1277934B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to which the taxpayer makes an election under this section.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8DA262D7B114F1E9E09ACAEE995C949"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Scenic Trail</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>National Scenic Trail</term> means any trail authorized and designated under section 5 of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1244">16 U.S.C. 1244</external-xref>), but only if such trail is at least 200 miles in length.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0395176C1CB54E38A50C46268DC14F84"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Trail corridor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>trail corridor</quote> means so much of the corridor of a trail as is—</text> <subparagraph id="H2CBAA09A9DF746E1873CE81371E02C19"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less than—</text>
 <clause id="HC756246D4AA14823B9A1A8066F517C99"><enum>(i)</enum><text>150 feet wide on each side of such trail, or</text> </clause><clause id="H2E93377CA4534E378056E21721DC8061"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of an interest in real property of the taxpayer which includes less than 150 feet on either side of such trail, the entire distance with respect to such interest on such side, and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14D84B3A7146456E9E0A4F739D5AF1C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not greater than 2,640 feet wide.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE732B1BFBDDC4CE58ACD70770E4BAEC0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualified conservation contribution; qualified real property interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>qualified conservation contribution</term> and <term>qualified real property interest</term> have the respective meanings given such terms by section 170(h), except that paragraph (2)(A) thereof shall be applied without regard to any qualified mineral interest (as defined in paragraph (6) thereof).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H61700959A6BC4DBBAA6923E0BCED5635"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <paragraph id="H91C47C3238814A67B991B64F7A02A4DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fair market value</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fair market value of any National Scenic Trail conservation contribution shall be determined under rules similar to the valuation rules under Treasury Regulations under section 170, except that in any case, to the extent practicable, fair market value shall be determined by reference to the highest and best use of the real property with respect to such contribution.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB5B3FDC814B04F7BB4E2650CFBB078D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Election irrevocable</header><text>An election under this section may not be revoked.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8BAB412528B4E67A3E6F1CB454205F6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>No deduction shall be allowed under this chapter with respect to any qualified conservation contribution with respect to which an election is made under this section.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA2AA80490DA4F44A22058BB7B519EC8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application with other credits</header>
 <paragraph id="H83E8A2DB4A2D47218D1EFC73BCF5F99E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Business credit treated as part of general business credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">So much of the credit which would be allowed under subsection (a) for any taxable year (determined without regard to this subsection) that is attributable to property used in a trade or business or held for the production of income shall be treated as a credit listed in section 38(b) for such taxable year (and not allowed under subsection (a)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8339099A33504F1C98AFB93D9F624BC8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Personal credit</header><text>For purposes of this title, the credit allowed under subsection (a) for any taxable year (determined after application of paragraph (1)) shall be treated as a credit allowable under subpart A for such taxable year.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H912B174573DD43B8BAC491BCCF6CBC70"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Carryforward of unused credit</header>
 <paragraph id="HF0DC3FA7A21A424FA753C0EA0CB241E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the credit allowable under subsection (a) exceeds the limitation imposed by section 26(a) for any taxable year reduced by the sum of the credit allowable under subpart A (other than this section), such excess shall be carried to the succeeding taxable year and added to the credit allowable under subsection (a) for such succeeding taxable year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4263E38A6D7949DF801AD39772884F44"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No credit may be carried forward under this subsection to any taxable year following the tenth taxable year after the taxable year in which the credit arose. For purposes of the preceding sentence, credits shall be treated as used on a first-in first-out basis.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC59964AE9F6D4257A1D925AF6BD8BF39"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Continued use not inconsistent with conservation purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A contribution of an interest in real property shall not fail to be treated as a National Scenic Trail conservation contribution (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/30E">section 30E(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) solely by reason of continued use of the real property, such as for recreational or agricultural use (including motor vehicle use related thereto), if, under the circumstances, such use does not impair significant conservation interests and is not inconsistent with the purposes of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1241">16 U.S.C. 1241</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HDC14D8E4872A448FAFF035AF9970E557"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Study regarding efficacy of National Scenic Trail conservation credit</header>
 <paragraph id="H549895D9058244479E068092DE79EA58"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, study—</text> <subparagraph id="H1C666889DE014C00A81777E8917D92A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the efficacy of the National Scenic Trail conservation credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/30E">section 30E</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 in completing, extending, and increasing the number of National Scenic Trails (as defined in section 30E(b) of such Code), and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C4904240FB942A4B95C44182158C8EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the feasibility and estimated costs and benefits of—</text> <clause id="H5C7551807D7942789AEFAED2AA652DC7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>making such credit refundable (in whole or in part), and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H06F5D066FF7A49B88D9239C86131AF15"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>allowing transfer of such credit.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5878890331DF4AD7BD2BC7386DF3148A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior shall submit a report to Congress on the results of the study conducted under this subsection.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H30C70D4B1470421E839548EBF35C2459"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="HC1D3F40ED4BF4A678180DD73F6BABAB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/23">Section 23(c)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>, 30E,</quote> after <quote>25D</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H66D1E996485F4BF1B73277982B4E19B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 25(e)(1)(C) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>30E,</quote> after <quote>25D,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H88F384E404454CCE99E349491299AE0A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 25D(c) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>and section 25D</quote> after <quote>other than this section</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H97512D1039B04B288254946D7A31AFD5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart B of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFCBFE9FD626544DCAF9B0D3206952316" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 30E. National Scenic Trail conservation credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8D2E6F76B6AF4982ADFC7162BE146B71"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to contributions made after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


