<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H03BEA94B58124B39BD2460BF33DBEB49" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2076 IH: Ending Homelessness Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2076</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide a path to end homelessness in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H36369F98C3254B0596020578A2804480" style="OLC">
 <section id="H242CD276E8D447DB82301C94E394AD76" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ending Homelessness Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H91CC99161BA74623B93E8B061E7CEA23" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCB83BB9E1F0D4AB6B59D5FEE3F80F556"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">although the United States has experienced a reduction in veteran homelessness after a surge of new Federal funding targeted to homeless veterans starting in fiscal year 2008, major progress towards the national goals for ending homelessness in our Nation has virtually stalled in the absence of increased funding;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8BC819B29C44FCABD0C1E58C7BAC741"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">according to the Department of Housing and Urban Development’s 2016 point-in-time count, there were 549,928 people experiencing homelessness in the United States on any given night, including over 120,000 children;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H887227C0872844E29DA2FDD342F7741D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>homelessness in many communities has reached crisis proportions and some cities have declared that homelessness has reached a state of emergency; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D4D46C0CC7C4FD9877D8827476FDFD2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Federal Government must renew its commitment to the national goals to end homelessness.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HAE863F4D2F4D40BD84A4D82CAC16CC71"><enum>3.</enum><header>Emergency relief funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title IV of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11360">42 U.S.C. 11360</external-xref> et seq) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1DAEC0453FFD4EFC8BA9B70F9EF2E580"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 491 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11408">42 U.S.C. 11408</external-xref>; relating to rural housing stability grant program) as section 441;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2F023A4FD7A482AAB69CC43BFF052A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating section 592 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11408a">42 U.S.C. 11408a</external-xref>; relating to use of FMHA inventory for transitional housing for homeless persons and for turnkey housing) as section 442; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD2F4CF243C447929EFCF7E8FB71E3A9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subtitle:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB11FCCEF22EE4B07A9F5FAA7D86ECE66" style="OLC"> <subtitle id="HE256837A50D545BFAF5495CA70601ADA"><enum>E</enum><header>5-Year path To end homelessness</header> <section id="H060A3CFFD14A4C45A4F4A5F38AC7F021"><enum>451.</enum><header>Emergency relief funding</header> <subsection id="H2FD0B8DB800B4D808D7A736B82505156"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Direct appropriations</header><text>There is appropriated out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, $1,000,000,000, to remain available until expended, for emergency relief grants under this section to address the unmet needs of homeless populations in jurisdictions with the highest need.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H9CF7C8830D5C4888B913555C3B44B679"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Formula grants</header>
 <paragraph id="HB683B8F25AB54FE5BAD9F127F8E93F6A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts appropriated under subsection (a) for a fiscal year shall be allocated among collaborative applicants that comply with section 402, in accordance with the funding formula established under paragraph (2) of this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E978F29086B43B598D0F272DA63F7C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Formula</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, in consultation with the United States Interagency Council on Homeless, establish a formula for allocating grant amounts under this section to address the unmet needs of homeless populations in jurisdictions with the highest need, using the best currently available data that targets need based on key structural determinants of homelessness in the geographic area represented by a collaborative applicant, which shall include data providing accurate counts of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE7A9FAF9BF3148648A11EA8605445FAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the poverty rate in the geographic area represented by the collaborative applicant;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B2BC624F26842F9A83CB28F4C44C604"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shortages of affordable housing for low-, very low-, and extremely low-income households in the geographic area represented by the collaborative applicant;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CE6E97482164C97B09422F4A9D33D40"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of overcrowded housing units in the geographic area represented by the collaborative applicant;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90076A31477E45C1B5923476385B26AC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of unsheltered homeless individuals and the number of chronically homeless individuals; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C3BE334E1B74E4FB3C69838B2222FFD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other factors that the Secretary considers appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F856E5D89224EC1AA01DAE80C733F5F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year for which amounts are made available under subsection (a), the Secretary shall make a grant to each collaborative applicant for which an amount is allocated pursuant to application of the formula established pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection in an amount that is equal to the formula amount determined for such collaborative applicant.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H9F0106DA1AAC47D2A8111ED7F998EA37"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Timing</header>
 <subparagraph id="H430D4F62A58A45A29CBC01E18833ECC2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Formula to be devised swiftly</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The funding formula required under paragraph (2) shall be established not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5238F210342401394F1BD5C4B539218"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>Amounts appropriated or otherwise made available under this section shall be distributed according to the funding formula established pursuant to paragraph (2) not later than 30 days after the establishment of such formula.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4E8F4056C264B33913A8E6EE4ACE8E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of grants</header>
 <paragraph id="H2697CBEF5EBB4390BC207F98A18F30AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraphs (2) through (4), a collaborative applicant that receives a grant under this section may use such grant amounts only for eligible activities under section 415, 423, or 441(b).</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H745D10C4295A404DBD6C595D779FC430"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permanent supportive housing requirement</header>
 <subparagraph id="HAE412451AC1B407AB681106451130FCB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), each collaborative applicant that receives a grant under this section shall use not less than 75 percent of such grant amount for permanent supportive housing, including capital costs, rental subsidies, and services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A8399AF93E34ABCA30BEF5FBD8AC162"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall exempt a collaborative applicant from the applicability of the requirement under subparagraph (A) if the applicant demonstrates, in accordance with such standards and procedures as the Secretary shall establish, that—</text>
 <clause id="H6FCD7D9A8246405DB1B9E2B898CBFEA8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>chronic homelessness has been functionally eliminated in the geographic area served by the applicant; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H88BF5CA63BC742278BA90F5C2A7294F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the permanent supportive housing under development in the geographic area served by the applicant is sufficient to functionally eliminate chronic homelessness once such units are available for occupancy.</text>
										</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">The Secretary shall consider and make a determination regarding each request for an exemption under
 this subparagraph not later than 60 days after receipt of such request.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8854159398A84CB7AF656F334E71CD12"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on use for administrative expenses</header><text>Not more than 5 percent of the total amount of any grant under this section to a collaborative applicant may be used for costs of administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE0A737EE6D84B34B622318EA57670B0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Housing First requirement</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that each collaborative applicant that receives a grant under this section is implementing, to the extent possible, and will use such grant amounts in accordance with, a Housing First model for assistance for homeless persons.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5BD549D582FD416F9B495C34715D36F7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Renewal funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expiring contracts for leasing, rental assistance, or permanent housing shall be treated, for purposes of section 429, as expiring contracts referred to in subsection (a) of such section.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HE0B202B092CA4251AE2ACED613EC1CF2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting to Congress</header>
 <paragraph id="H763A4C6021494AEAB84D220289B2728F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 1, 2017, the Secretary and the United States Interagency Council on Homelessness shall submit a report to the Committees on Financial Services and Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and Appropriations of the Senate describing the design and implementation of the grant program under this section, which shall include the formula required by subsection (b)(2).</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H2C51CD3DA2524DC4AA519EF97F22ACE6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Semiannual status reports</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC0856435B64746A6A8B5609DB23BD741"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reports to congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and the United States Interagency Council on Homelessness shall submit reports to the Committees specified in paragraph (1) semiannually describing the operation of the grant program under this section during the preceding 6 months, including identification of the grants made and a description of the activities funded with grant amounts.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69E70B82012E4CEAB635186884004478"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Collection of information by Secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall require each collaborative applicant that receives a grant under this section to submit such information to the Secretary as may be necessary for the Secretary to comply with the reporting requirement under subparagraph (A).</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDFB06DEA414E4E27A81412B4932C1229" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>452.</enum><header>Special purpose vouchers</header>
 <subsection id="HE2531401A0C54419AC6A0DACB5992679"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Direct appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is appropriated out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, $500,000,000, to remain available until expended, which shall be used as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H4D32E10FC3004A8F84E6C890419016BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rental Assistance</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), such amount shall be used for incremental assistance for rental assistance under section 8(o) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)</external-xref>) for persons and households who are homeless (as such term is defined in section 103 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11302">42 U.S.C. 11302</external-xref>)), which assistance shall be in addition to such assistance provided pursuant to renewal of expiring contracts for such assistance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H85BA516363BA4A048FA5D83A093177FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may use not more than 10 percent of such amounts provided for each fiscal year for administrative fees under 8(q) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(q)</external-xref>). The Secretary shall establish policies and procedures to provide such fees to the extent necessary to assist homeless persons and families on whose behalf rental assistance is provided to find and maintain suitable housing.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H26BEA9D33A09455E9F08A1257BB856EC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make assistance provided under this section available to public housing agencies based on geographical need for such assistance by homeless persons and households, as identified by the Secretary, public housing agency administrative performance, and other factors as specified by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H18071882FC664B16B5D877CDAD4A4D67"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Assistance made available under this section shall continue to remain available only for homeless persons and households upon turn-over.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H138EA15FD3434A5FAF8FE6EF32953258"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Renewal funding</header><text>Renewal of expiring contracts for rental assistance provided under subsection (a) and for administrative fees under such subsection shall, to the extent provided in appropriation Acts, be funded under the section 8 tenant-based rental assistance account.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF5F4AE7068CE48CAB25A0FF02F028FD4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Waiver authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon a finding by the Secretary that a waiver or alternative requirement pursuant to this subsection is necessary to ensure that homeless persons and households can obtain housing using rental assistance made available under this section, the Secretary may waive, or specify alternative requirements for, any provision of any statute or regulation that the Secretary administers in connection with the use of funds made available under this section (except for requirements related to fair housing, nondiscrimination, labor standards, and the environment) that relates to screening of applicants for assistance, admission of applicants, and selection of tenants. The Secretary shall require public housing agencies receiving rental assistance funding made available under this section to take all reasonable actions to help assisted persons and families avoid subsequent homelessness.</text>
							</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4332B0461D947619EA2D65A9BBF8691" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>453.</enum><header>Outreach funding</header>
 <subsection id="H18D2FA8FA53648FFB83DE7310458A8D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Direct appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is appropriated out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, $100,000,000, to remain available until expended, to the Secretary for grants under this section to provide outreach and coordinate services for persons and households who are homeless or formerly homeless.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HA45ADABDF1FA4FABB642E983BC195BDF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants</header>
 <paragraph id="HDCF554768DDC4B25B1CCD8A320A19CBD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make grants under this section on a competitive basis only to collaborative applicants who comply with section 402.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6790DB60CD2B4BFD85F14860E514F186"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The competition for grants under this section shall provide priority to collaborative applicants who submit plans to make innovative and effective use of staff funded with grant amounts pursuant to subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8D09A2A3F52944BE8024CBEB3A74AF51"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A collaborative applicant that receives a grant under this section may use such grant amounts only for providing case managers, social workers, or other staff who conduct outreach and coordinate services for persons and households who are homeless or formerly homeless.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H3274C83AC36148879AAC71A632079AC9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Timing</header>
 <paragraph id="H9E8D4E36F6D84C2A9DD5F9C74CDB67C3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Criteria to be established swiftly</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish the criteria for the competition for grants under this section required under subsection (b) not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5354A61F1BC4EC6BF227278E8D6C487"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>Amounts appropriated or otherwise made available under this section shall be distributed according to the competition established by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (b) not later than 30 days after the establishment of such criteria.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H607FAE929AA44D0586215E4351EF1724" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Housing Trust Fund</header>
			<subsection id="H57ABC495B1354304BE8D5C79A2BB31AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Funding</header>
 <paragraph id="HE44C99B9095141119FC87AE1F16D2946"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for fiscal year 2018 and each fiscal year thereafter, $1,000,000,000, to remain available until expended, which shall be credited to the Housing Trust Fund established pursuant to section 1338 of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4568">12 U.S.C. 4568</external-xref>) for use under such section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE855C62B4C3E4872BB482B17D769A42F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rental assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for fiscal year 2018 and each fiscal year thereafter, $50,000,000, to remain available until expended, for incremental project-based voucher assistance or project-based rental assistance, to be allocated to States pursuant to the formula established under section 1338 of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4568">12 U.S.C. 4568</external-xref>), to be used solely in conjunction with grant funds awarded under such section 1338.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H877677E6B2354453B90F1BB0B03293F0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority for housing the homeless</header>
 <subparagraph id="H96B29972BD884B4C886EED8AAE70A0E6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the first 5 fiscal years that amounts are made available under this subsection, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall ensure that priority for occupancy in dwelling units described in subparagraph (B) that become available for occupancy shall be given to persons and households who are homeless (as such term is defined in section 103 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11302">42 U.S.C. 11302</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6073BE2FCF0140C09337DE4A24819A80"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered dwelling units</header><text>A dwelling unit described in this subparagraph is any dwelling unit that—</text> <clause id="HACF50C1FD00145FA9DD480216EEA6C39"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is located in housing that was at any time provided assistance with any amounts from the Housing Trust Fund referred to paragraph (1) that were credited to such Trust Fund by such paragraph; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC83CFD64BDD64551A371A7E45434D3B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is receiving assistance described in paragraph (2) with amounts made available under such paragraph.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H47D332B3B5B846CF8149CD0E3310EBDF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tenant rent contribution</header>
 <paragraph id="HA075058C10364A399926C5180A834680"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) of section 1338(c)(7) of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4568">12 U.S.C. 4568(c)(7)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6E744D67A0A14369918B5A07D26A4EC8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>except that not less than 75 percent</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE8701B1B99A34018ADDDFB7E329C4C1F" style="OLC"> <text>except that—</text><clause id="HBF3C2579C5FE4E508B57A25074CC2C57"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 75 percent</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADC705F0918B47179F3B65B1A06C5AB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCFD8830A6C874A3383AF2568B15FC8D1" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H098ED8955F7047CF9104119171778DA2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding any other provision of law, all rental housing dwelling units shall be subject to legally binding commitments that ensure that the contribution toward rent by a family residing in the dwelling unit shall not exceed 30 percent of the adjusted income (as such term is defined in section 3(b) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)</external-xref>)) of such family; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5E5B61A4A084F8E9D35647BCD6E47F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall issue regulations to implement section 1338(c)(7)(A)(ii) of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992, as added by the amendment made by paragraph (1)(B) of this section, not later than the expiration of the 90-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD8FC16CABE2D4C3CAAE732C3F7A024CE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Technical assistance funds to help states and local organizations align health and housing systems</header>
 <subsection id="H07B78E9F91C246949F3D5E135C79149A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby made available to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development $20,000,000, to remain available until expended, for providing technical assistance under section 405 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11361">42 U.S.C. 11361(b)</external-xref>) in connection with expanding the Healthcare and Housing (H2) Systems Integration Initiative of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, in collaboration with the United States Interagency Council on Homelessness and the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFA75ADC1D9CF444D898AFE4850D862F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In expanding the Initiative referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary shall seek to—</text> <paragraph id="HA8A9C7A6EFBC4ACD9D5BD5977E2D225A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assist States and localities in integrating and aligning policies and funding between Medicaid programs, behavioral health providers, and housing providers to create supportive housing opportunities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEBABB7607C0045EEB638A03F2BE633D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>engages State Medicaid program directors, Governors, State housing and homelessness agencies, any other relevant State offices, and any relevant local government entities, to assist States in increasing use of their Medicaid programs to finance supportive services for homeless persons.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H67ED11B525B04FF786B9ECAA74004AC1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In using amounts made available under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to use for States and localities having the highest numbers of chronically homeless persons.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HCE430A947E2E4717B379F9C356E32C81"><enum>6.</enum><header>Permanent authorization of appropriations for McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 408 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11364">42 U.S.C. 11364</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC38F18D821DD4767BFF91A93F6FF7075" style="OLC">
 <section id="H12FACEF6BCBB4BBA91B0402A037CD13B"><enum>408.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this title such sums as may be necessary for each fiscal year.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HA9EA7CC855D049898609B4F8782D9CC5"><enum>7.</enum><header>Permanent extension of United States Interagency Council on Homelessness</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 209 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11319">42 U.S.C. 11319</external-xref>) is hereby repealed.</text> </section><section id="H2CA671AED382495EBCDB4639DF881D87"><enum>8.</enum><header>Emergency designation</header> <subsection id="HD354171A8FA64EE5AE35D90A9E3E28E4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amounts provided by this Act, and the amendments made by this Act, are designated as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 4(g) of the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/933">2 U.S.C. 933(g)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEBC7CB2A84974ABB850A77BF136CFAFE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation in Senate</header><text>In the Senate, this Act and the amendments made by this Act are designated as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 403(a) of S. Con. Res. 13 (111th Congress), the concurrent resolution on the budget for fiscal year 2010.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


