<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF628269F5659458C90D7A12FAFABAAA1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1342 IH: FILCCA of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1342</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170302">March 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000374">Mr. Abraham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000055">Mr. Aderholt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001062">Mr. Conaway</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000563">Mr. Gibbs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000388">Mr. Kelly of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000362">Mr. King of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000597">Mr. Rice of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000051">Mr. Sanford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000583">Mr. Smith of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit any institution of higher education that receives a Federal research and development
			 grant and does not comply with a lawful request for information or
			 detainment of an alien made by any officer or employee of the Federal
			 Government who is charged with enforcement of the immigration laws from
			 receiving indirect cost reimbursement funding, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF415ADC3F0EC45EAB527067BB762CEA3" style="OLC">
 <section id="HDB3C89C6B1FD4D648F033105AA0F83EB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Immigration Law Campus Compliance Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or as the <quote>FILCCA of 2017</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H614644037CA24781AE59C5B07E842BAF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on receipt of funds for indirect costs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An institution of higher education (as defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)) may not receive Federal funds for reimbursement of indirect costs under a research and development grant provided by a Federal agency with respect to any period during which the institution of higher education has failed to comply with a lawful request for information about or detainer pertaining to an alien made by any officer or employee of the Federal Government who is charged with enforcement of the immigration laws.</text>
		</section><section id="HB19D5BCE89AC418686784B4DB2D09744"><enum>3.</enum><header>Ensuring that local and Federal law enforcement officers may cooperate to safeguard our communities</header>
 <subsection id="H38E805E7CA9241B787B55950AED674D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To cooperate with federal officials</header><text>A State, a political subdivision of a State, or an officer, employee, or agent of such State or political subdivision that complies with a detainer issued by the Department of Homeland Security under section 236 or 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1226">8 U.S.C. 1226</external-xref> and 1357)—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8A58B8ED5B3A434181D4B49EA189AB87"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be deemed to be acting as an agent of the Department of Homeland Security; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEEF5025681C142E8885E33B6ACBD91BF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with regard to actions taken to comply with the detainer, shall have all authority available to officers and employees of the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB943EBE78D5349E8912D0BEE95E16562"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Legal proceedings</header><text>In any legal proceeding brought against a State, a political subdivision of a State, or an officer, employee, or agent of such State or political subdivision, which challenges the legality of the seizure or detention of an individual pursuant to a detainer issued by the Department of Homeland Security under section 236 or 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1226">8 U.S.C. 1226</external-xref> and 1357)—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFC7192F573344636BB420D21BA13B88E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>no liability shall lie against the State or political subdivision of a State for actions taken in compliance with the detainer; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6235B98CC6CB4AEFAA103619B0C6F030"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the actions of the officer, employee, or agent of the State or political subdivision were taken in compliance with the detainer—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H711F7073B3DE42408AC023AE8B24E863"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the officer, employee, or agent shall be deemed—</text> <clause id="H49CD7672DFA246CABB4FD1419BB4D89B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to be an employee of the Federal Government and an investigative or law enforcement officer; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC312E50F30FF473DBF57FF939FE68718"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to have been acting within the scope of his or her employment under section 1346(b) and <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C21D926D2724745B91C96354E603E03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 1346(b) of title 28, United States Code, shall provide the exclusive remedy for the plaintiff; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H337528115C5845A0ADC2D3DA29ED0FD8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the United States shall be substituted as defendant in the proceeding.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H255D3E7CAB6F48B4B072039A8DD946BF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to provide immunity to any person who knowingly violates the civil or constitutional rights of an individual.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H3BC36720D173454BBC821583AC11B7D8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization to issue detainers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the case of an alien who is in the custody of a Federal, State, or local law enforcement official, the Secretary of Homeland Security may issue a detainer for that alien requesting that the law enforcement official provide all relevant information collected pertaining to the alien and notification of any future release of the alien, or that the law enforcement official continue to detain the alien until the Secretary may take custody of the alien. The Secretary of Homeland Security is authorized to request from any entity that receives Federal funds in a fiscal year, for purposes of enforcing the immigration laws, pertinent information that pertains to an alien and that is not otherwise precluded by law from being disclosed.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


