<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H92EE3DE876E049568E99080CB22260CC" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3185 IH: Reforms to Encourage VA Meaningful Progress Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3185</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170711">July 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to evaluate the organizational structure of the
			 Veterans Health Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H461721F45F92488D8F1ABF6A2FD7D3B1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7A74EF945B7E4A3F9AB98FE79DF4355C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reforms to Encourage VA Meaningful Progress Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>REVAMP Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H29F0786E06C54331BF8B4AABA730A272" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Evaluations of organizational structure of Veterans Health Administration and realignment of Veterans Integrated Service Network</header> <subsection id="HEE300994108942FF803BD46F5ECAE248"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Organizational Structure</header> <paragraph id="HC43152D7388B4721877B367E274B8387"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Process</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, acting through the Under Secretary for Health, shall implement a process to consistently evaluate reviews described in paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H713D1DCB1F6D4E31B1AC53836A30FCA8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters included</header><text>The process under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HD7D0333951BB4905A8BC60EF7B883B28"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of the officials and the offices of the Department of Veterans Affairs responsible for evaluating and approving, and ensuring the implementation of, recommendations made by reviews described in paragraph (3), including—</text>
 <clause id="H26648E3712404F288950A63E11727F7F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the roles of each such official and office; and</text> </clause><clause id="H902A30CEA70C46239852B659C70AAC4E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of how decisions are made and documented to approve such implementation.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58D2F90F442D4144902F6240A1D6570B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how recommendations made by reviews described in paragraph (3) should be evaluated.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD27B0B48F99E4A78952217C656A8DFC8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of how timelines should be established to ensure recommendations are evaluated and implemented in a timely manner and metrics to assess the progress made with respect to such implementation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E01C62DBD2B4B96A4BCFB46363D54D1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reviews described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The reviews described in this paragraph are reviews of the organizational structure of the Veterans Health Administration conducted by the Secretary, the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Comptroller General of the United States, the Commission on Care established by section 202 of the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/146">Public Law 113–146</external-xref>; 128 Stat. 1773), or by an independent entity, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H77004057D0364BDBAAC30A423B332383"><enum>(4)</enum><header>First use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary shall use the process under paragraph (1) to evaluate the results of the evaluation conducted under subsection (b)(1). The Under Secretary shall make any required improvements to such process based on the lessons learned by the Under Secretary resulting from such use.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0469D825757E45489F8A8293C795498E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Veterans Integrated Service Network</header>
 <paragraph id="H67659AEDF53A41819FCE66D94D919674"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consistent with the report of the Comptroller General of the United States titled <quote>VA Health Care: Processes to Evaluate, Implement, and Monitor Organizational Structure Changes Needed</quote> (GAO–16–803), the Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Health, shall conduct an evaluation of the Veterans Integrated Service Network, including with respect to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H03A1195C0B8A4EEDA782303CFF4453FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the implementation by the Secretary of realignments to such Network; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EC8BDCAF59C45F19C7790AAB54CDB54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifying deficiencies to such Network that require corrective action.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H49892EAD768E458AAF7E37CC057BC3C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assessment and implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with subsection (a)(4), the Under Secretary shall use the process implemented under subsection (a) to assess the results of the evaluation conducted under paragraph (1) and to implement changes and other actions to improve the Veterans Integrated Service Network.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2563614AAED748468CD1F5493FC6187C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes a description of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFC4E611874A64FA1B2656D6F79999578"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the process implemented under subsection (a)(1);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2D4DAD5DE0A452095A4C8C01F347537"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the deficiencies identified under paragraph (1) of subsection (b); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H57EF70D9E45B4B8EB6247DF712474DCD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how the Under Secretary will carry out paragraph (2) of such subsection.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF8129D679BF4F1DA2EF05CCD833D778"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on new appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act, and this Act shall be carried out using amounts otherwise made available for such purposes.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


