<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCEA0808CAF77459F88579DF90F2D0B63" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 96 IH: TSA Loose Change Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 96</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170103">January 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to direct the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security
			 (Transportation Security Administration) to transfer unclaimed money
			 recovered at airport security checkpoints to nonprofit organizations that
			 provide places of rest and recuperation at airports for members of the
			 Armed Forces and their families, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HD95F93A808A84EBB8FBA7DD86069C890" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0EE3FE02F27645209F2B17203B0AB147" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>TSA Loose Change Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC33A9F69C0434836BD339DF402226311"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disposition of unclaimed money recovered at airport security checkpoints</header> <subsection id="H0ED4180A00154695A19D1CAF1FC1BE4B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disposition of unclaimed money</header><text>Section 44945(a) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF84E429AE91743DFB93520ED440E4EBC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>after the date of enactment of the TSA Loose Change Act,</quote> after <quote>title 31,</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H167D57861BF94CFD8292271C8C25B34A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>shall be retained by the Transportation Security Administration</quote> and all that follows through <quote>this chapter</quote> and inserting <quote>shall be annually transferred, based on requests for proposals, by the Assistant Secretary to nonprofit organizations that operate airport centers in multiple locations throughout the United States to provide places of rest and recuperation for members of the Armed Forces and their families</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE980C1EB4EFE4FFFAD30EAB5AD31359D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>The Assistant Secretary shall ensure that the name of each nonprofit agency to which funds are transferred under this subsection is printed in the Federal Register.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC5B003302DAD4E01A7B93FA638D7AE1D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Section 515(b) of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/334">Public Law 108–334</external-xref>; 118 Stat. 1318; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44945">49 U.S.C. 44945</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCB5039D4B32D4FF485F9AE64E0D404A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives</quote> and inserting <quote>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB8D683D6D6254872BE9DCDC915E904CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and specifically how the unclaimed money is being used to provide civil aviation security</quote> and inserting <quote>and the amount of unclaimed money transferred to nonprofit organizations under section 44945(a) of title 49, United States Code, and the dates of such transfers</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


