<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H42ACE96C74D145D1BF912580BE576B94" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2702 IH: SBIR Commercialization Assistance Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2702</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000586">Mr. Lawson of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Small Business Act to establish a commercialization assistance pilot program under the
			 SBIR program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H626013620575461AB411EA0E9838D0F4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H696D2D0F6A5740098D039F19EE182329" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>SBIR Commercialization Assistance Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H319DEEF5ED0B4FE8BED4A2E97367102A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Commercialization Assistance Pilot Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 9 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E68B9052D4D4D2792A808F24E7634C3" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H9C7B3AE26905460491D43B2BFFE5020A"><enum>(tt)</enum><header>Commercialization assistance pilot programs</header>
					<paragraph id="H6FB7B779633A4065AB1FD7B4CCFDD467"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pilot programs implemented</header>
 <subparagraph id="H15059C4FF67D44C4B6F8B5E1B7B3D041"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, a covered agency shall implement a commercialization assistance pilot program, under which an eligible entity may receive a subsequent Phase II SBIR award.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0F50CD267C94EE0A23AD8D2F308D1CE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If the Administrator determines that a covered agency has a program that is sufficiently similar to the commercialization assistance pilot program established under this subsection, such covered agency shall not be required to implement a commercialization assistance pilot program under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D6D0C8FB6F54475877ACDF11825DD3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Percent of agency funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each covered agency may allocate not more than 5 percent of the funds allocated to the SBIR program of the covered agency for the purpose of making a subsequent Phase II SBIR award under the commercialization assistance pilot program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0D2E671F20FC44518FFC28E4249D7E01"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>A commercialization assistance pilot program established under this subsection shall terminate on September 30, 2022.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF6A8532EDD841B69AC4A96587E9A16B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be selected to receive a subsequent Phase II SBIR award under a commercialization assistance pilot program, an eligible entity shall submit to the covered agency implementing such pilot program an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the covered agency may require, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8763A37492C643399CF5C71904EAA09A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an updated Phase II commercialization plan; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBCE35D6A4BF4BE1A684707FB6BA0F96"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the source and amount of the matching funding required under paragraph (5).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F211EB4B4D74ABFA7B3CB87AB63B831"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Matching funding</header>
 <subparagraph id="H77EEE1F4B21C43F7A9E993CE439134CA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall require, as a condition of any subsequent Phase II SBIR award made to an eligible entity under this subsection, that a matching amount (excluding any fees collected by the eligible entity receiving such award) equal to the amount of such award be provided from an eligible third-party investor.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H47E4C1E06D8B4F98854103D1BC0C3C39"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ineligible sources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity may not use funding from ineligible sources to meet the matching requirement of subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9B680E92FC04E1DABDAAD282DBD068A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Award</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A subsequent Phase II SBIR award made to an eligible entity under this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H4130FD84D665454CAB4E284E53B2B3A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not exceed the limitation described under subsection (aa)(1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H714557C34BFD4BDB8E72C466DC004D33"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be disbursed during Phase II.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H328C09A16CFD4E6180ED69566F414206"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The funds awarded to an eligible entity under this subsection may only be used for research and development activities that build on eligible entity’s Phase II program and ensure the research funded under such Phase II is rapidly progressing towards commercialization.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF85022E5014B4868818A27CA54F79EC8"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Selection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting eligible entities to participate in a commercialization assistance pilot program under this subsection, the head of a covered agency shall consider—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA07B9FA7EDAC45059FF6C711A11CE3E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which such award could aid the eligible entity in commercializing the research funded under the eligible entity’s Phase II program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7176E8EFD37448EA2295C25096BFD0C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the updated Phase II commercialization plan submitted under paragraph (4) provides a sound approach for establishing technical feasibility that could lead to commercialization of such research;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE95A7C6C698E44EBBDF4B4AF1F17AA09"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the proposed activities to be conducted under such updated Phase II commercialization plan further improve the likelihood that such research will provide societal benefits;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47ABB7ED686640CD9AB767FCB2D7D9BD"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the small business concern has progressed satisfactorily in Phase II to justify receipt of a subsequent Phase II SBIR award;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7E0CDB6A736419AAD070994CFA116C8"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the expectations of the eligible third-party investor that provides matching funding under paragraph (5); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D99EDBD6B294DBB8FE95FB6B934079A"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the likelihood that the proposed activities to be conducted under such updated Phase II commercialization plan using matching funding provided by such eligible third-party investor will lead to commercial and societal benefit.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4E35AA6DA8943DBA7B106AEEBC97724"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Evaluation Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate, a report including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2AAB3BEB06DB42908F0266BF9FBD5DC7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of the activities of commercialization assistance pilot programs carried out under this subsection;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAE3F2EEE54E4582B154EAB0EF273C9D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed compilation of results achieved by such commercialization assistance pilot programs, including the number of eligible entities that received awards under such programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D832CB3E27F48208A010500A5E2EA50"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rate at which each eligible entity that received a subsequent Phase II SBIR award under this subsection commercialized research of the recipient;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H749A9138FF754ECC9D0630A54F1568DD"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the growth in employment and revenue of eligible entities that is attributable to participation in a commercialization assistance pilot program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BB49FB804BF463E9669A189B7674551"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a comparison of commercialization success of eligible entities participating in a commercialization assistance pilot program with recipients of an additional Phase II SBIR award under subsection (ff);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18267E69269442A89A15A147374029F5"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demographic information, such as ethnicity and geographic location, of eligible entities participating in a commercialization assistance pilot program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37E4034245FC4EF5B07F809A0BBD9CA4"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an accounting of the funds used at each covered agency that implements a commercialization assistance pilot program under this subsection;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA1F5E36846E43AAA010A0E905BA5ACA"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of matching funding provided by eligible third-party investors, set forth separately by source of funding;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B5E33ADB49046FC8648CD34E0DDB3CC"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the effectiveness of the commercialization assistance pilot program implemented by each covered agency; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85E83F07207249D2A4176609A2DAA5A3"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for improvements to the commercialization assistance pilot program.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9ED35015ADC54779BF90147A16E090AC"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBE285E2E74BC4E0C8A8C2E864308EAEF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered agency</term> means a Federal agency required to have an SBIR program.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H888E07C8BB1348FD8A2B60430B95F83F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a small business concern that has received a Phase II award under an SBIR program and an additional Phase II SBIR award under subsection (ff) from the covered agency to which such small business concern is applying for a subsequent Phase II SBIR award.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E74BF62C1024C05B1B5E80F1A4B58BC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Eligible third-party investor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible third-party investor</term> means a small business concern other than an eligible entity, a venture capital firm, an individual investor, a non-SBIR Federal, State or local government, or any combination thereof.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AF1DEF51DFC4525A69899FF8FE245DE"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Ineligible sources</header><text>The term <term>ineligible sources</term> means the following:</text> <clause id="HB836297FECE64F099EEB5287AD03C56B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The eligible entity’s internal research and development funds.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1FCDDCAD7ACC40C79D5D959C3DCFE3EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funding in forms other than cash, such as in-kind or other intangible assets.</text> </clause><clause id="HE4CB811F24304410BAB316DA3724F9FF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funding from the owners of the eligible entity, or the family members or affiliates of such owners.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF33DF78282DD4DEC8F9E0BBBBB2E7CC2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funding attained through loans or other forms of debt obligations.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5F48260776A4607955B93C4A73D7898"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Subsequent Phase II SBIR award</header><text>The term <term>subsequent Phase II SBIR award</term> means an award granted to an eligible entity under this subsection to carry out further commercialization activities for research conducted pursuant to an SBIR program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


