<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC1B0588BD1514E12ADC22BBCDECC5832" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1235 : Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame Commemorative Coin Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1235</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20170926">September 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint coins in recognition of the 60th Anniversary of
			 the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H05D2FA72E14F4F0D8D8F74FFFA24150A" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCB970A7977D043A3A73AB3BD5C198942" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame Commemorative Coin Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBA03427A93CB48EF9044DC1FBCA6EF42"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H473B87A5C3D24E93AA8F3F35F583F5AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On December 21, 1891, a young physical education instructor named James Naismith, introduced the game of <quote>basket ball</quote> to his physical education class, in Springfield, Massachusetts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H79576A9795FB419D80209EE9C0C6688D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In 1959, the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame was founded and dedicated to the game’s creator Dr. James Naismith, in Springfield, MA, <quote>The Birthplace of Basketball</quote> and became the first and only museum to honor the game at all levels around the world.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H934F3D3D7B78435D8016095899B2AF66"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame honors players who have achieved greatness, exemplary coaches, referees and other major contributors to the sport of basketball. The Inaugural Hall of Fame Class of 1959 had seventeen honorees who were inducted, including Dr. James Naismith, George Mikan, Forrest C. Allen, Angelo Luisetti, Original Celtics and First Team.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA447659FFEB46BEA1D09C6B50723CFF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame is recognized throughout the world as the premier institution entrusted with recording and disseminating the history of the game of basketball and recognizing and honoring the achievements of its greatest players, coaches, and contributors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC5A8F56CD744EC0A36B3CC100FB61D6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame provides an entertaining, enriching experience and is known for its educational outreach programs and celebrates and promotes positive core values demonstrated by basketball’s hallowed heroes and its founder.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8C8E870975F4A97AC79042595395249"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Basketball is one of America’s national treasures, with its fast pace which reflects the freedom of expression and the modern experience of life in the 21st century.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H498B8231B7504D49BBAEA03F91014619"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Since its opening in 1959, the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame is home to the largest collection of basketball memorabilia in the world, including more than 30,000 three-dimensional objects, 800,000 photographs, and 1.5 million documents.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB29C04E00FBE4743993570CE1483EE33"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame welcomes more than 6 million visitors interested in discovering the rich history of the game through its stories, its personalities, and its most celebrated moments.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFAAD085DC0C241E6BE0877211E809C6F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame reaches over 7 million Americans through its educational programs, events, exhibits, social media, and its interactive website.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9626AAEAD3E64D4F935AB87F3074702B"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame’s customized educational programs use basketball to teach young students around the world the important lessons on a variety of topics including: financial literacy, mathematics, civil rights, leadership of character, women’s and men’s history, and geography.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H337BF4AE164E4116B1D50CEDEFEE9388"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame will lead the celebration of the 60th Anniversary of Basketball and will partner with a select group of constituents including the National Basketball Association, the National Collegiate Athletic Association, and USA Basketball in commemorating the game throughout the 2019–2020 basketball season.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H4BA4C08606AB42B283C015AAE95AC5C2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Coin specifications</header>
 <subsection id="H792F6E529F154A7D94F8591CA86FD997"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Denominations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In recognition and celebration of the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame, the Secretary of the Treasury (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall mint and issue the following coins:</text>
 <paragraph id="H69211670AFE54B20A7B1419FD33675CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>$5 Gold coins</header><text>Not more than 50,000 $5 coins, which shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H28B33138CC3543CE8716703C1E4A0C78"><enum>(A)</enum><text>weigh 8.359 grams;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H862A879FDCAA48D98404CA09C2CFAFDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be struck on a planchet having a diameter of 0.850 inches; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E018C09A41A434A866C3344375CC11B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contain 90 percent gold and 10 percent alloy.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD9A5C6DDC2E4F93A4D44052AE84D685"><enum>(2)</enum><header>$1 Silver coins</header><text>Not more than 400,000 $1 coins, which shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H8302EBC122154124A5EC052D78D91C71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>weigh 26.73 grams;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62882C2E2BE3474E818D97923C3FA31F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be struck on a planchet having a diameter of 1.500 inches; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAD7236F4C704453A580695F53365F6E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contain not less than 90 percent silver.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86C3C77CE66F442CAFC6D9DB670490BA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Half-dollar clad coins</header><text>Not more than 750,000 half-dollar coins which shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H3AFFE292FB224571918D44F374F5E7DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>weigh 11.34 grams;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36E82CD819C648A8AB7AEC954A300ADE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be struck on a planchet having a diameter of 1.205 inches; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CCB68A28BC64840A4D347534FA66B5C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be minted to the specifications for half-dollar coins contained in section 5112(b) of title 31, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6D5B7A40185F46349CA807BF90EA6F99"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Legal tender</header><text>The coins minted under this Act shall be legal tender, as provided in section 5103 of title 31, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H75CE0321E482450B8542DA778E776D4E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all coins minted under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H129A98315ED3493299C7B61728E9040B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Dome shape</header><text>The coins minted under this Act shall be in the shape of a dome.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H4DA3AB90029642189A42CA84573DBF97"><enum>4.</enum><header>Design of coins</header> <subsection id="HF9793E1A76564651AF58934A33C3D1CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The design for the coins minted under this Act shall be—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4E0405601576489394E20E52E5DB67ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>selected by the Secretary after consultation with the Commission of Fine Arts; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H14CB7B534AE44D1BA226C7F6504391AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reviewed by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDE22E765CEE841308C858B269EA73CC7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designations and inscriptions</header><text>On each coin minted under this Act there shall be—</text> <paragraph id="HF39BF1749D8B42C3B3C1116EFAE267B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a designation of the value of the coin;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H65572F054FF14C79A4C434899079BB2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an inscription of the year <quote>2020</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC96D4789BC8C40B885B380CB23415C02"><enum>(3)</enum><text>inscriptions of the words <quote>Liberty</quote>, <quote>In God We Trust</quote>, <quote>United States of America</quote>, and <quote>E Pluribus Unum</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H305595AC5C9448209A4CF67FE4FBA99C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection and approval process for obverse design</header>
 <paragraph id="H0FFA129ADD2B4F4EBA3559B352E076F3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall hold a competition to determine the design of the common obverse of the coins minted under this Act, with such design being emblematic of the game of basketball.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H534772A1F48344BF8C2FB3BA0E47CEAF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection and approval</header><text>Proposals for the design of coins minted under this Act may be submitted in accordance with the design selection and approval process developed by the Secretary in the sole discretion of the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CB5995F0DCE4EA6B3160C0E6FD16ADC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Proposals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of the competition described in this subsection, the Secretary may accept proposals from artists, engravers and other employees of the United States Mint, other Government employees, and members of the general public.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56CEB46E71C14E75ACCE67BD9703A982"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The Secretary shall determine compensation for the winning design under this subsection, which shall be not less than $5,000. The Secretary shall take into account this compensation amount when determining the sale price described in section 6(a).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H19DF7853B3374F19A8B22A2573AED3FD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reverse design</header><text>The design on the common reverse of the coins minted under this Act shall depict a basketball.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HD0D83F7F672D4307B870D5D9A50D30A1"><enum>5.</enum><header>Issuance of coins</header> <subsection id="HE1CDF3B5A79F4E149986E4C9971BD1B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Quality of coins</header><text>Coins minted under this Act shall be issued in uncirculated and proof qualities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H597BAAED82C84C2FBC78FAA8D7BB398C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Period for issuance</header><text>The Secretary may issue coins minted under this Act only during the 1-year period beginning on January 1, 2020.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H67435DAAD94442D1965CB7760671CA63"><enum>6.</enum><header>Sale of coins</header>
 <subsection id="HF2133B8BF7264BF4947CB6D657B0E5D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sale price</header><text>The coins issued under this Act shall be sold by the Secretary at a price equal to the sum of—</text> <paragraph id="H4DF0865FC5914CC1A05550B0270ED130"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the face value of the coins;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1507D7733D804E98A71149C8980EA838"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the surcharge provided in section 7(a) with respect to such coins; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2528B7A143F74E8DB6E6C60C7E1A2280"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the cost of designing and issuing the coins (including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, winning design compensation, overhead expenses, marketing, and shipping).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H721D1EB7DEC94BBCB6FDE0061C4AA350"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bulk sales</header><text>The Secretary shall make bulk sales of the coins issued under this Act at a reasonable discount.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HC28EBC1D97394721B7EBEC3948FDC68A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prepaid orders</header> <paragraph id="H6399B58D1EA64F249705DD6FCD6F171B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall accept prepaid orders for the coins minted under this Act before the issuance of such coins.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H47FEF4575EFF4EA7ACED2031D5DEDEEE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Discount</header><text>Sale prices with respect to prepaid orders under paragraph (1) shall be at a reasonable discount.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H49E1CA732A6844078E8D2CCA769A56E2"><enum>7.</enum><header>Surcharges</header> <subsection id="H73B303280D4D4355A186F18B1C2F3764"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All sales of coins minted under this Act shall include a surcharge as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7678F6173D694A77BC0D34C98BCA2E1E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A surcharge of $35 per coin for the $5 coin.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB17A1A5BA0D8405C8AFCBEE69042E437"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A surcharge of $10 per coin for the $1 coin.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A7853AC43134D7D9945D144DD31BA5A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A surcharge of $5 per coin for the half-dollar coin.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H87272F7125DA4446B37FF07ADD59173C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to section 5134(f) of title 31, United States Code, all surcharges received by the Secretary from the sale of coins issued under this Act shall be promptly paid by the Secretary to the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame to fund an endowment that will enable increased operations and educational programming of the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H35CB681F5ADD44E3B7BBD38C292010C6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Audits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame shall be subject to the audit requirements of section 5134(f)(2) of title 31, United States Code, with regard to the amounts received under subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3054E197829F4B35955D4FDE799FB789"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), no surcharge may be included with respect to the issuance under this Act of any coin during a calendar year if, as of the time of such issuance, the issuance of such coin would result in the number of commemorative coin programs issued during such year to exceed the annual commemorative coin program issuance limitation under section 5112(m)(1) of title 31, United States Code (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act). The Secretary of the Treasury may issue guidance to carry out this subsection.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170925">Passed the House of Representatives September 25, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


