<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8E4137C418014910963B78D8117878F7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2925 IH: To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide coverage for wigs as durable medical equipment under the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2925</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170615">June 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide coverage for wigs as durable medical
			 equipment under the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H113F96A5B00642ED891B4DB351F172C2" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD86AC9DB585546B890FA43686449FD06" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Providing coverage for wigs as durable medical equipment under the Medicare program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1861(n) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(n)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Such term also includes cranial prostheses furnished to an individual, but only where the dermatologist, oncologist, or attending physician of the individual certifies in writing the medical necessity of such prostheses as part of a proposed course of rehabilitative treatment.</quote>.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


