<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFF4BF2E25A9D46B3A9ECD93C6DD34E24" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1375 IH: Prescriber Support Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1375</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170307">March 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="J000297">Mr. Jenkins of West Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health of Human Services to award grants to States (or collaborations of States) to establish, expand, or maintain a comprehensive regional, State, or municipal system to provide training, education, consultation, and other resources to prescribers relating to patient pain, substance misuse, and substance abuse disorders, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1B99BD2BFA6C49B59B44B8FBFDCFA031" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB94D3E0761AB44D1BD04961F585CFBE9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prescriber Support Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H600ECF73B57648E6B9254341D15688B0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Resources for prescribers on patient pain, substance misuse, and substance abuse disorders</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 399O of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g-3">42 U.S.C. 280g–3</external-xref>) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3CFF4FBFAE8A444F96701B8BE7D01D83" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HCF900D3AD3EC4904B3566671F618A8C2"><enum>399O–1.</enum><header>Resources for prescribers on patient pain, substance misuse, and substance abuse disorders</header> 
<subsection id="H245A9ADB8C30423991DBAD3A52C0369A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award grants to States (or collaborations of States) to establish, expand, or maintain a comprehensive regional, State, or municipal system to provide training, education, consultation, and other resources to enable prescribers—</text> <paragraph id="H179EE2EBF6A642F0ADF8C3AFCBDE2790"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to effectively and appropriately treat and manage patient pain; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B9591A62A29409BBB4E08FBB41C60D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to prevent, identify, and respond to patient substance misuse and substance abuse disorders.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H42B88F83C41D4E4BA7823283D6BD1BFA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>System implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A system funded through this section may provide the training, education, consultation, and other resources described in subsection (a) directly or through a professional association, an institution of higher education, a nonprofit organization, or another appropriate entity.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5ADF1B2768AA43419B32B2194E250B05"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Number</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall make grants under this section to not fewer than 3 States (or collaborations of States).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD98B1907F8CE43D8B198A0B276628594"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to applications to States (or collaborations of States) demonstrating the greatest lack of, and need for, the training, education, consultation, and other resources described in subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H26076D0400DE47CEBC0D722872879E46"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date on which a State (or collaboration of States) receives a grant under this section, the State (or collaboration) shall submit to the Secretary an evaluation of the extent to which the system funded through the grant has been effective in—</text> <paragraph id="HF7CC860937B94CCA9A3A0D53096DD4EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improving the treatment and management of pain; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8BF6C579F09D4BAA9A4DC7694CF7E2F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>preventing, identifying, and responding to substance misuse and substance abuse disorders.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE3E6AC64A1D44F8AAE5291DCFC62A793"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Minimum requirements</header><text>To be eligible for assistance under this section, a system described in subsection (a) shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAA540F32B014461E90469E20733BD9F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a peer-to-peer consultation program that enables prescribers to receive real-time expert consultation (in person or remotely) with a pain or addiction specialist to aid in the individualized treatment and management of patient pain and in responding to patients who are exhibiting signs of substance misuse or substance abuse disorders;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A9D3B2B21F34EA881FBF485844ED6F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordination with community-based resources and services, including mental health and substance abuse resources, pain and addiction specialists, primary care resources, and support groups; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF03A21230E4C47909266E409DDDA0987"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a dedicated website to collect and disseminate information for prescribers, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H0F4FC718D1E24D629D78425FE73CE951"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information on the consultation program under paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H73CE33EE76C1402E8238C43CA1D5D636"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a detailed and continuously updated guide to the community-based resources and services identified and coordinated under paragraph (2), including information on the services provided and the populations served; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H22AF39E7D57A440CB0241BFC72495088"><enum>(C)</enum><text>appropriate training and educational materials, such as appropriate prescribing guidelines and information on the treatment and management of chronic pain, alternatives to opioid-based pain treatment, substance abuse screening, and follow-up support.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H37543CB0435848F28CAEFE8D5D73D4A1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To seek a grant under this section, a State (or collaboration of States) shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAE5EE48189694885A4E834948E2BFDE3"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Prescriber defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>prescriber</term> means a health care professional authorized under State law to prescribe drugs.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0EFACA2FA3C24857A0D57827DD777109"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

