<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCD19ED7646D1474DB7A776A44471DA79" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3297 IH: Paperwork Reduction for Farmers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3297</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170719">July 19, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000388">Mr. Kelly of Mississippi</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To streamline the application process for H–2A employers and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H009FD5C02B494A84B83B9CF6C71D245F" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA122701B89B44FFB81C0521CE05D14EC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Paperwork Reduction for Farmers Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8BDA06CD35EF4854AC9478CE1706036A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Electronic filing and appeals system for H–2A petitions</header> <subsection id="H3999E2A628114E43B29532F8C73002E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor shall establish a process for filing petitions for nonimmigrant visas under section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(a)</external-xref>) that ensures that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5488E5B249BB448486A0FB1B5927AB0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>petitioners may file such petitions through the Department of Labor’s website;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H73E472F4A67C4B2686F2D6CD01A04F87"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any software developed to process such petitions indicates to the petitioner any technical deficiency in the application before submission; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H68D8DB2B1A034D46BFC0E24B5F940EEE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any petitioner may file such petition in a paper format if such petitioner prefers such format.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H976713BD3E4248658007388CEAF7EFF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Request for evidence</header><text>Section 218(h) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1188">8 U.S.C. 1188(h)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80369E07F565468D9043C0CB1F93CAEC" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HE8C9089A00974EF19F22F508979CDF12" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services issues a Request for Evidence to an employer—</text> <subparagraph id="H75981673D1794557B1FBD2C05E2947A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the employer may request such Request for Evidence to be delivered in an online format; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBBBAF51B48847B6B1F70048E70B6AF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the employer makes the request described in subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="H73B81FF0D40E4F15AADA76BBF1474DBB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Request for Evidence shall be provided to the employer in an online format; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H87DD67204FD44FEBA3FF469DDC983B25"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than 10 business days after the employer submits the requested evidence online, U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services shall provide an online response to the employer—</text>
 <subclause id="HD2CF3E7E3420479E9C7C87E6FBCEB181"><enum>(I)</enum><text>indicating that the submitted evidence is sufficient; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H28CA961D408F424994BA8235F4942DEF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>explaining the reasons that such evidence is not sufficient and providing the employer with an opportunity to address any such deficiency.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H023490B169D841EE89A01733C4187D61" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>H–2A program updates</header>
 <subsection id="HDDB491916FC44E9BA71A674EF464AAB8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, labor as a year-round equine worker, labor as a year-round livestock worker (including as a dairy or poultry worker)</quote> before <quote>, and the pressing of apples</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1D6F575A6A364AA9B437D42337F7853B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Joint application; deficiency remedy</header><text>Section 214(c)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H940191EA4BBE413EBC3CB4EAE8C78429"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(A)</quote> after <quote>(1)</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08E14F75F9A943D5B59BA3AED87300BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE994CEA1C7B414587A2C863DDD18D3F" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H8F0B57E1E65641C49F54790451C8A45F" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Multiple employers may submit a joint petition under subparagraph (A) to import aliens as nonimmigrants described in section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(a). Upon the approval of such petition, each joint employer shall be subject to the provisions under section 218 with respect to each alien listed in such petition. If any individual party to such a joint contract violates any condition for approval with respect to the application or provisions under section 218 with respect to each alien listed in such petition, after notice and opportunity for a hearing, the contract may be modified to remove the party in violation from the contract at no penalty to the remaining parties.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82BB0347D672402BA7A99E8C256CE2C9" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>If a petition to import aliens as nonimmigrants described in section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(a) is denied or if the issuance of visas requested through such petition is delayed due to a problem with the petition, the Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services shall promptly notify the petitioner of the reasons for such denial or delay and provide the petitioner with reasonable time to remedy the problem.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5F6E2C9D8EA143DB884C603E2F93DE75"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Labor certification; staggered employment dates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 218(h) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1188">8 U.S.C. 1188(h)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3(b), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC5CE06731A6F46B7B1EB2D63998022E8" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HC4B1375591154E94A5E96405CDBB0714" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An employer that is seeking to rehire aliens as H–2A workers who previously worked for the employer as H–2A workers may submit a simplified petition, to be developed by the Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, which shall include a certification that the employer maintains compliance with all applicable requirements with respect to the employment of such aliens. Such petitions shall be approved upon completion of applicable security screenings.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2629B8C0C2E433A9818630A28C66921" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An employer that is seeking to hire aliens as H–2A workers during different time periods in a given fiscal year may submit a single petition to U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services that details the time period during which each such alien is expected to be employed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46377065B7764D8B9D7D39B59CB481D4" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Upon receiving notification from an employer that the employer’s H–2A worker has prematurely abandoned employment or has failed to appear for employment and such employer wishes to replace such worker—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD6899B48C67242DE99EBCF19BC77F672"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of State shall promptly issue a visa under section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(a) to an eligible alien designated by the employer to replace that worker; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4133A881079740479FD40015507F3B11"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security shall promptly admit such alien into the United States upon completion of applicable security screenings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


