<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAFFF72269FD7453290DAF1B8C2DFEBA6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3880 IH: Cardiomyopathy Health Education, Awareness, Research, and Training in the Schools Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3880</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170928">September 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize and support the creation and dissemination of
			 cardiomyopathy education, awareness, and risk assessment materials and
			 resources to identify more at-risk families, to authorize research and
			 surveillance activities relating to cardiomyopathy, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HCF7E1451DB2C4CE88AC603B033EFBD59" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4E4305CB64C142B3B69BE8A9A2EB3B26" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cardiomyopathy Health Education, Awareness, Research, and Training in the Schools Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HEARTS Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H005428AEA8534C49B3F849DC0E319D79"><enum>2.</enum><header>Materials and resources to increase education and awareness of car­di­o­my­op­a­thy among school administrators, educators, and families</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part P of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g">42 U.S.C. 280g</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD25F38C28AA4B8796CECB5D13116383" style="OLC">
				<section id="H2F5EBB1B256E42AABD8098669C1AB357"><enum>399V–7.</enum><header>Materials and resources to increase education and awareness of cardiomyopathy among school
			 administrators, educators, and families</header>
 <subsection id="H1CD61CF0AE15419D897D4D1692220FCA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Materials and resources</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary, in conjunction with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (in this section referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>) shall develop public education materials and resources to be disseminated to school administrators, educators, school health professionals, coaches, families, guardians, caregivers, and other appropriate individuals. The materials and resources shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD3BE2FCD485D4C9FAFFDF802FA3518B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>background information to increase education and awareness of cardiomyopathy among school administrators, educators, and families;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9D8087B976D4FDDA12E82D4A4CE0B74"><enum>(2)</enum><text>guidelines regarding the placement of automated external defibrillators in schools, early childhood education programs, and child care centers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9ED57EF3EDB4D9DB03022CB9AD01B17"><enum>(3)</enum><text>training information on automated external defibrillators and cardiopulmonary resuscitation; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H974EEBBF34D54081B64825CE1853229B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for how schools, early childhood education programs, and child care centers can develop and implement a cardiac emergency response plan.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC48AE9B050BB41E1A3A7230D29C991B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Dissemination of materials and resources</header><text>Not later than 30 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary, through the Director, shall disseminate the materials and resources developed under subsection (a) in accordance with the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H931C753572684B7BB540453F6831855B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Distribution by State educational agencies</header><text>The Secretary shall make available such materials and resources to State educational agencies to distribute—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H47DECD4A750A4981B3D11E4623A8D36E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to school administrators, educators, school health professionals, coaches, families, guardians, caregivers, and other appropriate individuals, the cardiomyopathy education and awareness materials and resources developed under subsection (a)(1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4A9717638227436095C1DF20C9B8CB4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to parents, guardians, or other caregivers, the risk assessment for individuals with or at risk for cardiomyopathy developed pursuant to section 399V–8(b)(1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7BDAB6E0C2C1437490646EFE57887D5F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to school administrators, educators, school health professionals, and coaches—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H5478147DCB2746C99FB0D391333CA2C8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the guidelines described in subsection (a)(2);</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HF08EF3A039A4471D96629CCD39728FEA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the training information described in subsection (a)(3); and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H05A020181EF54188B01C5A20D969F479"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the recommendations described in subsection (a)(4).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DE4B93AC0AC4C9987934B3CCF4FA1E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dissemination to health departments and professionals</header><text>The Secretary shall make available the materials and resources developed under subsection (a) to State and local health departments, pediatricians, hospitals, and other health professionals, such as nurses and first responders.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H7CA5D444D99941CEA251D9473D80F89D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Posting on website</header>
							<subparagraph id="H30B2093820E049199BF6A8154826D322"><enum>(A)</enum><header>CDC</header>
 <clause id="HDFF9B01495E9416BA36010F0AEBC5A1F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, through the Director, shall post the materials and resources developed under subsection (a) on the public Internet website of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H25DFA918ECF443EB9688C6F5F69A5833"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Additional information</header><text>The Director is encouraged to maintain on such public Internet website such additional information regarding cardiomyopathy as deemed appropriate by the Director.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H312E40000FAF4390BD8B717B7BA1BD6F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State educational agencies</header><text>State educational agencies are encouraged to create public Internet webpages dedicated to cardiomyopathy and post the materials and resources developed under subsection (a) on such webpages.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75B448314C404FC3B8D309759907B811"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H8FB34FC6EADA40AE87BE668F6F154E10"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>school administrator</term> means a principal, director, manager, or other supervisor or leader within an elementary school, secondary school, State-based early childhood education program, or child care center.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADCF113A2F3F48E696D223E0095A5DDE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>school health professional</term> means a health professional serving at an elementary school, secondary school, State-based early childhood education program, or child care center.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0C70CF0A66443BC825AABCADB6E2309"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>early childhood education program</term>, <term>elementary school</term>, and <term>secondary school</term> have the meanings given to those terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCE397626AAC34962A0FE3C617378F6F6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For carrying out this section and section 399V–8, there is authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H179F86B30B7E4F25BE4B5541356B9072" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Research and surveillance activities relating to cardiomyopathy</header>
 <subsection id="HF7DE589EDD37435BB61BCA302D64FB29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>CDC research and surveillance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part P of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g">42 U.S.C. 280g</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by section 2, is further amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H20BEC92555234BA4841ACECE180E9CC1" style="OLC">
					<section id="H9D5684B57BBD4428AA6DD8875C37BC2F"><enum>399V–8.</enum><header>Research and surveillance activities relating to cardiomyopathy</header>
						<subsection id="HA2A6D9B028434D86A245BBD59E7B9145"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reports on CDC national cardiomyopathy surveillance research activities</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H3F02969FAF3A497885E52BBB14086F9C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2020, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall submit to Congress an initial report on findings and data generated from surveillance and research activities conducted by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to improve the understanding of the prevalence and epidemiology of cardiomyopathy across the lifespan, from birth to adulthood, with particular interest in the following:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H206F49A203974E1BB4EAE99D595C46F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The health care costs, utilization, and natural history of individuals with cardiomyopathy, in both the pediatric and adult population.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7BC42472ABE640FAA1E59D7A98E96FF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of adults and children affected by cardiomyopathy, as well as age-specific mortality.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C341BE6044D41028CAC069463215C03"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2025, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall submit to Congress a final report on the content described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A856E359E2141339D9EAF4A395CF1AB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public access</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (4), the reports submitted under this subsection shall be made available to the public.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F3DA669E88F4A5A8E86005E44B77818"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Patient privacy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that this subsection is carried out in a manner that complies with the requirements applicable to a covered entity under the regulations promulgated pursuant to section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H45CECF8335054E878024C09446BB0FC8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Improving risk assessments for individuals with cardiomyopathy</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HDDD4A8C8D4B54FC18F8D590933277EA2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall develop and make publicly available a risk assessment for individuals with or at risk for cardiomyopathy. Such risk assessment shall, at a minimum, include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H128FBFE9210548E69D22F609D4763E47"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Background information of the prevalence, incidence, and health impact of car­di­o­my­op­a­thy, including all forms of car­di­o­my­op­a­thy and their effects on pediatric, adolescent, and adult individuals.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H38C2CE0FB00F458280A156967148494B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A worksheet with variables and conditions for an individual or health care provider to use in assessing whether the individual is at risk for cardiomyopathy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA4879F4DCD2F420882869BFAB6BFF479"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A worksheet with variables and stages of progression for an individual or health care provider to use in assessing whether and to what extent cardiomyopathy has progressed in the individual.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDB7CA675AFBA4D1E86DC975D1B192071"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Guidelines on cardiomyopathy screenings for individuals who are at risk for, or have a family history of, cardiomyopathy.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC198C3FEDCA9487188AD1F33CBEDD527"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Stakeholder Input</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall seek input from external stakeholders including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCE4AFB6233A74ED7B915D19391CCA5E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>representatives from national patient advocacy organizations expert in all forms of cardiomyopathy;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03AF2C50F13B444EA0DE770241FFD2DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>representatives from medical professional societies that specialize in the care of adults and pediatrics with cardiomyopathy; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8E98BD2E1614F0894C0AB0DBA21FD48"><enum>(C)</enum><text>representatives from other relevant Federal agencies.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBFA5C9AAD734480DBF6351555518151E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cardiomyopathy defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>cardiomyopathy</term> means a heart disease that affects the heart’s muscle (myocardium)—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2398FCA5ABE242E08D812C4AA7D6C5F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the symptoms of which may vary from case to case, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HFA497ACE869B46E7AACBE3E20040BE40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>cases in which no symptoms are present (asymptomatic); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3CFF779AB8D4E729331BD109062D719"><enum>(B)</enum><text>cases in which there are symptoms of a progressive condition that may result from an impaired ability of the heart to pump blood, such as fatigue, irregular heartbeats (arrhythmia), heart failure, and, potentially, sudden cardiac death; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD5B97B5856F45A89CDE13F1E0C6B57C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the recognized types of which include dilated, hypertrophic, restrictive, arrhythmogenic right ventricular dysplasia, and left ventricular non-compaction.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1B3EBB3EB6704212B0BE4F8077655847"><enum>(b)</enum><header>NIH research</header><text>Part A of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/281">42 U.S.C. 281</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 404E the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD98DC8FD5EBD47D4BC71409540FA805D" style="OLC">
					<section id="HCE562143FDA64126B2BC6EE439FCDFC1"><enum>404F.</enum><header>Cardiomyopathy research</header>
 <subsection id="H872F596FB47B49ACAC73D0589813FFF9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of NIH may expand, intensify, and coordinate research and related activities of the National Institutes of Health with respect to cardiomyopathy, which may include research with respect to—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H8281C101CB7B4AFF9F0E08A5D0371FF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>causation of cardiomyopathy, including genetic causes and molecular biomarkers;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC4A751947EB04C3FAB11945489924B21"><enum>(2)</enum><text>long-term health outcomes in individuals with cardiomyopathy, including infants, children, teenagers, adults, and elderly individuals; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB08E8AC5897349F98E55F6D12D403024"><enum>(3)</enum><text>studies using longitudinal data and retrospective analysis to identify effective treatments and outcomes for individuals with cardiomyopathy.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6AAA12E6CF0A4DAAACC5137CD876E31F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cardiomyopathy defined</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>cardiomyopathy</term> means a heart disease that affects the heart’s muscle (myocardium)—</text> <paragraph id="HAC86E3751EA44F52A042107EB7AD7D9E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the symptoms of which may vary from case to case, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H246C025398364DDE8208D9E25FE95EDA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>cases in which no symptoms are present (asymptomatic); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACE917365DA647BD9A5AE8F7D646325B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>cases in which there are symptoms of a progressive condition that may result from an impaired ability of the heart to pump blood, such as fatigue, irregular heartbeats (arrhythmia), heart failure, and, potentially, sudden cardiac death; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9179F8E8F67A48D1808626A41DF1FD80"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the recognized types of which include dilated, hypertrophic, restrictive, arrhythmogenic right ventricular dysplasia, and left ventricular non-compaction.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H79EEFBB41D89406CAC9269E71E4CA918"><enum>(c)</enum><header>NIH report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall submit to Congress a report—</text>
 <paragraph id="H41F79C41EFD046D38C623757A9714D4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>outlining the ongoing research efforts of the National Institutes of Health regarding cardiomyopathy; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4679B77F721843FE9F923AAD5FF126A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identifying—</text> <subparagraph id="H01AE916373E34613BF9C573A19D33792"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a research agenda regarding adult forms of cardiomyopathy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E4DC764BAAE4E7E90CC2B6C0DE93C67"><enum>(B)</enum><text>plans for researching cardiomyopathy affecting the pediatric population; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H268B97ADD9F8477B8E9E1F1E819A1478"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the areas of greatest need for such research.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


