<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4A099700EA7849FCA2127098FE55D19F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2121 IH: Pension, Endowment, and Mutual Fund Access to Banking Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2121</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170425">April 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000598">Mr. Rothfus</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the appropriate Federal banking agencies to revise regulations to specify that certain
			 funds shall not be taken into account when calculating any supplementary
			 leverage ratio for custodial banks, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2DB2C32E5370461693D56F96A3AA526C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H57A2E45702684F43912D708E2451FD6E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pension, Endowment, and Mutual Fund Access to Banking Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H69A5069344CD40E88FC92231456126DC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of funds deposited with a central bank in calculating the applicable supplementary leverage ratio</header> <subsection id="H91FA14AC6F184D53BE2E143712B917B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The appropriate Federal banking agencies shall amend the relevant sections of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, to specify that funds of a custodial bank that are deposited with a central bank shall not be taken into account when calculating the applicable supplementary leverage ratio for the custodial bank under such regulations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H33F318F233BB42F0B558FE84C3E2FD04"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The amount of funds described under subsection (a) may not exceed the total value of deposits of the custodial bank linked to fiduciary or custodial and safekeeping accounts.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6FB9D469C5CE4ED487C9EC89A84A4E27"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of funds described under subsection (a) may be limited to—</text> <paragraph id="HE65F3686FA4C49F2864DAF06C6ACA8C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount that is greater than a percentage specified by the appropriate Federal banking agency of the total leverage exposure of the custodial bank, based on considerations such as the potential impact on the safety and soundness of the custodial bank and the ability of the custodial bank to continue to accept cash deposits from customers that are linked to fiduciary or custodial and safekeeping accounts; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6437321BB7FA40039F5D459B4FD7AD58"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">amounts deposited with certain central banks<italic></italic>, as determined through rulemaking by the appropriate Federal banking agencies.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31FCCE9F69674AE8B4181FECDEA55BF6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H0480C2B182054F879C892A4881B686E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate federal banking agency</header><text>The term <term>appropriate Federal banking agency</term> has the meaning given that term under section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H9EAC022BD1D94595B07CA8E60CDCD91F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Custodial bank</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE50432DE884945B9BF37A20BF800E2FC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>custodial bank</term> means a depository institution and the depository institution holding company of such depository institution, both of which are primarily engaged in custodial banking.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB652347C27E640EA99F1DB12E3AE0FBF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Custodial banking defined</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the appropriate Federal banking agencies may define the term <term>custodial banking</term> based on factors including the percentage of total revenues generated by custodial businesses and the level of assets under custody.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DF2015D79654B24B0F6DF8AEA1056B9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Depository institution</header><text>The term <term>depository institution</term> has the meaning given that term under section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF73D88D616C24216AAC9E44683B83E3B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Depository institution holding company</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>depository institution holding company</term> has the meaning given that term under section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H898809F3EB344D278C6B681A476CB0C1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Supplementary leverage ratio</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>supplementary leverage ratio</term> means the supplementary leverage ratio, including applicable buffers, surcharges, and well-capitalized requirements relating to such supplementary leverage ratio, as defined by regulation of the appropriate Federal banking agency in title 12, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


