<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCC0871F4BFAE4643820F4737E8CDFD05" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4284 IH: Indexing Narcotics, Fentanyl, and Opioids Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4284</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171107">November 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000213">Mr. Barton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a Federal Coordinator within the Department of Health and Human Services, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H98727E81A46944AB90C2182B9D7ABB52" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3B8107D521D74AB3B1E42C15BEA9C1EA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Indexing Narcotics, Fentanyl, and Opioids Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>INFO Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HEF6E5712236D4E5DA19DFE26FF49A72A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of Federal Coordinator</header> <subsection id="H0A6AAC95BE254360A282AECF29B98D2C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall appoint a Federal Coordinator for the Department of Health and Human Services to carry out the duties described in subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H53D5180A5FE849938F7ED58B3733D85A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Federal Coordinator shall—</text> <paragraph id="H7DA796356B564581ACC8DA60B5C83840"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate programs within the Department of Health and Human Services that relate to opioid abuse reduction;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H37B7E06F67E74805A979E66BEBE47124"><enum>(2)</enum><text>serve as a liaison to State and local governments and entities carrying out activities relating to opioid abuse reduction pursuant to a Federal contract or grant; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H54B4EAF4E6BE42AB90C673A8B51AB3B8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in consultation with the United States Attorney General, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy, and any other individual that the Federal Coordinator determines appropriate, establish and operate a publicly available electronic database through which the Federal Coordinator shall carry out the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H049254CB6D2745D5898805B7DBC32B6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Collect data on opioid abuse from Federal agencies; State, local, and Tribal governments; nonprofit organizations; law enforcement; medical experts; public health educators; and research institutions.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58384316460741F3B5CD474EDB59A941"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Publish a comprehensive list of Federal funding resources available to States for research on opioid abuse.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E164497A3794132A65AADB5B7D8FC0F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Analyze causes and trends behind opioid addiction and pain management.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H207522F8CCFD41A5BB37F1E9090407E4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Evaluate the effectiveness of Federal programs for opioid abuse reduction, including opioid treatment programs and medicated-assisted treatments.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F48B320B1B3468286C78A760DF1F9E7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Evaluate whether any Federal programs for opioid abuse reduction are duplicative.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE16325801D2C4990A501FAEA84501BA6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Evaluate the extent to which Federal grants for the implementation of opioid abuse prevention strategies are successful in addressing opioid abuse in local communities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC1E9D5A06984087870FDB78FF9876D9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Provide recommendations to health care providers on alternatives to opioids for pain management and other areas in which health care providers can improve with respect to treating or preventing opioid abuse.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64AF6457880F48EC923523EF7A7B9BD9"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Analyze opioid prescription guidelines, the different types of opioids prescribed by health care providers, and the use of medicated-assisted treatments.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D9C9DB5FA6241098F2CF5E31F4983B4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Compare the rate of opioid abuse in veterans receiving health care through the Department of Veterans Affairs with the rate of opioid abuse in the general population.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H718A683D26664B329697096534FBB937"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Compare opioid abuse trends and prevention and treatment strategies in different regions and populations of the United States and determine whether certain strategies are more effective than others.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H322A4A82BC0E4D9A991CD59EB6FD97CB"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Analyze to what extent Federal prevention and treatment strategies for opioid abuse are aligned with State and local prevention and treatment strategies.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA96572C9380840CF8A327CFF033B14FC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <paragraph id="HF966E24792A94FDF9504C3EE1D4293B4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Federal Coordinator shall submit to Congress an initial report on the results of any analysis, evaluation, or comparison conducted under subsection (b)(3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D3D76EC24914A83843DAD5A3771F296"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updated report</header><text>Not later than five years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Federal Coordinator shall submit to Congress a report that provides updates with respect to any results submitted in the initial report under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6BC28052C7864F488901B0A2722FD815"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Each report submitted under this subsection shall be made publicly available on the electronic database established under subsection (b)(3).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


