<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3C5C4BA273164571A63ACE3C38D94A46" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4363 IH: Veterans Conservation Corps Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4363</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171109">November 9, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000390">Mr. Kihuen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a veterans conservation corps, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H57E1E5701BED4BBCB0D8F1312B4E838E" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA6A8DF8C832A4821B6470D9F8D55BD68" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Conservation Corps Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HCBFC4F47AD574DF09D4C1ABA714BD848"><enum>2.</enum><header>Veterans Conservation Corps</header> <subsection id="H2AB0387F62E149D4AA2A49F4A186A787"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> <paragraph id="H05EAB82EC46E41CEBB95D613D48CC99D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, in cooperation with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of the Interior, the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service, and the Chief of Engineers, establish a veterans conservation corps to assist veterans in the transition from service in the Armed Forces to civilian life and to employ veterans—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8A49D9E5B422476C889658D63765C04F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in conservation, resource management, firefighting, law enforcement, and historic preservation projects on public lands and maintenance and improvement projects for cemeteries under the jurisdiction of the National Cemetery Administration; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2683DFEDDD1E4F6A952893C1692120A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as firefighters, law enforcement officers, and disaster relief personnel.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H32431FAFAFAE407EB657B3388B991529"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Veteran eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to participate in the veterans conservation corps, a veteran shall be unemployed.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDFD467D924CF481FAA16E49F96E2CBB5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conservation, resource management, historic preservation, and cemetery maintenance and improvement
			 projects</header>
 <paragraph id="HC23626C784094FABBC0EAD50FE9F4A69"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of the veterans conservation corps, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Interior, the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service, and the Chief of Engineers shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H12D1348BD30C447BA068B3F0FE6FFA6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employ veterans to carry out projects described in subsection (a)(1); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61FB676CB5C94CA78BC6FE4D3E034679"><enum>(B)</enum><text>award grants to, or enter into contracts with, State governments, local governments, or nongovernmental entities to employ veterans to carry out projects described in subsection (a)(1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8EC76B1371844BC9862C61145EE6743A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In employing or awarding grants or contracts to employ veterans under this subsection, the Secretaries referred to in paragraph (1) and the Chief of Engineers shall give priority towards the employment of veterans who served on active duty in the Armed Forces on or after September 11, 2001.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB919D07D69B494C9F60467211B56F67"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall coordinate the activities of the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Interior, the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service, and the Chief of Engineers to employ veterans as part of the veterans conservation corps.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H066C5728733E4A32BEFED85909FB8A45"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Oversight of projects</header><text>The Secretaries referred to in paragraph (1) and the Chief of Engineers shall each provide oversight of the projects for which they employ veterans under subparagraph (A) of such paragraph or award grants or enter into contracts under subparagraph (B) of such paragraph.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H27FD512D5C954E11AF7B9A7FE58E44AF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>First responders</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HB0C6E7341A1844B9ABE50C99120F37F2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Firefighters</header><text>As part of the veterans conservation corps, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall award grants under section 34 of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2229a">15 U.S.C. 2229a</external-xref>) to hire veterans as firefighters.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2677A92BB46C4B2D80A298F8595E4DB3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Law enforcement officers</header><text>As part of the veterans conservation corps, the Attorney General shall award grants under part Q of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3796dd">42 U.S.C. 3796dd</external-xref> et seq.) to hire veterans as law enforcement officers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1D5CD57C4D0E49928E07F4D7CFB09EC2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disaster relief personnel</header><text>As part of the veterans conservation corps, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide funds to increase participation by veterans in the FEMA Corps program, which is a partnership between the Corporation for National and Community Service and the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE4AAFFA74E424BE6A1D5D9996CD79BAE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants or providing funds under this subsection to hire veterans, the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Attorney General shall give priority to the hiring of veterans who served on active duty in the Armed Forces on or after September 11, 2001.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD279D5F67F5F4DEDA9714847FE9299E8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Assistance</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1652434034B345DD9958F1E5CEBFAA1D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may provide assistance to the Secretaries referred to in subsection (a), the Attorney General, the Chief of Engineers, and the Chief Executive Officer to carry out the veterans conservation corps. Such assistance may take the form of a transfer under paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5E14E848DCF47578387D8AFD574E041"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfers</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, of amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out this section, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may transfer such amounts as the Secretary considers appropriate to carry out the veterans conservation corps to the following:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA245101C46A94E3689659649730777F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Attorney General.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3FCA38E1FA48430781523AF935A07F73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H213DA7C86A354AA894EB59DC5FFF5F9B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Secretary of Commerce.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1F06E763E694B4B884F5FDE58C9C534"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4F7609288994E3F8A1EEA2283A3C0B3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Interior.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67F16CED5CCB42DAA4CCA305ED7F6130"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Corporation for National and Community Service.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E54BFD186E2437AB2CEC6BA7CCEA096"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The Chief of Engineers.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H93094209AF034A11ABA843475F5BCFA4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assistance for conservation, resource management, historic preservation, and cemetery maintenance and improvement projects</header> <subparagraph id="H4992FCFEA9D14F8BB721B35195AFDA3D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application</header><text>If a Secretary referred to in subsection (b)(1) or the Chief of Engineers or the Chief Executive Officer seeks assistance under paragraph (1) to employ a veteran to carry out a project under subparagraph (A) of subsection (b)(1) or to award a grant or contract to carry out a project under subparagraph (B) of such subsection, such Secretary or the Chief of Engineers shall submit to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs an application therefor at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may require.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0887C053517E4E1C9A5E18C37A785644"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall, in consultation with the steering committee established under subparagraph (C), award assistance under this paragraph in accordance with such criteria as the steering committee establishes.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51ACFD5DEA9041508FA249EBD8ACDDD0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Steering committee</header>
 <clause id="H4068427D48FD42CB8B4892E5C6BE53B1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish a steering committee—</text> <subclause id="H6884035FD93E45F48CB9187BE26B41F8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to establish selection criteria for the awarding of assistance under paragraph (1) to employ a veteran to carry out a project under subparagraph (A) of subsection (b)(1) or to award a grant or contract to carry out a project under subparagraph (B) of such subsection; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB6D9A4FACF854CF6B8AAD5D0A6B1979A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to provide the Secretary of Veterans Affairs with advice on awarding assistance under this subsection with respect to projects described in subsection (a)(1) and carrying out the requirements of the veterans conservation corps under subsection (b).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HB376B911403C46F2A6434FB3804893C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The steering committee shall be composed of the following:</text> <subclause id="H529F0E8B04CA4BF2B7439554682DAC82"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H89C9C30EDF62473FB4A4BF63A1B81C45"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The Secretary of Agriculture.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H7F86DC26BAF0460C9672D2D52861B608"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The Secretary of Commerce.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4B3B55D2FF534E4CA954BAB6D1D1E398"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Interior.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H1D2909167412495A997E27FC2AD1CD4B"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Corporation for National and Community Service.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE097FF0193004280B527269FAB48892D"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>The Chief of Engineers.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H3D332455F8DA4F35B92D67838BD6D7AC"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The chairperson of the steering committee shall be the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H492CCC3D8DA44701BA92A5B2E50330D8"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Advisory input</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Labor, and the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service may provide advice to the steering committee.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H946744457D9B4454B330FA7733FB8C20"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Assistance for first responders</header><text>Not more than 10 percent of amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out this section may be transferred to the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security to employ veterans under subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEF98C79020C34B9496BD366B2C4E005E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting framework</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish a reporting framework to regularly monitor and evaluate the veterans conservation corps to ensure proper oversight and accountability of the veterans conservation corps.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE5A6A4B112444F18BD0069320BFC5EA9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that veterans employed under the veterans conservation corps are aware of benefits and assistance available to them under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5CA77C62262F48B9880FB19D32816345"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Donations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may solicit, accept, hold, administer, use, and dispose of, in furtherance of the purpose of this Act, donations of any money or property, real, personal, or mixed, tangible or intangible, received by gift, devise, bequest, or otherwise. Donations accepted under this subparagraph shall be used as nearly as possible in accordance with the terms, if any, of such donation.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HDE5132E1690D4910959CFFEAFD0CBF81"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="H6753E96E7E0542FD92507AE4273BC3D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is available without further appropriation to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out this section, $600,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H679ED7A322C0499E8193D9739B1B59C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Of amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to carry out this section, not more than five percent may be spent to administer the veterans conservation corps.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0EFB72A54BF4D1FA76B7A271D974B08"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definition of veteran</header><text>In this section, the term <term>veteran</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

