<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H41AF890023C74E6093F80C5B1F6FD12D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3901 IH: Moving and Fostering Innovation to Revolutionize Smarter Transportation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3901</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171002">October 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001199">Mr. Smucker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish the Strengthening Mobility and
			 Revolutionizing Transportation (SMART) Challenge Grant Program to promote
			 technological innovation in our Nation’s cities.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H02A13CA0BE4747D887430A4DA9EE95A4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H51E1240DECE84570A18EF747F920A8DE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Moving and Fostering Innovation to Revolutionize Smarter Transportation Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Moving FIRST Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H14ED8201FF754324BEE1913C568F3BCF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB0D8F445700F43BE99949DD88FA4DA06"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Beyond Traffic 2045, a comprehensive assessment of the national transportation system recently published by the Department of Transportation, identified transportation trends that need to be proactively addressed, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0823D59DFDD849158500C0A3E01A963F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the population of the United States will increase by 70,000,000 during the 30-year period ending in 2045;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0630DC3B73E9402BAF530179E1D9A395"><enum>(B)</enum><text>emerging megaregions could absorb 75 percent of the United States population by 2050;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB12023FC0BA545C9A7C09935D7A902B4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>freight volume will increase by more than 40 percent by 2045;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CCF4A0E68B64E47AC768D5A9A2B7465"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Americans are currently stuck in traffic for more than 42 hours each year, on average;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD7069B32CC543F1B7CE67BDBFCDB077"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the current annual cost of congestion in delays and lost fuel amounts to $160,000,000,000;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC56252349F0D4C948631E5E54704B6BE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>96 people die in motor vehicle crashes in the United States every day, on average, and nearly 6,700 are injured per day; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFDBDF91C5FB4BE18268131335CAB7AD"><enum>(G)</enum><text>connected vehicles and new crash avoidance technology could potentially address 81 percent of crashes involving unimpaired drivers.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H083167DE021F45BBAEA3C66582D2758B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>According to the Department of Transportation, in 2015—</text> <subparagraph id="H5865B7A7FBCE4709B1703E95DCF6BB8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>traffic crash-related deaths increased by more than 7 percent compared to 2014;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0943963D02D4834921635571BF5A672"><enum>(B)</enum><text>pedestrian fatalities increased by more than 9 percent compared to 2014; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EA2D37D6AD540E1B453E8982CE1C345"><enum>(C)</enum><text>pedalcyclist fatalities increased by more than 12 percent compared to 2014.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H23CB10538BD542D9AA23BB0AB5523B7C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 2015, the Secretary of Transportation created the Smart City Challenge to assist cities in addressing the challenges facing our Nation’s transportation system through innovative and creative means, utilizing both the public and the private sectors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H452187817C9245649F634968A9E00A0B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>By asking American cities to use emerging transportation technologies to address their most pressing problems, the Smart City Challenge aimed to spark and spread innovation through a mixture of collaboration, competition, and experimentation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB2FB301A2C8142398D6F4D25C2F990EF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The following outcomes were expected from the original Smart City Challenge and are expected to result from the SMART grants awarded under this Act:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6D2033EE39064A7DA9F137A5F0B8E78E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Improved safety from the use of advanced technologies, including connected vehicle technologies, to reduce the number of collisions, fatalities, and injuries for vehicle occupants and nonvehicle occupants.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF00786EA53EC40F8A600BEBE70027101"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Enhanced mobility by providing realtime traveler information and emerging mobility services to improve personal mobility for all citizens including people with lower incomes, people with disabilities, and older adults.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H827528AD0D224A06852636DB596E208A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Enhanced ladders of opportunity by—</text> <clause id="H813014B23DC945E6B7BE833BDBFF3C21"><enum>(i)</enum><text>providing access to advanced technology and its benefits for underserved areas and residents;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H383E5B18A6EA4F41A9FB93B1D9BA559D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>increasing connectivity to employment, education, and other services; and</text> </clause><clause id="HD11129E57F724AA689DE723C167EF8E3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>contributing to revitalization by incentivized reinvestment in underserved communities.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F52E5BFAA2048C6BD8D6A832EE62935"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Reduction in pollution by implementing advanced technologies and policies that support a more sustainable and cost-effective relationship between transportation and the environment through more efficient fuel use and emissions reductions.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H42867D908EF04BBFA30F8E456A94AFED"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H4D270F2DC36248AAABCEDBE3099AF358"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible applicant</header><text>The term <term>eligible applicant</term> means a large city, a mid-sized city, a rural community, or a regional partnership.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H64ADEDC6C9834265A8605A2EF8E3F0CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Large city</header><text>The term <term>large city</term> means a beneficiary city with a population between 400,000 and 1,000,000, according to the Census Bureau’s most recent annual estimates of resident population.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H37978A5FED8A4136843224E55B795C85"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mid-sized city</header><text>The term <term>mid-sized city</term> means a beneficiary city with a population between 75,000 and 400,000, according to the Census Bureau’s most recent annual estimates of resident population.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE13A391ED73B4812B51EBC7454BD4DCE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Multi-jurisdictional group</header><text>The term <term>multi-jurisdictional group</term> means a beneficiary composed of a combination of two or more States, tribal governments, local governments, public transit agencies, public toll authorities, or metropolitan planning agencies, each of which is eligible to apply for a SMART grant under section 4.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H708943725CE247819212A49060C713FA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Regional partnership</header><text>The term <term>regional partnership</term> means a group of two or more jurisdictions with a combined population between 10,000 and 75,000, according to the Census Bureau’s most recent annual estimates of resident population, which have entered into a partnership to apply for a SMART grant under section 4.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H13EBFE67A7B949898C744E429BF304CF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rural community</header><text>The term <term>rural community</term> means a beneficiary jurisdiction with a population between 10,000 and 75,000 people, not located within an urbanized area or cluster, according to the Census Bureau’s most recent annual estimates of resident population.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4EA853A2F2B43ADA2810C0536A2A6CF"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7FDFA3A8B014455EA219899E58198E5A"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Strengthening mobility and revolutionizing transportation grant; SMART grant</header><text>The terms <term>Strengthening Mobility and Revolutionizing Transportation grant</term> and <term>SMART grant</term> means a grant awarded to an eligible applicant under section 4.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H4CF3DA514E87425CB71AE16AB9D34F86"><enum>4.</enum><header>SMART Grant Program</header>
 <subsection id="HE898C41138634AF1909E81CEA69E3FAA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text>During each of the fiscal years 2019 through 2023, the Secretary is authorized to award—</text> <paragraph id="H55D72C6C7D664C8A928C5EF5D8007AB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>1 SMART grant of not less than $30,000,000 or more than $50,000,000 to an applicant on behalf of a large city to carry out an eligible project;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD6F0EBA818304F43B026C3EB83747FDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>1 SMART grant of not less than $30,000,000 or more than $50,000,000 to an applicant on behalf of a mid-sized city to carry out an eligible project; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H642A5007BA3C45D2B3F54065EE1CCCEF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>2 SMART grants, totaling not more than the greater of $20,000,000 or 20 percent of the amount appropriated pursuant to section 6(a) for the fiscal year, to applicants on behalf of rural communities or regional partnerships to carry out eligible projects.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE7F4FD59D73547CF9C59817AEC7CD4BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application process</header>
 <paragraph id="H59C745DC9B5D4743856E4691AD329449"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible applicant may apply for a grant under this section by submitting an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require to evaluate the merits of the proposed project in accordance with the selection criteria set forth in subsection (c).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HC6F3349CDF1049E3B7DE7EAE43EB776F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35AB0CBB125146D3A794F5C3C8AE6EDA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>State departments of transportation</header><text>Eligible rural and regional partnership applicants are strongly encouraged to seek technical assistance from the department of transportation in their respective States during the application process and during the implementation of a project that is awarded a SMART grant, as applicable.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA79AF3B8AD9041D9A6B8707AC2F86A65"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federal department of transportation</header><text>The Secretary, after reviewing all of the applications for SMART grants submitted in a fiscal year under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of subsection (a), shall—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8AA0A10236EE4814AE0615DE483D6A38"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide not fewer than 2 applicants from each of the 3 groups of applicants that submitted applications deemed superior by the Secretary with limited technical assistance to improve their respective applications; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2FE03DCF8A0A4C18B0BA456FAD1811A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>allow such applicants to resubmit their improved applications before determining which applicants will receive a SMART grant in such fiscal year.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4CF4F322B6243959209047369ED2E7C"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Multiple grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible applicant may not be awarded more than 1 SMART grant during the duration of the SMART Grant Program.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4DE796531859421FB1E6A516F9A3F826"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header>
 <paragraph id="H039402C9D28B433C93465A6BA37B217E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A panel of experts from the Department of Transportation, including representatives from the applicable subagencies within the Department, shall evaluate applications for SMART grants based on the applicable criteria described in paragraphs (2) through (4).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C456A58676E430E9D79C134335D88B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicant readiness</header><text>The panel referred to in paragraph (1) shall determine the extent to which the applicant or beneficiary city—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFF41FC4CBFA3463E9466308F77138695"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has a dense urban population typical for a large- or mid-sized American city;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0E5BFF450FE4B61A053E96424D036AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>represents more than 15 percent of the population of the census-designated place in which it is located, according to the Census Bureau’s most recent annual estimates of resident population;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61DCC712C4CF4B989E3E5464964CB8E9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has a public transportation system or other transit options committed to integrating with the sharing economy, and is considering options to reduce the frequency of single occupancy vehicles;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4C5379D17724F7DA539AAC37305B7A5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has an environment that is conducive to demonstrating proposed strategies;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB69846CD9304476A867DC79131BFEE07"><enum>(E)</enum><text>has continuity of committed leadership and capacity to carry out the proposed project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF3358BEF1F64D0DAE810A9186D80726"><enum>(F)</enum><text>is committed to making open, machine-readable data accessible, discoverable, and usable by the public, in a secure fashion, to fuel entrepreneurship and innovation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0D6D1F7A92C41899493EFB2DA2F79A0"><enum>(G)</enum><text>is likely to successfully implement the project, including technical and financial commitments from public and private sectors, and its functional capability to perform.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD799558322EB40FB9987FEC7C0700F1E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective use of technology and project benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The panel shall determine the extent to which the proposed project will use advanced data and intelligent transportation systems technologies and applications to provide significant benefits to a local area, a State, a region, or the United States, including the extent to which the project will—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBA026EE343214A5C970DFE1A86AC119D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduce congestion and delays for commerce and the traveling public;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DDF9648E57D4C029C32559CE94E0493"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improve the safety of transportation facilities and systems for pedestrians and the traveling public;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC7D0836DE974F0E92ADF3593B77BD27"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide access to jobs, education, and essential services, including health care;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E1B650C988E4C39A78B02BDD48C38FB"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">connect underserved populations and reduce their transportation costs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73A9FA54AF3D4976BED7AF468D5CE9BB"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contribute to medium- and long-term economic competitiveness;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0525C2FD0EF844A4A801DA1C5D18FBED"><enum>(F)</enum><text>improve the condition of existing transportation facilities and systems;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3312C7E453964045B63464C0677CD029"><enum>(G)</enum><text>promote connectivity between the public and transportation systems;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E22BC24C65044059BA3B16B0BD922C0"><enum>(H)</enum><text>use innovative strategies or technologies to pursue any of the primary selection criteria;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16F436D33DD8403AAF721EC9D225E190"><enum>(I)</enum><text>demonstrate strong collaboration among a broad range of participants, including the private sector, or the integration of transportation with other public service efforts;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H069AD971372E4DBA88AF2B3A9711A15F"><enum>(J)</enum><text>improve the environment, improve energy efficiency, reduce dependence on oil, or reduce pollution; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7B92582CF1014170B6F0FF141B8C4E01"><enum>(K)</enum><text>address issues identified by the Department of Transportation in the Beyond Traffic 2045 report.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA5F0D486B3414F7299CC9D24AA6877CD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of grant funds</header> <paragraph id="H4A194383FA384757B454F9FD7E270746"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Vision elements</header><text>A SMART grant may be used for a project that demonstrates a sound, innovative, integrated, and holistic approach and incorporates many aspects of the applicable vision elements set forth in this paragraph.</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE6EED10B1FF045F9BC838A4DDBF2C32A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Coordinated automation</header><text>The use of automated transportation and autonomous vehicles, which offer tremendous possibilities for enhancing safety, mobility, accessibility, equity, and the environment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFADACB1B78244919B15BB010CC36565B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Connected vehicles</header><text>Connected vehicles, which send and receive information about their movements in the network, use vehicle-to-vehicle and vehicle-to-infrastructure communications to provide connectivity that will enable countless safety, mobility, and environmental applications.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD27FAC15975747E1BB1AE08EF66D71F2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Intelligent, sensor based infrastructure</header><text>The use of a collective intelligent infrastructure allows sensors to collect and report real-time data to inform every day transportation-related operations and performance and trends of a city, ensuring that data collection and dissemination is conducted in a safe, secure manner.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD8B5FFDBC2047C99F3CA7B5DF0DB342"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Architecture and standards</header><text>The explicit use of architectures, which—</text> <clause id="H9F6547EE47F64C2BB8B6D50022BBE256"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are governed by rules, documentation, and standards;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6DF304A8ED464B5385525AEC45022B1A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may be extended to a nationwide or broader deployment;</text> </clause><clause id="H8CA64795E5E34035A9527294544039CA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>are defined and demonstrate integration of intelligent transportation systems with other systems which comprise a smart city; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H823AC023E1334D3896E5ACD29CB5A958"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>include a description of the required interfaces to other systems that utilize existing networking or other standards, if available, and any new standards that may be needed.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09EEFB5638DF44969A6C862B40D4EE5D"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Low-cost, efficient, secure, and resilient information and communications technology</header><text>Strategies and practices that advance information and communications technology that is affordable, adaptable, efficient, secure and resilient, including integrated telecommunications platforms, enterprise software, storage, and visualization systems.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38F2EFA9CBF54F7F867B7145176B9053"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Smart land use</header><text>Strategies and practices that ensure land use is efficiently optimized through a combination of planning and innovation deployments, altogether designed to lead to a better connected community that expands the range of transportation choices and access to employment, housing, education, and health services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H332AE5C181D24890B011764CABD3A0B3"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Comprehensive analytics</header><text>The development of platforms for understanding and analyzing data to address complex challenges, including personal safety and mobility, network efficiency, and environmental sustainability, and measuring the performance of a transportation network.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC27EED222DF4E9BA0D471922D4EBD64"><enum>(H)</enum><header>User-focused mobility services and choices</header><text>Strategies, initiatives, and services that increase transportation choices and options by supporting and improving mobility for all travelers, including aging Americans and persons with disabilities and advanced traveler information systems that provide real-time traffic, transit, parking, and other transportation-related information to travelers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79A59786F70F464CA8A8561FF18A2C2B"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Commerce delivery and logistics</header><text>Innovative solutions supporting efficient goods movement in ways that use data or deploy technology to create opportunities for a more efficient supply chain approach that delivers safer logistics management, improved on-time pickups and delivery, improved travel time reliability, reduced fuel consumption, and reduced labor and vehicle maintenance costs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C264949F59149DCB633DAF7A2B729F8"><enum>(J)</enum><header>Strategic business models and partnering opportunities</header><text>Creative strategic partnerships that draw in stakeholders, including private sector, nonprofit, foundation, philanthropic, academia, and other public agencies, to advance SMART grant solutions.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H509624108207429B8E0DA7635FC15DBE"><enum>(K)</enum><header>Smart grid, roadway electrification, and electric vehicles</header><text>Strategies and initiatives that leverage the smart grid (a programmable and efficient energy transmission and distribution system) in an effort to support the adoption or expansion of roadway electrification, and electric vehicle deployment. Interactions between electric vehicles and intelligent transportation systems with the smart grid should be explored and utilized.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E3343C9532B474C8D7D0E8744D9084E"><enum>(L)</enum><header>Synchronization of technology</header><text>Strategies and initiatives that utilize technology to enhance public interaction with transportation systems and increase intermodal efficiency, such as broadband or Wi-Fi access.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H29EFF2DAFB8A47D8BFB92490EDC1AEE2"><enum>(M)</enum><header>Connected, involved citizens</header><text>Strategies, local campaigns, and processes to proactively engage and inform citizens at the individual level by deploying hardware, software, and open data platforms in an effort to increase personal mobility.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC535BA750B8F4960966D34177B69FD7A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible project costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A SMART grant may be used for—</text> <subparagraph id="H4DBE08D00C924AA7897974C3A9E7309E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>development phase activities, including a reasonable amount of funding, as determined by the Secretary, for—</text>
 <clause id="H90B038C01AA648CA88151F895DA65882"><enum>(i)</enum><text>planning;</text> </clause><clause id="HE0D4D9062FAD470EA9C9B019A0639249"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>feasibility analysis;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9652BFBF1BD647568695662CF398764D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>revenue forecasting;</text> </clause><clause id="HBE820E924A644D9F8EFF6908DB946FE5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>environmental review;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H764B7F61868F4AE28BE0EE1DF274E0DA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>permitting;</text> </clause><clause id="HAAE0B15E4F204678804FA7D8E13F4B4D"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>preliminary engineering and design work;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8D98C3C3F76E4DA6A01587B51A1F74CE"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>systems development or information technology work; and</text> </clause><clause id="H714702C9C8F64C62A91B4E4E7C688BC2"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>other preconstruction activities; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FFA4D81DF5E41DD966B6AE197DD156E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>construction phase activities, including—</text> <clause id="HA1916BBC752A424BAC03D886EC8E322A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>construction;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H04DF1D47EE1540C3A8FED65DFA9F2A1F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reconstruction;</text> </clause><clause id="H308A1CAC46E34E13B516D515CA80EB54"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>rehabilitation;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4EDF4F2694B34D05A45EE60A997AAFDF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>replacement;</text> </clause><clause id="HA3445D7569AE46B9A2F8A3C7DCEA6752"><enum>(v)</enum><text>acquisition of real property (including land related to the eligible project and improvements to land);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAFDFF70B8AD7426FAEAD50F0E4853F5D"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>environmental mitigation;</text> </clause><clause id="H6B90E7A0F0A74C66ABCC8499CD086F28"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>construction contingencies; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB68CF5F0CFDB4587B22202D4EBFC9645"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>acquisition of equipment, including vehicles.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5483B0EF30FA49988EF27B09C247B29B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibited use of grant funds</header><text>SMART grants may not be used—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H86DE30F106D646C0A8D39E533ACA9020"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to reimburse any pre-award costs or application preparation costs under the proposed project application; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H591D0D74ABC0470A9EC7367277FB0451"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for traffic or parking enforcement activities.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDC53DE65CD61461DB811A16DFCA7FFC5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Transparency</header> <paragraph id="HDF232AD34C2947A387856E982C8CC232"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall include, in any notice of funding availability, a full description of how applications will be evaluated against the criteria set forth in subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6420BC3565554EECB0C2149B422DEB95"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultations on decisions</header><text>After all SMART grants have been awarded for a fiscal year, the Secretary (or the Secretary’s designee) shall be available to meet with any unsuccessful applicant, at a time and place that is mutually acceptable to the Secretary and the applicant, to review the application of the applicant.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC946173886C4E9E904D6247BB0A39CE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Submission of application for other Federal transportation funding programs To carry out proposed
 SMART grant projects</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an eligible applicant for a SMART grant under this section may submit an application for projects outlined in the applicant’s SMART grant application to seek Federal financial assistance for the proposed transportation project through—</text>
 <paragraph id="H919FDE56C27A48858CF5A4C54048FE02"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Transportation Investment Generating Economic Recovery grant program (commonly known as <quote>TIGER</quote>);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3DD78D394E644978BA9486447A7A9E60"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Infrastructure for Rebuilding America grant program (commonly known as <quote>INFRA</quote>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFCF90CDD1EE14D3BB81F9A7421DA4C2D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Transportation Infrastructure Finance and Innovation program established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/23/6">chapter 6</external-xref> of title 23, United States Code (commonly known as <quote>TIFIA</quote>); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H88A18AB3191241208BAD5FFB2907415C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Advanced Transportation and Congestion Management Technologies Deployment Program established under section 503(c)(4) of title 23, United States Code (commonly known as <quote>ATCMTD</quote>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2B498E70406C44A4A6615CD63718EB89"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header>
 <subsection id="HC72F89D328BB425897C1B09C67176EF2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report to Secretary</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which a SMART grant recipient receives a grant under section 4, and annually thereafter until such grant is expended, the recipient shall submit an implementation report to the Secretary that describes—</text>
 <paragraph id="H522D4486A85845B8A54E21B85C906A07"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the deployment and operational costs compared to the benefits and savings from the project; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6E2A2C4DF984F5385719BA9A2AF55AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how the project has met the original expectation as projected in the deployment plan submitted with the application, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2DB83B0131CC4D11AC681C8F3F30E712"><enum>(A)</enum><text>data on how the program—</text> <clause id="H21BCF3B133DF4199AD11C8379D2348D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has helped reduce traffic crashes, congestion, and costs;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBEC8F518FB7E4E67B19559EF0A4E81DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has improved access to jobs, education, or essential services; and</text> </clause><clause id="H0A6764BDD479418199DAFF98B304D5C3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has provided other benefits through deployed systems;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92A8F8FCE6AC446D804611631D6E32B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>data on the effect of measuring and improving transportation system performance through the deployment of advanced technologies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF005E5F9106C479D8EB964924D4CA697"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the effectiveness of providing real-time integrated traffic, transit, and multimodal transportation information to the public to make informed travel decisions; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H586CE0FF04634F43ADA7F376F1DC20B9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>lessons learned and recommendations for future deployment strategies to optimize transportation efficiency and multimodal system performance.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6A95163749B44C497F6A5524D9672F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO biennial reviews</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and biennially thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review of the SMART grant selection process and submit a report containing the results of such review to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H48565E6B11FD4F16A5E42AC697DE7EC1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the annual awarding of grants under section 4, the Secretary shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that describes the effectiveness of SMART grant recipients in meeting their projected deployment plan, including data on how the projects funded by such grants or by other Department of Transportation financial assistance described in section 4(f) have—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFFF19D3C345F46AAB23F59CCC0B267DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reduced traffic-related fatalities and injuries;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB624134443F4BAF902B72D06E1B8309"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reduced traffic congestion and improved travel time reliability;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H231B1D712906489B9E1AB3E8FA0D52E3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reduced transportation-related emissions;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA08D655A1564DB28A2F10B8125087B0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>optimized multimodal system performance;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0EF9560969A4A95856FF46D8D8469BB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>improved access to transportation alternatives;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7356C05451334202BD143C3CB7CB6785"><enum>(6)</enum><text>implemented technological innovation to increase efficiency with regards to intermodal communication, energy consumption, information and communications technology, and personal mobility;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59BF96C4998E4CFCBC1D208C9905E268"><enum>(7)</enum><text>provided the public with access to real-time integrated traffic, transit, and multimodal transportation information to make informed travel decisions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63306A5354FD4011819C80ABBBD95D4E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>provided cost savings to transportation agencies, businesses, and the traveling public;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E717DED824F448AA3184AC6AFAB088C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>provided other benefits to transportation users and the general public;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H401B73BE9C594F4B94568544EA6B9892"><enum>(10)</enum><text>reduced barriers to various essential services; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDDBDF1398F14556B5407A1E59ECA9A9"><enum>(11)</enum><text>utilized partnerships with the private sector.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEEF03C25331949428A1A3B865FCE764F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <subsection id="HBDFDF0E6D8E54A3B9AE81D968B48923F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Transportation $100,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2019 through 2023 to carry out this Act, of which—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB1C9E82443424D43BCEA0523C433C4DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>80 percent shall be used for SMART grants to large cities and mid-sized cities under paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 4(a); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD01142EFDA8D467B90D19C86489081C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>20 percent shall be used for SMART grants to rural communities or regional partnerships under section 4(a)(3).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE50C1B18654419DBE6547CD0A6A517E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts appropriated for a fiscal year pursuant to this section shall be available for obligation during the 2-year period beginning on the first day of the fiscal year for which they were appropriated.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


