<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H85CEB6B6ABF34631B0AF831BEB60664F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2179 IH: Drug Testing for Welfare Recipients Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2179</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170426">April 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require certain welfare programs to deny benefits to persons who fail a drug test, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1A12411CBB38476389E5874E17A5C167" style="OLC">
 <section id="H18EF27136E154BD9986E4023F89D3A15" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Drug Testing for Welfare Recipients Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5560FFB1576D484C950369E633D20193"><enum>2.</enum><header>Drug screening and testing under State programs for temporary assistance for needy families</header> <subsection id="H2276BC4CFABF4881AE8990FE48DFA00F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 408(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/608">42 U.S.C. 608(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03C3B67D05BB4EAFAB5F17754F1D2FCF" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="H5D782EF40AAB4C878B74A0A62A53F1AD"><enum>(13)</enum><header>No assistance for individuals who fail drug screening or testing or are not screened or tested for
			 drug use</header>
 <subparagraph id="H4CF3969E9E7841EE8B60FA4E0EC99E12"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State to which a grant is made under section 403 shall not use any part of the grant to provide assistance for an individual who has attained 18 years of age, unless, before receipt of the assistance—</text>
 <clause id="H0379284869544497A50FB6C3F92EFE9B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the State makes a determination, in a manner the State considers appropriate, of whether the individual has or has not been arrested for a drug-related offense during the 5-year period immediately preceding the date on which the determination is made;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H668B45742FAD42FF87D37EDCBEB20ABF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an individual who is determined by the State to have been arrested for a drug-related offense during the 5-year period provided in clause (i), the individual tests negative for not less than 1 controlled substance, as specified by the State, in such manner and at such times as the State determines to be appropriate; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H969AE3643069429A8AB8DD454319D31A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an individual who is determined by the State not to have been arrested for a drug-related offense during the 5-year period provided in clause (i), the individual—</text>
 <subclause id="HF4F8BEAF53B04161AF5A55EFF924706F"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">completes substance abuse screening in such manner and at such times as the State considers appropriate; and</text>
								</subclause><subclause id="H117A454B7A8C4B0E88715FEF4C26A1E4"><enum>(II)</enum>
 <item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H60C57673AA254AE5B2E5BA3D5B81E0E9"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is determined pursuant to such screening not to have a high risk of abuse of a controlled substance; or</text>
 </item><item id="HAF381DCA80DF4ED6B7DBE24D583206E1" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is determined pursuant to such screening to have a high risk of abuse of a controlled substance and tests negative for not less than 1 controlled substance, as specified by the State, in such manner and at such times as the State determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC759D72F2B474DE8BBBB2A4168A2CA1E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect of failing drug test</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual who tests positive for a controlled substance pursuant to subparagraph (A)(ii) or (A)(iii)(II)(bb), a State shall not provide assistance under the State program funded under this part for the individual for a period beginning on the date on which the State determines that the test result is positive and ending on the latest of—</text>
 <clause id="HC8AAE3DC6C61465FB8A265313BFE3F00"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 12 months after the date on which the State determines that the test result is positive;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEEEBD68CA037443A917F1D7B360E9C83"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which the individual successfully completes a treatment program for each controlled substance for which the individual tested positive; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H662651D092F74120A34553C4B533EE4C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the individual tests negative for each such controlled substance, in such manner and at such times as the State determines to be appropriate.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36CEFDC45470495F879843094A85DF8F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Responsibility for testing and screening</header>
 <clause id="HAADDD1532AD3441884E325B0A2CCD26C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Manner and time</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State may provide for testing and screening pursuant to paragraph (1), and retesting and rescreening pursuant to paragraph (2), in such manner and at such times as the State agency considers appropriate.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA163D0E2C78440428DF36C5E0B6F7E4A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Costs</header><text>A State may not require an individual to pay the cost of testing or screening conducted pursuant to this paragraph.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H002D610A4FB34C9E89A285EC5F2C98BB"><enum>(D)</enum><header>No effect on assistance for other family members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of assistance payable for a family member of an individual for whom assistance is denied pursuant to this paragraph shall not be affected by the denial.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H332D30890A4F4786A4ADE633EBBCBEED"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph:</text> <clause id="H5863A267727D414EAAFA48FCA2EEDC2D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Controlled substance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>controlled substance</quote> means, with respect to an individual, any controlled substance as defined in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>) that is not used by such individual pursuant to a valid prescription or as otherwise authorized by law.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB5E60E9CCEBF445C92CD4D3141514E9A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Drug-related offense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>drug-related offense</quote> means any criminal offense under State or Federal law relating to the manufacture, sale, distribution, use, or possession with intent to manufacture, sell, distribute, or use, of a controlled substance.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H24F3FDA108ED4267AFD14F3E32688F80"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Substance abuse screening</header><text>The term <quote>substance abuse screening</quote> means an interview, questionnaire, or other screening instrument approved by the State, that is designed to be used to determine whether an individual has a high risk of abuse of a controlled substance.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HD50C1B848689415BBC1F86092AB5C302"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalty</header>
 <paragraph id="H84F136B3A18245F09D99E077536BB27E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Section 409(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/609">42 U.S.C. 609(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51D7C449438C47269F915E06E0F7935B" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HC93B97AF723F43669874626BDCC12849"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Failure to condition receipt of benefits on passing drug testing or screening</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines that a State to which a grant is made under section 403 for a fiscal year has substantially failed to comply with section 408(a)(13) during the fiscal year, the Secretary shall reduce the grant payable to the State under section 403 for the immediately succeeding fiscal year by an amount equal to 15 percent of the State family assistance grant.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H491C3689AE11470B92726559C89E145D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inapplicability of good cause exception</header><text>Section 409(b)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/609">42 U.S.C. 609(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or (13)</quote> and inserting <quote>(13), or (17)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H56DE8BDF647E4F71B10127A1655170F2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inapplicability of corrective compliance plan requirement</header><text>Section 409(c)(4) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/609">42 U.S.C. 609(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or (16)</quote> and inserting <quote>(16), or (17)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC8ECA9047FFC4860A2A4F517C401F371"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the first day of the first calendar month that begins after the 240-day period that begins with the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE15C7E11975D4306ABF980FF9A478464" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Drug screening and testing under the supplemental nutrition assistance program</header>
 <subsection id="HEFECE76649574CC29D9F7EE3D6E03FF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Drug testing and screening required for eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2015">7 U.S.C. 2015</external-xref>) is amended by adding at end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H586896B959E54FDEB20E162EF9603371" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H0B232501374247C9A9BA183DE8CBE2A7"><enum>(t)</enum><header>Eligibility based on required drug testing and screening</header>
 <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A20C3E10C314CDD9CDE469D9809494A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who has attained 18 years of age and who is otherwise eligible to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program as a member of a household shall be eligible to participate in such program only if before such assistance is provided with respect to such individual—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAB3F288E466B49AA8735B56C21818E6A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the State determines, in a manner the State considers appropriate, whether such individual has or has not been arrested for a drug-related offense during the 5-year period ending on the date on which the determination is made;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H354C3E5F421045F5B069E6D09811AE86"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an individual who is determined by the State to have been arrested for a drug-related offense during such 5-year period, such individual tests negative for not less than 1 controlled substance, as specified by the State, in such manner and at such times as the State considers appropriate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33D2C264386044A18377D5359223C86A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an individual who is determined by the State not to have been arrested for a drug-related offense during such 5-year period, such individual—</text>
 <clause id="H25B7D8AAAB564DC39BC7B2E6DFEA7687"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">completes substance abuse screening, in such manner and at such times as the State considers appropriate; and</text>
								</clause><clause id="H4BF131A68FAD4890A7AE1F286C4F5C16"><enum>(ii)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H448E580595E34108B3D199E66494141D"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is determined pursuant to such screening not to have a high risk of abuse of a controlled substance; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HDC9899FF8D6C4B9C8F3167D7BEC03A6E" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is determined pursuant to such screening to have a high risk of abuse of a controlled substance and tests negative for not less than 1 controlled substance, as specified by the State, in such manner and at such times as the State considers appropriate.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AD09BEE6DD74ACFB240521D0C42EF4A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of a positive drug test result</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual tests positive for a controlled substance pursuant to paragraph (1), such assistance may not be provided with respect to such individual for a period beginning on the date on which the State agency determines that the test result is positive and ending on the latest of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEC9A88441612406CA1B9C0D25768657E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 1 year after the date on which the State agency determines that the test result is positive;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86E51D7E9FD24C8D816D153A39B6A196"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date on which such individual successfully completes a treatment program for each controlled substance for which the individual tested positive pursuant to paragraph (1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB96E65CC576246A284DF5B4851AF067F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date by which the test result for such individual is not positive for each controlled substance for which the individual tested positive pursuant to paragraph (1).</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA67B106EDBB45B699546E19312B3F3D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Responsibility for testing and screening</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0C2BF911D00E466699383991B0FE3787"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State agency may provide for testing and screening pursuant to paragraph (1), and retesting and rescreening pursuant to paragraph (2), in such manner and at such times as the State agency considers appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C4FE5E61637453DB1D6C0E8E9034ECD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The State agency may not require an individual or a household to pay the cost of a test or screening conducted pursuant to this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H37041D4ECB244A87A95E3AEAEC51EDE6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H5976D2BB71944A41813D8E3F8A55E81E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Controlled substance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>controlled substance</quote> means a controlled substance as defined in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>) that is not used by the tested individual pursuant to a valid prescription or as otherwise authorized by law.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE28006EBDF2C41A58DE046CE53E05380"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Drug-related offense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>drug-related offense</quote> means any criminal offense under State or Federal law relating to the manufacture, sale, distribution, use, or possession with intent to manufacture, sell, distribute, or use, of a controlled substance.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCD3E170B78745BAB54D44DFD7935AE9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Substance abuse screening</header><text>The term <quote>substance abuse screening</quote> means an interview, questionnaire, or other screening instrument approved by the State, that is designed to be used to determine whether an individual has a high risk of abuse of a controlled substance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB5218FDFB5FD44D6BECA374EA5D64ACD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reduction of reimbursement for administrative costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 16 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2025">7 U.S.C. 2025</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6B29DB518C834C03A6CAB6C6ABDDD446"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a) by striking <quote>subsection (k)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (k) and (l)</quote>, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H227A260E4DB945F7803D6FF24F19D4FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD94A1B188CF54E53A6B44F5DD120F685" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H9A5E9E6F1FC54752A395D17E09ED6626"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Failure To enforce drug testing and screening requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines that the State agency failed substantially to enforce the eligibility requirement established in section 6(t) in a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reduce by 15 percent the amount otherwise payable under subsection (a) to such State agency for the immediately succeeding fiscal year.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCF8E8185D5D94A79840CE3FC751CFD0D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall take effect 240 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H299E6C12048B4AD288B8965489005D37"><enum>4.</enum><header>Drug screening and testing under public housing and section 8 rental assistance programs</header>
 <subsection id="HF0B23412D7474BBC8D3A21312AC2FB6B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 214 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1436a">42 U.S.C. 1436a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC32CDA261321468DA7A18CCA59B509EA" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H610704458E084487A566F4776738D4AA"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Prohibition of housing assistance for individuals who fail drug screening or testing or are not
			 screened or tested</header>
 <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H164D10A88BBA49D0A48340993000D040"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the applicable administrative entity may not make covered housing assistance available for the benefit of any individual who has attained 18 years of age, unless, before such assistance is provided with respect to such individual—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6B6EFB407F5147B38575A0B7F55A7C95"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicable administrative entity makes a determination, in a manner the entity considers appropriate, of whether the individual has or has not been arrested for a drug-related offense during the 5-year period immediately preceding the date on which the determination is made;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C7A11DF19DE43F9BC993F97DDD5102D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an individual who is determined by the applicable administrative entity to have been arrested for a drug-related offense during the 5-year period provided in subparagraph (A), the individual tests negative for each controlled substance that the entity has determined to be appropriate for testing; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7A827D7E1F74A7D80D4F78B3E781382"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an individual who is determined by the applicable administrative entity not to have been arrested for a drug-related offense during the 5-year period provided in clause (i), the individual—</text>
 <clause id="HC5013E872D7D490FAF8706F253522280"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">completes substance abuse screening in such manner and at such times as the entity considers appropriate; and</text>
								</clause><clause id="HD97B9D6A37CC44C88BCC3BC194BFAEA1"><enum>(ii)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC3931FB2BDC748298711F63DCED3EB50"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is determined pursuant to such screening not to have a high risk of abuse of a controlled substance; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE0C3C94C7C1947F081BA9BBD149F04B7" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is determined pursuant to such screening to have a high risk of abuse of a controlled substance and tests negative for each controlled substance that the entity has determined to be appropriate for testing.</text>
									</subclause></clause></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The applicable administrative entity shall determine that not less than 1 controlled substance, as
			 specified by the entity, is appropriate for testing for purposes of this
 paragraph.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE651DB1C1F454A8B98A3B85489CEE0EF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of failing drug test</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual tests positive for a controlled substance pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) or (1)(C)(ii)(II), covered housing assistance may not be provided with respect to such individual for the period beginning on the date on which the applicable administrative entity determines that the test result is positive and ending on the latest of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H38EDB982FD6A443DABCE5EB2768DC9F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 12 months after the date on which the applicable administrative entity determines that the test result is positive;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8761F78F6ED43D39AEAB8B69D1786BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date on which the individual successfully completes a treatment program for each controlled substance for which the individual tested positive; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28C922167716415F9F441CAC22B2A5DE"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the individual tests negative for each such controlled substance, in such manner and at such times as the applicable administrative entity determines to be appropriate.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8C961D46F1B42FF892C11FD9E9BD5A4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Responsibility for testing and screening</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA1543BE55F864800A7C3FF9595AD88DC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Manner and time</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An applicable administrative entity may provide for testing and screening pursuant to paragraph (1), and retesting and rescreening pursuant to paragraph (2), in such manner and at such times as the entity determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BE59AC857D841A8896E020341824667"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An applicable administrative entity may not require an individual or family to pay the cost of a test or screening conducted pursuant to this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H49A2723F80A242EA83B64EB810C095C5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Proration of financial assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual for whose benefit covered housing assistance is prohibited pursuant to this subsection is a member of family that includes at least one other member whose eligibility under this subsection for such assistance has been affirmatively established pursuant to testing under this subsection, covered housing assistance made available to such family shall be prorated, based on the number of individuals in the family for whom eligibility under this subsection for such assistance has been affirmatively established pursuant to testing under this subsection as compared with the total number of individuals who are members of the family.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF024C765407D4689B2BD786606A0D117"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Failure to enforce drug testing requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development determines that a public housing agency has substantially failed to comply with this subsection during a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reduce by 15 percent the amount otherwise provided to the agency, for the immediately succeeding fiscal year, under each of the following programs:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB3526D2FFF6747CAAE486E6D8CF16BB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The public housing Capital Fund program under section 9(d) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437g">42 U.S.C. 1437g(d)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28D4E29EB2E740618376CA871C82B8A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The public housing Operating Fund program under section 9(e) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437g">42 U.S.C. 1437g(e)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD90948BA30A64B8DBF08F7069B3E2BB2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>All programs for rental housing assistance under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H89318F3CE98342698292357D70945020"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Use of housing assistance amounts for testing</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, amounts made available under the following provisions of law may be used for costs of testing individuals for controlled substances for purposes of compliance with this section, as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H77EF67C01FC543D1A0A311D622BE5763"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available under the public housing Operating Fund program under section 9(e) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437g">42 U.S.C. 1437g(e)</external-xref>) may be used for such testing for residents of, and applicants for residency in, public housing.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCA21332B61642A9BDBFDD32448948E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Amounts made available to a public housing agency for administrative fees under section 8(q) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(q)</external-xref>) may be used for such testing for individuals on behalf of whom rental assistance under such section is provided by the agency and applicants for such assistance.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FF3A593AF2E495C9893C42F691B8843"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Amounts made available for project-based rental assistance under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</external-xref>) may be used for such testing for residents of, and applicants for residency in, dwelling units in housing projects for which such assistance is provided.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE85CD915C19F41CEB422739FE8DC0835"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the following definitions shall apply:</text> <subparagraph id="HC573DDE0F53547A4970AB120D7353099"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Applicable administrative entity</header><text>The term <quote>applicable administrative entity</quote> means—</text>
 <clause id="HD1EE82AAAF044C968483B897980E8A6B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a public housing agency, with respect to covered housing assistance administered by such agency; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0A930D6F97854C2C90706C40160F0040"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary, with respect to project-based rental assistance under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28639D54E8EF4ADB98A8C2ED41794164"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Controlled substance</header><text>The term <quote>controlled substance</quote> means, with respect to an individual, a controlled substance as defined in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>) that is not used by such individual pursuant to a valid prescription or as otherwise authorized by law.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H033F38EE4BB24428A72FD48BF4EA6BBC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Covered housing assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered housing assistance</quote> means financial assistance made available pursuant to the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437">42 U.S.C. 1437</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF22C9A973994F738B6045A2C0A7602D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Drug-related offense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>drug-related offense</quote> means any criminal offense under State or Federal law relating to the manufacture, sale, distribution, use, or possession with intent to manufacture, sell, distribute, or use, of a controlled substance.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5832E3326C5047E6BBF5B5E7FDF7BC8B"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Substance abuse screening</header><text>The term <quote>substance abuse screening</quote> means an interview, questionnaire, or other screening instrument approved by the applicable administrative entity that is designed to be used to determine whether an individual has a high risk of abuse of a controlled substance.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7A5150A436E4E42B2D416C8C23AAA9D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Other provisions of law</header><text>This subsection may not be construed to affect the applicability of any provision of section 576 or 577 of the Quality Housing and Work Responsibility Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/13661">42 U.S.C. 13661</external-xref>, 13662) or of sections 6(l), 8(o)(7), or 16(f) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437n">42 U.S.C. 1437n(f)</external-xref>), except that the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall ensure that any standards or lease provisions established pursuant to such sections are consistent with this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5D591CF9FEF24C578720B1577A248516"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the first day of the first calendar month that begins after the 240-day period that begins with the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


