<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB6E137E6D9B84F5B99C40B50F4F868EF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2865 IH: Better Education and Skills Training for America’s Workforce Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2865</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170608">June 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a credit for employer-provided job training,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4DF22BEBE06E4C8DBCC56B6470CE7D30" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7EBBDB8429C64FE5BAF2EBF2CE06CC0A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Better Education and Skills Training for America’s Workforce Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6500DC8F0FD44DF5A0A4C114E2F4B560" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Job training tax credit</header> <subsection id="HD75AA5143AA64AF8AB2B47B8BAF1FCF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC24236F1A5284BC5B3F9FFEB9D23C981" style="OLC">
					<section id="HD4B846164BCC4C2A8C60D6D92CD23025"><enum>45S.</enum><header>Job training credit</header>
 <subsection id="HB51255B42B34476984BED167864359EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purposes of section 38, the job training credit determined under this section for the taxable year is an amount equal to 100 percent of the qualified training expenses paid by the qualifying taxpayer during the taxable year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAFD68231D8BA4D95A9F76B0436506223"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The credit allowed under subsection (a) with respect to any eligible trainee of the qualifying taxpayer shall not exceed the excess (if any) of $4,000 over the aggregate credit allowed to such taxpayer under this section with respect to such eligible trainee for all prior taxable years.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD128754EF95F4E6EB2D4BD523B02A8EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="HDC9A8BA143324A7480A33D203CE442F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified training expenses</header> <subparagraph id="H50D88D7CC37C43C6AF4C059C16F69A80"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified training expenses</term> means, with respect to any eligible trainee of the qualifying taxpayer, expenses paid or incurred by such taxpayer for qualified tuition costs of such eligible trainee.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D4B1D42D0494CA1B28A0A725FF980DB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified tuition costs</header><text>The term <term>qualified tuition costs</term> means costs for books and enrollment in a training program at a qualified educational organization, the outcome of which, if completed, will provide the eligible trainee a certificate or credential recognized by a State accrediting body, Federal Apprenticeship Agency, or any other national accrediting body recognized by the Department of Education as an independent, third-party accrediting body. Such training program—</text>
 <clause id="HFBE5A68675C44FE0A491B177E4D1C0CC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may include a single course, multiple courses, or a combination of work training and study, and</text> </clause><clause id="H0A578A864CC648D3A00B0A008DA38665"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>must be reasonably necessary for employment with the qualifying taxpayer.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCB9C16E4AFA4391A2DD22EE1A2CE2F5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualified educational organization</header><text>The term <term>qualified educational organization</term> means any educational organization described in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H41958980D1C343F69CE468DA43AB8A86"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifying taxpayer</header><text>The term <term>qualifying taxpayer</term> means any taxpayer who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE494A30206B247B6865BA5A6E408C684"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to any eligible trainee, is training and hiring individuals for positions based in the United States, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFD751EA8EF24D438AB8CD9D44C9E25B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides, with respect to any eligible trainee, such documentation as required by the Secretary regarding qualified training expenses and proof of unemployment status as described in paragraph (3)(A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7ACC76EF8304C0EBC7285D3291968B7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible trainee</header><text>The term <term>eligible trainee</term> means any individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="HD182E7E7CB6C4F8EBAD57C88BC74282D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has been unemployed for at least 90 days before the date of enrollment in a training program described in paragraph (1)(B), and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9071FE276DBD4322B783A7F2AAFDB860"><enum>(B)</enum><text>had not been employed by the qualifying taxpayer at any time during the 2-year period preceding the date on which such trainee was hired.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA8CA3965DA144060B697477176D57DE1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <paragraph id="HD864FACBF7D1498F8639A73452AAC11A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under subsection (a) for any qualified training expense for which a deduction or other credit is allowed to the taxpayer under any other provision of this chapter.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08FE791717D04587B0842C038D2228E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aggregation</header><text>For purposes of this section, all persons treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) or section 52, or subsection (m) or (o) of section 414, shall be treated as one person.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF5FDEBE09A334966AD5D649050142BF4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Election To have credit not apply</header><text>A taxpayer may elect (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe) to have this section not apply for any taxable year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1431087EE5404C9F823C56CF67707075"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>This section shall not apply to expenses paid after December 31, 2028.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H16E4ADDE853840558C26863F9F4DDB10"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit To be part of general business credit</header><text>Subsection (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/38">section 38</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (35), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (36) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA1B6B2F80B84A30B3F2C164B3D3E080" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HBEA759C0B23943A681D1520E30B94B2E"><enum>(37)</enum><text>the job training credit determined under section 45S(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H9C1E2911D2BA44238577A1E757301E72"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Credit allowed against alternative minimum tax</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/38">Section 38(c)(4)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating clauses (ix), (x), and (xi) as clauses (x), (xi), and (xii), respectively, and by inserting after clause (viii) the following new clause:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D1EDF4A5C794DE5A86D82B98E18B1FB" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H2D102166BC954273AA4B3E6C6291C596"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the credit determined under section 45S,</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HE810F5CABFE44DD1B4B3AFC5187EC3B9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6501">Section 6501(m)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>45S(e),</quote> after <quote>45H(g),</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H40511FE3231C4B83B859B5A62D7031E1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H4ED46FF4F0844518856D9D98842F6C61" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry idref="HD4B846164BCC4C2A8C60D6D92CD23025" level="section">Sec. 45S. Job training credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H32407EC17EB94474AFEE832221BD129E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2027, the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary's delegate) shall report to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate on the economic impact of the job training credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45S">section 45S</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added under subsection (a)).</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF5D317626EA74B1D9313C5F280C47231"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Effective dates</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21481EFDD2E24C1C971AB53ADCD01D19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to expenses paid or incurred after the date of the enactment of this Act, in taxable years ending after such date.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D51ADB5112B4FE9B63A3788855068EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum tax</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (c) shall apply to credits determined under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45S">section 45S</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 in taxable years ending after the date of the enactment of this Act, and to carrybacks of such credits.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA195C091295D4D6CAF9EB1C4752FAFA8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Qualified Job Training Partnership  credit</header>
 <subsection id="H27BB17D9496A47E0BEE46354C8EDFFE5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart E of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 48D the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block act-name="" id="H25C6EB6405214EA6BF438B98EB98B6B2" style="OLC">
					<section id="H30E0F93236A7492F974D5D00C3C01E93"><enum>48E.</enum><header>Qualified Job Training Partnership credit</header>
 <subsection id="H7D80FC9E077F45379CEFF9338664AEC3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of section 46, the Qualified Job Training Partnership credit for any taxable year is an amount equal to the percentage determined by the Secretary (not to exceed 100 percent) of the qualified investment for such taxable year with respect to any Qualified Job Training Partnership.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H7EB792B47845487E963F734AA6C45B17"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified investment</header>
 <paragraph id="H7A87A7E7567941AA9E2DCC87E0D7ECC2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the qualified investment for any taxable year is the aggregate amount of the costs paid or incurred in such taxable year for expenses necessary for and directly related to the conduct of a Qualified Job Training Partnership in the form of contributions of cash, cash equivalent, equipment, or any combination of the three where 100 percent of the investment is used for the planning, implementation, or operation of a Qualified Job Training Partnership and the training financed through the investment must result in a type of certificate or credential recognized by a State accrediting body, Federal Apprenticeship Agency, or any other national accrediting body recognized by the Department of Education as an independent, third-party accrediting body.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0AB9CE917C24CA1BC7AF4B22CD9185C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The amount which is treated as qualified investment for all taxable years with respect to any Qualified Job Training Partnership shall not exceed the amount certified by the Secretary as eligible for the credit under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E629225B27A4DF38A5C510DDEAC51DF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The qualified investment for any taxable year with respect to any Qualified Job Training Partnership shall not take into account any cost for student tuition or for any other expense as determined by the Secretary as appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DB0B2E71C0246AE94930FDAE3949DBF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Certain progress expenditure rules made applicable</header><text>In the case of costs described in paragraph (1) that are paid for property of a character subject to an allowance for depreciation, rules similar to the rules of subsections (c)(4) and (d) of section 46 (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990) shall apply for purposes of this section.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H214E82A1A6844EA3B23CD96EEDE8420B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified Job Training Partnership</header>
 <paragraph id="H6F2BE7ED85914F9796A8D9F5DEF794B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>Qualified Job Training Partnership</term> means a formal or informal partnership between at least 1 eligible private business employer and—</text> <subparagraph id="H145215F26F2B4B56BFF9ECAA89A52E80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1 qualified educational institution, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BF64611596646F991A798BCAD0ACF87"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1 labor organization (as defined in section 2(5) of the National Labor Relations Act),</text> </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">where the stated goal of the partnership is to train students in job-ready skills.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB23EAD24C404CA7B5AE6BDD463B2F89"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible private business employer</header><text>The term <term>eligible private business employer</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCB38F2AFA3CD4BC69B93907680B18F2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a business entity at least 50 percent of the gross income of which is derived from qualified production activities (within the meaning of section 199(c)), or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D2288DF7DB4428ABEFC3552BE991CC2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any type of domestic business entity the average number of employees of which for any taxable year is not more than 500 employees.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA21A90C1C998493FADC7D1DC965ED148"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified educational organization</header><text>The term <term>qualified educational organization</term> means any educational organization described in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 which provides a 2-year program that culminates in an associate degree.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA926F5F0BE554488A2C0A2BFD87BC600"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Qualified Job Training Partnership program</header>
							<paragraph id="H548064A6ABF7429A8F3C4303CEABA88E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC2E79369F6524B13B61B64794B3BF332"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall establish a Qualified Job Training Partnership program to consider and award certifications for qualified investments eligible for credits under this section to Qualified Job Training Partnerships.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91359CF458CB481C84741327571E8FCE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The total amount of credits that may be allocated under the program shall not exceed $1,000,000,000.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H89B2CF3704CB4847B787B7D3DF77E47A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9B1CD8B56F094EEB8BB168CEA4375A1F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application period</header><text>Each applicant for certification under this paragraph shall submit an application containing such information as the Secretary may require during the period beginning on the date the Secretary establishes the program under paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F55922A94BD4ABCAC100FC457037DBB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Time for review of applications</header><text>The Secretary shall take action to approve or deny any application under subparagraph (A) within 30 days of the submission of such application.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA1F813B4D46434CAB01C9426849CE97"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Multi-year applications</header><text>An application for certification under subparagraph (A) may include a request for an allocation of credits for more than 1 year.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8ED87B962B244E3289B5BED526AA78C1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>In determining the Qualified Job Training Partnerships with respect to which qualified investments may be certified under this section, the Secretary—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA50877B5D3B74BFBB130221F6994C3AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall give priority to those applications which demonstrate—</text> <clause id="H8CB26CA67E49421F8DFE6E9EA5E1E0FF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the greatest probability that those who complete the program will secure employment;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7734844E1E4F424C8E1FD83AB5220F55"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the greatest potential for providing workers who complete the program with skills that can provide long-term job and income security;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE45048A9E9F742E29F7E3DAE7FFF398B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the strongest market demand for the type of training offered;</text> </clause><clause id="H84AD50DF572A4B4DA30EF0DB8AFE948E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the greatest probability that the program would create a net increase in job training opportunities;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H178B22B45094449BA462F4BCFEE4EA5B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a strong need in the community for skills training;</text> </clause><clause id="H281CC091FF864061A917E438EBCBE8CF"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the ability to allow nontraditional learners to complete the training; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H653E2B0D7C124F31AA6C307E45FF8FE3"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the ability and capacity to implement the program in a reasonable period of time; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC421EBDA838B4FF082729CC7AF508304"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall take into additional consideration which applications show—</text>
 <clause id="H6BB703CE05F540288C71323FE6A5F51F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the ability to leverage additional sources of capital; and</text> </clause><clause id="HCB9D52D4F88043ADB398670D39600BF9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the greatest ability to offer training programs that result in a certificate or credential (within the meaning of subsection (b)(1)) that is stackable or portable or both.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H36EF41C0A4624CB19643A70F99DFF31B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Review and additional allocation</header>
 <subparagraph id="HCD3C34D417154C7992ADF45A560C5C7E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall review the credits allocated under this section as of such date.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F3DAEDD79DF4F6CBF49ADD322D96145"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional allocation</header><text>If the Secretary determines at the time of the review that credits under this section are available for allocation pursuant to the requirements set forth in paragraph (2), the Secretary is authorized to allocate such available credits through the conduct of an additional program or programs for applications for certification.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB4415C2832149D88E26903FEB9D3855"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Disclosure of allocations</header><text>The Secretary shall, upon making a certification under this subsection, publicly disclose the identity of the applicant and the amount of the credit with respect to such applicant.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2583DFD7E8644738559ADBF821F11C6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <paragraph id="HF58B924B52CF4146AE56AA7DE5529F4D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Basis adjustment</header><text>For purposes of this subtitle, if a credit is allowed under this section for an expenditure related to property of a character subject to an allowance for depreciation, the basis of such property shall be reduced by the amount of such credit.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H27D5A8890ADF49848AC9527370C86A7B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header>
 <subparagraph id="H6BAFAE6D73B944C284D5EF96E3D87E07"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Bonus depreciation</header><text>A credit shall not be allowed under this section for any investment for which bonus depreciation is allowed under section 168(k), 1400L(b)(1), or 1400N(d)(1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9DCFFB2A4ABD4E34AA40427AD5BC9B76"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Deductions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No deduction under this subtitle shall be allowed for the portion of the expenses otherwise allowable as a deduction taken into account in determining the credit under this section for the taxable year which is equal to the amount of the credit determined for such taxable year under subsection (a) attributable to such portion. This subparagraph shall not apply to expenses related to property of a character subject to an allowance for depreciation the basis of which is reduced under paragraph (1), or which are described in section 280C(g).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8C1BB7158B2F41BAA91DEA06204D090F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion as part of investment credit</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/46">Section 46</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HFAA6A815F9DF416E986F5C554671CEA0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (5);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H60BF1102208B447BBC7FE518DC15F066"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (6) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6AA0B9B1F572465FA78800D98F2327EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block act-name="" id="HBAB1E7F59BE84456B2F5035471191FBE" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H730A7FE66CB943E48E3120121674136F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Qualified Job Training Partnership credit.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2DFA66D9C5804DD19E6D3CBB7890921F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <paragraph id="HF22B1DFC3F334FE2BE081FAA9E4E7C69"><enum>(1)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/49">Section 49(a)(1)(C)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H312176F1057A4FC68B441BF174EE14AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of clause (v);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45C94DBD11564707A7BCF884DD06C14F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of clause (vi) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H445588EF42A442F9AA326185BFB40965"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block act-name="" id="HC9776DE3B01D416F91A7A5A208DA159A" style="OLC"> <clause id="H9F2D47A830C747A29E82D9FD9959DCE8"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the basis of any property to which paragraph (1) of section 48E(e) applies which is part of a Qualified Job Training Partnership under such section 48E.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1C1FDE812D940358F0BC0DA9836CB03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 280C of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block act-name="" id="H84EC59F0641644629F64F8FE2681FEE0" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H0D6C1BB1FF2F4099A206A738CF066773"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Qualified Job Training Partnership credit</header> <paragraph id="HB53C12CF79BE4EE882F9E6EC52763115"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No deduction shall be allowed for that portion of the qualified investment (as defined in section 48E(b)) otherwise allowable as a deduction for the taxable year which is equal to the amount of the credit determined for such taxable year under section 48E(a), reduced by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC00F1ECBDAE34862876CBFACD14D1FF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount disallowed as a deduction by reason of section 48E(e)(2)(B), and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE12216C2FD3B451190D1D0D8DC724D5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount of any basis reduction under section 48E(e)(1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2AE543A80384B71A0B4785BEBE8D950"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Similar rule where taxpayer capitalizes rather than deducts expenses</header><text>In the case of expenses described in paragraph (1)(A) taken into account in determining the credit under section 48E for the taxable year, if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H575DD98E452143508B8ACEAD2010A2AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount of the portion of the credit determined under such section with respect to such expenses, exceeds</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDADF9A26987C42EDB1CE2A0DD6027DB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount allowable as a deduction for such taxable year for such expenses (determined without regard to paragraph (1)),</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">the amount chargeable to capital account for the taxable year for such expenses shall be reduced by
 the amount of such excess.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD958C35E3AB04D54BF0A916BBA6A060B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Controlled groups</header><text>Paragraph (3) of subsection (b) shall apply for purposes of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5A01F0856B6C482486FCED46FFF04A85"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart E of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 48D the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A227B2DF48D41B99D29D7126D95E83A" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 48E. Qualified Job Training Partnership credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H48BEAA630DFE426A88C93DDF5F9C560B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grants for qualified investments in Qualified Job Training Partnerships in lieu of tax credits</header>
 <paragraph id="H0BE7D06871F04EDB86A63FB4EE1E873B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon application, the Secretary of the Treasury shall, subject to the requirements of this subsection, provide a grant to each person who makes a qualified investment in a Qualified Job Training Partnership in an amount not to exceed 100 percent of such investment.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H3A8C0289C1DB4C27B54495BF441EFB6A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <subparagraph id="H610FE9E3F7504CB393241EB07DE17672"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>At the stated election of the applicant, an application for certification under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/48E">section 48E(d)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for a credit under such section for any taxable year shall be considered to be an application for a grant under paragraph (1) for such taxable year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94475DE03240494190286D55318CEEE3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Submission date</header><text>An application for a grant under paragraph (1) for any taxable year shall be submitted—</text> <clause id="HFFC844754090411D9738372AE32E8319"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not earlier than the day after the last day of such taxable year; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H93F8DF3D09F9457D99CBA1BEB7DB0174"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than the due date (including extensions) for filing the return of tax for such taxable year.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H146AA40BCE804756962CF6DF3FDA098D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Information to be submitted</header><text>An application for a grant under paragraph (1) shall include such information and be in such form as the Secretary of the Treasury may require to state the amount of the credit allowable (but for the receipt of a grant under this subsection) under section 48E for the taxable year for the qualified investment with respect to which such application is made.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DBACE07AB7D4C9E98694348E3FA557E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Time for payment of grant</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9869DBF4377D4E19A0CCDA2BF750F3CF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall make payment of the amount of any grant under paragraph (1) during the 30-day period beginning on the later of—</text>
 <clause id="H3339D836BA8B42088F81803AD11F01E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date of the application for such grant, or</text> </clause><clause id="HBC5ADEB1903C4EC2B25C7F7E91370CFE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date the qualified investment for which the grant is being made is made.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB93F80023FB4A3B812C3C7BC0837588"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>In the case of investments of an ongoing nature, the Secretary of the Treasury shall issue regulations to determine the date on which a qualified investment shall be deemed to have been made for purposes of this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AB4ED3FE65944EF87F4CDF8EABB4E36"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualified investment</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>qualified investment</term> means a qualified investment that is certified under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/48E">section 48E(d)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for purposes of the credit under such section 48E.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HBECC803C218540D5812A97C32F921018"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Application of certain rules</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB784BC0DBE9D4F009B4269735C2AFC1B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In making grants under this subsection, the Secretary of the Treasury shall apply rules similar to the rules of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/50">section 50</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986. In applying such rules, any increase in tax under chapter 1 of such Code by reason of an investment ceasing to be a qualified investment shall be imposed on the person to whom the grant was made.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H697E2ABC40794CAFBF9D9200C0112FFC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <clause id="HA21114362EB8433DBE195570AB61659D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Recapture of excessive grant amounts</header><text>If the amount of a grant made under this subsection exceeds the amount allowable as a grant under this subsection, such excess shall be recaptured under subparagraph (A) as if the investment to which such excess portion of the grant relates had ceased to be a qualified investment immediately after such grant was made.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFB85ED93454D4F4A80139DFA36A13454"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Grant information not treated as return information</header><text>In no event shall the amount of a grant made under paragraph (1), the identity of the person to whom such grant was made, or a description of the investment with respect to which such grant was made be treated as return information for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC4B0CB371014BFD84190726B56FD7B3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>Any reference in this subsection to the Secretary of the Treasury shall be treated as including the Secretary's delegate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1FB10F69077D44449DBC721BF296ED43"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Other terms</header><text>Any term used in this subsection which is also used in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/48E">section 48E</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall have the same meaning for purposes of this subsection as when used in such section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DEAFEB2FB68482492D328BBDD913F6B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/46">section 46(7)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 by reason of section 48E of such Code for any investment for which a grant is awarded under this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H354039539C454E25A195EDFF261C0320"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Appropriations</header><text>There is hereby appropriated to the Secretary of the Treasury such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB60FEFA781C94647BADB79BA143FA4BC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsections (a) through (d) of this section shall apply to amounts paid or incurred after the date of the enactment of this Act, in taxable years beginning after such date.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


