<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H53FE3D5CDE254C1C8C5C0FD503914967" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 735 IH: Universal Security of American Values Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 735</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170130">January 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the enforcement of certain Executive orders.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H88E2E26F59064BC3B814AB8FAC82D1AC" style="OLC">
 <section id="H168E7319EB594584814420D0C74DEC1E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Universal Security of American Values Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or as the <quote><short-title>USA Values Act of 2017</short-title></quote> .</text> </section><section id="H3206804D0B31454D83DDC7CEE4456781" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H4BF5C931F26D4791BBAFA5C86F8642FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Constitution is the document that embodies the fundamental laws and principles by which the United States is governed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6602B96D8D3478081ED63614553A755"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In a Nation of laws, not of men, no person, including the President of the United States, has the power to violate the Constitution of United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA669933164EB4D09A820E4ED01905B55"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In a Nation whose symbol is the Statute of Liberty, which welcomes the <quote>tired, poor and huddled masses yearning to breathe free,</quote> the Executive order issued Friday, January 26, 2017, entitled, <quote>Protecting the Nation from Foreign Terrorist Entry into the United States</quote>, is an affront to national values and is therefore, null and void, shall have no force and effect, and may not be implemented, administered, enforced, or carried out.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H11806177DECD458D8B767C35453201D0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No Executive order may be enforced that would be in direct violation of an existing Executive order, public law, or fully executed regulatory agency process as it relates to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H07A0BA9E62AD4B1899F253FB5C429319"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Fourth Amendment due process;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAAE19ED1CB54401BBA34A5E43C8F4D1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Fourteenth Amendment protections;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H10EAD82714CC4A0B825283D741D6C3BB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Immigration and Nationality Act;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCDF1191C8FC049C2B34F3B5C9461BE3E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any laws that are intended to protect the civil liberties, civil rights, or human rights of persons lawfully admitted into the United States or natural born or naturalized citizens of the United States; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7F7C424546F04B959B70D5C350C6B1C8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>impact on individuals based upon race, religion, ethnicity, place of birth, place of residence, gender, sexual orientation and identity, age, or statuses that pose no undue health threat to the general population.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H170061089A93432C9F512D16EFD9EFE7"><enum>4.</enum><header>No funds available</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No amounts (including fees) made available to the Secretary of Homeland Security, or to any other official of a Federal agency, by any Act for any fiscal year, may be used to implement, administer, enforce, or carry out (including through the issuance of any regulations) any of the policy changes set forth in the Executive order entitled <quote>Protecting the Nation from Foreign Terrorist Entry into the United States</quote> (January 27, 2017).</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


