<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA866312076F24A41BC46A8997CA9065B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2069 IH: Fostering Stable Housing Opportunities Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2069</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide priority under certain federally assisted housing programs to assist youths who are
			 aging out of foster care, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H54960093A88A4C59BAD04973B27DF485" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB2EF4B9D1D324BD297834479805BD5C2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fostering Stable Housing Opportunities Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1D21A138D71F4C4AA94D2DBB83DD7D5C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition of family</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) of section 3(b)(3) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)(3)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H24157F4BD9E6491D906DA54E2C06A695"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first sentence—</text> <subparagraph id="H0CE5E9DF821C489C849894668152B697"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(v)</quote> and inserting <quote>(vi)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20511E245E494F64855EED4EF58D50B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>tenant family,</quote> the following: <quote>(v) a child who is in foster care and has attained an age such that the provision of foster care for such child will end by reason of the age of the child within 6 months,</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H58CA2859F97345BCA73500992B356DF8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by inserting <quote>or (vi)</quote> after <quote>clause (v)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H4A29414563A045649D5E47ACE5AB2CBB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Priority for public housing occupancy and section 8 assistance</header> <subsection id="H2D3375E5E47F4274845327979D768AF3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public housing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) of section 6(c)(4) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437d">42 U.S.C. 1437d(c)(4)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDA77B74A8C6C4E71BB29446E99498DED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>this subparagraph</quote> and inserting <quote>this clause</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H185F3AF5974B41EAABBBB3FB85FB2D0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the subparagraph designation and all that follows through <quote>making dwelling units available</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H946731F69EAC411EB856EF259C5E2192" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H9C9E12C0925F4D04997823F4CFEA5D7E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">making dwelling units in public housing available for occupancy, which shall provide that—</text> <clause id="H7593C80094CB41E3943F45D1D3A21480"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except for projects or portions of projects designated for occupancy pursuant to section 7(a), preference shall be given to otherwise eligible children who are in foster care, have attained an age such that the provision of foster care for such child will end by reason of the age of the child within 6 months, meet the requirements under clauses (i) and (ii) of paragraph (1) of the definition of <quote>at risk of homelessness</quote> in section 91.5 of the Secretary’s regulations (24 C.F.R. 91.5), as in effect on September 1, 2016, and have agreed to comply with the requirements under section 38(c); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6EDE6AAC783D494BA2569CEE884E38D1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the public housing agency may establish a system for making dwelling units that are not occupied pursuant to the preference under clause (i) available</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H98B06C0C65F649E6AD2B548AB012880A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Voucher assistance</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of section 8(o)(6) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)(6)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE030A84C687B442D98603E7AE8585029"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (i) and (ii) as clauses (ii) and (iii), respectively;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8E36DFB65EA4CEF9C9B911CF5BB188F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting before clause (ii), as so redesignated by paragraph (1) of this subsection, the following new clause:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA64C86CE1AAB47A08C11001DB16075E0" style="OLC">
 <clause id="HF7DD90929B9A4D5D8C3553CF0745E255"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Children aging-out of foster care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making tenant-based assistance under this subsection available on behalf of eligible families, each public housing agency shall give preference to otherwise eligible children who are in foster care, have attained an age such that the provision of foster care for such child will end by reason of the age of the child within 6 months, meet the requirements under clauses (i) and (ii) of paragraph (1) of the definition of <quote>at risk of homelessness</quote> in section 91.5 of the Secretary’s regulations (24 C.F.R. 91.5), as in effect on September 1, 2016, and have agreed to comply with the requirements under section 38(c).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF0FEE648C80449C7A1E678706C489388"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (ii), as so redesignated by paragraph (1) of this subsection, by inserting <quote>that is not made available in accordance with the preference under clause (i)</quote> after <quote>under this subsection</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBDA95A4F5A644A3496901012E877B434"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in clause (iii), as so redesignated by paragraph (1) of this subsection, by striking <quote>this subparagraph</quote> and inserting <quote>clause (ii)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H50E74E7BFEA048FE8E8D82B35D10E6CE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>PHA project-Based voucher assistance</header><text>Subparagraph (J) of section 8(o)(13) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)(13)(J)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1A20CA15F25D4A1196FB316CEA2785C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, except that the agency shall give preference to otherwise eligible children who are in foster care, have attained an age such that the provision of foster care for such child will end by reason of the age of the child within 6 months, meet the requirements under clauses (i) and (ii) of paragraph (1) of the definition of <quote>at risk of homelessness</quote> in section 91.5 of the Secretary’s regulations (24 C.F.R. 91.5), as in effect on September 1, 2016, and have agreed to comply with the requirements under section 38(c)</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4871AD444B76434CB5EBAC742D899A0D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the third sentence, by striking <quote>The agency</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>For units that are made available after preference is provided pursuant to the first sentence of this subparagraph, the agency</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79761696A499499FAD9A864FEEEB14E6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Project-Based section 8 rental assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) of section 8(d)(1) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(d)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H46C83D30DF7343B68DA79E22CE1000D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>except that with respect</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H28E36AE31CF347628A0E5C55DD52226D" style="OLC"> <text>except that—</text><clause id="HEC457BB3660E4D3194320042C7391571"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of assisted dwelling units in a project assisted with project-based assistance under this section, the tenant selection criteria used by the owner shall give preference to otherwise eligible children who are in foster care, have attained an age such that the provision of foster care for such child will end by reason of the age of the child within 6 months, meet the requirements under clauses (i) and (ii) of paragraph (1) of the definition of <quote>at risk of homelessness</quote> in section 91.5 of the Secretary’s regulations (24 C.F.R. 91.5), as in effect on September 1, 2016, and have agreed to comply with the requirements under section 38(c); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAC8A26AA160E400F9E689D34F3A69400"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H33ABAC29CE1349D887688EB47263D677"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>after preference is provided pursuant to clause (i)</quote> after <quote>to be assisted</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF36FFAD093A8429199640C4C2EE27EB2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Terms and conditions on priority</header><text>Title I of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437">42 U.S.C. 1437</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC11E6CB80AE840BF8D36677AD78F18EF" style="OLC">
					<section id="HDCD5DE4C4CF948EBA035A4D9334A01B9"><enum>38.</enum><header>Terms and conditions on preference for assistance for children aging out of foster care</header>
 <subsection id="H67D84B34B21443F584BB92FA53BD98CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Preference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>preference for housing assistance</quote> means preference, for an otherwise eligible child in foster care, for—</text> <paragraph id="HF431FAB0B8AF4ADF91CEDD93666222F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>occupancy in a public housing dwelling unit, pursuant to section 6(c)(4)(A)(i);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA20E0AE577E74D1DAC075F9FD83238DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>tenant-based assistance under section 8(o), pursuant to paragraph (6)(A)(i) of such section;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE68003FD0AC94E1AA2483AADE526B128"><enum>(3)</enum><text>project-based assistance under section 8(o)(13), pursuant to subparagraph (J) of such section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E25B59C3AA449D68DC443609F1D9BB8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>occupancy in a dwelling unit in a project assisted with project-based assistance under section 8, pursuant to subsection (d)(1)(A)(i) of such section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC65AAF908A08457499DC962E6683C0A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Early application for assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the period during which a preference for housing assistance is provided for a person, an otherwise eligible person may apply for such occupancy or assistance at any time after such person attains 16 years of age.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H8561059DAEE34CBCBBE8CBEE886BB22E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirement for employment, education, or training</header>
 <paragraph id="H7C47ACAD736B49B7869C074B95525DE1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), each person occupying a dwelling unit pursuant to a preference for housing assistance shall be, not later than 12 months after such initial occupancy and for at least 9 months of each successive 12-month period thereafter—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H51468AD1DE1A43ABA804A188681E35E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employed on average at least 35 hours of service per week;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75B3A0AE6D5F4EE9952D5680BFDAC73D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engaged in vocational, technical, or workforce development training or in an apprenticeship, on a full-time basis, as classified by a vocational, technical, or workforce development training institution or entity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AFCD61EF35946D6B61B52F82ABBBFBF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enrolled in a secondary school, an institution of higher education, or other institution providing post-secondary education, on a full-time basis, as classified by an educational institution; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BDE5C048F2C4B15B6C3E0A4E98234B3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>engaged in a combination of activities described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) to such an extent that, in the aggregate, such engagement is on such a full-time basis.</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The Secretary shall require the public housing agency or project owner, as applicable, to verify
			 compliance with the requirement under this paragraph by each person
			 occupying a dwelling unit assisted or administered by such agency or
			 owner, as applicable, pursuant to a preference for housing assistance
			 annually in conjunction with reviews of income for purposes of determining
 eligibility for assistance described in subsection (a).</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H134F255C13A74CC58FFF8ED1F30878EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The requirement under paragraph (1) shall not apply to—</text> <subparagraph id="HDD2E23E0312D405EB26D2C0B452FE65F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person physically or mentally unfit for employment, as determined in accordance with such standards as the Secretary shall establish;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2D9F151FC2944109E578A17ACE92059"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a parent or other household member responsible for the care of a dependent child under 6 or an incapacitated person; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAE61D92B6C14754A77352726297C24E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person who is regularly and actively participating in a drug addiction or alcoholic treatment and rehabilitation program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H004D8547482349F1B94A8C950F137406"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on bedrooms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A dwelling unit that is occupied by a person, or assisted with assistance made available on behalf of a person, pursuant to a preference for housing assistance may contain more than one bedroom only if such additional bedrooms are occupied only by other persons who occupy such dwelling unit, or receive assistance made available, pursuant to a preference for housing assistance.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H13C1F9B2C2C34852A3406092196A27EE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination of assistance</header><text>The public housing agency or project owner, as applicable, shall terminate any occupancy of, or assistance on behalf of, a person pursuant to any preference for housing assistance upon the person attaining 25 years of age or upon substantial noncompliance with the requirement under subsection (c), except that nothing in this clause may be construed to prohibit or affect the eligibility of any person for occupancy of housing assisted under this title or rental assistance under section 8, that is provided other than pursuant to a preference under this subparagraph.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="HDA7FEB296A0347CBB35FC6984AB97833"><enum>4.</enum><header>Priority for rural rental assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of section 521(a) of the Housing Act of 1949 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1490a">42 U.S.C. 1490a(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAEEB8F1FC3334D9E9F5D85B5417063EA" style="OLC">
				<subparagraph id="HC05E0FA2B7674A54AE28706FDFE945CB" indent="up2"><enum>(F)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEBCF373A4C234A48BA193809951D9E4A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making occupancy in a project assisted under this paragraph, and rental assistance under this paragraph, available on behalf of eligible families, the project owner shall give preference to otherwise eligible children who—</text>
 <subclause id="H48575064FAD2457A912843D50CC91B88" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are in foster care;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HCAF6770B47A94989AECF60C25EA6F5DC" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>have attained an age such that the provision of foster care for such child will end by reason of the age of the child within 6 months;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HAD0B763F0F1E4539801836C9E65145B8" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meet the requirements under clauses (i) and (ii) of paragraph (1) of the definition of <quote>at risk of homelessness</quote> in section 91.5 of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development’s regulations (24 C.F.R. 91.5), as in effect on September 1, 2016; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1CE033417C6F4106AFE9E2F969A6B273" indent="up1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>have agreed to comply with the requirements under clause (iii).</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H49129AE6DACA469CB398393FCAA85EBA" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Notwithstanding the period during which a preference pursuant to clause (i) for occupancy in a project assisted under this paragraph or for rental assistance under this paragraph is provided for a person, an otherwise eligible person may apply for such occupancy or assistance at any time after the person attains 16 years of age.</text>
					</clause><clause id="H8A1E6F6100FB4222ADD0762E0143030E" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H00D0826F06FC45608BB628756820F4DC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Except as provided in subclause (II), each person occupying a dwelling unit pursuant to a preference under this subparagraph shall be, not later than 12 months after such initial occupancy and for at least 9 months of each successive 12-month period thereafter—</text>
 <item id="H011AF0D3066142828C0FF94492D0A6C4" indent="up1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employed on average at least 35 hours of service per week;</text> </item><item id="HE54CF131EDD04B32AA145FF8469CC505" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engaged in vocational, technical, or workforce development training or in an apprenticeship, on a full-time basis, as classified by a vocational, technical, or workforce development training institution or entity;</text>
 </item><item id="H871C9EF80E8B4E1C92BF75EAF960C59E" indent="up1"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>enrolled in a secondary school, an institution of higher education, or other institution providing post-secondary education, on a full-time basis, as classified by an educational institution; or</text>
 </item><item id="H591D333192A241F9B4F4FBAD2370DD03" indent="up1"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>engaged in a combination of activities described in items (aa) through (cc) to such an extent that, in the aggregate, such engagement is on such a full-time basis.</text>
							</item><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subclause" indent="subsection">The Secretary shall require a project owner to verify compliance with the requirement under this
			 subclause by each person occupying a dwelling unit pursuant to a
			 preference under this subparagraph annually in conjunction with reviews of
			 income for purposes of determining eligibility for assistance described in
 clause (i).</continuation-text></subclause><subclause id="HE1C72DB50B8844778C6176FEAE74452F" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement under subclause (I) shall not apply to—</text> <item id="HFDC43C95C8584BA591AD22FE39170C61"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person physically or mentally unfit for employment, as determined in accordance with such standards as the Secretary shall establish;</text>
 </item><item id="H9D57449191B64F69B96AC09007E84855"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a parent or other household member responsible for the care of a dependent child under 6 or an incapacitated person; and</text>
 </item><item id="H99221D3D443F4BE1B6774AD7A9F313BB"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>a person who is regularly and actively participating in a drug addiction or alcoholic treatment and rehabilitation program.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H1C66BF336B674048BCC1361A43C90664" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A dwelling unit that is occupied by a person pursuant to a preference under this subparagraph may contain more than one bedroom only if such additional bedrooms are occupied only by other persons who occupy such dwelling unit pursuant to a preference under this subparagraph.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H17C55ABB6B5F48A086E3AF15AB7DFE94" indent="up1"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The project owner shall terminate any occupancy of a person pursuant to the preference under clause (i) upon the person attaining 25 years of age or upon substantial noncompliance with the requirement under clause (ii), except that nothing in this clause may be construed to prohibit or affect the eligibility of any person for occupancy in a project assisted under this paragraph or for rental assistance under this paragraph, other than pursuant to a preference under this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HE193D4D4917646418DF60D10C8DF0395"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header>
 <subsection id="H5FF7B5B3A1D84F038618373C2EC2F527"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Secretary of Agriculture shall jointly submit reports to the Congress regarding the status and outcomes of persons provided preference for housing assistance pursuant to the amendments made by sections 2 through 4 of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDA3F53C5EE7D43889027F24E8B4A4A1E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reports under this section shall include such information as may be necessary to assess and evaluate the long-term success of providing preference for housing assistance pursuant to such amendments and to identify any changes to facilitate improving such success. Such reports shall include information regarding the outcomes for persons provided such preference with respect to the period beginning upon initial provision of such housing assistance on behalf of such person and ending 10 years after termination of such assistance and shall include the following information regarding such persons:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1C3118AB7D784325B4594B74731298B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Employment and career status.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5054587548141FEB4D40F14CEC4CAE2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Housing situation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HACCF8E31BCDE465CA4FE95F968BDFDA6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Educational, training, or vocational attainment.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H89C543FC22124AC48A8FEB19187B0083"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Physical, mental, and emotional well-being (including any instances of substance abuse).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD3C2F1B9714C4B05A04246B861FDF228"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Instances of arrests, incarcerations, and other interactions with the criminal justice system.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBFE3BB83A039460F8967660BA8BBBAAF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Marital and familial status.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD668E474F71042999193E1884A1E2ECC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any other relevant information as the Secretaries consider appropriate to facilitate successful operation of the program under the amendments made by this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H12DAD63B420C4895BDD4BC1531D79C76"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Protection of privacy</header><text>Reports under this section shall contain aggregate information regarding outcomes described in subsection (b) and shall not contain any personally identifiable information.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDD9E6490DA9D4915AE73A9633CF41C0A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The first report under this section shall be submitted to the Congress not later than the expiration of the 10-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and the Secretaries referred to in subsection (a) shall submit a report not later than the expiration of each successive 5-year period thereafter.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


