<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7038A630672F43E2B048FDC6B3631CF6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4197 IH: To create qualifications for, and certain limitations on, staffs of special counsels.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4197</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171031">October 31, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To create qualifications for, and certain limitations on, staffs of special counsels.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H196AF77DC78746539B3C1EFD5C95F6F7" style="OLC">
		<section id="H1E19CB3B31794F499A4E067A46783049" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Qualifications and limitations on staffs of special counsels</header>
 <subsection id="H76C5A74B679E414EA05A14F532A08A17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section applies with respect to any Federal officer or employee—</text> <paragraph id="H30D72F385E714DFA90AFC0C9BE8451F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>who is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H74D780900F9945C1AA94138B357ED408"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a special counsel appointed by the Attorney General under Department of Justice regulations; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDB615458F2A43D8871BD95496711CF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other official appointed by the Attorney General who exercises a similar degree of independence from the normal Department of Justice chain of command; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C6CE640ED984D7186E50158E9E53B8F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whose investigation or prosecution involves an elected official.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H946B8A46AFEA4FEB8BA74AED2C30B49F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualifications To work on the staff or advice</header> <paragraph id="HF81BB4B2DA2D4968A97F0C20806E30F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contributions while serving</header><text>It disqualifies a person for further advising or working on the staff of an officer or employee to whom this section applies that such person makes a contribution to a candidate for elective office or to a political party during such service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBADF386FA67B44ED917B11642D4C2656"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Statement under penalty of perjury required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before taking up the duties of working in the staff of an officer to whom this section applies, a person must sign, under penalty of perjury, a statement that such person has not made, within the 8-year period ending on the date such person begins such duties, a contribution to a candidate for elective office or to a political party.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63D4A51BB8EA424CBA629B8B74FCA1B0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations on Federal employment after working on staff</header><text>A person who works on the staff of an official to whom this section applies shall not be employed, during the 5-year period after that person leaves the staff, in any Federal executive branch office or in a position within the civil service other than one within the competitive service in the Department of Justice—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB0176881B593465391EAC72D111EB939"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for which the compensation is determined under the General Schedule pursuant to title 5, United States Code, and any other law applicable to the salary levels set forth in that General Schedule; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6B4B7658B874DAFAEA26782C7B511E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>which the person held immediately prior to taking up duties working on the staff.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

