<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7BF5D5B282464DA899EA88289A87BB00" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1863 IH: To designate the area between the intersections of Wisconsin Avenue, Northwest and Davis Street, Northwest and Wisconsin Avenue, Northwest and Edmunds Street, Northwest in Washington, District of Columbia, as “Boris Nemtsov Plaza”, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1863</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170403">April 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate the area between the intersections of Wisconsin Avenue, Northwest and Davis Street,
			 Northwest and Wisconsin Avenue, Northwest and Edmunds Street, Northwest in
			 Washington, District of Columbia, as <quote>Boris Nemtsov Plaza</quote>, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H6AA2F5E9FCD4473EBAE3595C4D07C75B" style="OLC">
		<section id="H897DC5C0EA78476FBBAE76DD028016B5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Designation of Boris Nemtsov Plaza</header>
			<subsection id="H6946780B7CE342729CA63E041A0063DF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation of plaza</header>
 <paragraph id="H4A6F1D96DC9B4747B562E58C73B50F9B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The area between the intersections of Wisconsin Avenue, Northwest and Davis Street, Northwest and Wisconsin Avenue, Northwest and Edmunds Street, Northwest in Washington, District of Columbia, shall be known and designated as <quote>Boris Nemtsov Plaza</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61A7D96C868A40CDBBCE46220B44CF0F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the area referred to in paragraph (1) shall be deemed to be a reference to Boris Nemtsov Plaza.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E70A63646BF475EB873AA22A1DF4A33"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation of address</header>
 <paragraph id="H5DD49523DF414DDFB948F26C9CC07A2D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The address of 2650 Wisconsin Avenue, Northwest, Washington, District of Columbia, shall be redesignated as 1 Boris Nemtsov Plaza.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF777B0D8D1BB42AD893E6ACE084626A2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the address referred to in paragraph (1) shall be deemed to be a reference to 1 Boris Nemtsov Plaza.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H62E28D20D6DE4FEAA8BCB279E414AC58"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Signs</header><text>The Administrator of General Services shall construct street signs that shall—</text> <paragraph id="H81F32E7E4AD749B7B63265FCFB6DE114"><enum>(1)</enum><text>contain the phrase <quote>Boris Nemtsov Plaza</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F4F236E5E56482BAF3B952E55811206"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be similar in design to the signs used by Washington, District of Columbia, to designate the location of Metro stations; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1376B65ABCFE499E95314D7FF5EBA929"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be placed on—</text> <subparagraph id="H653840E365E64572B7B25FB29090EC60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the parcel of Federal property that is closest to 1 Boris Nemtsov Plaza (as redesignated by subsection (b)(1)); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD23E17FC380F4D2FBFE4F9B51F87B494"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the street corners of Wisconsin Avenue, Northwest and Davis Street, Northwest and Wisconsin Avenue, Northwest and Edmunds Street, Northwest in Washington, District of Columbia.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


