<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC979B017810C4DA896F49B69F9B1CDDE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3225 IH: Oregon Tribal Economic Development Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3225</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170713">July 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000791">Mr. Walden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To allow the Confederated Tribes of Coos, Lower Umpqua, and Siuslaw Indians, the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community of Oregon, the Confederated Tribes of Siletz Indians of Oregon, the Confederated Tribes of Warm Springs, and the Cow Creek Band of Umpqua Tribe of Indians to lease or transfer certain lands.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDF216041B36B4204883E54C66AB66189" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H60EE6B5487F1497281124FD023791649" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Oregon Tribal Economic Development Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4760A460FB074541B75018811EB8B5AF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Approval not required to validate land transactions</header> <subsection id="HC3E9CAFB3D6849A19FFA672E16A5FB50"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, without further approval, ratification, or authorization by the United States, the Confederated Tribes of Coos, Lower Umpqua, and Siuslaw Indians, the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community of Oregon, the Confederated Tribes of Siletz Indians of Oregon, the Confederated Tribes of Warm Springs, and the Cow Creek Band of Umpqua Tribe of Indians may lease, sell, convey, warrant, or otherwise transfer all or any part of its interests in any real property that is not held in trust by the United States for the benefit of such tribe.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H031F8049B9D14B82BCD192352BCDA149"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Trust land not affected</header><text>Nothing in this section shall—</text> <paragraph id="H05B78BE8A9684AC9A284CD2E32939251"><enum>(1)</enum><text>authorize the Confederated Tribes of Coos, Lower Umpqua, and Siuslaw Indians, the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community of Oregon, the Confederated Tribes of Siletz Indians of Oregon, the Confederated Tribes of Warm Springs, and the Cow Creek Band of Umpqua Tribe of Indians to lease, sell, convey, warrant, or otherwise transfer all or any part of an interest in any real property that is held in trust by the United States for the benefit of such tribe; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCD17DE159E354D378999B1A6CE2B398E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affect the operation of any law governing leasing, selling, conveying, warranting, or otherwise transferring any interest in such trust land.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

