<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD3CB4A67A43B4A6FA3724BC19337A9D3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3666 IH: Fort McClellan Health Registry Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-08-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3666</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170825">August 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O'Rourke</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a registry of certain veterans who were stationed at Fort McClellan, Alabama, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H237C3543BBF44CAD98C21E29FF0FEB59" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB4738B9326A54E8D97C6AC1D5BA484AF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fort McClellan Health Registry Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBB878A6FBB8A4F708267C3771A8DD7A3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Fort McClellan Health Registry</header> <subsection id="H12283E5D972E448690F6EB12F050E9F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish and maintain a special record to be known as the <quote>Fort McClellan Health Registry</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Registry</quote>).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H9C3E57A91380422DB791F2F1E5C811D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (c), the Registry shall include the following information:</text> <paragraph id="HD518611F98D648EE8AC37C25DCB1C361"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list containing the name of each individual who, while serving as a member of the Armed Forces, was stationed at Fort McClellan, Alabama, at any time during the period beginning January 1, 1935, and ending on May 20, 1999, and who—</text>
<subparagraph id="HA6249811B1634BA99326FE35302A14C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>applies for care or services from the Department of Veterans Affairs under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3D402816FBE8458491E900B1D8D67318"><enum>(B)</enum><text>files a claim for compensation under chapter 11 of such title on the basis of any disability which may be associated with such service;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2DD3816DDF9D4496A0AE67ED8F322C05"><enum>(C)</enum><text>dies and is survived by a spouse, child, or parent who files a claim for dependency and indemnity compensation under chapter 13 of such title on the basis of such service;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H15B2B7098B8B40A98F5933138EE638C2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>requests from the Secretary a health examination under subsection (d); or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H43109C52CACB4A308E5A031E3BAC27FB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>receives from the Secretary a health examination similar to the health examination referred to in subparagraph (D) and requests inclusion in the Registry.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F63A95FEABF47A8A6F959D71005B88D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Relevant medical data relating to the health status of, and other information that the Secretary considers relevant and appropriate with respect to, each individual described in paragraph (1) who—</text>
<subparagraph id="H3479449FD5C7479F83DBCE64045CE097"><enum>(A)</enum><text>grants to the Secretary permission to include such information in the Registry; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1415FDE774484F82B187EEAAA84608A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at the time the individual is listed in the Registry, is deceased.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H24795C6336C44D02A80B623121C5B4B0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Individuals Submitting Claims or Making Requests Before Date of Enactment</header><text>If in the case of an individual described in subsection (b)(1) the application, claim, or request referred to in such subsection was submitted, filed, or made before the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall, to the extent feasible, include in the Registry such individual's name and the data and information, if any, described in subsection (b)(2) relating to the individual.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA25534D777F4472CABDFB80180F98C93"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Examinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the request of a veteran who was stationed at Fort McClellan, Alabama, at any time during the period beginning January 1, 1935, and ending on May 20, 1999, the Secretary shall provide the veteran with a health examination (including any appropriate diagnostic tests) and consultation and counseling with respect to the results of the examination and the tests.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HB7A2FEC7892649D28A67BA4A2711B094"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Outreach</header>
<paragraph id="H55DF9D7797D44DC3920705264DF18AAC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Ongoing outreach to individuals listed in Registry</header><text>The Secretary shall, from time to time, notify individuals listed in the Registry of significant developments in research on the health consequences of potential exposure to a toxic substance or environmental hazard related to service at Fort McClellan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D91864D3214427BAEB9CA9188F12A6E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Examination outreach</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out appropriate outreach activities with respect to the provision of any health examinations (including any diagnostic tests) and consultation and counseling services under subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H44D06F64171141B0B8673230DE5CA518"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall consult with the Secretary of Defense to acquire information maintained by the Secretary of Defense that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs considers necessary to establish and maintain the Registry.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

