<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H42AC0E38C17B4CF193B348286811C8FF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2486 IH: Equity and Inclusion Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2486</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170517">May 17, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to restore the right to individual civil actions
			 in cases involving disparate impact, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9176E6F0E92B41AA978D79F6CBA3F85C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7A4D5D1B84704DBCB2507F7903EB1896" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Equity and Inclusion Enforcement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0C93A5298A0F446DBB0C3197A1F98C79"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HCC8D1F97DE814CBD848785FAC73C81B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1964, Congress adopted title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref> et seq.) to ensure that Federal dollars would not subsidize or support programs or activities that discriminate on the basis of race, color, or national origin.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE920C3BA509A4CF38746F1260645822F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Supreme Court decision in Alexander v. Sandoval, 532 U.S. 275 (2001) overturned four decades of statutory protections against discrimination by stripping victims of discrimination of the right to bring actions under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref> et seq.) to challenge disparate impact.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A8A03879EF346BE9865FC279F966DA2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For effective enforcement of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref> et seq.), it is necessary that the private right of action includes the means to challenge all forms of discrimination that are prohibited by such Act, including practices that have a disparate impact and are not justified as necessary to achieve the legitimate goals of programs or activities supported by Federal financial assistance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56BC3EEA724140AFA3E63E384B8F5397"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Failure to reinstate or confirm a private right of action to challenge disparate impact under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref> et seq.) leaves only the Federal Government with the burden to pursue equal opportunity under the law.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HB1FAEF4314B74CDA96CB53A366834987"><enum>3.</enum><header>Restoration of right to civil action in disparate impact cases under title VI of the Civil Rights
 Act of 1964</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H097E2244BE3D47C3A230B0C9181E9425" style="traditional">
 <section id="H85BEC8ECFAF54131AB442545A63FB172"><enum>607.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The violation of any regulation relating to disparate impact issued under section 602 shall give rise to a private civil cause of action for its enforcement to the same extent as does an intentional violation of the prohibition of section 601.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HFC403895F5FD49E59847B6936B7E90F8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Designation of monitors under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref> et seq.) is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D666CD0B5F6404DBEB7B34CF4CD3C21" style="traditional">
				<section id="H46FA640225FA4787B9F0A4BFC2716798"><enum>608.</enum>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9CACDE14808341778DF4DAD1CD922ABB"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Each recipient shall—</text> <paragraph id="HB77519200B704F4FBDA31BC777B29767"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designate at least one employee to coordinate its efforts to comply with requirements adopted pursuant to section 602 and carry out the responsibilities of the recipient under this title, including any investigation of any complaint alleging the noncompliance of the recipient with such requirements or alleging any actions prohibited under this title; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB0C5C9ADC7B41A4844C6931E8456AE0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>notify its students and employees of the name, office address, and telephone number of each employee designated under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEA27362CB7E74E51920408AEB1819F10"><enum>(b)</enum><text>In this section, the term <term>recipient</term> means a recipient referred to in section 602 that operates an education program or activity receiving Federal financial assistance authorized or extended by the Secretary of Education.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H136798ABA1574073AA0337E844B53D2C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Special assistant for equity and inclusion</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 202(b) of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3412">20 U.S.C. 3412(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4CDA087C054E4BE3A376F8699864ECE1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6810228CD6924F6DB9F0022E15FA9C71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3), the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E7C4190CCCB46F282A41582198594E4" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HD6816EC2931C499E9DBEC308D5FBE9BC"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be in the Department, a Special Assistant for Equity and Inclusion who shall be appointed by the Secretary. The Special Assistant shall promote, coordinate, and evaluate equity and inclusion programs, including the dissemination of information, technical assistance, and coordination of research activities. The Special Assistant shall advise the Secretary and Deputy Secretary on all matters relating to equity and inclusion in a manner consistent with title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref> et seq.).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


