<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8807634E684549C4B2E7241B3C972FF7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 790 IH: Return to Prudent Banking Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 790</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170201">February 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To repeal certain provisions of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act and revive the separation between
			 commercial banking and the securities business, in the manner provided in
			 the Banking Act of 1933, the so-called <quote>Glass-Steagall Act</quote>, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA41EAE9B8930419596CEF8CA4A7539EE" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7C04AB35EB6947DA916ABC8B7C25F832" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Return to Prudent Banking Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7011EDF7B5754E15A05EB59DF7343E58"><enum>2.</enum><header>Glass-Steagall revived</header> <subsection id="HBD0BFD130B3B46C2A003DCA2C584ECB3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Wall between commercial banks and securities activities reestablished</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 18 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1828">12 U.S.C. 1828</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9439B281EF164A3AA4F59F3F8AD49BC3" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HED506B6877814FEFBA48DC6ABC016784"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Limitations on security affiliations</header>
						<paragraph id="H37E304126A4A406CA067D16D99BD6D69"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition on affiliation between insured depository institutions and investment banks or
 securities firms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An insured depository institution may not be or become an affiliate of any broker or dealer, any investment adviser, any investment company, or any other person engaged principally in the issue, flotation, underwriting, public sale, or distribution at wholesale or retail or through syndicate participation of stocks, bonds, debentures, notes, or other securities.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HC9AAADF8254442C4A5553F2B00679CFF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on officers, directors, and employees of securities firms service on boards of
			 depository institutions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1D919250205341A6A45B11EC768C494A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who is an officer, director, partner, or employee of any broker or dealer, any investment adviser, any investment company, or any other person engaged principally in the issue, flotation, underwriting, public sale, or distribution at wholesale or retail or through syndicate participation of stocks, bonds, debentures, notes, or other securities may not serve at the same time as an officer, director, employee, or other institution-affiliated party of any insured depository institution.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4A0CB652490D46F5BDD495E6F86C40D5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply with respect to service by any individual which is otherwise prohibited under such subparagraph if the appropriate Federal banking agency determines, by regulation with respect to a limited number of cases, that service by such individual as an officer, director, employee, or other institution-affiliated party of any insured depository institution would not unduly influence the investment policies of the depository institution or the advice the institution provides to customers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B24155033E64AA5A1F6437BE2C29FF2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Termination of service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to a determination under subparagraph (B), any individual described in subparagraph (A) who, as of the date of the enactment of the Return to Prudent Banking Act of 2017, is serving as an officer, director, employee, or other institution-affiliated party of any insured depository institution shall terminate such service as soon as practicable after such date of enactment and no later than the end of the 60-day period beginning on such date.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB1C0DC13E3C4E52A63AAB26028C1781"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination of existing affiliation</header>
 <subparagraph id="H5CAB38C0418F4B7B83B0E941A7F7BBF7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Orderly wind-down of existing affiliation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any affiliation of an insured depository institution with any broker or dealer, any investment adviser, any investment company, or any other person, as of the date of the enactment of the Return to Prudent Banking Act of 2017, which is prohibited under paragraph (1) shall be terminated as soon as practicable and in any event no later than the end of the 2-year period beginning on such date of enactment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE66BF525F2F445908BA1C2213A561901"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Early termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appropriate Federal banking agency, after opportunity for hearing, may terminate, at any time, the authority conferred by the preceding subparagraph to continue any affiliation subject to such subparagraph until the end of the period referred to in such subparagraph if the agency determines, having due regard for the purposes of this subsection and the Return to Prudent Banking Act of 2017, that such action is necessary to prevent undue concentration of resources, decreased or unfair competition, conflicts of interest, or unsound banking practices and is in the public interest.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E979BAD0EC64AB9855F1ED7845DE718"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Extension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to a determination under subparagraph (B), an appropriate Federal banking agency may extend the 2-year period referred to in subparagraph (A) from time to time as to any particular insured depository institution for not more than 6 months at a time, if, in the judgment of the agency, such an extension would not be detrimental to the public interest, but no such extensions shall in the aggregate exceed 1 year.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA89C6C95319F430395B0A9C5C66B7774"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the terms <quote>broker</quote> and <quote>dealer</quote> have the same meanings as in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 and the terms <quote>investment adviser</quote> and <quote>investment company</quote> have the meaning given such terms under the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 and the Investment Company Act of 1940, respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBA6A61CB89504E51B288DB668C0CC5B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on banking activities by securities firms clarified</header><text>Section 21 of the Banking Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/378">12 U.S.C. 378</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H306EFC008F69441F99771672E71B78C2" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H46662B4EFABD4AF991ECDB7E2A95AC21"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Business of receiving deposits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>business of receiving deposits</quote> includes the establishment and maintenance of any transaction account (as defined in section 19(b)(1)(C) of the Federal Reserve Act).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HF1092590E34B4321B9D43472F1DD66DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Continued applicability of ICI v. Camp</header>
 <paragraph id="H81B9CB4659BA4B4FB74B50D621FD618E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress ratifies the interpretation of the paragraph designated the <quote>Seventh</quote> of section 5136 of the Revised Statutes of the United States (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/24">12 U.S.C. 24</external-xref>, as amended by section 16 of the Banking Act of 1933 and subsequent amendments) and section 21 of the Banking Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/378">12 U.S.C. 378</external-xref>) by the Supreme Court of the United States in the case of Investment Company Institute v. Camp (401 U.S. 617 et seq. (1971)) with regard to the permissible activities of banks and securities firms, except to the extent expressly prescribed otherwise by this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6BD4A597A03F4E72B24C962FF406E724"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability of reasoning</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The reasoning of the Supreme Court of the United States in the case referred to in paragraph (1) with respect to sections 20 and 32 of the Banking Act of 1933 (as in effect prior to the date of the enactment of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act) shall continue to apply to subsection (aa) of section 18 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (as added by subsection (a) of this section) except to the extent the scope and application of such subsection as enacted exceed the scope and application of such sections 20 and 32.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H529C56E4D17D4578803F83C86B2E7FA0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on agency interpretation or judicial construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No appropriate Federal banking agency, by regulation, order, interpretation, or other action, and no court within the United States may construe the paragraph designated the <quote>Seventh</quote> of section 5136 of the Revised Statutes of the United States (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/24">12 U.S.C. 24</external-xref>, as amended by section 16 of the Banking Act of 1933 and subsequent amendments), section 21 of the Banking Act of 1933, or section 18(aa) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act more narrowly than the reasoning of the Supreme Court of the United States in the case of Investment Company Institute v. Camp (401 U.S. 617 et seq. (1971)) as to the construction and the purposes of such provisions.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD6F3D826E1C544C6890516802348FF4C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Repeal of Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act provisions</header>
			<subsection id="HB22735FF7BE84846B31D78B982D8048D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Financial holding company</header>
 <paragraph id="H144D1EDF795B4195B632BF3EBDA7906B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4 of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1843">12 U.S.C. 1843</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsections (k), (l), (m), (n), and (o).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H979C0F3D20DB4B4EA2A09D4926543C55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transition</header>
 <subparagraph id="H44804F5DCAB84065858B21C6A19F3FA3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Orderly wind-down of existing affiliation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a bank holding company which, pursuant to the amendments made by paragraph (1), is no longer authorized to control or be affiliated with any entity that was permissible for a financial holding company, any affiliation by the bank holding company which is not permitted for a bank holding company shall be terminated as soon as practicable and in any event no later than the end of the 2-year period beginning on such date of enactment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27D49A0FF6A3458BBEC211A650D8EC28"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Early termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, after opportunity for hearing, may terminate, at any time, the authority conferred by the preceding subparagraph to continue any affiliation subject to such subparagraph until the end of the period referred to in such subparagraph if the Board determines, having due regard to the purposes of this Act, that such action is necessary to prevent undue concentration of resources, decreased or unfair competition, conflicts of interest, or unsound banking practices, and is in the public interest.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC86A6AE6FFA34A9A941815CA7AAD582E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Extension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to a determination under subparagraph (B), the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System may extend the 2-year period referred to in subparagraph (A) above from time to time as to any particular bank holding company for not more than 6 months at a time, if, in the judgment of the Board, such an extension would not be detrimental to the public interest, but no such extensions shall in the aggregate exceed 1 year.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H15CF742771D74CFE9CD5DA795736F2B4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header>
 <subparagraph id="H450FD5E3E35B48D0A80FFA1B8729A82E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2 of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1841">12 U.S.C. 1841</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (p).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60B6AD41F7A9459492B08DF1FA652AB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 5(c) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1844">12 U.S.C. 1844(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="H8C085CB1603C47FC805A938ABE95C376"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraphs (3) and (4); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDC9513829A8D4CC5B68FF35668556A77"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (5) as paragraph (3).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D581A15CE0D44A487CE54E5B5089944"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 5 of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1844">12 U.S.C. 1844</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (g).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C94DBC1AF2C4597BCD7E3E738DDE5A6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1811">12 U.S.C. 1811</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by striking section 45.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1171EA7AE1FF40DDA18DE1202E394F44"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Subtitle B of title I of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act is amended by striking section 114 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1828a">12 U.S.C. 1828a</external-xref>) and section 115 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1820a">12 U.S.C. 1820a</external-xref>).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8EB903BBCB724939AAA631D56AA132D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Financial subsidiaries repealed</header>
 <paragraph id="HB2FA4C55D1F7441796685ECEFFBD845E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5136A of the Revised Statutes of the United States (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/24a">12 U.S.C. 24a</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E5C42410C4A4A9695A4B2845FE8639F" style="OLC">
						<section id="HE337E8C062B040EFA66F6A194568C573"><enum>5136A.</enum><header>[repealed]</header></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HD3FFC6CC6EB44F79A804E6C260C2B0D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transition</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC0249FE63F9B4A3290003670BE65E79E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Orderly wind-down of existing affiliation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a national bank which, pursuant to the amendments made by paragraph (1), is no longer authorized to control or be affiliated with a financial subsidiary as of the date of the enactment of this Act, such affiliation shall be terminated as soon as practicable and in any event no later than the end of the 2-year period beginning on such date of enactment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H019EB554671948E2A0FE7883019BF582"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Early termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller of the Currency, after opportunity for hearing, may terminate, at any time, the authority conferred by the preceding subparagraph to continue any affiliation subject to such subparagraph until the end of the period referred to in such subparagraph if the Comptroller determines, having due regard for the purposes of this Act, that such action is necessary to prevent undue concentration of resources, decreased or unfair competition, conflicts of interest, or unsound banking practices and is in the public interest.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8036367E6F93426D8183B1D7064AAA17"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Extension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to a determination under subparagraph (B), the Comptroller of the Currency may extend the 2-year period referred to in subparagraph (A) above from time to time as to any particular national bank for not more than 6 months at a time, if, in the judgment of the Comptroller, such an extension would not be detrimental to the public interest, but no such extensions shall in the aggregate exceed 1 year.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C8E4117587548B9AF900A74CF4B21E4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE58DECE7E18D4450AF873023106B678F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 20th undesignated paragraph of section 9 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/335">12 U.S.C. 335</external-xref>) is amended by striking the last sentence.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77BDF0FBB5FD40ED8B6FB1809BEE81C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Federal Deposit Insurance Act is amended by striking section 46 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1831w">12 U.S.C. 1831w</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4985294B032B42718F8863192274A519"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for chapter one of title LXII of the Revised Statutes of the United States is amended by striking the item relating to section 5136A.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE879FDE9DC9473B9D0CC5AE728D2D0E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition of broker</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3(a)(4)(B) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)(4)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6F1B645AF0204BA39324D3D855E21761"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking clauses (i), (iii), (v), (vii), (x), and (xi); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA00223210B645AE8E2A552B92FF15BD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (ii), (iv), (vi), (viii), and (ix) as clauses (i), (ii), (iii), (iv), and (v), respectively.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H914C9032526E4282BF199F0A29AAE351"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition of dealer</header><text>Section 3(a)(5)(C) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)(5)(C)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2263B6A6AC1D4F678D3057F7D7FFAA62"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking clauses (i) and (iii); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD78BF5976A614091AAD198679E3990F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating clauses (ii) and (iv) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58D0FFC39A304DA1B1FEC37487F4FB4F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition of identified banking product</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 206 of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA6E5D34907F840DE85C3CF9DC8046C37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end of paragraph (4);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B24C0386B2243DC8709569D4F6784CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(B)(ii), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a period; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H81387E50CA9C453CB03CCDF3E27C7646"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (6) and all that follows through the end of such subsection.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C545BF1CE264CFABB48E1E71CCF9444"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition of activities closely related to banking</header> <paragraph id="H2B651002F9474FCFABAED8E9259E7D8F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 4(c)(8) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1843">12 U.S.C. 1843(c)(8)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the day before the date of the enactment of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act</quote> and inserting <quote>January 1, 1970</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B3C39E8429F47929EAF6CF5433B8D8B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Provision allowing for exceptions after report to the Congress</header><text>Subsection (j) of section 4 of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1843">12 U.S.C. 1843(j)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1CED569F10BC468F94448E35B9380E10" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="HAEFE4E17B4984475AB854684C3534424"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Approval for certain post-1970 subsection <enum-in-header>(c)(8)</enum-in-header> activities</header>
 <paragraph id="HCE0397F9660849699FF257FFCF15695D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the limitation of the January 1, 1970, approval deadline in subsection (c)(8), the Board may determine an activity to be so closely related to banking as to be a proper incident thereto for purposes of such subsection, subject to the requirements of this subsection and such terms and conditions as the Board may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9EEA3DDCDEBC46688FC0F2AD9B99B65F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>General standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making any determination under paragraph (1), the Board shall consider whether performance of the activity by a bank holding company or a subsidiary of such company can reasonably be expected to result in a violation of section 18(aa) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, section 21 of the Banking Act of 1933, or the spirit of section 2(c) of the Return to Prudent Banking Act of 2017, and other possible adverse effects, such as undue concentration of resources, decreased or unfair competition, conflicts of interests, or unsound banking practices.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6EAB4489A96C4D74A28525CA7B061379"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report and wait</header><text>No determination of the Board under paragraph (1) may take effect before the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date by which notice of the determination has been submitted to both Houses of the Congress together with a detailed explanation of the activities to which the determination relates and the basis for the determination, unless before the end of such period, such activities have been approved by an Act of Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA65EFC312754CF69E337C510BD47D7C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Repeal of provision relating to foreign banks filing as financial holding companies</header><text>Section 8(c) of the International Banking Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/3106">12 U.S.C. 3106(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (3).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H2D8B3695F11744C7B6AE9221F87A6E71"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reports to the Congress</header>
 <subsection id="H9F640B9EFEF149C29C2D0F8E5E855DEA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reports required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each time the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, or another appropriate Federal banking agency makes a determination or an extension under subparagraph (B) or (C) of paragraph (2) or (3) of section 18(aa) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (as added by section 2(a)) or subparagraph (B) or (C) of subsection (a)(2) or (b)(2) of section 3, as the case may be, the Board, Comptroller, or agency shall promptly submit a report of such determination or extension to the Congress.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA6F98926072548B7A5C32A3AF31A418C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report submitted to the Congress under subsection (a) shall contain a detailed description of the basis for the determination or extension.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


