<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA2096BFAA8E048338BF90ECF872D4E97" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4130 IH: Mandatory Arbitration Transparency Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4130</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171025">October 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O'Rourke</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 9, United States Code, with respect to arbitration.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3F00FA59CBF345A182ED3B63645CBD9E" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF6A01A3A578E43268A1E68D7D54943CD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mandatory Arbitration Transparency Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1314CE21A2CD45839B70898800C16F50"><enum>2.</enum><header>Validity and enforceability of predispute arbitration agreements containing confidentiality clauses</header> <subsection id="HB26BD54AE363438FB6CC5E513AAC326D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title 9, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9CEFCB8F69D49F682E02EF4C300E9F6" style="USC">
					<chapter id="H349BF51075744E3D95D64D44CC3D0796"><enum>4</enum><header>Predispute arbitration agreements containing confidentiality clauses</header>
						<toc>
							<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">401. Definitions.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">402. Validity and enforceability.</toc-entry></toc>
						<section id="H5F3B1F6659D244A6B7D57D967B6D4EAB"><enum>401.</enum><header>Definitions</header>
 <subsection id="HEC152219B1C84054AA2D738DA22E6A98"><enum>(a)</enum><text>In this chapter—</text> <paragraph id="H82EAAAEFA8ED4F768C62B3A000B26681"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>civil rights dispute</term> means a dispute—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2A7A5ACE144D4B87BA823B2E4CA16834"><enum>(A)</enum><text>arising under—</text> <clause id="HAED27734DAD749E6A94CA8971318B5F6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Constitution of the United States or the constitution of a State; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCD6EA7DDFA074A1F897CEDD60EB253F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a Federal or State statute that prohibits discrimination on the basis of race, sex, disability, religion, national origin, or any invidious basis in education, employment, credit, housing, public accommodations and facilities, voting, or any program funded or conducted by the Federal Government or a State government, including any statute enforced by the Civil Rights Division of the Department of Justice and any statute enumerated in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/62">section 62(e)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to unlawful discrimination); and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB033F3B6305D4A0682156C284F1DA26F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in which at least 1 party alleging a violation of the Constitution of the United States, a State constitution, or a statute prohibiting discrimination is an individual;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D657ABE1A824F4BAB8CEDA8A746B45B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>consumer dispute</term> means a dispute between an individual who seeks or acquires real or personal property, services, securities or other investments, money, or credit for personal, family, or household purposes and the seller or provider of such property, services, securities or other investments, money, or credit;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE56DD6B9C6BD4DBC9867664413E98273"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>covered confidentiality clause</term> means a provision of a predispute arbitration agreement that, with respect to an employment dispute, consumer dispute, or civil rights dispute, purports to, or could be interpreted by a reasonable person to, prohibit a party to the dispute from—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H261DCC65241E40B09FC8C7D13EF1C5D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>making a communication in a manner such that the prohibition would violate a State or Federal whistleblower statute; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC70013A2D0D54A22B3050838A0EE43A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reporting or making a communication, including to any relevant public official, elected official, or other State or Federal authority, about—</text>
 <clause id="HEF16F13693464A48A1418EDD46A51033"><enum>(i)</enum><text>tortious conduct;</text> </clause><clause id="H5DAF001B87DD402CBBD4A3A57FD6D3A1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>otherwise unlawful conduct; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B5FA7CD52954799AE7343E858CD15A1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>issues of public policy or public concern;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H80C47B291FCA43B29034CEF953A91B11"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>employment dispute</term> means a dispute between an employer and employee arising out of the relationship of employer and employee as defined in section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5BA4F014C8384E9D8024AD135926F747"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>predispute arbitration agreement</term> means any agreement to arbitrate a dispute that had not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCC6E298E3BDD4ECDB19B7A1EA640EDA9"><enum>402.</enum><header>Validity and enforceability</header>
							<subsection id="H51D58C1984664B49906C51813AA1DBEF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="HF07931FECD794EF2AFA63227EDF0F53D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition on predispute arbitration agreements with confidentiality clauses</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, no predispute arbitration agreement shall be valid or enforceable if the agreement contains a covered confidentiality clause.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58C9602B53954C8EB5F54C78B46418CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a predispute arbitration agreement if a party to the agreement can demonstrate a confidentiality interest that significantly outweighs the private and public interest in disclosure.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H37DE3B91D6BF4D4EAFA8CFDA294AED9D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header>
 <paragraph id="H704DEBDB07684A4FBBC64ADD77DF0047"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An issue as to whether this chapter applies to an arbitration agreement shall be determined under Federal law. The applicability of this chapter to an agreement to arbitrate and the validity and enforceability of an agreement to which this chapter applies shall be determined by a court, rather than an arbitrator, irrespective of whether the party resisting arbitration challenges the arbitration agreement specifically or in conjunction with other terms of the contract containing such agreement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5BDFDA02EA944250B06B9B8E68886188"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Collective bargaining agreements</header><text>Nothing in this chapter shall apply to any arbitration provision in a contract between an employer and a labor organization or between labor organizations, except that no such arbitration provision shall have the effect of waiving the right of an employee to seek judicial enforcement of a right arising under a provision of the Constitution of the United States, a State constitution, or a Federal or State statute, or public policy arising therefrom.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H0A516C0BDC8941F582D7CF2274286FA5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of chapters for title 9, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D6D0AE2E2BC4753A53085B0F4C1836F" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<multi-column-toc-entry bold="on" level="chapter"><toc-enum>4.</toc-enum><level-header level="chapter">Predispute arbitration agreements containing confidentiality clauses</level-header><target>401</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H252FCFB696DA4DCF98FE6118FC43BA9B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive act or practice</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H91FE4A9065584828BBD0DEE2AA81C2EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HD263CAF5613C4D2F8F5ECA10F4D850BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0218D9F4D31E421195FBE5EECF803234"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the terms <term>covered confidentiality clause</term> and <term>predispute arbitration agreement</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 401 of title 9, United States Code, as added by section 2.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H811A3930CC5846E4BE11DD377FE09BC9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header>
 <paragraph id="H07598792A66041D5BA82788AFA67AB21"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a person to knowingly offer to another person for ratification a predispute arbitration agreement that contains a covered confidentiality clause.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H93E243E6A2444F37AC64C8D9BCD6EAD9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H663757EC8B1947BDBF11631C2431F20C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Confidentiality interest</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a person that offers a predispute arbitration agreement with a covered confidentiality clause if the person can demonstrate a confidentiality interest that significantly outweighs the private and public interest in disclosure.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B6249DDCB8D4CDB9E3FC4A226959164"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Collective bargaining agreements</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to any arbitration provision in a contract between an employer and a labor organization or between labor organizations, if the arbitration provision does not waive the right of an employee to seek judicial enforcement of a right arising under a provision of the Constitution of the United States, a State constitution, or a Federal or State statute, or public policy arising therefrom.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4041B3CB8EC84747B402797ADA2AA20D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header>
 <paragraph id="H3F4835EA9E8D416B90942E8F8730C090"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Treatment as unfair or deceptive act or practice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of subsection (b) by a person with respect to which the Commission is empowered under section 5(a)(2) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(a)(2)</external-xref>) shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEACF7623C16A45EDA4A82DED2DF7E806"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Powers of Commission</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H884277B780554619BEF82E5C9E92A93A"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41</external-xref> et seq.) were incorporated into and made a part of this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35EF700AAE834A2685D9FDCB1A14C16D"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Privileges and immunities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who violates subsection (b) shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5954659911BB40B88B82EECC2D7411D1"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall promulgate standards and rules to carry out this section in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3084286A92B48A38780DB7F2FD1BEA6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Civil action</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6DA56CD96D8B472BB604802C8832369D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text>Any person aggrieved by a violation of subsection (b) may bring a civil action in an appropriate district court of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF8760F203E749658DD99184E10D5E5B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Remedies</header><text>In an action under paragraph (1), the court may award—</text> <subparagraph id="H936A484D1A4D46778A2D351A3F52F37C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>actual damages, but not less than liquidated damages in an amount equal to $1,000;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD3118BFBDB949ECA8BCAF96272EA63F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>punitive damages;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H037B241B97514C1E9BD01254A7FBDBC3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reasonable attorney's fees and other litigation costs reasonably incurred; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CF0444A8FF94122B70AFFB34972F064"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other preliminary and equitable relief that the court determines appropriate, including injunctive relief.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H275F705CDFED499B8B5ED04C5CA66660"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H52B0FD958544429C8D90299099D27D07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act, and the amendments made by this Act, shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4435158017604EC6A6DA6C2F6F7FBE5F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H90371D591A954F909047985828F7E08C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Validity and enforceability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/9/4">Chapter 4</external-xref> of title 9, United States Code, as added by section 2, shall apply with respect to any dispute or claim that arises on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H755EF6F467FF43608ABB6B01482C3504"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive act or practice</header><text>Section 3 shall apply with respect to any predispute arbitration agreement offered for ratification on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


