<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H77583C8B56D04925950712DE27869CEA" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 88 : Shiloh National Military Park Boundary Adjustment and Parker’s Crossroads Battlefield Designation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 88</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20170228">February 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To modify the boundary of the Shiloh National Military Park located in Tennessee and Mississippi,
			 to establish Parker’s Crossroads Battlefield as an affiliated area of the
			 National Park System, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H88251086F90A4B4684783ECEC1CC2F33" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAF2D8EC917C24CC0AF62C57508264E25" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Shiloh National Military Park Boundary Adjustment and Parker’s Crossroads Battlefield Designation Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="H114CEF6447AF40E1942B81E57F150BB2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="H976EE0749DC64F2AA101BD3364C0C3F2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affiliated area</header><text>The term <term>affiliated area</term> means the Parker’s Crossroads Battlefield established as an affiliated area of the National Park System under section 4.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2269C1C0102B406DA9A7BA5E9BF3B83A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Park</header><text>The term <term>Park</term> means Shiloh National Military Park, a unit of the National Park System.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3792CA9784F24454A424CE240EAC6485"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HEA5938CA7A2648238E558843DBB0BA20"><enum>3.</enum><header>Areas to be added to Shiloh National Military Park</header>
 <subsection id="H5ED3F3F9A7324F17B5A5E1384E1E81AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Additional areas</header><text>The boundary of Shiloh National Military Park is modified to include the areas that are generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Shiloh National Military Park, Proposed Boundary Adjustment</quote>, numbered 304/80,011, and dated July 2014, as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H8AFF0F918E984C9BB8C674A7A951DA0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Fallen Timbers Battlefield.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB72836513EE40FDBD1371B0C411E53A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Russell House Battlefield.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F40136D054146EE98CDF08BB65A9FD9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Davis Bridge Battlefield.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB1CA2945BB2244B4B4AB23DD72CD2F1B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Acquisition authority</header><text>The Secretary may acquire lands described in subsection (a) by donation, purchase from willing sellers with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE7F477C3B6124D0A8329E71172D77D3F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Any lands acquired under this section shall be administered as part of the Park.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H896CE3BAC4544F67B13B5EAEA60C92FC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of affiliated area</header> <subsection id="HF4F2BC005562402CA25DAB2E6A620ADB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Parker’s Crossroads Battlefield in the State of Tennessee is hereby established as an affiliated area of the National Park System.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H209E5A0D01A14873AD09F67F1840426B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Description</header><text>The affiliated area shall consist of the area generally depicted within the <term>Proposed Boundary</term> on the map entitled <term>Parker’s Crossroads Battlefield, Proposed Boundary</term>, numbered 903/80,073, and dated July 2014.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H7B75C4D109DC440FB11501630F8FD74C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The affiliated area shall be managed in accordance with this Act and all laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC06A2B8AF2404266AE3F94357EB889CF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Management entity</header><text>The City of Parkers Crossroads and the Tennessee Historical Commission shall jointly be the management entity for the affiliated area.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H83394C22B77547788A7AB2DF483CE9A8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>The Secretary may provide technical assistance and enter into cooperative agreements with the management entity for the purpose of providing financial assistance with marketing, marking, interpretation, and preservation of the affiliated area.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5D9DDB6DBBC6414A900DAE9C81BB8850"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limited role of the secretary</header><text>Nothing in this Act authorizes the Secretary to acquire property at the affiliated area or to assume overall financial responsibility for the operation, maintenance, or management of the affiliated area.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HB8AC9246A6D843FDB0506C24B0EBBED0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>General management plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H86EAF27F20C54C46B594E745782B94FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the management entity, shall develop a general management plan for the affiliated area. The plan shall be prepared in accordance with section 100502 of title 54, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBBC92D819F8944928C4AD0A22CBFD239"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transmittal</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date that funds are made available for this Act, the Secretary shall provide a copy of the completed general management to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA13B04EBA16A40319E264BE038E0323A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Private Property Protection</header>
 <subsection id="HC6085DCFF0A542A791235290C6B25B72"><enum>(a)</enum><header>No use of condemnation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior may not acquire by condemnation any land or interests in land under this Act or for the purposes of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC576E263197243DB95C0BF77EC1F4FA6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Written consent of owner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No non-Federal property may be included in the Shiloh National Military Park without the written consent of the owner.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9A2F39F2362345A78D4C15AF4C6971F9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No buffer zone created</header><text>Nothing in this Act, the establishment of the Shiloh National Military Park, or the management plan for the Shiloh National Military Park shall be construed to create buffer zones outside of the Park. That activities or uses can be seen, heard, or detected from areas within the Shiloh National Military shall not preclude, limit, control, regulate, or determine the conduct or management of activities or uses outside of the Park.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170227">Passed the House of Representatives February 27, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


