<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC6F990A4D9604CBEAF63417B501A5203" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3351 IH: Emergency Nursing Supply Relief Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3351</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170720">July 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for the admission of certain health care
			 workers as immigrants, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HBC94F4B302674BD286C78D9B5A776A61" style="OLC">
 <section id="H537E42ED999E4B0EBCCE76FD351DBAE8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Emergency Nursing Supply Relief Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF02171926B304467BCE787DBF342A242"><enum>2.</enum><header>Health care worker shortage relief</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 203(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H23EA32E54B2440B3B2C94CB1B760D4A4" style="OLC">
				<paragraph id="HC0B1C9E3470F40489DEE71C24D6C755B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Healthcare workers</header>
 <subparagraph id="HBF42F937C30045F49B5C88366AFACF47"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (B), the numerical limitations set forth in sections 201(d) and 202(a) shall not apply to employment-based immigrants (and their family members accompanying or following to join under subsection (d)) who are—</text>
 <clause id="HF2FC8758013849BDA43401E66F597C64"><enum>(i)</enum><text>members of the occupations listed on Schedule A, Group I as defined in section 656.5 of title 20, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation thereto);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA5DCBBD7D18B4BB69D7B6CD5B85427B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>members of the occupations who are required to submit health care worker certificates pursuant to section 212(a)(5)(C); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5AF36063E28244AD9BA93A0DD0E9765A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>members of the occupations who provide certified statements pursuant to section 212(r).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49BA93C1F0DD4B80BC430D37ECFB42DB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on number of visas</header><text>The Secretary of State may not issue more than 8,000 immigrant visa numbers in any one fiscal year (plus any available visa numbers under this paragraph not used during any preceding fiscal year) to principal beneficiaries of petitions pursuant to subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H226A4BDE0EC4418F96445B7AD99C89BB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reduction</header><text>The number described in subparagraph (B) shall be reduced, for each fiscal year, by the cumulative number of visas actually used under paragraph (A) for the previous fiscal year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABDA641CA597489B90B971AA8F3042D9"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Legitimacy of employer’s ability to employ and pay wages</header><text>Any petition filed on behalf of an employment-based immigrant who qualifies under this paragraph must be accompanied by evidence that the prospective United States employer has the ability to pay the proffered wage. The petitioner must demonstrate this ability at the time the priority date is established and continuing until the beneficiary obtains lawful permanent residence. Evidence of this ability shall be either in the form of copies of annual reports, Federal tax returns, or audited financial statements. In a case where the prospective United States employer employs 100 or more workers, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall accept a statement from a financial officer of the organization as evidence of that prospective employer’s ability to pay the proffered wage. In a case where the prospective United States employer does not employ 100 or more workers, the Secretary may consider additional evidence, such as profit/loss statements, bank account records, or personnel records, that are submitted by the petitioner or requested by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


