<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB78200BE967F43F8B298F100688F8E75" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 990 IH: To prohibit any hiring freeze from affecting Department of Defense civilian positions in facilities that perform depot maintenance or are designated as a center for industrial and technical excellence, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 990</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170209">February 9, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001250">Mr. Bishop of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit any hiring freeze from affecting Department of Defense civilian positions in facilities
			 that perform depot maintenance or are designated as a center for
			 industrial and technical excellence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA4D7920BB66C47A0A13CC822BAAFEC6B" style="OLC">
		<section id="H11F05253622742CB9E523B5FD9FF4E65" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition on hiring freeze from affecting Department of Defense civilian positions at certain
 facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The memorandum titled <quote>Presidential Memorandum Regarding the Hiring Freeze</quote> published on January 23, 2017, or any other substantially similar memorandum, Executive order, or other action by the President to prevent a department or agency of the Federal Government from filling vacant Federal civilian employee positions or creating new such positions, shall have no force or effect with respect to any Department of Defense civilian position at, or in support of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5DA02B6E922D49E881AB0E7AF9C445CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any facility at which depot-level maintenance and repair (as that term is defined in section 2460 of title 10, United States Code) is carried out; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA9EBAABEFA14D998222F9162068948F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any facility designated under section 2474 of such title as a center for industrial and technical excellence.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


