<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H2E6CD9A5D3F1443C9CDD17A9FD13CFD5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2824 EH: Increasing Opportunity and Success for Children and Parents through Evidence-Based Home Visiting Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2824</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend title V of the Social Security Act to extend the Maternal, Infant, and Early Childhood Home Visiting Program, and to amend the Social Security Act to make certain revisions to provisions limiting payment of benefits to fugitive felons under titles II, VIII, and XVI of the Social Security Act.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H018E03D81C064437901A90E5DD7CE2F5" style="OLC"><pagebreak/> 
<section id="H3076E788D2474D39BDCA106BCC46EE40" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Table of Contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> <toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> <toc-entry idref="H3076E788D2474D39BDCA106BCC46EE40" level="section">Sec. 1. Table of Contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HF8A8CBEF4B1F4EA4B5061023D8543839" level="title">Title I—Increasing Opportunity and Success for Children and Parents through Evidence-Based Home Visiting Act</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HC71623011420430FBCB8DB6FDC2A474B" level="section">Sec. 101. Short title.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HE799206578F8403B924E11E8999B8649" level="section">Sec. 102. Continuing evidence-based home visiting program.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H8B78E1321694471C967CDD4D17959DB2" level="section">Sec. 103. Continuing to demonstrate results to help families.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H40AAEEEA08F344858132637E79421B5F" level="section">Sec. 104. Reviewing statewide needs to target resources.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H5E6EA90B114347738131AFE8D92FB9FB" level="section">Sec. 105. Improving the likelihood of success in high-risk communities.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H830BDDA3294F4FFCB3D9467562A96552" level="section">Sec. 106. Measuring improvements in family economic self-sufficiency.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H5F41FC2007BA47E4B647B89C91A63EA5" level="section">Sec. 107. Option to fund evidence-based home visiting on a pay for outcome basis.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H8DF5C58DD1A340B38A6A98E99C91FB84" level="section">Sec. 108. Strengthening evidence-based home visiting through state, local, and private partnerships.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H788EA756A3E24F98B456DBAC8541E2D4" level="section">Sec. 109. Data exchange standards for improved interoperability.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HC9272366CA724C06B1E3D86E730D89E1" level="section">Sec. 110. Allocation of funds.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HE8DC2E6F51C04F3DACE6C1E6238BDB7B" level="title">Title II—Control Unlawful Fugitive Felons Act</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H1034B20C203F4AF188622910CC5E9B11" level="section">Sec. 201. Short title.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H89516A1E781E4B21B990722A9B636628" level="section">Sec. 202. Revisions to provisions limiting payment of benefits to fugitive felons under title XVI of the Social Security Act.</toc-entry> </toc></section> <title id="HF8A8CBEF4B1F4EA4B5061023D8543839"><enum>I</enum><header>Increasing Opportunity and Success for Children and Parents through Evidence-Based Home Visiting Act</header> <section id="HC71623011420430FBCB8DB6FDC2A474B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>101.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Increasing Opportunity and Success for Children and Parents through Evidence-Based Home Visiting Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HE799206578F8403B924E11E8999B8649"><enum>102.</enum><header>Continuing evidence-based home visiting program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 511(j)(1)(H) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/711">42 U.S.C. 711(j)(1)(H)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>fiscal year 2017</quote> and inserting <quote>each of fiscal years 2017 through 2022</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8B78E1321694471C967CDD4D17959DB2"><enum>103.</enum><header>Continuing to demonstrate results to help families</header> <subsection id="H9ACD5937A24F489F935BF86A9DB87C2F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Require service delivery models To demonstrate improvement in applicable benchmark areas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 511 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/711">42 U.S.C. 711</external-xref>) is amended in each of subsections (d)(1)(A) and (h)(4)(A) by striking <quote>each of</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H965ADE3295484987ABAA29FFDF78F32B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Demonstration of improvements in subsequent years</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 511(d)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/711">42 U.S.C. 711(d)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6A52F6EC2764C98BD74FA93B64C61D4"> <subparagraph id="H94D1D3BAEAE848D198C4EED8552ACE57"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Demonstration of improvements in subsequent years</header> <clause id="HF2632D526F3842EFBB706EE19B18760E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Continued measurement of improvement in applicable benchmark areas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The eligible entity, after demonstrating improvements for eligible families as specified in subparagraphs (A) and (B), shall continue to track and report not later than 30 days after the end of fiscal year 2020 and every 3 years thereafter, information demonstrating that the program results in improvements for the eligible families participating in the program in at least four of the areas specified in subparagraph (A) that the service delivery model or models, selected by the entity, intend to improve.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3CF6419DAF264947A9B154CD1EFD1D17"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Corrective action plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the eligible entity fails to demonstrate improvement in at least four of the areas specified in subparagraph (A), the entity shall develop and implement a plan to improve outcomes in each of the areas specified in subparagraph (A) that the service delivery model or models, selected by the entity, intend to improve, subject to approval by the Secretary. The plan shall include provisions for the Secretary to monitor implementation of the plan and conduct continued oversight of the program, including through submission by the entity of regular reports to the Secretary.</text></clause> <clause id="H29B24705D3B74ADA81F9456AA56B12A5"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide an eligible entity required to develop and implement an improvement plan under clause (ii) with technical assistance to develop and implement the plan. The Secretary may provide the technical assistance directly or through grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7B16A58FF6F146DCA2C64E8A5A6A1AEC"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>No improvement or failure to submit report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines after a period of time specified by the Secretary that an eligible entity implementing an improvement plan under clause (ii) has failed to demonstrate any improvement in at least four of the areas specified in subparagraph (A) that the service delivery model or models intend to improve, or if the Secretary determines that an eligible entity has failed to submit the report required by clause (i), the Secretary shall terminate the grant made to the entity under this section and may include any unexpended grant funds in grants made to nonprofit organizations under subsection (h)(2)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H2CBB62BE00F74B57A54EF7261BCCAA85"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Including information on applicable benchmarks in application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 511(e)(5) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/711">42 U.S.C. 711(e)(5)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>that the service delivery model or models, selected by the entity, intend to improve</quote> before the period at the end.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H40AAEEEA08F344858132637E79421B5F"><enum>104.</enum><header>Reviewing statewide needs to target resources</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 511(b)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/711">42 U.S.C. 711(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>Not later than</quote> and all that follows through <quote>statewide</quote> the second place it appears and inserting <quote>Each State shall, as a condition of receiving payments from an allotment for the State under section 502, review and update the statewide needs assessment not later than October 1, 2020 (which may be separate from but in coordination with the statewide</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5E6EA90B114347738131AFE8D92FB9FB"><enum>105.</enum><header>Improving the likelihood of success in high-risk communities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 511(d)(4)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/711">42 U.S.C. 711(d)(4)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, taking into account the staffing, community resource, and other requirements to operate at least one approved model of home visiting and demonstrate improvements for eligible families</quote> before the period.</text></section> 
<section id="H830BDDA3294F4FFCB3D9467562A96552"><enum>106.</enum><header>Measuring improvements in family economic self-sufficiency</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 511(d)(1)(A)(v) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/711">42 U.S.C. 711(d)(1)(A)(v)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(which shall include measures of employment and earnings)</quote> before the period.</text></section> <section id="H5F41FC2007BA47E4B647B89C91A63EA5"><enum>107.</enum><header>Option to fund evidence-based home visiting on a pay for outcome basis</header> <subsection id="HD63FCDE662D544C09B59884E25C4EA9B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 511(c) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/711">42 U.S.C. 711(c)</external-xref>) is amended by redesignating paragraphs (3) and (4) as paragraphs (4) and (5), respectively, and by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC02222E45EF94808BCC01C9659230396"> 
<paragraph id="H5223FC474CDA4AFEBE82ED797568F5BB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority to use grant for a pay for outcomes initiative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity to which a grant is made under paragraph (1) may use the grant to pay for the results of a pay for outcomes initiative that satisfies the requirements of subsection (d) and that will not result in a reduction of funding for services delivered under this section while an eligible entity develops or operates such an initiative.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H0299FB8451DD41B59554B3A108C4A934"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of pay for outcomes initiative</header><text>Section 511(k) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/711">42 U.S.C. 711(k)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84D083D0D2864C3F89BB0A4EE148AFAF"> 
<paragraph id="H60E686984B8D413BB8153001E0E3DFDE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Pay for outcomes initiative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pay for outcomes initiative</term> means a performance-based grant, contract, cooperative agreement, or other agreement awarded by a public entity in which a commitment is made to pay for improved outcomes that result in social benefit and direct cost savings or cost avoidance to the public sector. Such an initiative shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H3D4CE447C0F34AEE9980A276EA0EBE92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a feasibility study that describes how the proposed intervention is based on evidence of effectiveness;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDB3DE7B5D246427FAF980D5E36EFFBF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a rigorous, third-party evaluation that uses experimental or quasi-experimental design or other research methodologies that allow for the strongest possible causal inferences to determine whether the initiative has met its proposed outcomes;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB932FC140FF84E65B3C97A42A6D4CDF0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an annual, publicly available report on the progress of the initiative; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7C016D19D4074AA2892FE3088D2FB011"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a requirement that payments are made to the recipient of a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement only when agreed upon outcomes are achieved, except that this requirement shall not apply with respect to payments to a third party conducting the evaluation described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H4ACA763D437D48ECBA4C73E144FAB264"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Extended availability of funds</header><text>Section 511(j)(3) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/711">42 U.S.C. 711(j)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9A1E8F5DE41845BF95ECB964B1EE519D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(3) <header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Availability.—</header-in-text>Funds</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEDCE4642B5D84C18A6A4076ACB600933"> <paragraph id="H639EA6EA9F8849A6AAE1311021FFE5A4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability</header> <subparagraph id="HE8980A88A35D4267884A833DFB82441C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), funds</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA612D800FD204858952DF9A6EAC78042"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A2AB32BC3504ADCA547CDEBEA970A8B"> <subparagraph id="HFEF9652E3BDD431FB9D1D52E037A4B5E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Funds for pay for outcomes initiatives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds made available to an eligible entity under this section for a fiscal year (or portion of a fiscal year) for a pay for outcomes initiative shall remain available for expenditure by the eligible entity for not more than 10 years after the funds are so made available.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8DF5C58DD1A340B38A6A98E99C91FB84"><enum>108.</enum><header>Strengthening evidence-based home visiting through state, local, and private partnerships</header> 
<subsection id="H8BA2D8C30BF24832A6F046A80E0E0A89"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 511 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/711">42 U.S.C. 711</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD34057DDC43A470FADAE9B8FCA5AB840"> <subsection id="H1CF60B5ECF4A4C7E98E60356BE35690D"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header> <paragraph id="H0BA3F2859E52426EBBD36C77F2F8FA2A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Program home visiting share</header> <subparagraph id="HDB8318D9C1D8433AA348AD128062AE03"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity to which a grant is made under this section for fiscal year 2020 or any succeeding fiscal year shall not use the grant to cover more than the applicable percentage of the costs of providing services or conducting activities under this section during the fiscal year.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB341BCC8629043328C6D48A733E11EF2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>In subparagraph (A), the term <term>applicable percentage</term> means, with respect to a fiscal year—</text> <clause id="HF754A9FDC17E4A2DB1F90BF116FA0313"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible entity that is a State or nonprofit organization—</text> 
<subclause id="H957256040EBC46588BFA64C5C69AF768"><enum>(I)</enum><text>70 percent, in the case of fiscal year 2020;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H51C0E3FEC8CE40BF81C78189D3B5F560"><enum>(II)</enum><text>60 percent, in the case of fiscal year 2021; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H296C2C349AC0427A89170755C28DD299"><enum>(III)</enum><text>50 percent, in the case of fiscal year 2022 or any succeeding fiscal year; or</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H933F1D2CB161443AB26590A6A42CD67B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an eligible entity that is an Indian Tribe (or a consortium of Indian Tribes), a Tribal Organization, or an Urban Indian Organization, 100 percent.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBFF48AED11C340118B1F6AAE1473B16E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-program home visiting share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The share of the costs of providing services or conducting activities under this section not covered by grant funds may include—</text> <subparagraph id="H28BC1B7B153D45379173928E548A9F20"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State expenditures of Federal funds made available other than under this section expended for activities under this section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0133CCF9FF584282B0F99E2E180F090C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State expenditures of State funds expended for activities under this section as a condition of receiving Federal funds other than under this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCB9BD34B0E9345058413294083D50638"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contributions made for activities under this section from any other source, paid in cash or in kind, valued at the fair market value of such contribution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1B6130CC82C64A73ABE3E6756AA56F65"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 511(h)(2)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/711">42 U.S.C. 711(h)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended in the second sentence by striking <quote>Such</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subsection (l)(1), such</quote>. </text></subsection></section> <section id="H788EA756A3E24F98B456DBAC8541E2D4"><enum>109.</enum><header>Data exchange standards for improved interoperability</header> <subsection id="H162646A48A0D4E6083DF54B0B1719B5C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 511(h) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/711">42 U.S.C. 711(h)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4FB1C7B3B660412B81F38C452A669E02"> 
<paragraph id="H840D86CE495D4BF08F69EE045CA189A7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Data exchange standards for improved interoperability</header> 
<subparagraph id="H6F565FEACA754744838E1D985B50CDA1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Designation and use of data exchange standards</header> 
<clause id="H71611A35B8FF4BB180ECB542C6658E7C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The head of the department or agency responsible for administering a program funded under this section shall, in consultation with an interagency work group established by the Office of Management and Budget and considering State government perspectives, designate data exchange standards for necessary categories of information that a State agency operating the program is required to electronically exchange with another State agency under applicable Federal law.</text></clause> <clause id="H3C7D610AE7484B7C802833D90CD83F15"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Data exchange standards must be nonproprietary and interoperable</header><text>The data exchange standards designated under clause (i) shall, to the extent practicable, be nonproprietary and interoperable.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H938D974E20694BCC804C3DB770EB9D3E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Other requirements</header><text>In designating data exchange standards under this paragraph, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, incorporate—</text> <subclause id="H4E024078F44144CCBCC0A25EBE1D89C1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>interoperable standards developed and maintained by an international voluntary consensus standards body, as defined by the Office of Management and Budget;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB0A15D626FE8457FAD26DC3357208C4D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>interoperable standards developed and maintained by intergovernmental partnerships, such as the National Information Exchange Model; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H5B954672C134489CA244D6F794D2C1E2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>interoperable standards developed and maintained by Federal entities with authority over contracting and financial assistance.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4033D066954A47A28419DE77D09C81C5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Data exchange standards for federal reporting</header> 
<clause id="HDD5CD07D47A949F68DCAF398798FBB07"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The head of the department or agency responsible for administering a program referred to in this section shall, in consultation with an interagency work group established by the Office of Management and Budget, and considering State government perspectives, designate data exchange standards to govern Federal reporting and exchange requirements under applicable Federal law.</text></clause> <clause id="HC381269D59F64F6D99DE065A018CB9E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The data exchange reporting standards required by clause (i) shall, to the extent practicable—</text> 
<subclause id="H7C31ABED13FE428A94DC6E01894DE298"><enum>(I)</enum><text>incorporate a widely accepted, nonproprietary, searchable, computer-readable format;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0F872756DB4C43BFA351FED7ADCEB311"><enum>(II)</enum><text>be consistent with and implement applicable accounting principles;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF54A45F8C70942BB9FA53D79DBFA947B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>be implemented in a manner that is cost-effective and improves program efficiency and effectiveness; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HAF2094E6364C45319A17943DB383B939"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>be capable of being continually upgraded as necessary.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H5BDDC58126824C0F96613C6A04E09E6B"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Incorporation of nonproprietary standards</header><text>In designating data exchange standards under this paragraph, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, incorporate existing nonproprietary standards, such as the eXtensible Markup Language.</text></clause> <clause id="H2E0F998A089B42A3B7B20AD9951AB03F"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to require a change to existing data exchange standards for Federal reporting about a program referred to in this section, if the head of the department or agency responsible for administering the program finds the standards to be effective and efficient.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3F25D7F942FD4207BBDE8F8B6F03E3A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall take effect 2 years after the date of the enactment of this title.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HC9272366CA724C06B1E3D86E730D89E1"><enum>110.</enum><header>Allocation of funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 511(j) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/711">42 U.S.C. 711(j)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H92100500B35548AE9B10AB8C94958E04" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HC26836A6612D4AE58A75AA998D4819DD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Allocation of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent that the grant amount awarded under this section to an eligible entity is determined on the basis of relative population or poverty considerations, the Secretary shall make the determination using the most accurate Federal data available for the eligible entity.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></title> <title id="HE8DC2E6F51C04F3DACE6C1E6238BDB7B"><enum>II</enum><header>Control Unlawful Fugitive Felons Act</header> <section id="H1034B20C203F4AF188622910CC5E9B11" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>201.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Control Unlawful Fugitive Felons Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H89516A1E781E4B21B990722A9B636628"><enum>202.</enum><header>Revisions to provisions limiting payment of benefits to fugitive felons under title XVI of the Social Security Act</header> 
<subsection id="H9F7D814F21F44DADB07A08055F56A5CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fugitive felon warrant requirement</header><text>Section 1611(e)(4)(A)(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1382">42 U.S.C. 1382(e)(4)(A)(i)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HBBB6C08F8107468493DBC70347F0695E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>fleeing to avoid</quote> and inserting <quote>the subject of an arrest warrant for the purpose of</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC8CCAA90D0D84FD2A75253FFDA5F1285"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the place from which the person flees</quote> the first place it appears and inserting <quote>the jurisdiction issuing the warrant</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5985D4A07A8B419FB4FFDF337D6EBFE7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the place from which the person flees</quote> the second place it appears and inserting <quote>the jurisdiction</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0E27B91E81A04D52918B2BAD38E9B6A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Probation and parole warrant requirement</header><text>Section 1611(e)(4)(A)(ii) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1382">42 U.S.C. 1382(e)(4)(A)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HF4D65466F2794E2E85BB4170976C9E11" style="OLC"> <clause id="HE4DEE862CE654A97A4BE32A2188E2F1D" indent="up2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the subject of an arrest warrant for violating a condition of probation or parole imposed under Federal or State law.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H27305F2D764947BE8660EF20B0A91D09"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>Section 1611(e)(5) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1382">42 U.S.C. 1382(e)(5)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HBAF8A0A76A0E432EB531B2A612662A30"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>any recipient of</quote> and inserting <quote>any individual who is a recipient of (or would be such a recipient but for the application of paragraph (4)(A))</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8DF284EE9CC4A21B88FBBA47D66F27B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the recipient</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>the individual</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4A2D2452A40B4800B483E0910FE62F57"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall be effective with respect to benefits payable for months that begin on or after January 1, 2021.</text></subsection></section></title> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20170926" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives September 26, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> 
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> 
</bill> 


