<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HABCD437301294F5CB46E8EEE661EC5C2" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4204 IH: International Regulated Investment Company Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4204</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171101">November 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001158">Mr. Marchant</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for International Regulated Investment
			 Companies.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HABB9483928B54B14B51D999E26560C0A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H150F0A895D104495ADCD8266C1BD8286" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>International Regulated Investment Company Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3EBFD4FE201843E48E20231A9D63E5F9"><enum>2.</enum><header>International regulated investment companies</header> <subsection id="H758CE59FA565432CBD56CB03D49E7297"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter N of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating part V as part VI and inserting after part IV the following new part:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D022FF52D314DC9BBABBE5F20326181" style="OLC">
					<part id="H6A690B7F657A43E183A8F680D7107AD7" style="OLC"><enum>V</enum><header>International regulated investment companies</header>
						<toc>
							<toc-entry idref="HFDBDCF3EBE9040D3A64B50AC645583F3" level="section">Sec. 998. Definition of international regulated investment company.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H701D3C1BD51748D4845DE2CD3A28B6AF" level="section">Sec. 998A. Taxation of IRICs.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="HD5BB5978668D467998D8D27DD82B14F8" level="section">Sec. 998B. Other rules.</toc-entry></toc>
						<section id="HFDBDCF3EBE9040D3A64B50AC645583F3"><enum>998.</enum><header>Definition of International regulated investment company</header>
 <subsection id="H4DA8BA631B6141AA8B681E802F9B62B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>For purposes of this title, the terms <term>international regulated investment company</term> and <term>IRIC</term> mean, with respect to any taxable year, a domestic corporation which, at all times during the taxable year, meets the following requirements:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA163138A2B6D4BF0B97FA296A7AFB655"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The corporation is registered under the Investment Company Act of 1940.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3C87C53F489486A85849CB5C2122C39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Except as provided in subsection (c), the corporation holds no assets other than the stock of a single regulated investment company—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD6D88F7AEA3D4C3AA41196730D812C38"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to which part I of subchapter M applies, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D5775ADD9FA47348B5055077DF00F61"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which is not a qualified investment entity (as defined in section 897(h)(4)(A)(ii)).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF473D10C14640E39AD68F71EF580A91"><enum>(3)</enum><text>All outstanding stock of the corporation is held by nonresident alien individuals (and their foreign estates) and qualified foreign pension funds (within the meaning of section 897(l)(2)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1751499920AB4DCA9DBC8DE03C1812DB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The corporation has in effect an election to be treated as an IRIC.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H276E03A493B1427A96CF334B4976D84A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Election</header><text>An election to be treated as an IRIC shall apply to the taxable year for which made and all subsequent taxable years until terminated. Such election shall be made for any taxable year not later than the due date (with extensions) for the return of tax imposed by this subtitle for the taxable year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC9F9A3D493BA49339B759604265369C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Permitted assets</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a)(2), an IRIC may hold—</text> <paragraph id="H0555F8DFECC845E7BEFF5861F5B961B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an amount of cash and cash equivalents reasonably necessary or appropriate for the corporation to conduct its normal affairs, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96269947356B4846AAA9CD3D09093244"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such other assets as are incidental to the corporation’s conduct of its normal affairs or otherwise allowed by the Secretary.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA383805FA411488C896B42ADBEA0A1A9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination</header>
 <paragraph id="HB57413E4268D4427AFCAAA0C860F3EB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), if a corporation fails to meet the requirements of subsection (a) at any time during the taxable year, the corporation shall not be treated as an IRIC for such taxable year.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H32BA7D0332A94276807F022E37A0EB47"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inadvertent failure</header>
 <subparagraph id="H42EC477173AB49EFB76BE0FDE3615AC7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A corporation which fails to meet the requirements of subsection (a) for any taxable year shall nevertheless be considered to have satisfied the requirements of such subsection for such taxable year if—</text>
 <clause id="H082888FB3FD9492692C4500184FA369A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the failure was due to reasonable cause and not due to willful neglect,</text> </clause><clause id="HCF6A022FBFE44D08BB9833926A2184A9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>no later than 30 days after the discovery of the event causing such failure, the corporation meets the requirements of subsection (a),</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC42F4F04B87A4966A74661EE37F1B7B7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of a failure to meet the requirements of subsection (a)(3) for any period, the failure was caused by persons not described therein holding, in the aggregate, less than 1 percent of the stock (by value) of the corporation, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H69EE962267204D0BB0793511ED63BAF1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the corporation pays the additional tax imposed by reason of subparagraph (B).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE1F9D3FBECF4C45B1DFE090B6F943F5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Imposition of additional tax on certain failures</header><text>In the case of a failure described in subparagraph (A)(iii) for any taxable year, the tax imposed by section 998A(a) on the IRIC shall be equal to the sum of—</text>
 <clause id="H62F0908F40FC4A4B9997474013330513"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the tax determined under such section (without regard to this subparagraph) on amounts received by the IRIC for the taxable year other than amounts so received which are attributable to stock held by persons not described in subsection (a)(3) for the period so held, plus</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7F1FB0098A4340F7B722AA8DF0B16507"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>100 percent of the amounts received which are so attributable.</text> </clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">The Secretary shall prescribe rules for the proper allocation of deductions to amounts described in this subparagraph.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H701D3C1BD51748D4845DE2CD3A28B6AF"><enum>998A.</enum><header>Taxation of IRICs</header> <subsection id="HE3E233EAF3A944E19BBEE45C95594CC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an IRIC, there shall be imposed, in lieu of the tax imposed by section 11, a tax equal to 30 percent of the excess of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8616EC6DDD3B48C3882D984726E30750"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the amounts received by the IRIC which (before the application of any treaty) would be subject to tax under section 871(a) if received by a nonresident alien individual, over</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E87C49375604D1EB3261A20D6AEFF37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the deductions properly allocable to such amounts (other than deductions allowed under sections 163, 172, 243, and such other provisions as the Secretary may prescribe in regulations to prevent abuse).</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCDBB43EEDE844B0D882ADDE4A0607738"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treaties</header>
 <paragraph id="H5C496AF3BCD04176816E9407246AC325"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a treaty IRIC, subsection (a) shall be applied by substituting <quote>15 percent</quote> for <quote>30 percent</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA00375C0587149B4B16E073B4121BD63"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treaty IRIC</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <term>treaty IRIC</term> means an IRIC—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H928753A7EB444514AECE5B510CC84559"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all the outstanding stock of which is held by persons resident in a country that has in effect with the United States an income tax treaty pursuant to which such persons would, by reason of section 894(a), be subject to tax under section 871(a) on dividends at a rate not greater than 15 percent, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0654E05D29B746688A23020B6D7A1386"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which elects to be a treaty IRIC.</text> </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Rules similar to the rules of section 998(b) shall apply to an election under subparagraph (B).</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD5BB5978668D467998D8D27DD82B14F8"><enum>998B.</enum><header>Other rules</header> <subsection id="H967B17D3B07148699FDF5FE247C77879"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coordination with subchapter M</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (e), an IRIC shall not be treated as a regulated investment company for purposes of this title.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HE198ECA9875F4CB98C116FBDCBA4C956"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No carryovers</header>
 <paragraph id="H17AF3FA11EE640738860E798B4BE6C9F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Carryovers to IRIC years</header><text>No carryforward, and no carryback, arising for a taxable year for which the corporation is not an IRIC may be carried to a taxable year for which such corporation is an IRIC.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD06FDEC3E1A4B26898F64AF3256FA3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Carryovers from IRIC years</header><text>No carryforward, and no carryback, shall arise for a taxable year for which a corporation is an IRIC.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDCC1C7443A3D4906868CAD295DC10598"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certain taxes not To apply</header><text>Sections 55, 531, and 541 shall not apply to an IRIC.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HEB130137CBB044B1A27F919C08E21463"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Credits not allowed</header><text>No credits under this chapter shall be allowed to an IRIC.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H542480F59A494E659104985931DE6777"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Redemptions</header><text>In applying section 302(b)(5), an IRIC shall be treated as a publicly offered regulated investment company.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H1AF89C19421F41DC83C6779414EED2B4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reliance on certification</header>
 <paragraph id="HC91412DE66DB4DEA8DE15E964D4A3E36"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reliance</header><text>With respect to the requirement in sections 998(a)(3) and 998A(b)(2)(A), a corporation may rely on the certification of its shareholders, unless or until such time that the corporation has reason to know that the certification is false or is no longer true.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC98A89E7957E4DA783A30239EC6219E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Redemption upon false certification</header><text>If a corporation has reason to know that the certification made by one of its shareholders is false or is no longer true, the corporation must redeem the stock held by such shareholder as soon as reasonably practicable (and in no case more than 30 days after the corporation obtains such reason to know). Failure to redeem such stock in a timely manner shall result in the corporation failing the requirement of section 998(a)(3) or 998A(b)(2)(A), whichever is applicable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58DB02406F634FCCADB5B04542A59821"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Certification by certain institutions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, a certification with regard to a person which is made by an institution described in section 871(h)(5)(B) in a form satisfactory to the Secretary under section 871(h) shall be deemed to be a certification by such person.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H71C2A93B9E114F14A12EC87405609CAB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of parts for subchapter N of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating the item relating to part V as relating to part VI and inserting after the item relating to part IV the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HB52867F618DF42DB9CAAD6972D725498" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry idref="H6A690B7F657A43E183A8F680D7107AD7" level="part">Part V—International regulated investment companies</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H89F0A94F9E084251AD7B13050F970F41"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


