<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB93493A976434C44900ED00E0E3B170E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4123 IH: North Korea Ballistic Missile Investigations Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4123</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171025">October 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000607">Mr. Francis Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Director of National Intelligence, in coordination with the Secretary of State, to
			 submit a report to Congress with respect to North Korea’s procurement of
			 engines and technologies from a foreign source, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HDEC2FC3D543E45CB9D39DE094A8199F7" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD94E35CD90D14055A11AAADABCAF00E2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>North Korea Ballistic Missile Investigations Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H44B392F4AF8145188321C436E61E2AFB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H11FAD670454F4D7F97449473A5ADB7A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to experts, North Korea’s missile program has made <quote>astounding strides over the past two years</quote>, marked particularly by the successful launching of two new missiles within ten months: the intermediate-range Hwasong–12 and the intercontinental ballistic missile Hwasong–14.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H808C0C9B0B3D4B6286BA6A8D3D633895"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to a August 14, 2017, report by the International Institute for Strategic Studies, North Korea made these advancements by acquiring a high-performance liquid-propellant engine from a foreign source, likely from Ukraine.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H033F289D0CF046AF98A9EE326758FC3F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Available evidence indicates that the liquid-propellant engine is based on the Soviet RD–250 family of engines, and has been modified to operate as the boosting force for the Hwasong–12 and the Hwasong–14. Those engines are linked to a missile factory in Dnipro, Ukraine, which has been struggling financially over the past decade.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF322CB3CEAA642CC9392009736F68584"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The New York Times reported on September 17, 2017, that North Korea may have initially procured rocket fuel from China and Russia, including the highly volatile fuel unsymmetrical dimethyl hydrazine.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H406F6DBFD69E4C98A58242DA5ADE9F76"><enum>3.</enum><header>Investigation with respect to North Korea</header>
 <subsection id="H9FD016F5522A4EF89D3DC22CBD9D9B8E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of National Intelligence, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall conduct an investigation into North Korea’s alleged procurement of engines and related technology, including the procurement of unsymmetrical dimethyl hydrazine, from foreign sources.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD3B2777B49BF4A8BA7F9AF41CB4F703A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 105 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains the conclusions of the investigation conducted under <internal-xref idref="H9FD016F5522A4EF89D3DC22CBD9D9B8E" legis-path="3.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> and addresses each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2A8D48B2A6664C0C91F9D70C4DF3B200"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">North Korea’s indigenous capabilities to have produced unsymmetrical dimethyl hydrazine and intercontinental ballistic missile engines, and the likelihood of foreign procurement of such fuel and missiles.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4236358C66A94B5AA7AA76AF183410DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The role of Russia and China in helping North Korea to illegally procure missile technology.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8632BFB30289441C96803FD52D755FA6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation required</header><text>The Director of National Intelligence shall conduct the investigation under <internal-xref idref="H9FD016F5522A4EF89D3DC22CBD9D9B8E" legis-path="3.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> in consultation with the Government of Ukraine.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H0BD053E1C90D4A53A7E9371E885AD6EF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Cooperative threat reduction enhancement</header>
 <subsection id="H5E85FC377AEE4688A915A306B6122DB9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H7165E086FD834BD78364006C71374264"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Cooperative Threat Reduction Program was established to combat the type of proliferation alleged by the International Institute for Strategic Studies report described in <internal-xref idref="H808C0C9B0B3D4B6286BA6A8D3D633895" legis-path="2.(2)">section 2(2)</internal-xref>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD92504EA52A4FE9914533C931C3D222"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States needs to take steps to strengthen that program, particularly in Ukraine, to thwart the proliferation of sensitive technology or expertise.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HACDE1C362C1A48F4950409099AA32F53"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report including recommendations to improve the implementation of the Department of Defense Cooperative Threat Reduction Program established by section 1321 of the Department of Defense Cooperate Threat Reduction Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3711">50 U.S.C. 3711</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H5F049668B2CC4BC0AD204B0F84242C2E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H68B31A9E48D94DF6B81436AE99340C5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F49A7A37003409FA96A14804730E9AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Select Committee on Intelligence, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


