<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9C125732010A49F2A7C2FAE77D3AB7D2" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2139 IH: To amend the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 and title 49, United States Code, with respect to disadvantaged business enterprises, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2139</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170425">April 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 and title 49, United States Code, with
			 respect to disadvantaged business enterprises, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9DB0E6D921E94A729662F4D07914D839" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB821C3209EEB4123ADE8A8F879173CA0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Inspector General report on participation in FAA programs by disadvantaged small business concerns</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 140 of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6339E50D899843239C56F783FD343C37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H99DC9BDA574B4574A742A51F5ACC09D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) by striking <quote>each of fiscal years 2013 through 2017</quote> and inserting <quote>fiscal year 2017 and periodically thereafter</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50AFEF8CAEC0437682088E7361209F8D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(A) by striking <quote>a list</quote> and inserting <quote>with respect to the large and medium hub airports in the United States that participate in the airport disadvantaged business enterprise program referenced in subsection (a), a list</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0847E0925974F6B936EA580A1DD75F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H27CAC11D54354EC69C009CA9B87C8E2F" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H021772F3321047DDBDFF67BB6CE96058"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Assessment of efforts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General shall assess the efforts of the Federal Aviation Administration with respect to implementing rec­om­men­da­tions suggested in reports submitted under subsection (c) and shall include in each semiannual report of the Inspector General that is submitted to Congress a description of the results of such assessment.</text>
					</subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H6C514EC51E84465B84039CF10CFD25AF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Minority and disadvantaged business participation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 47113 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HEE89697183A24640B18F736EDF7283F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1C24114A18A342B9BE68F603CC8ED816"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretary shall</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HADC8375AD537479C9E69AD6C1384958B" style="USC"> <paragraph id="HA81B58203BDE4787BBB303A4B363F6DF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68BE90A16B184A91A51D3CEFC1C83B16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30FAFA06699F4A3C8F0AD6768BF9FD12" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H1862A9F5B4784F5DB32CE879CAA4B118"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consistency of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop and maintain a training program—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA19EFB30B46D49E9828319F852BC28E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for employees of the Federal Aviation Administration who provide guidance and training to entities that certify whether a small business concern qualifies under this section (and for employees of the other modal administrations of the Department of Transportation who provide similar services); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35BC9172F4E940008500D068CB08A35C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that ensures Federal officials provide consistent communications with respect to certification requirements.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC84CACB69814FE1BFEE1889A48DDD2D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Lists of certifying authorities</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that each State maintains an accurate list of the certifying authorities in such State for purposes of this section and that the list is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0288560DDC084FCC896CFE7D1D23A67B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>updated at least twice each year; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4547B6AFAA9B4A00BC83E482630C9A22"><enum>(B)</enum><text>made available to the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF89DF77D53C740F5A666922A4497A415"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e) by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CB1A9930EF64580BBEC4627F2E221E9" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H851E98251829497086641BCF7E5A2344"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall determine, for each fiscal year, the number of individuals who received training under this subsection and shall make such number available to the public on an appropriate website operated by the Secretary. If the Secretary determines, with respect to a fiscal year, that fewer individuals received training under this subsection than in the previous fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress, and make available to the public on an appropriate website operated by the Secretary, a report describing the reasons for the decrease.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB07F80F3879A423C8074727A058769EE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this paragraph, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall assess the training program, including by soliciting feedback from stakeholders, and update the training program as appropriate.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE10EA6759E9F49A69714C506237803BE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52E47FA31E5544678B6FCBE2945788D5" style="USC"> <subsection id="H7C57530C128C45049EEAF8902A15BA51"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Trend assessment</header> <paragraph id="HB40ED9AC55F444098A5D49834507A17C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this subsection, and at least every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall study, using information reported by airports, trends in the participation of small business concerns referred to in subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC83BFE139A8547CC8BA4882CE2AB5AA4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The study under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HC5E69FEA3667430FA72291B4C19EAFCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of whether the participation of small business concerns referred to in subsection (b) at reporting airports increased or decreased during the period studied, including for such concerns that were first time participants;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2029E633E6234DA99A955847DC480ADD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the factors relating to any significant increases or decreases in participation compared to prior years; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD87C0AE6B2DB4A3386AC43D4FF9773D9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>development of a plan to respond to the results of the study, including development of recommendations for sharing best practices for maintaining or boosting participation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H995C651608F64CAF975FFA9D9DDE566B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each study completed under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to Congress, and make available to the program contact at each airport that participates in the airport disadvantaged business enterprise program, a report describing the results of the study.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HF7046A3D6F374872A1950573294A5E75"><enum>3.</enum><header>Passenger facility charges</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 40117(c) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE045C52DD3FD4BE184627D3355084337" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H19C24FAAF8A84C4981D48BE8C2A1EBCB" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an application under this subsection that relates to an airport that participates in the airport disadvantaged business enterprise program referenced in section 140(a) of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/47113">49 U.S.C. 47113</external-xref> note), the application shall include a detailed description of good faith efforts at the airport to contract with disadvantaged business enterprises in relation to any project that is a subject of the application and to ensure that all small businesses, including those owned by veterans, fairly compete for work funded with passenger facility charges.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H43EAFB4003A94CBB8B5F6645A14E6AC3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Annual tracking of certain new firms at airports with a disadvantaged business enterprise program</header>
 <subsection id="HE0E4ADFE572D4596BB8E5DC3948AA59F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Tracking required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning in fiscal year 2017, and each fiscal year thereafter, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall require each covered airport to report to the Administrator on the number of new disadvantaged business enterprises that were awarded a contract or concession during the previous fiscal year at the airport.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H50EC5652DD464CAF9FDEE93E36081D79"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training</header><text>The Administrator shall provide training to airports, on an ongoing basis, with respect to compliance with subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H512417D6A16D45BCA7CB622BDCDA1530"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the first fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of this Act and every fiscal year thereafter, the Administrator shall update dbE–Connect (or any successor online reporting system) to include information on the number of new disadvantaged business enterprises that were awarded a contract or concession during the previous fiscal year at a covered airport.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H95683018DA1840DC94399A6FE3321F04"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Covered airport defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>covered airport</term> means a large or medium hub airport that participates in the airport disadvantaged business enterprise program referenced in section 140(a) of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/47113">49 U.S.C. 47113</external-xref> note).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H0DA1062A28F64761B5045DB1C3A30499"><enum>5.</enum><header>Audits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Inspector General of the Department of Transportation shall conduct periodic audits regarding the accuracy of the data on disadvantaged business enterprises contained in the Federal Aviation Administration’s reporting database related to such enterprises or any similar or successor online reporting database developed by the Administration.</text>
		</section><section id="H9CEA20B069564F8EAB518157CD9AFD6F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Prompt payments</header>
 <subsection id="H92B0B6AD8AAE4335BDF629E870314DB9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting of complaints</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall ensure that each airport that participates in the Program tracks, and reports to the Administrator, the number of covered complaints made in relation to activities at that airport.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HC99F5297EB51499CAA669691C7367EAE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Improving compliance</header>
 <paragraph id="H424277CD248D46F983A7BC4AE02F1BAB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall take actions to assess and improve compliance with prompt payment requirements under part 26 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H27AF808E65D14DCEBD4803FE8177FE6B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of assessment</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Administrator shall assess—</text> <subparagraph id="HE8ECAE63C5A34577AED92C6DEA28594A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether requirements relating to the inclusion of prompt payment language in contracts are being satisfied;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3EAC2D1B27D4DC683158A48969CCBBE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether and how airports are enforcing prompt payment requirements;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FB61C2863E8439FBB17C1A558DACD1F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the processes by which covered complaints are received and resolved by airports;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94C2D06D6B0E48B9AFD305BE2CEB0B98"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether improvements need to be made to—</text> <clause id="H88B2ED5CA441429381D924747DD94FC9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>better track covered complaints received by airports; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFF2B1ABE5D2F40918B7DF360BF23D25E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assist the resolution of covered complaints in a timely manner;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE186D5B758A64C3683FEEE6638A27AB0"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of alternative dispute resolution mechanisms with respect to resolving covered complaints;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BC63932C5ED45D19FE08ABA6A020B1C"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">best practices that ensure prompt payment requirements are satisfied;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H013364C08F2449AF9477CBA5FF6F3A97"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal Aviation Administration resources, including staff, that are dedicated to helping resolve covered complaints; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE26150B5445448DA4BD00005A16D9DA"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the Federal Aviation Administration can enhance efforts to resolve covered complaints, including by using timelines and providing additional staffing and other resources.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H983C5408C7C14D9B87C42E6DC40FEE34"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall make available to the public on an appropriate web­site operated by the Administrator a report describing the results of the assessment completed under this subsection, including a plan to respond to such results.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2267813FA53F4D22A357C81240734691"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="H4287C4066AD24B9BBE78FC0F63B5E0B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered complaint</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered complaint</term> means a complaint relating to an alleged failure to satisfy a prompt payment requirement under part 26 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2220A13C08344465983D627E9D9A4268"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the airport disadvantaged business enterprise program referenced in section 140(a) of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/47113">49 U.S.C. 47113</external-xref> note).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


