<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H98570BA134CB4EE0B694651719732DDC" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3519 IH: Bad Actor Disqualification Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3519</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170727">July 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To increase accountability of the Securities and Exchange Commission and to require the Commission
			 to implement a rigorous, fair, and public process for waiving bad actor
			 disqualifications in the securities laws.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H508FBC8242074FA9862EB3340A4F21A8" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCD9E7480C06E43068E1C63F787656B84" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bad Actor Disqualification Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0853C5C51C5344E880C52AA8D75F8CE6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA2B25ED3AD8D4FCA9A6E6F920EA8A105"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The automatic disqualification provisions in the securities laws are valuable tools that protect investors, the markets, and the public by deterring misconduct, reducing recidivism, promoting market integrity, and removing bad actors from the market.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF2CA4C39A8B4865990553C004305524"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">These tools are inappropriately underutilized and waivers of the automatic disqualification provisions are disproportionately granted to the largest financial institutions on Wall Street, many of which are recidivists. Between July, 2003, and December, 2014, large financial firms received the vast majority of waivers of sanctions, about 82 percent of 201 total waivers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDD6E497596F4B00B7D1F8498948B0C6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Waivers of these automatic sanctions should be granted sparingly and only through an open and transparent process.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H83475333219D4CA98CC995EEAB0F47A6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Increasing transparency and accountability in waiving bad actor disqualifications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 36 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78mm">15 U.S.C. 78mm</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD2DDD191A7B4221AF95CF6B0793C473" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H9E1589C6FD6A4089B0E4B00692B3AC13"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver procedure and identification of bad actors</header>
					<paragraph id="HCF656111D0374601A413821AB420F5DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Waiver procedure</header>
						<subparagraph id="H9DED77BF1A1547D99070DA68A24612C6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Temporary waiver</header>
 <clause id="H1C3BCD8E92B24B8CBF0D84847569282D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Petition for waiver</header><text>A person may petition the Commission for a temporary waiver of a disqualification or pending disqualification described under subparagraphs (A) through (G) of paragraph (3).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H66A768DC571A4258B2ACCC79A765AACD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Grant of waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a petition made by a person under clause (i), when such person becomes an ineligible person, the Commission may vote to provide such person with a single 180-day temporary waiver, by order, if the Commission determines that such person has demonstrated immediate irreparable injury.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H029676E29EBF4F0AA02CBEA325C61323"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Publication of petition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall publish any petition for a temporary waiver along with the order containing an explanation for any Commission determination immediately following the related vote under clause (ii).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H225774BD2D5D4DBD8B8B1E565E539FBF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>General waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the 180-day period provided under subparagraph (A), the Commission, by vote during a meeting open to the public, may not waive any disqualification described under subparagraphs (A) through (G) of paragraph (3), unless the Commission determines, without regard to the direct costs to the ineligible person associated with a denial, that such waiver—</text>
 <clause id="H2FD3F26D49AE4B78909A93F9EC139EBE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is in the public interest;</text> </clause><clause id="HBD643BD8807146DCBE4E712B949D33EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is necessary for the protection of investors; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA49F47D85BBA45F3876BF8525FDB7604"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>promotes market integrity.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H881E59311A2A48DDA7C55F230088D639"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Federal Register notice; public hearing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before making a determination under subparagraph (B), the Commission shall publish adequate notice in the Federal Register of the pendency of the waiver determination and shall afford the public and interested persons an opportunity to present their views, including at a public hearing.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H304EBBB3F18849B8AE04706F3F0A8835"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Prohibition on advance advice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Commission staff may not advise any person of the recommendation of staff to the Commission or on the likelihood of a waiver being granted or denied under this paragraph for such person.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33189BB076C44B2E8E54F8F3E0056878"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Recordkeeping requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall keep a public record of all requests for a waiver under this paragraph that are later withdrawn.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1EAFA43A039D4DE09848D8CEF862FAC2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Database of ineligible persons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall establish, and maintain, a public database of all ineligible persons that the Commission has voted against providing a waiver under this subsection or that have indicated their ineligibility in any disclosure to the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2D6E460B5F8E451D9264D3682D2E7A89"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ineligible person defined</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>ineligible person</quote> means any person that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0434258B128F4B1BAB78D6710839C35A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an ineligible issuer and not eligible to qualify as a well-known seasoned issuer (as such terms are defined under section 230.405 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H36026BD71F304C529E5ECB19FD38C011"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not eligible to make use of an exemption provided for certain Regulation D private offerings under section 230.505 or 230.506 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0C9B18D8BC0D452590DA07D314609792"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not eligible for any safe harbor for forward-looking statements provided for under section 27A(c) of the Securities Act of 1933;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC32E29ED3F5047898E0E4518F1CB378B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is not eligible for any safe harbor for forward-looking statements provided for under section 21E(c) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4C8A193BC0934C888A1DCBF2C8AD7C8D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>is disqualified from receiving a cash fee, directly or indirectly, from an investment adviser with respect to solicitation activities, as described under section 275.206(4)-3 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4400BC0C6ED34944832AC7EBAB2A21DD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>is not eligible to make use of an exemption provided for certain Regulation A offerings under section 230.262 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD39CFCAC444844DC9E77E9F10DE48E66"><enum>(G)</enum><text>is not eligible to make use of an exemption provided for certain Regulation E offerings under section 230.602 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HE0BD99BF91BF4FEBBFD1055341CBA096"><enum>4.</enum><header>GAO study</header>
 <subsection id="H623C14A505C745B38AF074A01E7A5598"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall carry out a study of the Securities and Exchange Commission’s existing waiver process, and the standard used by the Commission in granting an application for an exemption, under section 9(c) of the Investment Company Act of 1940.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HED8C57D9C28448C4BD35B4C5DDAF0CF6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall issue a report to the Congress containing—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC8F9F27BDF7E460DA5F106535931D459"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all findings and determinations made in carrying out the study required under subsection (a);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H08FE78B14AF443568731970EC20C6023"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a comparison of the Commission’s standard used in granting an application for an exemption under section 9(c) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 with the standard used to grant a waiver under section 36(c) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, as added by this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB3CDABA024F4EE4A1C787C7E9BD9EC0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations on how to increase transparency and opportunity for public participation in the waiver process under section 9(c) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 and ensure that the disqualification and waiver process used by the Commission under such section 9(c) is protective of investors, the markets, and the public and deters misconduct, reduces recidivism, promotes market integrity, and removes bad actors from the market.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


