<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCD197A6ABAB34BF1BF2DF58B655AAFBC" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2746 IH: American Renewable Energy and Efficiency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2746</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title VI of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to establish a Federal
			 renewable electricity standard for retail electricity suppliers and a
			 Federal energy efficiency resource standard for electricity and natural
			 gas suppliers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1D7FA7589CEE408399967A54D424D65F" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0288BFA883A140978BAAD4B0B8ECEF8F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Renewable Energy and Efficiency Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H70306EA4049F443F94F94DCAE4312366"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal renewable electricity standard</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VI of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2601">16 U.S.C. 2601</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding after section 609 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/918c">7 U.S.C. 918c</external-xref>) the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2752ABD70FA4E41B9A15DACA4A402D3" style="OLC">
				<section id="H05307B05A09F40F0BC068A830BBFAAE5"><enum>610.</enum><header>Federal renewable electricity standard</header>
 <subsection id="HEA0B947C000449E2B25E8A0361397EF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="HB00750A9DD2A446FA1B7E36CE2CF6DD7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal renewable electricity standard established by this section establishes a market-based policy to create ongoing competition among renewable electricity generators across the United States and provide the greatest quantity of clean electricity for the lowest price; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H671EE380A3534342B68EB0F96CFD7C15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States has vast wind, solar, hydropower, biomass, and geothermal resources that—</text> <subparagraph id="H91BC6D9B9432429DB2A4F724D2A2C03A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are renewable;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC668D1903982426FA68CD8F2B21FF39D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are dispersed widely across different regions of the United States; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC1DC2CBA8194322914EF700805B21E4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>can be harnessed to generate a significant share of electricity in the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8D3CD767A86243058416A32FEEF8321E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HC010F3351FD949A29EF2F45530E80426"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Brownfield site generation facility</header><text>The term <term>brownfield site generation facility</term> means a facility that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFBA3CBCCD6EB458A889B60A86615A2C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>generates renewable electricity; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FB7454F566943BEBF2D846AD95DDD41"><enum>(B)</enum><text>occupies a brownfield site (as that term is defined in section 101 of the <act-name parsable-cite="CERCL">Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FF35E7691AF47E6B48B3551FBB540F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distributed renewable generation facility</header><text>The term <term>distributed renewable generation facility</term> means a facility that—</text> <subparagraph id="H5598F953B7DC48FD903E7C84DB8BCE04"><enum>(A)</enum><text>generates renewable electricity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4566F6C586BA4104B6F0F347CF7236A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>primarily serves one or more electric consumers at or near the facility site; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96DB772DE4B14FBD936165017A1CA1D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has not more than 2 megawatts in capacity.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5BC13F38FE3490094F7B3C47238AF38"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal renewable electricity credit</header><text>The term <term>Federal renewable electricity credit</term> means a credit, representing 1 megawatt hour of renewable electricity, issued pursuant to subsection (f).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D83C46983E841F9AE691DE1FF41B6DD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Indian land</header><text>The term <term>Indian land</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HE5A7C17FC29443EA83A821EDC01E101D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any land within the limits of any Indian reservation, pueblo, or rancheria;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBBE2A08B9EE406383E9309EA4D0401D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any land not within the limits of any Indian reservation, pueblo, or rancheria, title to which was on the date of enactment of this section held by—</text>
 <clause id="H5433BD6F36954041ABD725EC9E22ED8F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the United States for the benefit of any Indian tribe or individual; or</text> </clause><clause id="H36D3EA73ADC449C3ADFB47C30F5E6B08"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any Indian tribe or individual subject to restriction by the United States against alienation;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5CA746C502A43A9ADF6BC3A6E44615A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any dependent Indian community; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AD400B3A60647ABBE014FC9203110FF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any land conveyed under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601</external-xref> et seq.) to any Native Corporation (as that term is defined in section 3 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1602">43 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D21811BC6CD4088B491E33A3EF8B2C4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian tribe</term> means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or community (including any Native village, Regional Corporation, or Village Corporation (as those terms are defined in section 3 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1602">43 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>))) that is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC543E1888C8049A1807B5A2287941186"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Qualified hydropower</header><text>The term <term>qualified hydropower</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H7E1FA13E22004E1CB884A6538F92588C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>energy produced from increased efficiency achieved, or additions of capacity made, on or after January 1, 2001, at a hydroelectric facility that—</text>
 <clause id="H646C05B1CEE544E9B7C86CD554FAF296"><enum>(i)</enum><text>was placed in service before that date; and</text> </clause><clause id="HAF2896B46A484270961EA0ECEE41546E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not include additional energy generated as a result of operational changes not directly associated with efficiency improvements or capacity additions; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD555ACBB3A6045D99D28B9085198804C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>energy produced from generating capacity added to a dam on or after January 1, 2001, if the Commission certifies that—</text>
 <clause id="H4978A762166541C48D1F940D14F74471"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the dam—</text> <subclause id="H43D0E934A82B4D54848472CC058732FB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>was placed in service before the date of enactment of this section;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H25822FD6121D490ABA65A7CE1F1AF9D4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>was operated for flood control, navigation, or water supply purposes; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HE9D3E15085EE48F280680EABB40E055C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>was not producing hydroelectric power prior to the addition of the capacity; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H03353406EFEE4F698813C360A951395A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the hydroelectric project installed on the dam—</text> <subclause id="H4B9E6AAF6FDC4D858A0B7BCBAC49CD58"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is licensed or is exempt from licensing by the Commission;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3206C97A91F742F59A4C8ED04AB7F6DE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is in compliance with—</text> <item id="H474AF85AB5A54B74905806EE557437FF"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the terms and conditions of the license or exemption; and</text>
 </item><item id="HF88FD133FAB34B2AAA2DF6242006AAF1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>other applicable legal requirements for the protection of environmental quality, including applicable fish passage requirements; and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="HA4F577FA7C8D4087A5875AB5DCB6706B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is operated so that the water surface elevation at any given location and time that would have occurred in the absence of the hydroelectric project is maintained, subject to any license or exemption requirements that require changes in water surface elevation for the purpose of improving the environmental quality of the affected waterway.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AE77FC12D694D069401049912392BFA"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Qualified renewable biomass</header><text>The term <term>qualified renewable biomass</term> means renewable biomass that, when combusted, yields, on a weighted-average basis, a 50-percent reduction in lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions (as defined in section 4(a) of the <short-title>American Renewable Energy and Efficiency Act</short-title>) per unit of useful energy, as compared to the operation of a combined cycle natural gas electric generating facility using the most efficient commercially available technology, when calculated over a 20-year life cycle.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD60EC143738B4F2BA8FCED4FC342BC52"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Renewable biomass</header><text>The term <term>renewable biomass</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H0C195805A1AE4729A3EE294956A5471E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>crop byproducts or crop residues harvested from actively managed or fallow agricultural land that is cleared prior to the date of enactment of this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC5AADA4BE624F9199F67177683BD43F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>planted trees, brush, slash, and residues from an actively managed tree farm dedicated to energy crop production and located on land cleared prior to the date of enactment of this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE75A2113996340F0B5788C743889B746"><enum>(C)</enum><text>byproducts of wood or paper mill operations, including lignin in spent pulping liquors;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CCD7EF1446E4BA1AEA68B1B912341DD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>algae;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C993D387A7A452CBCC3D6A1BA0A7010"><enum>(E)</enum><text>nonhazardous plant matter derived from waste—</text> <clause id="H6731E42C6F834F3CB2510193F9B7AE82"><enum>(i)</enum><text>including separated yard waste, landscape right-of-way trimmings, or food waste; but</text>
 </clause><clause id="H89DDB54F1CBD4FD29F45176A8D4D8388"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not including municipal solid waste, recyclable waste paper, painted, treated or pressurized wood, or wood contaminated with plastic or metals; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA035140C741647FE969E9FAE0C882393"><enum>(F)</enum><text>vegetative matter removed from within 200 yards of any man-made structure or campground for the purposes of hazardous fuels thinning.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H625520703819464380BC631E327339B4"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Renewable electricity</header><text>The term <term>renewable electricity</term> means electricity generated (including by means of a fuel cell) from a renewable energy resource.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF36D5ED95B1403AAB8BCC27F2D38A43"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Renewable energy resource</header><text>The term <term>renewable energy resource</term> means each of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2F731300DAC14D6B89236AEE1CD8798B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Wind energy.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC1407ECDE9B4D28B242CC095FEEC509"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Solar energy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB723601C0F7D4E64ABAC1960DFBC233B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Geothermal energy.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD88488DF34C4B0CA81F1056349EC292"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Qualified renewable biomass.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B39A99938294D4FB47B49CFBCF5F592"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Biogas derived from qualified renewable biomass.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E6F89E434314D5FBAC8B39C85EA775C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Biofuels derived from qualified renewable biomass.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09976A2F83B94ABABE6D6443B90F5BC6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Qualified hydropower.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDB00E4DAA26455889F91F0D5E40401C"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy (as defined in section 632 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17211">42 U.S.C. 17211</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB43F2FC19F1447BB2FBB7A1FE26FA8C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Landfill gas.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H63AA742D81B346A582B3EE130822D541"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Retail electric supplier</header> <subparagraph id="HCE86D51DB22941F0B37A7FD0D31DC5DD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>retail electric supplier</term> means, for any calendar year, an electric utility that sells not fewer than 1,000,000 megawatt hours of electric energy to electric consumers for purposes other than resale during the preceding calendar year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AE9B2D0A50149B798CCCEE80853E6FC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions and limitations</header><text>For purposes of determining whether an electric utility qualifies as a retail electric supplier under subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <clause id="HCFAFDB2E8453477AA71868EA6D8B4674"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the sales made by any affiliate of the electric utility to electric consumers, other than sales to lessees or tenants of the affiliate, for purposes other than resale shall be considered to be sales made by the electric utility; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA64342F06DF449FA90B97A7FAAE87288"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>sales made by the electric utility to an affiliate, lessee, or tenant of the electric utility shall not be treated as sales to electric consumers.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CE5B51E3C8245008606E435A6F63FC1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Affiliate</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>affiliate</term> when used in relation to a person, means another person that directly or indirectly owns or controls, is owned or controlled by, or is under common ownership or control with, that person, as determined under regulations promulgated by the Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA89A7087BA845CABBD1B4913E02EA71"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Retail electric supplier's base quantity</header><text>The term <term>retail electric supplier's base quantity</term> means the total quantity of electric energy sold by the retail electric supplier, expressed in megawatt hours, to electric customers for purposes other than resale during the relevant calendar year, excluding—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8A774312FF5640C1A623680588EFC474"><enum>(A)</enum><text>electricity generated by a hydroelectric facility, other than qualified hydropower; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B3E72DCDA3740599F710A6AD31DFF61"><enum>(B)</enum><text>electricity generated by the combustion of municipal solid waste.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H12830039E6E64B57ABE258B56B07863D"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Retire and retirement</header><text>The terms <term>retire</term> and <term>retirement</term> with respect to a Federal renewable electricity credit, mean to disqualify the credit for any subsequent use under this section, regardless of whether the use is a sale, transfer, exchange, or submission in satisfaction of a compliance obligation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H462CA5FFBDB741EBBDAF78BABFBEE6FD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual compliance obligation</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (g), for each of calendar years 2019 through 2042, not later than March 31 of the following calendar year, each retail electric supplier shall submit to the Commission a quantity of Federal renewable electricity credits that is equal to at least the annual target of the retail electric supplier under subsection (e).</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="HE4E76010E92B4922ABEC9477C0B65A77"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Establishment of program</header>
 <paragraph id="HFD09FB3D57CD42CDBDB03EE66A29C7F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Commission shall promulgate regulations to implement and enforce the requirements of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61A009850A5D4DDBAB1E1F5A2C2003F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In promulgating regulations under paragraph (1), the Commission shall, to the maximum extent practicable—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1FCDB73493584926A2E061AD820C0D56"><enum>(A)</enum><text>preserve the integrity and incorporate best practices of existing State and tribal renewable electricity programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E1E559B645A48B49B65CC5A0E6BAAAD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>rely on existing and emerging State, tribal, or regional tracking systems that issue and track non-Federal renewable electricity credits; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D53051C5A9C4DC5B52D0E3F4591F619"><enum>(C)</enum><text>cooperate with States and Indian tribes—</text> <clause id="H42D8AA1C60AA4B3BAF3573FB26F097A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to facilitate coordination between State, tribal, and Federal renewable electricity programs; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7F77F0FE9A4D474B9BB3F07C0C34CF3A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to minimize administrative burdens and costs to retail electric suppliers.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C564F1A36FE43D5899126179B939323"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual compliance requirement</header> <paragraph id="HB7514741C27346D19D0B43C4FC73901F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual targets</header><text>For each of calendar years 2019 through 2042, the annual target of a retail electric supplier shall be equal to the product obtained by multiplying—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCC27736EBFC6440C8D14EF91923C913E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the required annual percentage for that calendar year under paragraph (2); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC874A000C99742B280C49C3F9C007537"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the retail electric supplier’s base quantity for that calendar year.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H67B0C70B43DF40D7A23E217AAB40B3C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required annual percentage</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H3EBA066F2D6740AC800E79192815CF5A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Calendar years 2019 through 2042</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), for each of calendar years 2019 through 2042, the required annual percentage shall be as follows:<pagebreak></pagebreak></text>
								<table align-to-level="section" blank-lines-before="1" colsep="0" frame="none" line-rules="no-gen" rowsep="0" rule-weights="0.0.0.0.0.0" table-template-name="Flush/hang, 1 text, 1 num, bold hds" table-type="Leaderwork">
									<tgroup cols="2" rowsep="0"><colspec coldef="txt" colname="column1" colwidth="129pts" min-data-value="55"></colspec><colspec align="justify" coldef="fig" colname="column2" colwidth="142pts" min-data-value="5"></colspec><thead>
											<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" morerows="0" namest="column1" rowsep="0"></entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" morerows="0" namest="column2" rowsep="0"><bold>Required annual</bold></entry></row>
											<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" morerows="0" namest="column1" rowsep="0"><bold>Year:</bold></entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" morerows="0" namest="column2" rowsep="0"><bold>percentage:</bold></entry></row></thead>
										<tbody>
											<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">2019</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">10.0</entry></row>
											<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">2020</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">11.0</entry></row>
											<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">2021</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">12.0</entry></row>
											<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">2022</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">13.5</entry></row>
											<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">2023</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">15.0</entry></row>
											<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">2024</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">17.0</entry></row>
											<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">2025</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">19.0</entry></row>
											<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">2026</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">21.0</entry></row>
											<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">2027</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">23.0</entry></row>
											<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">2028</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">25.0</entry></row>
											<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">2029</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">27.5</entry></row>
											<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">2030</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">30.0</entry></row>
											<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">2031</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">32.5</entry></row>
											<row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">2032–2042</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">35.0.</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7C33BE38B06C42EFB7324E9F1EEEAC26"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Increase authorized for calendar years 2032 through 2042</header><text>The Commission may issue orders increasing the required annual percentage amounts for each of calendar years 2032 through 2042 to reflect the maximum achievable level of renewable electricity generation potential, taking into account regional resource availability, economic feasibility, and technological capability.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1BEEC66B0BE94FF3BBCC3EB727EE66AE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Federal renewable electricity credits</header>
						<paragraph id="H098CB33204194712A9D1D1BB9F2A5852"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <subparagraph id="H29CB98D610D543C79441E8E922DCA27B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Issuance; tracking; verification</header><text>The regulations promulgated under this section shall include provisions governing the issuance, tracking, and verification of Federal renewable electricity credits.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H320540216B54429580CDD5E0AF99E1DD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Credit ratio</header><text>Except as provided in paragraphs (2) through (4), the Commission shall issue to each generator of renewable electricity, 1 Federal renewable electricity credit for each megawatt hour of renewable electricity generated by the generator after December 31, 2018.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H943D9B02960642B38EB4EF52DC4A9362"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Serial number</header><text>The Commission shall assign a unique serial number to each Federal renewable electricity credit.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0581E76A31943FBB5D07CEF81B5E556"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Generation from certain State renewable electricity programs</header> <subparagraph id="H256F7A5A30D24A36AE42451ABFD740BB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If renewable electricity is generated with the support of payments from a retail electric supplier pursuant to a State renewable electricity program (whether through State alternative compliance payments or through payments to a State renewable electricity procurement fund or entity), the Commission shall issue Federal renewable electricity credits to the retail electric supplier for the portion of the relevant renewable electricity generation that is attributable to payments made by the retail electric supplier, as determined pursuant to regulations promulgated by the Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B56D88CACB44A88843FA7DDD88D36E5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Remaining portion</header><text>For any remaining portion of the relevant renewable electricity generation, the Commission shall issue Federal renewable electricity credits to the generator, as provided in paragraph (1), except that not more than 1 Federal renewable electricity credit shall be issued for the same megawatt hour of electricity.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56DC398204E0440E82183B206F6A5A78"><enum>(C)</enum><header>State guidance</header><text>In determining how Federal renewable electricity credits will be apportioned among retail electric suppliers and generators under this paragraph, the Commission shall consider information and guidance issued by the applicable one or more States.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AAC3853F2B4457F825C3EB058BB5E54"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Certain power sales contracts</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (2), if a generator has sold renewable electricity to a retail electric supplier under a contract for power from a facility placed in service before the date of enactment of this section, and the contract does not provide for the determination of ownership of the Federal renewable electricity credits associated with the generation, the Commission shall issue the Federal renewable electricity credits to the retail electric supplier for the duration of the contract.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H32EE16287503419CB88D78931E6C9458"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Credit multipliers</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE66FA5292B8C4B1181960B8EC704974A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Commission shall issue—</text> <clause id="H0C3A6D24DCF948ADBC55DDC0BCFE71E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not more than 3 Federal renewable electricity credits for each megawatt hour of renewable electricity generated by a distributed renewable generation facility;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB5648704C72B4EEE9F299C9DED515F9C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not more than 2 Federal renewable electricity credits for each megawatt hour of renewable electricity generated on Indian land; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2CD6332275D9421B9CF217065DD00AB5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>not more than 2 Federal renewable electricity credits for each megawatt hour of renewable electricity generated by a brownfield site generation facility.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA2FB3F7EEA0446E9A3883E484C4018D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Adjustment</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), not later than January 1, 2021, and not less frequently than every 4 years thereafter, the Commission shall review the effect of this paragraph on the aggregate quantity of renewable electricity produced under the standard and shall, as necessary and after providing 1 year of notice, reduce the number of Federal renewable electricity credits per megawatt hour issued under this paragraph for any given energy source or facility, but not below one, to ensure that the number is no higher than the Commission determines is necessary—</text>
 <clause id="H69AE2BC616224480A72BBF1C0CDBD962"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to incentivize incremental renewable energy generation on Indian land and brownfield sites; and</text> </clause><clause id="HA33C6CE78E2945C68A10BFC7AF1A11BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to make distributed renewable generation facilities cost competitive with other sources of renewable electricity generation.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BE1CB657BDA47978F185BF632AAE007"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Facilities placed in service after enactment</header>
 <clause id="H40E37AAB12F544B7977068048530AA7D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For any renewable generation facility placed in service after the date of enactment of this section, subparagraph (B) shall not apply for the first 10 years after the date on which the facility is placed in service.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9451BF31E03F4B3CB43DCDAEB4198299"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Initial period</header><text>For each year during the 10-year period described in clause (i), the Commission shall issue to the facility the same number of Federal renewable electricity credits per megawatt hour as are issued to that facility in the year in which the facility is placed in service.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCA52829DAA6F464D8CD385F701A793BF"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Subsequent period</header><text>After the 10-year period described in clause (i), the Commission shall issue Federal renewable electricity credits to the facility in accordance with subparagraph (B).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H97A24251AA714824AECFDD1B7E502465"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Credits based on qualified hydropower</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the number of Federal renewable electricity credits issued for qualified hydropower shall be calculated—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H659C170DEC974261998A5533F8B13851"><enum>(A)</enum><text>based solely on the increase in average annual generation directly resulting from the efficiency improvements or capacity additions described in subsection (b)(6)(A); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5690DC3CC8DD471391635FE5545E7E7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>using the same water flow information used to determine a historic average annual generation baseline for the hydroelectric facility, as certified by the Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9658BEB1D0BD4F46AAB65A5F26276BE1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Generation from mixed renewable and nonrenewable resources</header><text>If electricity is generated using both a renewable energy resource and an energy source that is not a renewable energy resource (such as cofiring of renewable biomass and fossil fuel), the Commission shall issue Federal renewable electricity credits based on the proportion of the electricity that is attributable to the renewable energy resource.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H76B65D806B7D44F099E45D68BEB8ED9E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Prohibition against double-counting</header><text>The Commission shall ensure that—</text> <subparagraph id="HF4DE26EF22D84861BEF0D3EAE262BA6B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no Federal renewable electricity credit is used more than once for compliance with this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19202610A2824BDDA13DFBBAD6F9FF79"><enum>(B)</enum><text>except as provided in paragraph (4), not more than 1 Federal renewable electricity credit is issued for any megawatt hour of renewable electricity.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA86F15C33B4E47EBBDFCF42BA1493BD4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Trading</header><text>The lawful holder of a Federal renewable electricity credit may—</text> <subparagraph id="HFC747365EE814FE9A98F7E949DF824CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sell, exchange, or transfer the credit;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F8A36558462455187A3023708EF25B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit the credit for compliance under subsection (c); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB7E1F5342764503ADBF09AB43920E7A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>submit the credit for retirement by the Commission.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D4A48480E0942C49F4D66388C467F63"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Banking</header>
 <subparagraph id="H08413B74F98C42B8A880C446457D5DB0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A Federal renewable electricity credit may be submitted in satisfaction of the compliance obligation under subsection (c) for the compliance year in which the credit was issued or for any of the 3 immediately subsequent compliance years.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB80EE094F2B84321B7BFC5DF78384A28"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Retirement</header><text>The Commission shall retire any Federal renewable electricity credit that has not been retired by April 2 of the calendar year that is 3 years after the calendar year during which the credit was issued.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H642A51A1C0AF4856AEE22335EB0FA86A"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Retirement</header><text>The Commission shall retire a Federal renewable electricity credit immediately upon submission by the lawful holder of the credit, whether in satisfaction of a compliance obligation under subsection (c) or for another reason.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C7BC13D8485414D8BFF4CD17CD188E8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Alternative compliance payments</header>
 <paragraph id="H8E81224647EF4752A41CCB00EDB4763B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A retail electric supplier may satisfy the requirements of subsection (c) in whole or in part by submitting in accordance with this subsection, in lieu of each Federal renewable electricity credit that would otherwise be due, a payment equal to $50, adjusted for inflation on January 1 of each year following calendar year 2019, in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Commission.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H279BEC31D8E6448D911267F95A9CF40A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment to State funds</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE08D081250A3467FB0DECE6D2DD8C1A3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, payments made under this subsection shall be made directly to one or more States in which the retail electric supplier sells electric energy, in proportion to the portion of the retail electric supplier's base quantity that is sold within each applicable State, if—</text>
 <clause id="H7C568D231521450DB36105514DE78BAA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the payments are deposited directly into a fund of the State treasury established for that purpose; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1429B5A555ED49E99D75381C42215E76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the State uses the funds in accordance with paragraphs (3) and (4).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86F0E54DCF64403EB13D397DB4DE0263"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Noncompliance</header><text>If the Commission determines that a State is in substantial noncompliance with paragraph (3) or (4), the Commission shall direct that any future alternative compliance payments that would otherwise be paid to the State under this subsection shall instead be paid to the Commission and deposited in the Treasury.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7D028FA3E4644AFB11094ECBF3A6458"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State use of funds</header><text>As a condition of receipt of alternative compliance payments under this subsection, a State shall use the payments exclusively for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1BAD0B623CCD451486B6665D43078A97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>deploying technologies that generate electricity from renewable energy resources; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF094CE9CE32346F8BE385FD237ED7807"><enum>(B)</enum><text>implementing cost-effective energy efficiency programs to achieve energy savings.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A16D448DA79401AB64F0BAFD773EAF8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reporting</header>
 <subparagraph id="H605C9113B48240FBAB90D047EE563E79"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As a condition of receipt of alternative compliance payments pursuant to this subsection, a State shall submit to the Commission an annual report, in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Commission, containing a full accounting of the use of the payments, including a detailed description of the activities funded by the payments and demonstrating compliance with the requirements of this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CF21648B334460BB409A18D942B6944"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>A State shall submit a report under this paragraph—</text> <clause id="H6C05DE0455704994B42A556AA27DC891"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date on which the first alternative compliance payment is received; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H727AE5B7A5514F8592E6EDA92C08E080"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>every 1 year thereafter until all alternative compliance payments are expended.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD51FEF241AD443DA841C4DB451562618"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Information collection</header> <paragraph id="H43D9621B4BC84D5DB066C1C18D2AEF8B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission may require any retail electric supplier, renewable electricity generator, or any other entity that the Commission determines appropriate, to provide any information the Commission determines appropriate to carry out this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E30C0DAEA484E8E866A20C6EDA39601"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Failure to submit; false or misleading information</header><text>Any entity required to submit information under paragraph (1) that fails to submit the information or submits false or misleading information shall be in violation of this section.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H29EBD39687AD4CB39DE5B41E046A5CA0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Enforcement and judicial review</header>
 <paragraph id="HD542015C071449A283DB5192BB3C1E85"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Failure to submit credits</header><text>If any person fails to comply with the requirements of subsection (c) or (g), the person shall be liable to pay to the Commission a civil penalty equal to the product obtained by multiplying—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7930F21CCE104D8783C294425932110E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>double the alternative compliance payment calculated under subsection (g)(1); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6935740793449F6988F99E92250721E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the aggregate quantity of Federal renewable electricity credits or equivalent alternative compliance payments that the person failed to submit in violation of the requirements of subsections (c) and (g).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8133215E26634BDA8108CEE98721C35A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The Commission shall assess a civil penalty under paragraph (1) in accordance with the procedures described in section 31(d) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/823b">16 U.S.C. 823b(d)</external-xref>).</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H0A490D5AFF284AE2A9EEEE5CD182ACB9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Violation of requirement of regulations or orders</header>
 <subparagraph id="H97B5932DBAC245018FAD991DB4538DFF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person who violates or fails or refuses to comply with any requirement of a regulation promulgated or order issued under this section shall be subject to a civil penalty under section 316A(b) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/825o-1">16 U.S.C. 825o–1(b)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65D7C88D295E427F8382DC0D04AA6C91"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>The penalty under subparagraph (A) shall be assessed by the Commission in the same manner as in the case of a violation referred to in section 316A(b) of that Act.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DDEF750D7C0455F9328C1A90F0D06DB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Judicial review</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB0FB482739624150A43A69AB6FFC6B64"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person aggrieved by a final action taken by the Commission under this section, other than the assessment of a civil penalty under paragraphs (1) through (3), may use the procedures for review described in section 313 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/825">16 U.S.C. 825</external-xref><italic>l</italic>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H368B4015AEFD491E8AFE796E5BCF3B6E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reference</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, references to an order in section 313 of that Act shall be considered to refer also to all other final actions of the Commission under this section other than the assessment of a civil penalty under paragraphs (1) through (3).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1528429B641F44A28F4A555B6EC009DC"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Nothing in this section—</text> <paragraph id="H4EFC48F7EA15469BAC11D7B658AC403A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>diminishes or qualifies any authority of a State, a political subdivision of a State, or an Indian tribe—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA754B9998E834DCBB1A6437B67F72D4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to adopt or enforce any law or regulation respecting renewable electricity, including any law or regulation establishing requirements that are more stringent than those established by this section, provided that no such law or regulation may relieve any person of any requirement otherwise applicable under this section; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50AADF86DE7A4696B4A868B511DB55D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to regulate the acquisition and disposition of Federal renewable electricity credits by retail electric suppliers within the jurisdiction of the State, political subdivision, or Indian tribe, including the authority to require the retail electric supplier to acquire and submit to the Commission for retirement Federal renewable electricity credits in excess of those submitted under this section; or</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DC9D339A4A742008D7CE553E98C34D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affects the application of or the responsibility for compliance with any other provision of law or regulation, including environmental and licensing requirements.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2705F359B17D487E9BB3D47EB7D4253A"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority provided by this section expires on December 31, 2043.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section id="HB96C2BDF5AC54851B8782BFA48F47E96"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clarifying State authority to adopt renewable energy incentives</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 210 of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824a-3">16 U.S.C. 824a–3</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4FCBBFAA3A34674AAD5EF0E5A752831" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H49456AD359D740B79C7A3CEF82A81E9D"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Clarification of State authority To adopt renewable energy incentives</header>
 <paragraph id="H866F470C1FB44658849327C93B62ECA4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition of State-approved production incentive program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>State-approved production incentive program</term> means a requirement imposed pursuant to State law or by a State regulatory authority acting within its authority under State law that an electric utility purchase renewable energy (as defined in section 609(a)) at a specified rate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E181144BF6B4DE6A29A3CD73F483542"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State authority to adopt renewable energy incentives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act or the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/791a">16 U.S.C. 791a</external-xref> et seq.), a State legislature or regulatory authority may set the rates for a sale of electric energy by a facility generating electric energy from renewable energy sources pursuant to a State-approved production incentive program under which the facility voluntarily participates in the State-approved production incentive program.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H942981DC71A645229F90E530DE9D020F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Guidelines for determining qualified renewable biomass</header>
 <subsection id="HD8AF9759546945FCBEF1E200BCF26537"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HBBA5CD8CA9F94EDC8FFDA9E01382C995"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H9D9DEBA6E99A474DA7627A1E39D039B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H245986CA65054B70847D94B2A4CBA789"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions</term> means the aggregate quantity of greenhouse gas emissions, adjusted to account for the relative global warming potential of the emissions relative to all greenhouse gas emissions.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBCD48F1A6D046F897E4F667FE1F0E6B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>greenhouse gas emissions</term> includes—</text> <clause id="HD7696A32E063483DA97452A125C64EA3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>direct emissions; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE89F0A970BE54C299ACE79779A18952D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>significant indirect emissions, including from—</text> <subclause id="HA8BE1F65BCE34A32A39C31AE6DB442F2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>land use changes and temporal changes in forest carbon sequestration;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H67245595788E4D0DBD2BA5E139F060B1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>biomass harvests, regrowth, and avoided decomposition related to the full fuel life cycle, including all stages of fuel and feedstock production and distribution; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H291BD127595B48FD879AA328ECA51D79"><enum>(III)</enum><text>feedstock generation or extraction through the distribution and delivery of the finished fuel to the ultimate consumer.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBCE03783172A44AB9D01515367A1BF80"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall, recognizing the recommendations of and coordinating with the Scientific Advisory Board of the Environmental Protection Agency regarding the accounting of biogenic carbon dioxide emissions and after notice and public comment, issue guidelines for calculating lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions for renewable biomass (as that term is defined in section 610(b) of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HC12002B56D434339B86DC76A0AB0504D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Energy efficiency resource standard for retail electricity and natural gas suppliers</header>
 <subsection id="H6FFB624FDE7E4603931B2116292E3754"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title VI of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2601">16 U.S.C. 2601</external-xref> et seq.) (as amended by section 2) is amended by adding after section 610 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCFC7232CB46D4253A6CAEC44916050C3" style="OLC">
					<section id="H347C4FDF1D9B48E296F4EB0E7ECA6780"><enum>611.</enum><header>Federal energy efficiency resource standard for retail electricity and natural gas suppliers</header>
 <subsection id="H941A1B080DDE4ED69F7BBB6790936546"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="H3F2DF86098AB4717A5C0739052363CBC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal energy efficiency resource standard established by this section—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H837E267010B14296969A446F3E3761EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishes nationwide minimum levels of electricity and natural gas savings to be achieved through utility efficiency programs, building energy codes, appliance standards, and related efficiency measures; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EFB277AF2054780AA1CB494EACDFD8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>rewards energy-saving improvements achieved through—</text> <clause id="H60D51BA9B44246E396B5A968DFD6140F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>end-use energy efficiency upgrades;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H672E24446AEB4D6AA5CC3F149B789B38"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reduced losses in transmission and distribution of energy; and</text> </clause><clause id="HECF655BAC06943069EF667462AAA05F0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>fuel-switching, to the extent that the switching results in reduced primary energy use; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C30D32D71954545986B9DC3965FA590"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in light of the cost-effective energy efficiency opportunities that exist across the United States in every sector of the economy, retail electricity suppliers, retail natural gas suppliers, and States should—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC6342EF6DA63448B9BE7E9797EE24109"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider energy efficiency as a resource in utility planning and procurement activities; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H065B4D040DB84F2CBB84756F5F358226"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seek to achieve all energy efficiency that is available at lower cost than other energy supply options.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D34C2F73CC543318514199723B5F265"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HBE9249D3347649A5BFB9CBB63DD19DF9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affiliate</header><text>The term <term>affiliate</term> when used in relation to a person, means another person that owns or controls, is owned or controlled by, or is under common ownership control with, that person, as determined under regulations promulgated by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC072E5A36214580973984C878A795AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ASHRAE, ansi, and iesna</header><text>The terms <term>ASHRAE</term>, <term>ANSI</term>, and <term>IESNA</term> mean the American Society of Heating, Refrigerating and Air-Conditioning Engineers, the American National Standards Institute, and the Illuminating Engineering Society of North America, respectively.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H7789EE92F7604F1E86B1848636BE2BAB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Base quantity</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF6FF7CA3C6574176BFE71A762D74C958"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>base quantity</term>, with respect to a retail electricity supplier or retail natural gas supplier, means, for each calendar year for which a performance standard is established under subsection (d), the average annual quantity of electricity or natural gas delivered by the retail electricity supplier or retail natural gas supplier to retail customers during the 3 calendar years immediately preceding the year that compliance is required under subsection (d)(1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB50D11B0EF014CC8A098C2CCE9FC8C70"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>base quantity</term>, with respect to a retail natural gas supplier, does not include natural gas delivered for purposes of electricity generation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB74A5FC1E0E746D882CEDCEEF92D7845"><enum>(4)</enum><header>CHP savings</header><text>The term <term>CHP savings</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HE6CE862F9CD34D279F51988E0FE0F15F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>CHP system savings from a combined heat and power system that commences operation after the date of enactment of this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7627983601A24D618171EF1688F034B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the increase in CHP system savings from upgrading or replacing, after the date of enactment of this section, a combined heat and power system that commenced operation on or before the date of enactment of this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEF30CB420234979926694DA65EB9B1C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>CHP system savings</header><text>The term <term>CHP system savings</term> means the electric output, and the electricity saved due to the mechanical output, of a combined heat and power system, adjusted to reflect any increase in fuel consumption by that system as compared to the fuel that would have been required to produce an equivalent useful thermal energy output in a separate thermal-only system, as determined in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HEF3EF9F119A34B2A99D8A3920256A8C8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Codes and standards savings</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB51FF110ABC6468DB34B0F3ECC465E85"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>codes and standards savings</term> means a reduction in end-use electricity or natural gas consumption by a retail electricity supplier or in the service territory of a retail natural gas supplier as a result of the adoption and implementation, after the date of enactment of this section, of new or revised appliance and equipment efficiency standards or building energy codes.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA681B32BA6C34D27898B13886B744584"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Baselines</header><text>In calculating codes and standards savings under subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="HC716E5475C944AFCA51EB0353DAE536F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the baseline for calculating savings from building codes shall be the more stringent of—</text>
										<subclause id="HAE45BB30043D4ADAB976EA9611D9154A"><enum>(I)</enum>
 <item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H35BE4C400BF84BE8A78B0BD5E82542D0"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the 2015 International Energy Conservation Code for residential buildings; or</text> </item><item id="HCD64461EA0F94D6D9BF00A89E01E1D34" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the ASHRAE/ANSI/IESNA Standard 90.1–2013 for commercial buildings; or</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H5B9AB44359744975821E8DC7E61A6A2B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the applicable State building code in effect on the date of enactment of this section; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H7007B5DA587246319A63487F71D4EE2A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the baseline for calculating savings from appliance standards shall be the average efficiency of new appliances in the applicable one or more categories prior to the adoption and implementation of the new standard.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1BB539320D6442F8510706DEFDEFB9F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Combined heat and power system</header><text>The term <term>combined heat and power system</term> means a system that uses the same energy source both for the generation of electrical or mechanical power and the production of steam or another form of useful thermal energy, if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8F37AE98C6744CD481ABA4F51EA25069"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the system meets any requirements relating to efficiency and other operating characteristics that the Secretary promulgates by regulation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD22510D7C3542E7AA45DDCD0D4F342C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the net wholesale sales of electricity by a facility does not exceed 50 percent of total annual electric generation by the facility.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0D89B804CCA548F0A6FF077731A55D7F"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Cost-effective</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cost-effective</term>, with respect to an energy efficiency measure, means that the measure achieves a net present value of economic benefits over the life of the measure, both directly to the energy consumer and to the economy, that is greater than the net present value of the cost of the measure over the life of the measure, both directly to the energy consumer and to the economy, using the societal benefit-cost test calculated using the lower of a utility weighted average cost of capital or a social discount rate of 3 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0495B07EDF04E06ABD8413318E1B81C"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Customer facility savings</header><text>The term <term>customer facility savings</term> means a reduction in end-use electricity or natural gas consumption (including waste heat energy savings) at a facility of an end-use consumer of electricity or natural gas served by a retail electricity supplier or natural gas supplier, as compared to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0A367093521E4C619952F3A6EBF5EEEB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a new facility, consumption at a reference facility of average efficiency;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E9ECB4288F14BD989D93CE639104764"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an existing facility, consumption at the facility during a base period of not less than 1 year;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CBA44DC69EF4A3298877BC561B20DB5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of new equipment that replaces existing equipment at the end of the useful life of the existing equipment, consumption by new equipment of average efficiency of the same equipment type, except that customer savings under this subparagraph shall not be counted towards customer savings under subparagraph (A) or (B); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8ABAB6D2AFD94883BD7EBC76944E005A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the case of new equipment that replaces existing equipment with remaining useful life—</text> <clause id="H8FAE63BBE1D54C7E9F75AB945A41B972"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consumption of the existing equipment for the remaining useful life of the equipment; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6028C856DFA643AEB92F6FA94E98B8A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>thereafter, consumption of new equipment of average efficiency.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H819B20405F934CC9B4C1B604769CBD94"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Electricity savings</header><text>The term <term>electricity savings</term> means reductions in electricity consumption achieved through measures implemented after the date of enactment of this section, as determined in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary, that are limited to—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H29F0FB08006A4A358F083F806FB76600"><enum>(A)</enum><text>customer facility savings of electricity, adjusted to reflect any associated increase in fuel consumption at the facility;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1D21449A10BF47D18B7F3A7C18C2DD27"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reductions in distribution system losses of electricity achieved by a retail electricity supplier, as compared to losses attributable to new or replacement distribution system equipment of average efficiency, as defined in regulations promulgated by the Secretary;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H44D5DE01B9BD4A0FB408BDF8F0D8D2C1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>CHP savings;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5B7FD27A8EC24A90A4CBF4179B3BFB81"><enum>(D)</enum><text>codes and standards savings of electricity; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD3516574561545A58F3B5F22172D6A89"><enum>(E)</enum><text>fuel switching energy savings that results in net savings of electricity.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H58843F9F01D14A78BA4F6D9890A857EE"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Fuel switching energy savings</header> <subparagraph id="HD32A4C08C31F4B7BBB7051AAF6D75B1B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>fuel-switching energy savings</term> means net energy savings, calculated in accordance with subparagraph (B), from end-user switches from 1 energy source to another, as determined in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC96979F5EF9F47859B0ABE3DD081BBB4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Calculation</header><text>For purposes of calculating fuel-switching net energy savings—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HC9275EA2D0D146A5A8B5FE12D6123D95"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">electricity use shall be evaluated based on the average quantity of fuel burned at a new power plant taking into account existing and planned renewable energy generators to provide each kilowatt hour of electricity;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3B4A88B162064E3A9185AAA88D68D5D6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>electricity and natural gas use shall include losses in the transmission and distribution system; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H75EC2F55BE6243C0BE6BE29EE3942F75"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>fuel-switching that is not cost-effective to the end-user shall not be counted.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H03AE8EA7B31A447EB13EE680C59FFBCF"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Natural gas savings</header><text>The term <term>natural gas savings</term> means reductions in natural gas consumption from measures implemented after the date of enactment of this section, as determined in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary, that are limited to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDEDE5F7B03594B64BB3B5EF494B88580"><enum>(A)</enum><text>customer facility savings of natural gas, adjusted to reflect any associated increase in electricity consumption or consumption of other fuels at the facility;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEE4EDEB90BAC404CBE715723DAFB7F18"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reductions in leakage, operational losses, and consumption of natural gas fuel to operate a gas distribution system, achieved by a retail natural gas supplier, as compared to similar leakage, losses, and consumption during a base period of not less than 1 year;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC1C1AE3DB2542768D7ABB591C329709"><enum>(C)</enum><text>codes and standards savings of natural gas; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2455D3D68B643C7BB4BC77B4EDCDAC3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>fuel switching energy savings that results in net savings of natural gas.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H026333011661404BA35F0DE97E4EF839"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Power pool</header><text>The term <term>power pool</term> means an association of two or more interconnected electric systems that have entered into an agreement to coordinate operations and planning for improved reliability and efficiencies, including a Regional Transmission Organization or an Independent System Operator, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H353AE17FDFB748FDB9EABCB2B84D9151"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Reporting period</header><text>The term <term>reporting period</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HF6428CCF3BE74EB09AA5E84E03FC7C9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>calendar year 2019; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3BAA9B8D5304370892E4B62D8D29B63"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each successive 2-calendar-year period thereafter.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85EBC7B5A185466F89B775E2D2B01190"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Retail electricity supplier</header> <subparagraph id="HA4A09488F9F74444A8AD279338A010C6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>retail electricity supplier</term> means, for any given calendar year, an electric utility that sells not less than 1,000,000 megawatt hours of electric energy to electric consumers for purposes other than resale during the preceding calendar year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4B7B9D104AF4F3DABE6FB30F1E62985"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions and limitations</header><text>For purposes of determining whether an electric utility qualifies as a retail electricity supplier under subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <clause id="HEEA5608AE966452C94BE45736B3C4BF0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>deliveries by any affiliate of an electric utility to electric consumers for purposes other than resale shall be considered to be deliveries by the electric utility; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H076D7F5A69BB4BCF9416838898A8A782"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>deliveries by any electric utility to a lessee, tenant, or affiliate of the electric utility shall not be considered to be deliveries to electric consumers.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H39FFDFC8B2DC43A6AFA65F474D3CBA7B"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Retail natural gas supplier</header>
 <subparagraph id="H51627F6B1C12461C90DD340CFABA4CC9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>retail natural gas supplier</term> means, for any given calendar year, a local distribution company (as defined in section 2 of the Natural Gas Policy Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3301">15 U.S.C. 3301</external-xref>)), that delivered to natural gas consumers more than 5,000,000,000 cubic feet of natural gas for purposes other than resale during the preceding calendar year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72F9F122329449E697B16829121F34CF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions and limitations</header><text>For purposes of determining whether a person qualifies as a retail natural gas supplier under subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <clause id="HA2AD4CE1F4E64DE58A57D1EF12485467"><enum>(i)</enum><text>deliveries of natural gas by any affiliate of a local distribution company to consumers for purposes other than resale shall be considered to be deliveries by the local distribution company; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD2EB464095F745F28ACC286C1A6DA059"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>deliveries of natural gas to a lessee, tenant, or affiliate of a local distribution company shall not be considered to be deliveries to natural gas consumers.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA71733DB8EE141D4B9E48F425A475BCD"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Third-party efficiency provider</header><text>The term <term>third-party efficiency provider</term> means any retailer, building owner, energy service company, financial institution, or other commercial, industrial, or nonprofit entity that is capable of providing electricity savings or natural gas savings in accordance with subsections (e) and (f).</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H08A325450B074095B95C538495346182"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Waste heat energy savings</header>
 <subparagraph id="H62C03F26F0E7475A8FF728C7A5DF3C44"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>waste heat energy savings</term> means a reduction in electricity or natural gas consumption that results from a modification of an industrial or commercial system that commenced operation before the date of enactment of this section, in order to recapture electrical, mechanical, or thermal energy that would otherwise be wasted, as determined in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H395EC8FC91A24983908DC0BD8CB0EF1F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>Such savings shall be included as part of customer facility savings.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F49B1F8BCDC43D581E3B44D0A9A1FDB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Establishment of program</header> <paragraph id="H4CAB54A0DC2442B8A1DAF21E3188B526"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall, by regulation, establish a program to implement and enforce the requirements of this section, including by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1311EEF40FEA4F8AAEA5F14A75D4D0EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishing measurement and verification procedures and standards under subsection (f);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF205E7D269834F02B4125FD71C7B2DA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing requirements under which retail electricity suppliers and retail natural gas suppliers shall—</text>
 <clause id="H4D80E10248644571B5870409DD401A42"><enum>(i)</enum><text>demonstrate, document, and report the compliance of the retail electricity suppliers and retail natural gas suppliers with the performance standards under subsection (d); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H48EE66C9CADB44299E1C4C92376F9DF2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>estimate the impact of the standards on current and future electricity and natural gas use in the service territories of the suppliers; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C09C61EB8C3432EB7474F3BB23D3101"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establishing requirements governing applications for, and implementation of, delegated State administration under subsection (h).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3D6524468A14391B616218A6D0472E6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination with State programs</header><text>In establishing and implementing this section, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, preserve the integrity and incorporate best practices of existing State energy efficiency programs.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF13393E1B83B4412B52929BEC53CAEBA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Performance standards</header>
 <paragraph id="H8A984F78E46F4E0697ED9C69CC3B107E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compliance obligation</header><text>Not later than May 1 of the calendar year immediately following each reporting period—</text> <subparagraph id="H753629E674174BAF9248A2F44757B816"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each retail electricity supplier shall submit to the Secretary a report, in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary, demonstrating that the retail electricity supplier has achieved cumulative electricity savings (adjusted to account for any attrition of savings measures implemented in prior years) in each calendar year that are equal to the applicable percentage, established under paragraph (2), (3), or (4), of the base quantity of the retail electricity supplier; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58ADF31C662F4B56A7F9FA90C76DC5C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each retail natural gas supplier shall submit to the Secretary a report, in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary, demonstrating that it has achieved cumulative natural gas savings (adjusted to account for any attrition of savings measures implemented in prior years) in each calendar year that are equal to the applicable percentage, established under paragraph (2), (3), or (4), of the base quantity of such retail natural gas supplier.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB691F5ACE39A4F42BE56FE16E33D7215"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Standards for 2019 through 2032</header><text>For each of calendar years 2019 through 2032, the applicable percentages are as follows:</text> <table align-to-level="section" blank-lines-before="1" colsep="0" frame="all" line-rules="hor-sides" rowsep="1" rule-weights="4.4.4.4.0.0" table-template-name="Generic: 3 text, even cols" table-type=""> <tgroup cols="3" grid-typeface="1.1" rowsep="1" thead-tbody-ldg-size="10.10.10"><colspec align="center" coldef="fig" colname="column1" colwidth="95pts" min-data-value="17"></colspec><colspec align="center" coldef="fig" colname="column2" colwidth="95pts" min-data-value="17"></colspec><colspec align="center" coldef="fig" colname="column3" colwidth="95pts" min-data-value="17"></colspec><thead> <row><entry align="center" colname="column1" morerows="0" namest="column1">Calendar Year</entry><entry align="center" colname="column2" morerows="0" namest="column2">Cumulative Electricity<linebreak></linebreak> Savings Percentage</entry><entry align="center" colname="column3" morerows="0" namest="column3">Cumulative Natural Gas<linebreak></linebreak> Savings Percentage</entry></row></thead> <tbody> <row><entry align="center" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">2019</entry><entry align="center" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr">1.00</entry><entry align="center" colname="column3" leader-modify="clr-ldr">0.50</entry></row> <row><entry align="center" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">2020</entry><entry align="center" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr"> 2.00</entry><entry align="center" colname="column3" leader-modify="clr-ldr"> 1.25</entry></row> <row><entry align="center" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">2021</entry><entry align="center" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr"> 3.00</entry><entry align="center" colname="column3" leader-modify="clr-ldr"> 2.00</entry></row> <row><entry align="center" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">2022</entry><entry align="center" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr"> 4.25</entry><entry align="center" colname="column3" leader-modify="clr-ldr"> 3.00</entry></row> <row><entry align="center" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">2023</entry><entry align="center" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr"> 5.50</entry><entry align="center" colname="column3" leader-modify="clr-ldr"> 4.00</entry></row> <row><entry align="center" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">2024</entry><entry align="center" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr"> 7.00</entry><entry align="center" colname="column3" leader-modify="clr-ldr"> 5.00</entry></row> <row><entry align="center" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">2025</entry><entry align="center" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr"> 8.50</entry><entry align="center" colname="column3" leader-modify="clr-ldr"> 6.00</entry></row> <row><entry align="center" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">2026</entry><entry align="center" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr"> 10.00</entry><entry align="center" colname="column3" leader-modify="clr-ldr"> 7.00</entry></row> <row><entry align="center" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">2027</entry><entry align="center" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr"> 11.50</entry><entry align="center" colname="column3" leader-modify="clr-ldr"> 8.00</entry></row> <row><entry align="center" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">2028</entry><entry align="center" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr"> 13.00</entry><entry align="center" colname="column3" leader-modify="clr-ldr"> 9.00</entry></row> <row><entry align="center" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">2029</entry><entry align="center" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="trace"> 14.75</entry><entry align="center" colname="column3" leader-modify="clr-ldr">10.00</entry></row> <row><entry align="center" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">2030</entry><entry align="center" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="trace">16.50</entry><entry align="center" colname="column3" leader-modify="clr-ldr">11.00</entry></row> <row><entry align="center" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">2031</entry><entry align="center" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="trace">18.25</entry><entry align="center" colname="column3" leader-modify="clr-ldr">12.00</entry></row> <row><entry align="center" colname="column1" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1">2032</entry><entry align="center" colname="column2" leader-modify="clr-ldr" stub-definition="trace">20.00</entry><entry align="center" colname="column3" leader-modify="clr-ldr">13.00</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table> </paragraph><paragraph id="H99B686B05DE34722BBC58F20A5512B42"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subsequent years</header> <subparagraph id="H44F48E09FC15489BA1232747E66A8C0A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Calendar years 2033 through 2042</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2030, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations establishing performance standards (expressed as applicable percentages of base quantity for both cumulative electricity savings and cumulative natural gas savings) for each of calendar years 2033 through 2042.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABEED0B2BDF8459097B6FAF840B34FBA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subsequent extensions</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (A), not later than December 31 of the penultimate reporting period for which performance standards have been established under this paragraph, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations establishing performance standards (expressed as applicable percentages of base quantity for both cumulative electricity savings and cumulative natural gas savings) for the 10-calendar-year period following the last calendar year for which performance standards previously were established.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5D50584D4FC44EC9C6798F795D37604"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Secretary shall establish standards under this paragraph at levels reflecting the maximum achievable level of cost-effective energy efficiency potential, taking into account—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HFECC09AE03C041BF832954A7CEA35C63"><enum>(i)</enum><text>cost-effective energy savings achieved by leading retail electricity suppliers and retail natural gas suppliers;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H51804624164545E1A7CDD0655310C481"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>opportunities for new codes and standards savings;</text> </clause><clause id="HCD078C5122F4400484149F0FC45F4B12"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>technology improvements; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9303099440594B7CA7AB961CEE61E4F9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other indicators of cost-effective energy efficiency potential.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25F17D5AC95A4B37B0323F06C6AD8C73"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Minimum percentage</header><text>In no case shall the applicable percentages for any calendar year be less than the applicable percentages for calendar year 2032 (including any increase in the standard for calendar year 2032 established pursuant to paragraph (4)).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FAE2AA076594864B67931D2E32C1137"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Midcourse review and adjustment of standards</header>
 <subparagraph id="H731EF1CA56BD41C6A3D2858ED49EC56E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2025, and at 10-year intervals thereafter, the Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="H3240B08C42794CCF81A80D0323040731"><enum>(i)</enum><text>review the most recent standards established under paragraph (2) or (3); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEC124C528D254748AD08A3FE67A0C924"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>increase the standards by regulation if the Secretary determines that additional cost-effective energy efficiency potential is achievable, taking into account the requirements described in paragraph (3)(C).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA05E50EDD3E454E906E1C8B289B0C4A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Lead time</header><text>If the Secretary revises standards under this paragraph, the regulations shall provide adequate lead time to ensure that compliance with the increased standards is feasible.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H55A2ED3D35D14B65A3D4AE1C1FBD275D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Delay of submission for first reporting period</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD0298329D07C4497A32C3D83A82555F4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2), for the 2019 reporting period, the Secretary may accept a request from a retail electricity supplier or a retail natural gas supplier to delay the required submission of documentation of all or part of the required savings for up to 2 years.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7DB4F73EEC346B8A704DFA04601AF61"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Plan for compliance</header><text>The request for delay under subparagraph (A) shall include a plan for coming into full compliance by the end of the 2020–2021 reporting period.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6DB7E03B6524596AB207E866EB76B17"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Applying unused savings to future years</header><text>If savings achieved in a year exceed the performance standards specified in this subsection, any savings in excess of the performance standards may be applied toward performance standards specified for future years.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H369A0A7681DB41E7939425628D66EEBD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Transfers of electricity or natural gas savings</header>
 <paragraph id="H58B8F17C9119457CAD5F42A457A11FA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bilateral contracts for savings transfers</header><text>Subject to the limitations of this subsection, a retail electricity supplier or retail natural gas supplier may use electricity savings or natural gas savings purchased pursuant to a bilateral contract from another retail electricity supplier or retail natural gas supplier, a State, or a third-party efficiency provider to meet the applicable performance standard under subsection (d).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB91AF48E8539464EBE0FCA795C348252"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Electricity savings or natural gas savings purchased and used for compliance under this subsection shall be—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD244E67A988340BA87B4AC43454DC8AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>measured and verified in accordance with subsection (f);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11E248928DCA4B178B2191583750EF3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reported in accordance with subsection (d); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H131098A8EA424311B3B90C26B64A9B0A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>achieved within the same State as is served by the retail electricity supplier or retail natural gas supplier.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H81B1BDBBEB3F4621B12AAAE000E43AD9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (2)(C), a State regulatory authority may authorize a retail electricity supplier or a retail natural gas supplier regulated by the State regulatory authority to purchase savings achieved in a different State, if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H635DF7874E2D4713B66D53BCDEC1A239"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the savings are achieved within the same power pool; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B5BB21AC87540D9B3F9CDBC11974329"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the State regulatory authority that regulates the purchaser oversees the measurement and verification of the savings pursuant to the procedures and standards applicable in the State in which the purchaser is located.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H74D021D37BDA4E829C4CE6169FDF2878"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regulatory approval</header><text>Nothing in this subsection limits or affects the authority of a State regulatory authority to require a retail electricity supplier or retail natural gas supplier that is regulated by the State regulatory authority to obtain the authorization or approval of the State regulatory authority of a contract for transfer of electricity savings or natural gas savings under this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H389A5B1CE47C4DBDAABEE94F11198F80"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>To optimize the achievement of cost-effective efficiency potential, the Secretary may prescribe such limitations as the Secretary determines appropriate with respect to the proportion of the compliance obligation of a retail electricity or natural gas supplier under the applicable performance standards under subsection (d) that may be met using electricity savings or natural gas savings that are purchased under this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8FF785F818D24CBBB2856702F2C8B874"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Measurement and verification of savings</header><text>The regulations promulgated pursuant to subsection (c) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H2361DA08C78246BF89AD91DBCCF7DC47"><enum>(1)</enum><text>procedures and standards for defining and measuring electricity savings and natural gas savings that can be counted towards the performance standards established under subsection (d), that shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEB4B55101C5F48CE984AE88FA2F3D059"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specify the types of energy efficiency and energy conservation measures that can be counted;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3ACCC961CA5840FC90AF8896C446D76A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require that energy consumption estimates for customer facilities or portions of facilities in the applicable base and current years be adjusted, as appropriate, to account for changes in weather, level of production, and building area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25D3A2BFD37B4E92B177F71F2D596725"><enum>(C)</enum><text>account for the useful life of measures;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE688CE88B99946838C3C966FEB6D3B3C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>include assigned savings values for specific, commonly used measures;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF98DDB003B3B4C9C8CD92121F85943E8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>allow for savings from a program to be estimated based on extrapolation from a representative sample of participating customers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF2ED2D90D764C339062F7F19E5E8EFD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>include procedures for calculating and documenting CHP savings, fuel-switching energy savings, and waste heat energy savings;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H459CAC129C444781B988C5FCB869D3E1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>establish methods for calculating codes and standards energy savings, including the use of verified compliance rates;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BD7DB8BE9BF4C9EBF9E07584797A3A6"><enum>(H)</enum><text>include procedures for calculating and documenting—</text> <clause id="HB2111059B05B4532877BA89C06B4E517"><enum>(i)</enum><text>customer facility savings and reductions in distribution system losses of electricity and natural gas that are achieved as a result of smart grid deployment, as described in section 1301 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17381">42 U.S.C. 17381</external-xref>); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0DA39F75A266404A94D71CD11EBD936A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reductions in natural gas distribution system losses attributable to pipeline repair and replacement programs;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA683D0FD2D594BF2A6AB479C1EE3FD45"><enum>(I)</enum><text>count only measures and savings that are additional to business-as-usual customer purchase practices;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49D81C4092734BDC8E13AAED82327A3E"><enum>(J)</enum><text>ensure that the retail electricity supplier or retail natural gas supplier claiming the electricity savings or natural gas savings, including codes and standards savings, played a significant role in achieving the savings (including through the activities of a designated agent of the supplier or through the purchase of transferred electricity savings or natural gas savings);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F0FAFA945244C5F94977CD260DEDEF2"><enum>(K)</enum><text>avoid double-counting of savings used for compliance with this section, including transferred savings;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DA3EDB973184B879E7CE5595BF7EB09"><enum>(L)</enum><text>include electricity savings or natural gas savings from programs administered by the retail electric supplier or natural gas supplier that are funded by Federal, State, or other sources;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB3AB6D1D5AE44C8B8AE9F5D1700755E"><enum>(M)</enum><text>credit large customer self-directed electricity savings or natural gas savings to the retail electricity supplier or the retail natural gas supplier if the large customers receive incentives or rate reductions from the retail supplier for self-directed energy efficiency improvements;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B6E4043C5A74F0DB6B5199A0342AC1E"><enum>(N)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include procedures for counting electricity savings and natural gas savings achieved by solar heating and cooling technologies, solar light pipe technology, geothermal heat pumps, and other technologies utilizing renewable resources that do not produce electricity or gaseous fuel but that reduce on-site energy use;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45ED80ECC2D240C0AE2137C222AC787A"><enum>(O)</enum><text>in any State in which the State regulatory authority has designated one or more entities to administer electric ratepayer-funded efficiency programs approved by the State regulatory authority, provide that electricity savings and natural gas savings achieved through the programs shall be distributed proportionally among retail electric suppliers and retail natural gas suppliers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF48D4685F8374CC890F3FB77918F2D04"><enum>(P)</enum><text>include guidance for utilities to calculate and document business-as-usual consumption projections; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E54FEED4694465693F3BC622888E451"><enum>(2)</enum><text>procedures and standards for third-party verification of reported electricity savings or natural gas savings.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0D14CB188BFC4D40BF1A711E2383899A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Enforcement and judicial review</header>
							<paragraph id="H03E4B697BC2B4B1FB8BACC2B2542BCCF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Review of retail supplier reports</header>
 <subparagraph id="H86F3FA0384FD4066A5B0DBE98AF70D64"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall review each report submitted to the Secretary by a retail electricity supplier or retail natural gas supplier under subsection (d) to verify that the applicable performance standards under subsection (d) have been met.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13BD58BB462841F48D2F3072888356BD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>In determining compliance with the applicable performance standards under subsection (d), the Secretary shall exclude reported electricity savings or natural gas savings that are not adequately demonstrated and documented, in accordance with the regulations promulgated under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2911947CBD95417B8C23E8859E8E92BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty for failure to document adequate savings</header><text>If a retail electricity supplier or a retail natural gas supplier fails to demonstrate compliance with an applicable performance standard under subsection (d), or to pay to the State an applicable alternative compliance payment under subsection (h)(4), the Secretary shall assess against the retail electricity supplier or retail natural gas supplier a civil penalty for each failure in an amount equal to, as adjusted for inflation in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may promulgate—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8BB653E85F8B46D2BD9D979567A6737F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$100 per megawatt hour of electricity savings or alternative compliance payment that the retail electricity supplier failed to achieve or make, respectively; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF255BE098C9B4ADC99EB0BE7AC1148D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$10 per million Btu of natural gas savings or alternative compliance payment that the retail natural gas supplier failed to achieve or make, respectively.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B1FB2BFF60143CCB1BDDC9244FF7AF8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Offsetting State penalties</header><text>The Secretary shall reduce the amount of any penalty under paragraph (2) by the amount paid by the relevant retail electricity supplier or retail natural gas supplier to a State for failure to comply with the requirements of a State energy efficiency resource standard during the same compliance period, if the State standard—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H66D159C1D573416FA42670FB9171D9A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is comparable in type to the Federal standard established under this section; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6DCAD18A066474D913B74016D789F13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is more stringent than the applicable performance standards under subsection (d).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H60CB3F3B94EC458997696465285C8A1F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Enforcement procedures</header><text>The Secretary shall assess a civil penalty, as provided under paragraph (2), in accordance with the procedures described in section 333(d) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6303">42 U.S.C. 6303(d)</external-xref>).</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H704C0FCDFCCF4737A2F15DE1946BF93C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Judicial review</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD598A1D35FF743D59637BDE1DD4DE358"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person adversely affected by a final action taken by the Secretary under this section, other than the assessment of a civil penalty, may use the procedures for review described in section 336(b) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6306">42 U.S.C. 6306(b)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3704F5882DF44C33BA4A552C28169E03"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reference</header><text>In this paragraph, references to a rule in section 336(b) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6306">42 U.S.C. 6306(b)</external-xref>) shall be considered to refer also to all other final actions of the Secretary under this section other than the assessment of a civil penalty.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEBC30FCFDC02405289D23A5200608BAC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>State administration</header>
 <paragraph id="H8300FDD21A0640E294A8507BA45CE5A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon receipt of an application from the Governor of a State (including the Mayor of the District of Columbia), the Secretary may delegate to the State responsibility for administering this section within the territory of the State if the Secretary determines that the State will implement an energy efficiency program that meets or exceeds the requirements of this section, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBE142D66CB1C44B7B0916BCFAA31C9BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>achieving electricity savings and natural gas savings that are at least as great as those required under the applicable performance standards established under subsection (d);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0A06B8113A04B72A8646867BCBCA8BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reviewing reports and verifying electricity savings and natural gas savings achieved in the State (including savings transferred from outside the State); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE725073CC4F4BBF909B6581618B42BF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>collecting any alternative compliance payments under paragraph (4) and using the payments to implement cost-effective efficiency programs.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CB2304949504933B491226495E59B45"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretarial determination</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which a complete application is received by the Secretary, the Secretary shall make a substantive determination approving or disapproving a State application, after public notice and comment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H81997DE84E5F43E3A801A6337139116C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Alternative measurement and verification procedures and standards</header><text>As part of an application submitted under paragraph (1), a State may request to use alternative measurement and verification procedures and standards from the procedures and standards described in subsection (f), if the State demonstrates that the alternative procedures and standards provide a level of accuracy of measurement and verification that are at least equivalent to the Federal procedures and standards under subsection (f).</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H5CC4A943EBC64E97B53C6F0E95C2661B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Alternative compliance payments</header>
 <subparagraph id="H34CE1E76AABF49A8ABAB691F57C8FD4F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As part of an application submitted under paragraph (1), a State may permit retail electricity suppliers or retail natural gas suppliers to pay to the State, by not later than May 1 of the calendar year immediately following the applicable reporting period, an alternative compliance payment in an amount equal to, as adjusted for inflation in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may promulgate, not less than—</text>
 <clause id="H4BFEE4A275B74191979F74D46592B516"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$50 per megawatt hour of electricity savings needed to make up any deficit with regard to a compliance obligation under the applicable performance standard; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFBE3701180564CB0A1BF618BA19A2559"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$5 per million Btu of natural gas savings needed to make up any deficit with regard to a compliance obligation under the applicable performance standard.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D4E1BEE11C5423E9E005A05DAA8C0D7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of payments</header><text>Alternative compliance payments collected by a State under subparagraph (A) shall be used by the State to administer the delegated authority of the State under this section and to implement cost-effective energy efficiency programs that—</text>
 <clause id="H328FD93C57294E8E9BC15AB63FDD6A8D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, achieve electricity savings and natural gas savings in the State sufficient to make up the deficit associated with the alternative compliance payments; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H19E30B535DC646479FBB4BEE7AE0ACBD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>can be measured and verified in accordance with the applicable procedures and standards under subsection (f) or paragraph (3), as applicable.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H259F8D9420624DB2B2AAE31D96F47AD0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Review of State implementation</header>
 <subparagraph id="H970F444092E94E3A830FFAFAC30B89FE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Periodic review</header><text>Every 2 years, the Secretary shall review State implementation of this section for conformance with the requirements of this section in approximately <fraction>½</fraction> of the States that have received approval under this subsection to administer the program, so that each State shall be reviewed at least every 4 years.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF120D715ACB40E1AED2A8366BD899F4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text>To facilitate the review under subparagraph (A), the Secretary may require the State to submit a report demonstrating the conformance of the State with the requirements of this section, including—</text>
 <clause id="HBEE3EF6B82C74CC68CE038704BB261EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reports submitted by retail electricity suppliers and retail natural gas suppliers to the State demonstrating compliance with applicable performance standards;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9E6E379CAB7A4CAE98328F889DED3EB4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the impact of the standards on projected electricity and natural gas demand within the State;</text> </clause><clause id="H1E868A136E474424B27B60118D7C4573"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an accounting of the use of alternative compliance payments by the State and the resulting electricity savings and natural gas savings achieved; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFC2897C54644491C8BF5579034E30784"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other information that the Secretary determines appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H034958E5321D4FCD8C17643414507A87"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Review upon petition</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), upon receipt of a public petition containing credible allegation of substantial deficiencies, the Secretary shall promptly review the State implementation of delegated authority under this section.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A440FED93CF4DB7AD8EB032E322009E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Deficiencies</header>
 <clause id="HCFD105D451FB436CACB6A5D3D158E112"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In completing a review under this paragraph, if the Secretary finds deficiencies, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subclause id="H3937097CC19B4286ADC17975AA85CC87"><enum>(I)</enum><text>notify the State of the deficiencies;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H9C344034596B47D4BA4B96CF0CA79466"><enum>(II)</enum><text>direct the State to correct the deficiencies; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF59BBD331647412CB8A5E89EA48D7715"><enum>(III)</enum><text>require the State to report to the Secretary on progress made by not later than 180 days after the date on which the State receives notice under subclause (I).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H0D9FB3FE07534F9C8188E54A850F5078"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Substantial deficiencies</header><text>If the deficiencies are substantial, the Secretary shall—</text> <subclause id="H43A0B91A7A0B4CE1A4ECED1FE6A45D8E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>disallow the reported electricity savings or natural gas savings that the Secretary determines are not credible due to deficiencies;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7769A3B1ED2F456583C343192EA1236C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>re-review the State not later than 2 years after the date on which the original review was completed; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H80C85E3DE01A41BAAD46936ADA63D698"><enum>(III)</enum><text>if substantial deficiencies remain uncorrected after the review provided for under subclause (II), revoke the authority of the State to administer the program established under this section.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H499E67AFDA324BE0A7AED3415E932320"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Calls for revision of State applications</header><text>As a condition of maintaining the delegated authority of a State to administer this section, the Secretary may require a State to submit a revised application under paragraph (1) if the Secretary has—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H337AD990B6FD46BD996A99478C135F79"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promulgated new or revised performance standards under subsection (d);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DF3049E0A09440D904E75C866973208"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promulgated new or substantially revised measurement and verification procedures and standards under subsection (f); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD90891F9BE7498BAEEC77AE3A9EDFE3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>otherwise substantially revised the program established under this section.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3297488E2212471E8B113F59DCC3FAED"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Cost recovery, fixed cost recovery and shareholder incentives</header><text>State utility regulatory commissions are encouraged to review the rules and regulations of the commission to ensure that utilities under the jurisdiction of the commission can—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD25654780D8844F09A68CB35B2322822"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recover the direct costs of energy efficiency programs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37C7D1DA97914103BFB3954923BBF5C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>fully recover authorized fixed costs, including lost margins from lower annual sales due to energy efficiency programs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A9D6597F0BB4ADD84220C968BF81EFA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>earn an incentive for shareholders if the energy efficiency standards are achieved.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDB3C96EB4FAA4B2883A7FB08923DE2E7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Information and reports</header><text>In accordance with section 13 of the Federal Energy Administration Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/772">15 U.S.C. 772</external-xref>), the Secretary may require any retail electricity supplier, retail natural gas supplier, third-party efficiency provider, or any other entity that the Secretary determines appropriate, to provide any information the Secretary determines appropriate to carry out this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2A7B1C198B8D45C9A67FA8B1CA797C30"><enum>(j)</enum><header>State law</header><text>Nothing in this section diminishes or qualifies any authority of a State or political subdivision of a State to adopt or enforce any law or regulation respecting electricity savings or natural gas savings, including any law or regulation establishing energy efficiency requirements that are more stringent than those under this section, except that no State law or regulation shall relieve any person of any requirement otherwise applicable under this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H32CB9AEA71024D518326B8188E574E64"><enum>6.</enum><header>Program review</header>
 <subsection id="HB82D6441353A4D369F3B576C6149C575"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National academy of sciences review</header><text>The Secretary of Energy shall enter into a contract with the National Academy of Sciences under which the Academy shall, not later than July 1, 2023, and every 10 years thereafter, submit to Congress, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, and the Secretary of Energy a comprehensive evaluation of all aspects of the programs established under sections 610 and 611 of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (as added by this Act), including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD44D0D07DEE046FE9A69B4E25EFB35AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an evaluation of the effectiveness of the programs, including the specific design elements of the programs, in increasing the efficiency of retail natural gas and electricity distribution and consumption and increasing the deployment of renewable electricity capacity;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE8A48E5A175417BA98DDF1E40C3BEBB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the opportunities for additional technologies and sources of efficiency and renewable electricity that have emerged since the date of enactment of this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF640E8D112574575A1E0FB6E00D1A549"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the impact of the programs on the reliability of electricity and natural gas supply;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DE3868DFAE948A5A50B0643C511CF75"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the net benefits or costs of the programs to the United States and the States, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H93C570E16B2A4B0EB537276B1C88808F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effects on electricity and natural gas demand and prices;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H246003D68842428CA1691BEBA20E6C64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the economic development benefits of investment;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC56FFCDD6EB7464C979DB79E9AED7261"><enum>(C)</enum><text>environmental costs and benefits;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82217B224DF5472B954BAD0A71CE36C2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the impacts on public health and health care costs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98149D9A5DDF432393E214B09D67C48A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>avoided costs related to environmental and congestion mitigation investments that otherwise would have been required;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD429E9BC51EF4722B938FC2352518EAD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an assessment of the benefits and costs of increasing the performance standards established under section 611(d) of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (as added by this Act);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD62EF0C1F4B4F51930176FA89226FCE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the feasibility, advantages, and disadvantages of alternative models for demonstrating compliance with a Federal energy efficiency resource standard, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4F89CAD3F9B84A878E7C85504F622DD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishing a national trading system for energy efficiency credits; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18A41317974C47F69A63F37D1497A1AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrating compliance through actual reductions in delivery or sales of electricity and natural gas, rather than on program savings; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5103020CE0040FC95A9CD4E6174E072"><enum>(7)</enum><text>recommendations regarding potential changes to the programs, including to regulations and procedures for implementing the programs, or to related public policies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6630BA6DBB0C4FD790B5FE44008CDCFA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recommendations to Congress</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2024, and every 10 years thereafter, the Secretary of Energy shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report making recommendations for modifications and improvements to the programs established under sections 610 and 611 of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (as added by this Act), including an explanation of the inconsistencies, if any, between the recommendations of the Secretary of Energy and the recommendations included in the evaluation of the National Academy of Sciences under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HCC5BCB7D5CA146A8ACB91886E1FEFEA0"><enum>7.</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (16 U.S.C. prec. 2601) is amended by adding at the end of the items relating to title VI the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC0DCF16960A4370BE23BBAEA10A9C3D" style="OLC">
				<toc>
					<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 609. Rural and remote communities electrification grants.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 610. Federal renewable electricity standard.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 611. Federal energy efficiency resource standard for retail electricity and natural gas
			 suppliers.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


