<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7B4FC0ED0D9E4BFFB1E6CB80EE1E3EBD" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2728 IH: Cleaning Product Labeling Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2728</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require labeling of ingredients of cleaning products, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H0F3E4110D179410C803BD539B033D707" style="OLC">
 <section id="H62CFA4450FA34385956DCF504F7AF418" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cleaning Product Labeling Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H025FDC5D9E9142658C7FA3522AF65113"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cleaning products labeling requirement</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H9E7F36FF12784E8881B5BDCA20977C0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Labeling requirement</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date on which the Commission issues regulations under subsection (d), a cleaning product manufactured for sale, offered for sale, distributed in commerce, or imported to the United States after such date shall bear a label on the product’s container or packaging with, and the manufacturer of the product shall include on the Internet website of the manufacturer (if the manufacturer maintains an Internet website), a complete and accurate list of all the product’s ingredients, including the individual ingredients in dyes, fragrances, and preservatives. Ingredients shall be listed in accordance with the following:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H73369C2BEC164CAAB897172F927CD4FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Ingredients shall be listed in descending order of predominance in the product by weight, other than ingredients that constitute less than 1 percent of the product, which may be listed at the end in any order.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF550B6C28E27480A8A6D54AE1EE67F21"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The list of ingredients on the Internet website of the product shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB81189528D074DA1A0A2F67D752326C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include the CAS Registry Number of each ingredient;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7D64231EF07E4CF693F17E7656E64138"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include an explanation of each ingredient’s purpose for being in the cleaning product; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H95D8798A3ADF4CC3BA187ED86E958DF1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be available in English, Spanish, and any other language the Commission or Administration determines necessary to ensure that users of the product in the United States are informed as to the complete list of the product’s ingredients and their function.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4C025883C1064E68A4A90E3BBECD4D3D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of nonconforming products</header>
 <paragraph id="H02D34C1B865F4EE881B7EE98A70EB3C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consumer products</header><text>A cleaning product under the jurisdiction of the Commission that is not in conformity with the labeling requirements of subsection (a), including a product the manufacturer of which is not in compliance with the Internet website listing requirement with respect to such product, shall be treated as a substance defined in section 2(p) of the Federal Hazardous Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1261">15 U.S.C. 1261(p)</external-xref>) for purposes of such Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H331286667BD649669AC349245F6489BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other cleaning products</header><text>A cleaning product under the jurisdiction of the Occupational Safety and Health Administration that is not in conformity with the labeling requirements of subsection (a), including a product the manufacturer of which is not in compliance with the Internet website listing requirement with respect to such product, shall be treated as a product in violation of a rule promulgated under section 6 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/655">29 U.S.C. 655</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H111A8E2C655B41A3A469504AF04DBD9A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No effect on existing labeling requirements</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be interpreted as having any effect on any labeling requirements in effect before the date of enactment of this Act as described in section 2(p) of the Federal Hazardous Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1261">15 U.S.C. 1261(p)</external-xref>), section 3 of the Poison Prevention Packaging Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1472">15 U.S.C. 1472</external-xref>), or the Hazard Communication Standard of the Occupational Safety and Health Administration.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF9B07B16264D45118337CF7C5FD34A72"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulemaking authority of the Consumer Product Safety Commission</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency as necessary, the Commission shall issue regulations for cleaning products under the jurisdiction of the Commission—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3B3A17AFF4D14EA1A43D72EB13E6E292"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to ensure a standardized method of listing ingredients in an accessible, uniform, and legible manner on both the label and Internet website of a product as required by subsection (a); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H81188200677A4FB7B41B3AA121A30700"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide for the effective enforcement of this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0C9237E540CB49B1BD13B3B061BB8A69"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rulemaking authority of the Occupational Safety and Health Administration</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency as necessary, the Secretary of Labor shall issue regulations, including occupational safety or health standards, for cleaning products under the jurisdiction of the Administration—</text>
 <paragraph id="H206CB3BC58ED4F908E99A3ECB9DF3FC2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to ensure a standardized method of listing ingredients in an accessible, uniform, and legible manner on both the label and website of a product as required by subsection (a); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8748CD02920945A49D191614D083F8F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide for the effective enforcement of this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H35380CEC08A14416A4FACEF68B90264B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Preservation of existing agency jurisdiction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed as having any effect on which cleaning products fall within the jurisdiction of the Commission or the Occupational Safety and Health Administration.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H4072D1A1154B4764B3A0166E068895D1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Public right to know petition</header>
 <subsection id="H2908FB730A3C4F338BBF945333C9968C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Petition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person may submit a petition to the agency of jurisdiction alleging that a cleaning product available in interstate commerce does not satisfy the labeling requirements of this Act, including a product the manufacturer of which is not in compliance with the requirement to list the product’s ingredients on its Internet website.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5575DFE66F984E15A23A9C818B60D7F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Action by the agency of jurisdiction</header><text>The agency of jurisdiction shall notify a petitioner of the receipt of a petition within 30 days after receipt of such petition. The agency shall investigate the claims made by the petition and make a determination as to the validity of such claims within 180 days after acknowledging the receipt of such petition. If the agency sustains the claim or claims made by the petition, the agency shall initiate the proper enforcement actions required by law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE8EF025885AB48BAA9A07A4D36254AD3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The agency of jurisdiction may issue such regulations as it determines necessary to require that petitions include a reasonable evidentiary basis for the claims made therein.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H6973D37000794281AB5C3FBFDECAD9CD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Relationship to State laws</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act affects the right of a State or political subdivision of a State to adopt or enforce any regulation, requirement, or standard of performance that is different from, or in addition to, a regulation, requirement, liability, or standard of performance established pursuant to this Act unless compliance with both this Act and the State or political subdivision of a State regulation, requirement, or standard of performance is impossible, in which case the applicable provision of this Act shall control.</text>
 </section><section id="H60BDFF9D4F5B46B488E8C450DB1B5975"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H2E8546C9BFD742469A0F7FA451BD31E0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency of jurisdiction</header><text>The term <term>agency of jurisdiction</term> means the Occupational Safety and Health Administration with respect to cleaning products and matters under the jurisdiction of the Administration and the Commission with respect to cleaning products and matters under the jurisdiction of the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF48DB843B77C409D8D1295DBB9C43DA7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Air care product</header><text>The term <term>air care product</term> means a mixture of one or more chemicals the purpose of which is to clean and freshen air or to deodorize and neutralize unwanted odors in the indoor air, including solid gels, air freshener spray, an outlet or battery operated air freshener, a hanging car air freshener, and a potpourri product.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBED11079F39F4BC391405DE377F66FEA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Automotive product</header><text>The term <term>automotive product</term> means a chemically formulated consumer product designed to maintain the appearance of a motor vehicle, but does not include automotive paint or a paint repair product.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE97DFCBE5425456AA4B63FFBBED26CE4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cleaning product</header><text>The term <term>cleaning product</term> means any chemically formulated product used primarily for commercial, domestic, or institutional cleaning purposes, including an air care product, automotive product, disinfectant (except as provided in subparagraph (B)), and polish or floor maintenance product. Such term shall not include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H84EFEBB4A055432BB398D0088DE1F467"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any drug or cosmetic, including personal care items such as toothpaste, shampoo, and hand soap; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H527F21818E034B7EA6FCA9DB3249A136"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a product labeled, advertised, marketed, and distributed for use only as a pesticide, as defined by section 2(u) of the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/136">7 U.S.C. 136(u)</external-xref>), including a disinfectant intended for use solely on critical or semi-critical devices as described by such section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H345ABC1CD3EE4F5DAABDFABA686EC21C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Consumer Product Safety Commission.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H75C138C31902470698B400E90B883B09"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Ingredient</header><text>The term <term>ingredient</term> means a chemical intentionally incorporated in a cleaning product, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H60D641848B82414798F10D8F9306FF3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a chemical intentionally added to the product that provides a technical or functional effect;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H646CC5A43409460988F0E88950CD2055"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the intentional breakdown product of a chemical that has an effect on the cleaning product;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BA412CD9993449DB8A28DF82ECFD91A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to a fragrance or preservative, each individual component part of the fragrance or preservative; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8880C9CCA027404CBE85F1EEB9B32F2A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any individual component of an ingredient or of an incidental ingredient that the Commission determines should be considered an ingredient.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H07FB7309EBF3432BAC0B1CCE12047F1B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Incidental ingredient</header><text>The term <term>incidental ingredient</term> means a chemical in a cleaning product, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H7E2EAC82F53A4721ACF1D1DD8EFCE265"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any substance that is present by reason of having been added to a cleaning product during processing for its technical or functional effect;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC95C1710FC7B46178181DDA9733BA80D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a chemical that has no technical or functional effect but is present by reason of having been incorporated into the cleaning product as a component of an ingredient of another chemical; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD25F375C29B84A9D91DFBB73E45959A9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any contaminant that may form via reactions over the shelf life of a cleaning product and that may be present at levels where detection is technologically feasible.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1840A199467F410CAC88088F27DE3EC5"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Polish or floor maintenance product</header><text>The term <term>polish or floor maintenance product</term> means a chemically formulated consumer product designed to polish, protect, or maintain furniture, floors, metal, leather, or other surfaces, including polish, wax, and restorer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC31B900F5C674DD3930028A0FEC67D1C"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary of Labor</header><text>The term <term>Secretary of Labor</term> means the Secretary of Labor, acting through the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Occupational Safety and Health.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


