<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H36FA704FC6B74A31A6EE78563290386C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2677 IH: Stop Mental Health Stigma in Our Communities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2677</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for behavioral and mental health outreach and
			 education strategies to reduce stigma associated with mental health among
			 the Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander population.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB401D8F2085845B9A43184A27759C1B8" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8513EC8B71464143B91C3DB1379E333A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Mental Health Stigma in Our Communities Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5CCA86D72ADC432285D10D0BFD44E87A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander behavioral and mental health outreach and education strategies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290dd">42 U.S.C. 290dd</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAFC69C74101448B7A876EB6565DEED20" style="OLC">
				<section id="H9F73D85224564FCB9D1138BAC6DC830B"><enum>544.</enum><header>Behavioral and mental health outreach and education strategies</header>
 <subsection id="H2E5D2449B4E44D339F2CED73C4434F9C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, shall, in coordination with advocacy and behavioral and mental health organizations serving populations of Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander individuals or communities, develop and implement an outreach and education strategy to promote behavioral and mental health and reduce stigma associated with mental health conditions and substance abuse among the Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander populations. Such strategy shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H441128D0BD214887BD1F856C49B95193"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be designed to—</text> <subparagraph id="H2A20528B66114E159E15256592B663AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meet the diverse cultural and language needs of the various Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander populations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF613F4DBEE394699BD6B91AA87FA3EF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure such strategies are developmentally and age appropriate;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H583B8FC8A5A94D998AAB99FD3E40962C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increase awareness of symptoms of mental illnesses common among such populations, taking into account differences within subgroups, such as gender, gender identity, age, sexual orientation, or ethnicity, of such populations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0DBDF3854434A9C85B2C52E78CE408B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide information on evidence-based, culturally and linguistically appropriate and adapted interventions and treatments;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD924384620DC4830ACD8DEE6347ACEE3"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure full participation of, and engage, both consumers and community members in the development and implementation of materials; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCA3749EA9CBA498EBE3DC1D8226DB7E1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seek to broaden the perspective among both individuals in these communities and stakeholders serving these communities to use a comprehensive public health approach to promoting behavioral health that addresses a holistic view of health by focusing on the intersection between behavioral and physical health.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14BC8560435C448B98335F11D39BFF7A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $300,000 for fiscal year 2018.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section></legis-body></bill> 

