<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF1E6E12E7D254BBFB4B0D75F10BF6AA0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 968</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170207">February 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enforce the Sixth Amendment right to the assistance of effective counsel at all stages of the adversarial process, to confer jurisdiction upon the district courts of the United States to provide declaratory and injunctive relief against systemic violations of such right, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3E0FC4F574AD4187B4D6FD9FB084B182" style="OLC"> 
<section commented="no" id="H9ABDBD7C6D9E4E088488AE335F1940CC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Equal Justice Under Law Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H58FEA22FAC6447A39930A810D9B308BC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Effective assistance of counsel</header> <subsection id="H75C55E55999A45C4AFCCAE3B39C6112F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An indigent individual facing criminal prosecution or juvenile delinquency in a State court shall be entitled to the effective assistance of counsel, as guaranteed by the Sixth and Fourteenth Amendments, at the State’s expense. If the State delegates fiscal or administrative authority over the indigent defense function to one of its political subdivisions, the State retains ultimate responsibility for securing counsel for the individual.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFF86DD362D8745CF90F37FF5AA36CF2C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ineffective assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The assistance of counsel is considered ineffective when a class can demonstrate that counsel’s performance was not reasonable under prevailing professional norms.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H251224DC4B694FF3BD57FA0F0D377925"><enum>3.</enum><header>Remedy</header> <subsection id="H7CC89F6F5FD74DA0ADBCB495C46138A3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Class action authorized</header><text>If a State official or one or more of a State’s political subdivisions fails on a systemic basis to guarantee the right to the assistance of effective counsel as guaranteed by the Sixth and Fourteenth Amendments, aggrieved persons may, prior to conviction, commence a civil class action in the district courts of the United States to seek declaratory, injunctive, or other equitable relief.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1B3C17A1EAF04D5C9FBBEDA2B2FE0E64"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Abstention doctrine</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A court entertaining a petition for relief filed under this Act need not apply the abstention restrictions articulated in Younger v. Harris (401 U.S. 37).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H395B981378194355809C6CECF2933F99"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the class shall have the burden of establishing that there is a likelihood of imminent and irreparable injury from that violation.</text></subsection> 
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13CF220D33E04AC390F61AAC022E75CB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Attorney’s fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any action or proceeding under this section, the court, in its discretion, may allow the prevailing party, other than a named official of a State or political subdivision of a State, a reasonable attorney’s fee as part of the costs. In awarding an attorney’s fee under this subsection, the court, in its discretion, may include expert fees as part of the attorney’s fee.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0D58AE8F56FD449EB2BE5E5FA4A85FDA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this section shall restrict any right that any individual has under any other statute or under common law to seek redress for a violation of the right to counsel.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

