<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7EBF6A93AA18418588CE78CCA6B273CF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3240 IH: Smart Manufacturing Leadership Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3240</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170713">July 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve the productivity and energy efficiency of the manufacturing sector by directing the
			 Secretary of Energy, in coordination with the National Academies and other
			 appropriate Federal agencies, to develop a national smart manufacturing
			 plan and to provide assistance to small- and medium-sized manufacturers in
			 implementing smart manufacturing programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8E4EE1307C2440BE90C47BDB1C9ED1A8" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4DFB0F2090B94DF58A5C1AADDDF02D26" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Smart Manufacturing Leadership Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H070F1F3ECA3C40C48F96787CE823377F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDF1C119C40A84B8F837E89857F86C699"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the industrial sector—</text> <subparagraph id="H505BAAB3B1564B7EA936399C8952D922"><enum>(A)</enum><text>represents approximately 20 percent of the economy of the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD590D78193AB4EAC8BD3BC4108CD0403"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides approximately 13 percent of employment in the United States; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H589D24FE1CEC424F8ECECA1876D5C115"><enum>(C)</enum><text>accounts for more than 30,000,000,000,000,000 Btus of energy, a quantity that is equal to almost <fraction>1/3</fraction> of the energy consumption of the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBD5D99A5E41424EAB9F61AC6A78446D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>smart manufacturing is set to transform the manufacturing sector and the use by the manufacturing sector of energy, water, raw materials, and labor over the 10 years following the date of enactment of this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H02D0CACAB1814512A5AEA7720762286D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the transformation described in paragraph (2) will result in savings in electricity, natural gas, transportation fuels, chemical feedstocks, and many other fuels;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD4FA556606F2497E8C1D9EBBC5EA897C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the interconnection of the many components of manufacturing within a manufacturing plant with other business functions within a company and across companies within a supply chain will enable new production efficiencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H66D901AB792F4FD086D38A5D56F9DF36"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the improvements in automation described in paragraph (4) are estimated to produce between $5,000,000,000 and $25,000,000,000 in energy savings per year across the manufacturing sector for electricity alone by 2035;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H681EDF3CC1154DCB907999F8BEC07780"><enum>(6)</enum><text>smart manufacturing technologies are estimated to add between $10,000,000,000,000 and $15,000,000,000,000 to the global gross domestic product over 20 years following the date of enactment of this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5FCA862F08F24FC19B52CCBB38300E80"><enum>(7)</enum><text>market barriers exist to the widespread adoption of smart manufacturing practices by all sizes of firms and to the investment in smart manufacturing technologies, including lack of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H235D41B1679942CE9502584D00AF447C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>common communication protocols between smart manufacturing devices, which prevents interoperability, reduces system efficiencies, and stifles innovation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F585ED85ACB40CA90F9CCFC1AA7D887"><enum>(B)</enum><text>common standards for storing and sharing information relating to energy consumption and energy savings;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFCB68AAED3A4A9A9B83C3EBAB7A2D0F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an open-access smart manufacturing platform that enables the networking of business and automation systems of multiple vendors; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA30639425A1D4715A9D9697C04F1C502"><enum>(D)</enum><text>common cybersecurity protocols and standards;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB752AB8AE96D407B82A95B79BB8D306B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>addressing the barriers described in paragraph (7) is in the interest of the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01CDC606C0BF4090B46E5AD6520AEB3B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in response to the barriers described in paragraph (7), the Secretary of Energy is working with the private sector to reduce the market barriers through the development of voluntary protocols and standards;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB71EA093FBE94B7D899C23D0CB6BB646"><enum>(10)</enum><text>there exist many technologies of which many domestic manufacturers are unaware that could—</text> <subparagraph id="H6CEB7B39019B4429A2C9854CDF8C2D57"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improve the competitiveness of the domestic manufacturers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD10213C002F44F5A8A214CEC397C1993"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduce the environmental impacts of the domestic manufacturers;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D9FD2A70B9D42CBA731AA1F354C556C"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Federal agency action can facilitate greater economic growth through outreach and engagement in the smart manufacturing technology area; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCDD670CD914648DB84B7A885DE1A2608"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the United States would benefit from a concerted and focused effort to advance the adoption of smart manufacturing throughout the manufacturing sector of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H603E8F1F981848E6A066A9FEA40C0CCB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H9089307A212A47B0914C4C38F34173B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Energy management system</header><text>The term <term>energy management system</term> means a business management process based on standards of the American National Standards Institute that enables an organization to follow a systematic approach in achieving continual improvement of energy performance, including energy efficiency, security, use, and consumption.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD44D65018C142EDBFD03F31C3D4671E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Industrial assessment center</header><text>The term <term>industrial assessment center</term> means a center located at an institution of higher education that—</text> <subparagraph id="HDBA81C2736924C91859E1BFD533B621F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>receives funding from the Department of Energy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5F4BB4DDA944DCA961C355AA47B60CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides an in-depth assessment of small- and medium-sized manufacturer plant sites to evaluate the facilities, services, and manufacturing operations of the plant site; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95A331F72AD8401A858BB1539A7DDEFB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identifies opportunities for potential savings for small- and medium-sized manufacturer plant sites from energy efficiency improvements, waste minimization, pollution prevention, and productivity improvement.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDC770066E3845339678A19BE150FB96"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information and communication technology</header><text>The term <term>information and communication technology</term> means any electronic system or equipment (including the content contained in the system or equipment) used to create, convert, communicate, or duplicate data or information, including computer hardware, firmware, software, communication protocols, networks, and data interfaces.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE3AF5E2B7CAC45F1936B47F73F0B9FEC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F0023E71EA341CC8A8AAFAB0E0DC12B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>National Laboratory</header><text>The term <term>National Laboratory</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F2BDDC97D0D4A419BE2562E23EE58BE"><enum>(6)</enum><header>North American Industry Classification System</header><text>The term <term>North American Industry Classification System</term> means the standard used by Federal statistical agencies in classifying business establishments for the purpose of collecting, analyzing, and publishing statistical data relating to the business economy of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0258A50BEDD446F2961DE8A5F85A522B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H35DFC1E87EA4424AAB505C29B7EF94CF"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Small and medium manufacturers</header><text>The term <term>small and medium manufacturers</term> means manufacturing firms—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0DB84D835E5E4D519D937B69193A5E61"><enum>(A)</enum><text>classified in the North American Industry Classification System as any of sectors 31 through 33;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECEF16A134484AD5AF33BDE93D1690AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with gross annual sales of less than $100,000,000;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6DAE9D47A5E40738F63FA83DB3083FF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with fewer than 500 employees at the plant site; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28B4D4A6456241A88F55F2737D7A6884"><enum>(D)</enum><text>with annual energy bills totaling more than $100,000 and less than $2,500,000.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H52DF120A922B4F499422A486C7D5C024"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Smart manufacturing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>smart manufacturing</term> means advanced technologies in information, automation, monitoring, computation, sensing, modeling, and networking that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8C57FF7E4444412B9F4607F20F197411"><enum>(A)</enum><text>digitally—</text> <clause id="H095FCC5EBFE1487F915A2BCF176D433B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>simulate manufacturing production lines;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6E6327305D27406AB88394B588FC7470"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>operate computer-controlled manufacturing equipment;</text> </clause><clause id="H961D004DC92B40A388F796BD5D684ACD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>monitor and communicate production line status; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB632D4F8FA254E65A6B8D26AB76F73BB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>manage and optimize energy productivity and cost throughout production;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51A0C94086164C0C8AD0D696B866E976"><enum>(B)</enum><text>model, simulate, and optimize the energy efficiency of a factory building;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D522A3757E0481C8C91EF218C007143"><enum>(C)</enum><text>monitor and optimize building energy performance;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E59843EAE924C28BE4ECE2FD1D97D88"><enum>(D)</enum><text>model, simulate, and optimize the design of energy efficient and sustainable products, including the use of digital prototyping and additive manufacturing to enhance product design;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1569FB88E1D7450F8CD6C93BA737D402"><enum>(E)</enum><text>connect manufactured products in networks to monitor and optimize the performance of the networks, including automated network operations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92B083D8CE8849FDBBAD6EBE26F0A270"><enum>(F)</enum><text>digitally connect the supply chain network.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H50FBD9003DA84414A9D7F9C869FF0B7E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Development of national smart manufacturing plan</header> <subsection id="H658DCA4C63DF4E21884E9A35BD0A00C2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the National Academies, shall develop and complete a national plan for smart manufacturing technology development and deployment to improve the productivity and energy efficiency of the manufacturing sector of the United States.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H97B5C3F823254421883BBC6F1CE011C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content</header>
 <paragraph id="H93449AD163E14E57AAF85154370DE43A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The plan developed under subsection (a) shall identify areas in which agency actions by the Secretary and other heads of relevant Federal agencies would—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFE04C463F4AB4259813BA52302916727"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate quicker development, deployment, and adoption of smart manufacturing technologies and processes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF92C7196143E4098AAED974FEB984EAE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">result in greater energy efficiency and lower environmental impacts for all American manufacturers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19BCE9D029014841A3FAB74235EE2429"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enhance competitiveness and strengthen the manufacturing sectors of the United States.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A35A070B0A5436DB2431A76AB3B9F40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Agency actions identified under paragraph (1) shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0902F83D445B48D79904C8F7FBED66D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of previous and current actions of the Department of Energy relating to smart manufacturing;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DA19A35D4904907AB748B27C494F5BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the establishment of voluntary interconnection protocols and performance standards;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79C1AF79E6544602A07881F34395F00B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deployment of existing research results; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H405F42F3BB874B66AB24700DC5A8B935"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the leveraging of existing high-performance computing infrastructure.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H25E5FE3D34764308B370FDB41C96D950"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Biennial revisions</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which the Secretary completes the plan under subsection (a), and not less frequently than once every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall revise the plan to account for advancements in information and communication technology and manufacturing needs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H33A3799640684A0BB2866720F210EDBC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Annually until the completion of the plan under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the progress made in developing the plan.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H86DFD8E00BB24785BF29588DE48124F1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Secretary shall use unobligated funds of the Department of Energy to carry out this section.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HBD88AB7D34B342E98B624E45D765C4B3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Leveraging existing agency programs to assist small and medium manufacturers</header> <subsection id="HF4B92923C56749F3936C4B4C5CD09F01"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H39034A71538D4FE5807CBF817A638910"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Department of Energy has existing technical assistance programs that facilitate greater economic growth through outreach to and engagement with small and medium manufacturers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9D4635C5F3F4873B4C9A2A86167CA6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>those technical assistance programs represent an important conduit for increasing the awareness of and providing education to small and medium manufacturers regarding the opportunities for implementing smart manufacturing; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58C3938A71864395B7F5D438EC0E3A4F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>those technical assistance programs help facilitate the implementation of best practices.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE51F9EFC684841999CCFCE3C610EA473"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expansion of technical assistance programs</header><text>The Secretary shall expand the scope of technologies covered by the Industrial Assessment Centers of the Department of Energy—</text>
 <paragraph id="H09322929BA2E4517B67DE1960F310A4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to include smart manufacturing technologies and practices; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8085F0462B3D4B3C93A34BC0DFC699DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to equip the directors of the Industrial Assessment Centers with the training and tools necessary to provide technical assistance in smart manufacturing technologies and practices, including energy management systems, to manufacturers.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFAF352741FD3483FB6CF0F0C32235463"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Secretary shall use unobligated funds of the Department of Energy to carry out this section.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H71DC882EEE784EABBF727F4FB811A5FB"><enum>6.</enum><header>Leveraging smart manufacturing infrastructure at National Laboratories</header> <subsection id="HC807DE194AA2425C9DF7AD365922B1CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header> <paragraph id="HAE383114E48642A99E84621E9111BC19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall conduct a study on how the Department of Energy can increase access to existing high-performance computing resources in the National Laboratories, particularly for small and medium manufacturers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BFB68FCA2FF48E6867BC56B995BED19"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In identifying ways to increase access to National Laboratories under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9E86D9D0CC4745788508A888E06ED099"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">focus on increasing access to the computing facilities of the National Laboratories; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98945799D22441FB859A3EA78C6AAA5B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that—</text>
 <clause id="H411DC13BE61B44809880EAF7792EE0E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the information from the manufacturer is protected; and</text> </clause><clause id="H2D32669450B1496FABC6A68A92F949CA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the security of the National Laboratory facility is maintained.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H84E1C19FE9CD4F3CA4D7191F60799DD0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing the results of the study.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H12AE3FC2DA414126AC82F1B3678E540D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Actions for increased access</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall facilitate access to the National Laboratories studied under subsection (a) for small and medium manufacturers so that small and medium manufacturers can fully use the high-performance computing resources of the National Laboratories to enhance the manufacturing competitiveness of the United States.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HB76A17B54D78421781A580DF47155A95"><enum>7.</enum><header>State leadership grants</header>
 <subsection id="HE4E418723283490FAFCB7FA0574F44C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Finding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds that the States—</text> <paragraph id="HAFBA0EE74B134E6BA24640DE4669D46D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are committed to promoting domestic manufacturing and supporting robust economic development activities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEAD9C36D2CA1456891F77CF995BF77F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are uniquely positioned to assist manufacturers, particularly small and medium manufacturers, with deployment of smart manufacturing through the provision of infrastructure, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H23CE61FAC6E9421DB65322F7823D690E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">access to shared supercomputing facilities;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H912AB129F0714B86B8D270C2758E833C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assistance in developing process simulations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AB20BE10E8A40FEBB5026F3E56CA419"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conducting demonstrations of the benefits of smart manufacturing.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4F7DA56F8A3E4D1EA26DBB1B9707DC72"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may make grants on a competitive basis to States for establishing State programs to be used as models for supporting the implementation of smart manufacturing technologies.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H4F388692D648448F857846654F5885EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <paragraph id="H247163AE334145A2B7C6F4ADA5E31DF0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a State shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H91F9DA49C7B349C6AF9497DF88340680"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The Secretary shall evaluate an application for a grant under this section on the basis of merit using criteria identified by the Secretary, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H48AAEEE9EEC94E358F9DE0E3EC66D994"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the breadth of academic and private sector partners;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC660A3D9BE8C46C3A1448B1132A1B691"><enum>(B)</enum><text>alternate sources of funding;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2CB8B2D46E7494E8D1F6DCBF19E54FB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>plans for dissemination of results; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62F8E951810B4EB6ADBF13724124BCC4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the permanence of the infrastructure to be put in place by the project.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD717AF2D0EB44919A61BAB8F6589AA92"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirements</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H9F9B2E204C3A492FAC4657AD5F31368A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term of a grant under this section shall not exceed 3 years.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5263B64228E04F76B9580489314AD8ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum amount</header><text>The amount of a grant under this section shall be not more than $3,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7D846962EE2A4F84A4E12A0A9B5D19B6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><text>Each State that receives a grant under this section shall contribute matching funds in an amount equal to not less than 30 percent of the amount of the grant.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HAB07EACD337B4A59AAA3291A6147CAE1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header>
 <paragraph id="H0699CBA8E7AB45AB83F525863AAC37E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State shall use a grant provided under this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H48288AD78D4140A2BFE11AC2ABFD6322"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to provide access to shared supercomputing facilities to small and medium manufacturers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6A245B9CA8E40EFBAA714667128C1E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to fund research and development of transformational manufacturing processes and materials technology that advance smart manufacturing; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88BC363BE24C448E8DBE2D283CE8A3B0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to provide tools and training to small and medium manufacturers on how to adopt energy management systems and implement smart manufacturing technologies in the facilities of the small and medium manufacturers.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C1619AAF564470480559938C517236F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct biannual evaluations of each grant made under this section—</text> <paragraph id="HAE569DEC3301484187AA6D065BF25385"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to determine the impact and effectiveness of programs funded with the grant; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB86EFC44AFF84B08B41041C14F286E50"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide guidance to States on ways to better execute the program of the State.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD8490BC6616F4944B9012A20DB5721BA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2021.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H08F128985EB149478BF211A9A9E5343C"><enum>8.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary annually shall submit to Congress and make publicly available a report on the progress made in advancing smart manufacturing in the United States.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


