<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7FA8932373BF4F909C17152521D7536E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2387 IH: Worker Ownership, Readiness, and Knowledge Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2387</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170504">May 4, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish an Employee Ownership and Participation Initiative, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H24C7C15811FA4FF9A861C80F2ED54DDD" style="OLC">
 <section id="H895D99A82D234D5EA638D4A809E33569" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Worker Ownership, Readiness, and Knowledge Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA9F06043308F473D82071DFDEDF17396"><enum>2.</enum><header>Worker ownership, readiness, and knowledge</header> <subsection id="H356E0E52B42C43B488CAB0656597210F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA1ACD5215EBB4C74931AB6EEFE26135A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Existing program</header><text>The term <quote>existing program</quote> means a program, designed to promote employee ownership and employee participation in business decisionmaking, that exists on the date the Secretary is carrying out a responsibility authorized by this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC81C4177D6E248CD8772409641FE7AB8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initiative</header><text>The term <quote>Initiative</quote> means the Employee Ownership and Participation Initiative established under subsection (b).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD546A4687478482496CD2EC4F0EFBBDA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>New program</header><text>The term <quote>new program</quote> means a program, designed to promote employee ownership and employee participation in business decisionmaking, that does not exist on the date the Secretary is carrying out a responsibility authorized by this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE54C29CADDB74277AF2D1DCD2DE815CF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Labor, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Employment and Training.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7BC8134222ED4CA78AFEF33CA9382CCA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means any of the 50 States within the United States of America.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H990179D4A8644E89B8DE8C9FE606B04B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employee ownership and participation initiative</header>
 <paragraph id="H3BD2747BC879483583953F88B1750DC2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall establish within the Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor an Employee Ownership and Participation Initiative to promote employee ownership and employee participation in business decisionmaking.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83F8929FA7364EEB837925F4B642D4EF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>In carrying out the Initiative, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HD021674F8E89473B8EE6C515A0B0882F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>support within the States existing programs designed to promote employee ownership and employee participation in business decisionmaking; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18C27B04A1194FCE80ACBACA2EEBB70E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitate within the States the formation of new programs designed to promote employee ownership and employee participation in business decisionmaking.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HADF8911478C4402C96931B8AA93478F4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>To carry out the functions enumerated in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H707DF1C8188B486898D8FC7F742DF4CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>support new programs and existing programs by—</text>
 <clause id="H7B90F026922A452BAB28000C9ED4BB00"><enum>(i)</enum><text>making Federal grants authorized under subsection (d); and</text> </clause><clause id="H20F0ADBB271F4F80BF5B3BF376C27327"><enum>(ii)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7A60F0D51B2A4271A63FAF7092E3BD41"><enum>(I)</enum><text>acting as a clearinghouse on techniques employed by new programs and existing programs within the States, and disseminating information relating to those techniques to the programs; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7D4693691E3F4CD090B39961297A7D0A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>funding projects for information gathering on those techniques, and dissemination of that information to the programs, by groups outside the Employment and Training Administration; and</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9135E900619419FB8C75B35715F44F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitate the formation of new programs, in ways that include holding or funding an annual conference of representatives from States with existing programs, representatives from States developing new programs, and representatives from States without existing programs.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H28239E624D9046258C7ADA978A2E4C74"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Programs regarding employee ownership and participation</header>
 <paragraph id="H2D2B5E00735347008953B2795A7F3356"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment of program</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a program to encourage new programs and existing programs within the States to foster employee ownership and employee participation in business decisionmaking throughout the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1787557A36B8412482DB97034FD55055"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose of program</header><text>The purpose of the program established under paragraph (1) is to encourage new and existing programs within the States that focus on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCB8B562E37B04E28B42EBA9BF8FC9710"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing education and outreach to inform employees and employers about the possibilities and benefits of employee ownership, business ownership succession planning, and employee participation in business decisionmaking, including providing information about financial education, employee teams, open-book management, and other tools that enable employees to share ideas and information about how their businesses can succeed;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H702B830FDF7C4499849F1F1BD5281B60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing technical assistance to assist employee efforts to become business owners, to enable employers and employees to explore and assess the feasibility of transferring full or partial ownership to employees, and to encourage employees and employers to start new employee-owned businesses;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA6000D7F09F489D8A2C8748F7F1759A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>training employees and employers with respect to methods of employee participation in open-book management, work teams, committees, and other approaches for seeking greater employee input; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC27663690B214CBD92175AE013D11330"><enum>(D)</enum><text>training other entities to apply for funding under this subsection, to establish new programs, and to carry out program activities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAAE83540A2544539EF6102EE4C073BB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Program details</header><text>The Secretary may include, in the program established under paragraph (1), provisions that—</text> <subparagraph id="HB49354E74CFA40D38A64D1D563E99F98"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of activities described in paragraph (2)(A)—</text>
 <clause id="H7D3103B5C32148C9BD27B127A999A5A2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>target key groups, such as retiring business owners, senior managers, unions, trade associations, community organizations, and economic development organizations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0F48203CEAF546F39F041E6B8CD82872"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>encourage cooperation in the organization of workshops and conferences; and</text> </clause><clause id="H4303E28AA1DF45218141130B4981E6B7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prepare and distribute materials concerning employee ownership and participation, and business ownership succession planning;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4113A23AE35C43A1AC6CE7E86F821BA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of activities described in paragraph (2)(B)—</text> <clause id="H70DCC235601F4918B92BA21715A86FC9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide preliminary technical assistance to employee groups, managers, and retiring owners exploring the possibility of employee ownership;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1B5EA34C4E66419096B1C981B5E05EF1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide for the performance of preliminary feasibility assessments;</text> </clause><clause id="H48E2257E50C34038B2C79B8B9B83C652"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>assist in the funding of objective third-party feasibility studies and preliminary business valuations, and in selecting and monitoring professionals qualified to conduct such studies; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8CE2668E2B294DD2B004B047152BFCE8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>provide a data bank to help employees find legal, financial, and technical advice in connection with business ownership;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FDAC962E8A942A4BD319A3DDA331EEF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of activities described in paragraph (2)(C)—</text> <clause id="H55CEDAB36D8A4F5EA0EB2B5CC26A36B8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide for courses on employee participation; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H75CF59D4BE934DC8B375B6AFD77D9511"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide for the development and fostering of networks of employee-owned companies to spread the use of successful participation techniques; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDDFB767F5BF42F2AD1FCD2C792C10AD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the case of training described in paragraph (2)(D)—</text> <clause id="H6BFD4AD7C5894D6EA4C22B3609833FAC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide for visits to existing programs by staff from new programs receiving funding under this section; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDD460110E185412B85D55A9230922ACC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide materials to be used for such training.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H99651E9921294792B89C4196D081346B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>The Secretary shall issue formal guidance, for recipients of grants awarded under subsection (d) and 1-stop partners affiliated with the statewide workforce investment systems described in section 106 of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2881">29 U.S.C. 2881</external-xref>), proposing that programs and other activities funded under this section be—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB235ADB63B1B4181BA1451B4FF2CB6E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>proactive in encouraging actions and activities that promote employee ownership of, and participation in, businesses; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F63B354B87541A5AA3CB877BD29446A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>comprehensive in emphasizing both employee ownership of, and participation in, businesses so as to increase productivity and broaden capital ownership.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H10688098ABBD446EBEFA861CA3B854D1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grants</header>
 <paragraph id="H29863E06718A47208A411B97D9F6C767"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the program established under subsection (c), the Secretary may make grants for use in connection with new programs and existing programs within a State for any of the following activities:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDA753E024D654B5F91E4CA15B8564262"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Education and outreach as provided in subsection (c)(2)(A).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66619A9BD8A2478A8301F8FDD84A0D64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Technical assistance as provided in subsection (c)(2)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H643CBE2C9430485CB368B50C67E3E346"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Training activities for employees and employers as provided in subsection (c)(2)(C).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC19817A71B6E476F95B7AF9924BED9D5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Activities facilitating cooperation among employee-owned firms.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B4258796DF849DCB8C9C0C14C25890B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Training as provided in subsection (c)(2)(D) for new programs provided by participants in existing programs dedicated to the objectives of this section, except that, for each fiscal year, the amount of the grants made for such training shall not exceed 10 percent of the total amount of the grants made under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4806E2C11095434F808923E2DABB35B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amounts and conditions</header><text>The Secretary shall determine the amount and any conditions for a grant made under this subsection. The amount of the grant shall be subject to paragraph (6), and shall reflect the capacity of the applicant for the grant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H463816F5C6374E4B98426C331924B6D4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>Each entity desiring a grant under this subsection shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6375AD9D63734B9188361E20082714FB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State applications</header><text>Each State may sponsor and submit an application under paragraph (3) on behalf of any local entity consisting of a unit of State or local government, State-supported institution of higher education, or nonprofit organization, meeting the requirements of this section.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HF953BE4C5A384D1F9D0C0AF75D86B334"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Applications by entities</header>
 <subparagraph id="H883B00D5AD6541B5B2C244FBA9DECCF3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Entity applications</header><text>If a State fails to support or establish a program pursuant to this section during any fiscal year, the Secretary shall, in the subsequent fiscal years, allow local entities described in paragraph (4) from that State to make applications for grants under paragraph (3) on their own initiative.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD7C222B7E714343BCC218836927F565"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application screening</header><text>Any State failing to support or establish a program pursuant to this section during any fiscal year may submit applications under paragraph (3) in the subsequent fiscal years but may not screen applications by local entities described in paragraph (4) before submitting the applications to the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H474423CCF94B453CAB5C8F7E700D4A5D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>A recipient of a grant made under this subsection shall not receive, during a fiscal year, in the aggregate, more than the following amounts:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9FC56677771A4EAABCF6BB6EDAC62103"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2018, $300,000.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62DA0F3D5DAA4B70A915529246BBAD4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2019, $330,000.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H271620D060D1433998F73DFE66F88379"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2020, $363,000.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2A788F066264B99BB58D1AA95419557"><enum>(D)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2021, $399,300.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DC6BF6739074BEFBB520910ED6828E2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2022, $439,200.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD78D33D3370B4E8D8AF5881AA9EC0673"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>For each year, each recipient of a grant under this subsection shall submit to the Secretary a report describing how grant funds allocated pursuant to this subsection were expended during the 12-month period preceding the date of the submission of the report.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H026F3071883B483296333AC5C874A24D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evaluations</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to reserve not more than 10 percent of the funds appropriated for a fiscal year to carry out this section, for the purposes of conducting evaluations of the grant programs identified in subsection (d) and to provide related technical assistance.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H683B157C4FD9442AAAD06DE4BB3CDE5D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than the expiration of the 36-month period following the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to Congress a report—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2F07A74B0F784EEA80073C3E2C25177B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on progress related to employee ownership and participation in businesses in the United States; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2EB373E2FBE4AE2A1E15F6B05257036"><enum>(2)</enum><text>containing an analysis of critical costs and benefits of activities carried out under this section.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA09E15CBF09D4A1EBC0BF50DD0082E8A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorizations of appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="HF077F7B041714146813E1773D4F14F1F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of making grants pursuant to subsection (d) the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H97A3821283C24410BC4C64D07FC47A93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2018, $3,850,000.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0CF3A3B6D5D439A8481C132BAC905CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2019, $6,050,000.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72CF346F6E934DC1BA04CB9AEBB9396E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2020, $8,800,000.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H325E7092DBBC4834B531C26BB5B987E2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2021, $11,550,000.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B1AA28AE644446FB06DDC0B87E5E9CE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2022, $14,850,000.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A944EE38B2A4F2BA04A0939AB255B9A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of funding the administrative expenses related to the Initiative, for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, an amount not in excess of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8A72854C5EBE4B94A6AF6E29EEAF42F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$350,000; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F82ED4BE5734A10A7970CFC8D1E4CC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>5.0 percent of the maximum amount available under paragraph (1) for that fiscal year.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


