<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA67ABA2C23254E9BB845E90A006671E5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2767 IH: Stimulating Innovation through Procurement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2767</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170530">May 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001202">Mrs. Murphy of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Small Business Act to require senior procurement executives, procurement center representatives, and the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization to assist small business concerns participating in the Small Business Innovation Research Program and the Small Business Technology Transfer Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDF71EB1009FD407DB0FAA702AADFA30D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE757A25980404A27AB19FDEE265321C3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stimulating Innovation through Procurement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3BA17594F15243ABA8597561BF63AEEE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition of senior procurement executive</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 9(e) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3C2681E54A4942E5970E6F0AAE78530D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (12)(B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC113A2D084414896A1D3FC7B478D4E69"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (13)(B), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD3681AC6645848699903B586A4353F23"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H553140378F6B42DF86C42ADFF7CA0A2D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HD53A0F75D916498F8E15898340AA92BF"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>senior procurement executive</term> means an official designated under section 1702(c) of title 41, United States Code, as the senior procurement executive of a Federal agency participating in a SBIR or STTR program.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H3F1F142AF6A648C8B4DFA31BF8E2FB8D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Inclusion of senior procurement executives in SBIR and STTR</header> 
<subsection id="H02731636EC074E7AB35FEA248BB29431"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 9(b) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HBD422FC8424D408ABD52AC83A897491A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA2F6BA8BA0EC46F588EECD518A1ED309"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53B76D0D4321435EAEEAAEB6D6E2450D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4B1F74DCA60D40A7AAD6CDF7A086912E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H8ABD1C5A209F473F87A43DADF8EDEA33"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to coordinate, where appropriate, with the senior procurement executive of the relevant Federal agency to assist small business concerns participating in a SBIR or STTR program with commercializing research developed under such a program before such small business concern is awarded a contract from such Federal agency.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD16D9991AEF142A4B8D84AC6458E9D56"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 9(b)(3) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HACB6121E58074C66A344B6DC2A9012FE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Modifications relating to procurement center representatives and other acquisition personnel</header> 
<subsection id="H41B7376A3F8D43168E8EF9CCAD695F8D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>SBIR amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 9(j) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638(j)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H50E473BB08494751B5D1587379A479DD" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H85941A1C234544BDAC81B95D13D3635C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Modifications relating to procurement center representatives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the enactment of this paragraph, the Administrator shall modify the policy directives issued pursuant to this subsection to require procurement center representatives (as described in section 15(l)) to assist small business concerns participating in the SBIR program with researching solicitations for the award of a Federal contract (particularly with the Federal agency that has a funding agreement with the concern) and to provide technical assistance to such concerns to submit a bid for an award of a Federal contract. The procurement center representatives shall coordinate with the appropriate senior procurement executive and the appropriate Director of the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization established pursuant to section 15(k) for the agency letting the contract.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC822084677DF4699A97336A6F97EA200"><enum>(b)</enum><header>STTR amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 9(p)(2) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638(p)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE39B85ACB51C4D2FAD517045B41EDA68"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E)(ii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB7CE8876E09427C8092A9597956776C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95205E41E45D493CAC97F748FF4D416C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB4E73969699A464285D80C207BEAFFD3" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H18C09D54F6FC4506841C74A6869C978C"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">procedures to ensure that procurement center representatives (as described in section 15(l))—</text> <clause id="H53C53FD91BD044AB8F7F9D2C14470BA9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist small business concerns participating in the STTR program with researching applicable solicitations for the award of a Federal contract (particularly with the Federal agency that has a funding agreement with the concern);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H253CD146E7054CB0B87096991D91AB6A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide technical assistance to such concerns to submit a bid for an award of a Federal contract; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF0549AFCB187466CA9730486C97A40E8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate with the appropriate senior procurement executive and the appropriate Director of the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization established pursuant to section 15(k) for the Federal agency letting the contract in providing the assistance described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD783DFEB04614A2D8C859C13E7234D30"><enum>5.</enum><header>Amendment to duties of procurement center representatives</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 15(l)(2) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644(l)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF7E65AF11B1B4CCE89D669D9CEA05587"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F42140A7F2B4AC18578E5F2CAEE2B71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (J) as subparagraph (L); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B94FC86C564487795578D476D7B9CE6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (I) the following new subparagraphs:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H458443430A6C4147A656F87FD2D8E71F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="HD64CCCAB81974236BF030D2FE8D80EC7"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist small business concerns participating in a SBIR or STTR program under section 9 with researching applicable solicitations for the award of a Federal contract to market the research developed by such concern under such SBIR or STTR program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF109359DC6D3498394956DA7C7808DD2"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide technical assistance to small business concerns participating in a SBIR or STTR program under section 9 to submit a bid for an award of a Federal contract, including coordination with the appropriate senior procurement executive and the appropriate Director of the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization established pursuant to subsection (k) for the agency letting the contract; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H5290273F9C994700BC166DE4361FCBDC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Amendment to the duties of the Director of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization for Federal agencies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 15(k) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644(k)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA49D34C296D0425BB5CC6EBB43041F3C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (19), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9DB3684876DE4D008EEC87A4559314EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (20), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEED54626E2354AFBA50144FBFEECB441"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF7D89DBCB988479D99A3057EF3299258" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H16FBF3E8B5714F2191A89A509C8BDF85"><enum>(21)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall assist small business concerns participating in a SBIR or STTR program under section 9 with researching applicable solicitations for the award of a Federal contract (particularly with the Federal agency that has a funding agreement (as defined under section 9) with the concern) to market the research developed by such concern under such SBIR or STTR program; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE64D74FB9EA4495C8392EFC2FF804A86"><enum>(22)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall provide technical assistance to small business concerns participating in a SBIR or STTR program under section 9 to submit a bid for an award of a Federal contract, including coordination with procurement center representatives and the appropriate senior procurement executive for the agency letting the contract.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

