<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5FCBC5630E0D4F1995973724C3B206A7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1798 IH: Veterans Collaboration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1798</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170329">March 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program to promote and encourage
			 collaboration between the Department of Veterans Affairs and nonprofit
			 organizations and institutions of higher learning that provide
			 administrative assistance to veterans.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7C8C48B387584291BE3DDDFBC99A6A9B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8A466B59820B4E86B64EB5DA2F611AF1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Collaboration Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5A7D05A160EC439EACC00B957CCF935E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program on collaboration with nonprofit organizations</header> <subsection id="H9AC21B68A5DE45D2914593E1BF9AF54D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a two-year pilot program to promote and encourage collaboration between the Department of Veterans Affairs and nonprofit organizations and institutions of higher learning. In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary shall emphasize collaboration with—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE973E1849F754FDD8FE77988C8DBD6D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>veterans service organizations that provide personnel with appropriate credentials to assist veterans in filing claims and appeals with the Department for disability compensation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H126BEFCC4FB245FBA372DE01EBA9818C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>educational institutions that provide pro bono legal assistance to veterans.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB19C4E04565944C6B8C36C94AC27F140"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Metrics</header><text>The Secretary shall establish metrics to determine which organizations and institutions provide the best service to veterans and seek to encourage such organizations and institutions to participate in the pilot program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H594C60FC1BE54E09A604A2F55D33C0EB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Location</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program in States with the highest veteran populations, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H79319ACEF64B484DA00691D3052B1DD0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of social media</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary shall use social media to promote the collaboration efforts carried out under the pilot program and to notify veterans of such collaborations. Quarterly reports will be provided to members of the Veterans’ Affairs Committee that document the reach of the social media efforts and the number of veterans who use the program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H31FCF2BCA03248ECA1185586EBCF76E6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the end of a fiscal quarter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on the pilot program, including the use of social media under subsection (d) and the number of veterans who receive administrative assistance from organizations and institutions through the program.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


