<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0D075E4FF2674AE98ECE1DF6E333C343" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 624 PCS: Social Security Number Fraud Prevention Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<calendar>Calendar No. 106</calendar><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 624</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date>May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To restrict the inclusion of social security account numbers on Federal documents sent by mail, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H1FDCC71528794807B80278303ABB6565" style="OLC">
 <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65824B78CD6244588E58B1122D8CD54E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Social Security Number Fraud Prevention Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H32F9BD8D9D7A4B6A9DDF2BFA788CA13A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restriction of social security numbers on documents sent by mail</header> <subsection id="HD7455719B7F94FCFB25DA97FCE8BEB74"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Restriction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agency may not include the social security account number of an individual on any document sent by mail unless the head of the agency determines that the inclusion of the social security account number on the document is necessary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H09E790EB59DC4539B63DE4873944A0BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of each CFO Act agency shall issue regulations specifying the circumstances under which inclusion of a social security account number on a document sent by mail is necessary. Such regulations shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H670AFC8A227944508B9CC6857588407C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>instructions for the partial redaction of social security account numbers where feasible; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9070019C1A574BFDB45B020B39F40AFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a requirement that social security account numbers not be visible on the outside of any package sent by mail.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HA44F24F547F64A0CAF11C3E11DB43895"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not later than the first, second, third, fourth, and fifth-year anniversary of such date of enactment, the head of each CFO Act agency shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and any other appropriate authorizing committees of the House of Representatives and the Senate, a report on the implementation of subsection (a) that includes the following:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H04A6E442A37E478AAF4CFF14B7150697"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The title and identification number of any document used by the CFO Act agency during the previous year that includes the complete social security account number of an individual.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD338D6843664A639834A5703425BE47"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the first report submitted, a plan that describes how the CFO Act agency will comply with the requirements of subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0C8441C75A6402EAD3435A36449FAB1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the final report submitted, the title and identification number of each document used by the CFO Act agency for which the head of the agency has determined, in accordance with regulations issued pursuant to subsection (b), that the inclusion of a social security account number on such document is necessary, and the rationale for such determination.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4651DEAC65D8475DB1D811A62FE5B4BE"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any other report that is not the first or final report submitted, an update on the implementation of the plan described under paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD6FB011F22F4417EA127511613776712"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HDBF85571B84140229DF5E50DA76D9D05"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>agency</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code, but includes an establishment in the legislative or judicial branch of the Government (except the Senate, the House of Representatives, and the Architect of the Capitol, and any activities under the direction of the Architect of the Capitol).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9B35C041B9C4EFFA81B49CF57019AE0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>CFO Act agency</header><text>The term <quote>CFO Act agency</quote> means the agencies listed in paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 901(b) of title 31, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB0A0C30AD21D482899A3FB16DA954717"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Subsection (a) shall apply with respect to any document sent by mail on or after the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170524">Passed the House of Representatives May 24, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
	<endorsement display="yes"><action-date>May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


