<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE6183DCC343E48C187BF1BCD9B649C53" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 722 IH: No Funds for Unconstitutional Executive Orders Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 722</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20170130">January 30, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster of New Hampshire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O'Rourke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of Federal funds to implement, administer, or enforce the Executive order 
entitled <quote>Protecting the Nation from Foreign Terrorist Entry into the United States</quote> signed by President Donald J. Trump on January 27, 2017.
</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H685DB15E5E774CD78B408B349D99012A" style="OLC">
		<section id="HFF559F491E95421682984A126C27BAD9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Funds for Unconstitutional Executive Orders Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id8A60B05FF92E4D3C8FB9BB7B62174E85" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="id95C57DF08B3741AD8532F45E8DE9669B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The first 10 words of the Bill of Rights state: <quote>Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment of religion</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id431FFAD579EB473D8EDB3F2A0D97A342"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In Larson v. Valente, the Supreme Court stated: <quote>The clearest command of the Establishment Clause is that one religious denomination cannot be officially preferred over another.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id95FF15B170EF4E1988044250C3D5AE38"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On January 27, 2017, President Donald J. Trump signed into force an Executive order imposing a selective ban on immigration from majority-Muslim nations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idE51AD3B74215470FB03AE46508B1C6C0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>On January 27, 2017, President Trump signed into force an Executive order that permits the Secretaries of State and Homeland Security to admit individuals to the United States as refugees if they are a religious minority in their home nation, because that is in the <quote>national interest</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idC155D4A3C21E4860BF1289049BEDF0C0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>On January 27, 2017, the Christian Broadcasting Network published an interview between David Brody and President Trump entitled Brody File Exclusive: President Trump Says Persecuted Christians Will Be Given Priority As Refugees in which President Trump says persecuted Christians will be given priority for admission to the United States over other religions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6CF498C2869D4526823FC88794D1601D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Executive order entitled <quote>Protecting the Nation from Foreign Terrorist Entry into the United States</quote> authored and signed by President Trump violates the Establishment Clause of the United States Constitution.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="id3EB64C47F6574451893BBC2260A85909"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds, resources, or fees made available by the United States Congress to any Federal agency may be used to implement, administer, enforce, or carry out (including through the issuance of any regulations) any of the policy changes set forth in the Executive order titled <quote>Protecting the Nation from Foreign Terrorist Entry into the United States</quote> signed by President Donald J. Trump on January 27, 2017.</text></section></legis-body>
</bill>


