<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA5CF2836F93C4616A0634F0A160EB1EB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2662 IH: Restoring Accountability in the Indian Health Service Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2662</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000184">Mrs. Noem</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001250">Mr. Bishop of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. McMorris Rodgers</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Indian Health Care Improvement Act to improve the recruitment and retention of
			 employees in the Indian Health Service, restore accountability in the
			 Indian Health Service, improve health services, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB8F7CBE4F26944C4A99DB053120E1F2C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H241D26D4AA72427A824E383B1C525037" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restoring Accountability in the Indian Health Service Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HEF47C45720D04F68B00B51E07A5B33EB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
			<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
				<toc-entry idref="H241D26D4AA72427A824E383B1C525037" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HEF47C45720D04F68B00B51E07A5B33EB" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H6832772511924194BAC30CB1F0A7EEE8" level="title">Title I—Indian Health Service improvements</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H1D5458DE145741CCA89A9CA2F5F4D20E" level="section">Sec. 101. Incentives for recruitment and retention.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H7C188B5D39434B1DB7DEC22B39F9F3EA" level="section">Sec. 102. Medical credentialing system.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H0CD5C87D4F86417B9768B90A29B173BC" level="section">Sec. 103. Liability protections for health professional volunteers at Indian Health Service.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H01F77A4D0C7A4F8ABAF2FA70945ECEEF" level="section">Sec. 104. Clarification regarding eligibility for Indian Health Service loan repayment program.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HFE04E18FD1D3455690E089850771E7D7" level="section">Sec. 105. Improvements in hiring practices.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H9616E125160144E9930DBF9677AD7734" level="section">Sec. 106. Removal or demotion of Indian Health Service employees based on performance or
			 misconduct.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HC9191AA2F6804FDAAB42DF7D1A31EFE6" level="section">Sec. 107. Standards to improve timeliness of care.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H32F6CBDAC98340E0862AACF26970F74A" level="section">Sec. 108. Tribal culture and history.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H1F9C925D9DE14877AC084B44EBF1D114" level="section">Sec. 109. Staffing demonstration project.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HC48096AE60F44267831A0F3F94C5935D" level="section">Sec. 110. Rule establishing tribal consultation policy.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HE10B1DFEDC464B5FAE4CB8CD817A36AF" level="title">Title II—Employee protections</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H470FD33D4C3941FABEB93CACA67B4906" level="section">Sec. 201. Right of Federal employees to petition Congress.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H1E80F3D222BB45C491CBCA89F07D6B03" level="section">Sec. 202. Fiscal accountability.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HF54B2D2AEF6941C49CDC382A667A0B50" level="title">Title III—Reports</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HB1CC6BBAF4AF441DBA421976D2216E91" level="section">Sec. 301. Definitions.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H5EC34B06E1ED4A878675588DEC9EDF22" level="section">Sec. 302. Reports by the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H36860E1CF2644579BF779C903A73C4A9" level="section">Sec. 303. Reports by the Comptroller General.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H0FC6E38D292B4E97857FB04BBD42ACDC" level="section">Sec. 304. Inspector General reports.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H6A3D80D3FBEB4D0A87D0529241A47D5C" level="section">Sec. 305. Transparency in CMS surveys.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H7B6637BD32064DC1982FF74712CE4BFF" level="title">Title IV—Technical amendments</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H7D3F884B179A45FB88F133114AC4E688" level="section">Sec. 401. Technical amendments.</toc-entry>
			</toc>
		</section><title id="H6832772511924194BAC30CB1F0A7EEE8"><enum>I</enum><header>Indian Health Service improvements</header>
 <section id="H1D5458DE145741CCA89A9CA2F5F4D20E"><enum>101.</enum><header>Incentives for recruitment and retention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1611">25 U.S.C. 1611</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H078336E688A54D1FAFFCDBAD8F05E3EC" style="OLC">
					<section id="H97B09792EA004D508AC42148B02C7F7F"><enum>125.</enum><header>Incentives for recruitment and retention</header>
 <subsection id="H43BB9F8E1EDA4069B60589E1238D1A44"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Parity in pay</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a pay system for physicians, dentists, nurses, and other health care professionals employed by the Service that provides pay that, to the maximum extent practicable, is comparable to the pay provided to physicians, dentists, nurses, and other health care professionals, respectively, under subchapters III and IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/74">chapter 74</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H12B3BE97971E40459B5623A33330E680"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relocation costs</header><text>The Secretary may provide to an employee of the Service reimbursement for any relocation costs the employee incurs if—</text>
 <paragraph id="H14575DFBD98D4ED3B877390F78DAD96E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the employee relocates to a Service area experiencing a high level of need for employees, as determined by the Secretary; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H104345DF58E448A2B8F4DC483EE98A98"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the employee is filling a position that would otherwise be difficult to fill, as determined by the Secretary, in the absence of an incentive.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7C2798567334821B25AC6A5DC2CF2D9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Housing vouchers</header>
 <paragraph id="H68DC66CB352742C18C3340F2403B962B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Restoring Accountability in the Indian Health Service Act of 2017</short-title>, the Secretary may establish a program to provide tenant-based rental assistance to an employee of the Service who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1D9187C8E4304F67877CCCFDB4E19DA9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>agrees to serve for not less than 1 year at a Service unit designated by the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration as a health professional shortage area, as defined in section 332(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254e">42 U.S.C. 254e(a)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE32B2EB518C344E38337EBAADD8FFAB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is a critical employee, as determined by the Secretary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D465A95B4C2480BBA9508361955B427"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>Any program established by the Secretary under paragraph (1) shall terminate on the date that is 3 years after the date on which any such program is established.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C25692B0AAF4FB8959BC5B035175DB1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header>
 <paragraph id="H8CD3B3F5E4F64704908A1CEA9690D21F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>OPM guidelines</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out this section in accordance with any guidelines of the Office of Personnel Management relating to the recruitment and retention of employees, including section 575.109 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Restoring Accountability in the Indian Health Service Act of 2017</short-title>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H714666826B364F55840232C602D8E552"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Service agreements</header><text>The Secretary may only provide reimbursement for any relocation costs under subsection (b) or any other benefit under subsection (c) to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9D42FC1D281448E29258531D83DE3D83"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a full-time employee who agrees to serve for not less than 1 year in the Service, beginning on the date of the agreement; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC6ADC88F7C14DEDA84B75E6FC3C5A49"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a part-time employee who agrees to serve for not less than 2 years in the service beginning on the date of the agreement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H7C188B5D39434B1DB7DEC22B39F9F3EA"><enum>102.</enum><header>Medical credentialing system</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1611">25 U.S.C. 1611</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by section 101, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2CB5A3276B342F5BC3CE1D156922530" style="OLC">
					<section id="HEB9DBF306C674EBD9261E9B93633EFF5"><enum>126.</enum><header>Medical credentialing system</header>
 <subsection id="HF32F3B6C3F2247B9AC9E8A49D07AF1D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>By not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Restoring Accountability in the Indian Health Service Act of 2017</short-title>, the Secretary, acting through the Service and in accordance with the requirements described in subsection (b), shall develop and implement a Service-wide centralized credentialing system (referred to in this section as the <quote>credentialing system</quote>) to credential licensed health professionals who seek to provide health care services at any Service unit.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4FD4F4D122D941CDA73F852A034E89FD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In developing the credentialing system under subsection (a), the Secretary shall ensure the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H5A2C3447F1CA42D1A4A6933425CA06F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Credentialing procedures shall be uniform throughout the Service.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC8F08F42F0B46C58D71C9BADD580A13"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With respect to each licensed health professional who successfully completes the credentialing procedures of the credentialing system, the Secretary shall authorize each such professional to provide health care services at any Service unit.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEB72672D28FC4538B87C341C8C4DA7D9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing the credentialing system under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with Indian tribes and may also consult with any public or private association of medical providers, any government agency, or other relevant expert, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6B1AF88ADB2A46169EA1F0F514FCE582"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A licensed health care professional may not provide health care services at any Service unit, unless such professional successfully completes the credentialing procedures of the credentialing system developed under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0E9F5F6ECCD147EC97F80AAA1F3097F4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary may prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4D70C4AF73BB4EAAA91A7E74F13EF3F8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>This section may not be construed to inhibit the authority of an Indian tribe to enter into or maintain a compact or contract under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref> et seq.).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H0CD5C87D4F86417B9768B90A29B173BC"><enum>103.</enum><header>Liability protections for health professional volunteers at Indian Health Service</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 224 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/233">42 U.S.C. 233</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF09BA9E8AB1448BA8380C23CECD1B6EC" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H8973676B9F334862A77AE8CBAF63C95C"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Certain Indian Health Service volunteers deemed Public Health Service employees</header>
 <paragraph id="H1C9E4B95D93E4BE8BB31AA635D1261C6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, a health professional volunteer at a Service unit shall, in providing a health service to an individual, be deemed to be an employee of the Public Health Service for a calendar year that begins during a fiscal year for which a transfer was made under paragraph (4)(C). The preceding sentence is subject to the provisions of this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE655D29B008547C3A9A5ED4D8823FDAA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>In providing a health service to an individual, a health care practitioner shall, for purposes of this subsection, be considered to be a health professional volunteer at a Service unit if all of the following conditions are met:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD4EEF7508F0A409191292651EC4B66FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The service is provided to the individual at the facilities of a Service unit, or through offsite programs or events carried out by the Service unit.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB98C8827C304F12A51C5F1361A8AF8B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Service unit is sponsoring the health care practitioner pursuant to paragraph (3)(C).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H551EED588F614CFA9E2F391B8585EEC7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The health care practitioner does not receive any compensation for the service from the individual, the Service unit, or any third-party payer (including reimbursement under any insurance policy or health plan, or under any Federal or State health benefits program), except that the health care practitioner may receive repayment from the Service unit for reasonable expenses incurred by the health care practitioner in the provision of the service to the individual.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD64BC76D4F984BB6AFD3E005CE36C7F7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Before the service is provided, the health care practitioner or the Service unit posts a clear and conspicuous notice at the site where the service is provided of the extent to which the legal liability of the health care practitioner is limited under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB97F91A95C04A4C9A181465BF5C1178"><enum>(E)</enum><text>At the time the service is provided, the health care practitioner is licensed or certified in accordance with applicable law regarding the provision of the service.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C5FEC340BA549DF969A7FE4173CD7EC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Subsection (g) (other than paragraphs (3) and (5)) and subsections (h), (i), and (l) apply to a health care practitioner at a Service unit for purposes of this subsection to the same extent and in the same manner as such subsections apply to an officer, governing board member, employee, or contractor of an entity described in subsection (g)(4), subject to paragraph (4) and subject to the following subparagraphs:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6B8012C57D5B489D9210B7085284B720"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Each reference to an entity in subsections (g), (h), (i), and (l) shall be considered to be a reference to a Service unit.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C966D87C24F4C50AC69F7957781B0D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The first sentence of paragraph (1) applies in lieu of the first sentence of subsection (g)(1)(A).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2EF9DCEC0024B06B542D69C6673B4C8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>With respect to a Service unit, a health care practitioner is not a health professional volunteer at the Service unit unless the Service unit sponsors the health care practitioner. For purposes of this subsection, the Service unit shall be considered to be sponsoring the health care practitioner if—</text>
 <clause id="H5933236533F54107BB7F7191250B6A7B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to the health care practitioner, the Service unit submits to the Secretary an application meeting the requirements of subsection (g)(1)(D); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4C229BEDF1EC443AB0D50DEC33A034FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary, pursuant to subsection (g)(1)(E), determines that the health care practitioner is deemed to be an employee of the Public Health Service.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03CA27BCFE6C476C837C42AB2942B3A4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>In the case of a health care practitioner who is determined by the Secretary pursuant to this subsection and subsection (g)(1)(E) to be a health professional volunteer, this subsection applies to the health care practitioner (with respect to services performed on behalf of the Service unit sponsoring the health care practitioner pursuant to subparagraph (C)) for any cause of action arising from an act or omission of the health care practitioner occurring on or after the date on which the Secretary makes that determination.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39571534649E45E989E3FA1EF2612A2C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Subsection (g)(1)(F) applies to a health care practitioner for purposes of this subsection only to the extent that, in providing health services to an individual, each of the conditions described in paragraph (2) is met.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD87316FFAB4E4F85A6E74BAFCBEB35C0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Funding</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB93BBD585B914024B1A79E56C8720A84"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Amounts in the fund established under subsection (k)(2) shall be available for transfer under subparagraph (C) for purposes of carrying out this subsection.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H698BE329627D433697B1BDDB288E4A92"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Annual estimates</header>
 <clause id="H2C903926C5C74F24A5D84AE150C7118D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than May 1 of each fiscal year, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary, shall submit to Congress a report providing an estimate of the amount of claims (together with related fees and expenses of witnesses) that, by reason of the acts or omissions of health professional volunteers, will be paid pursuant to this section during the calendar year that begins in the following fiscal year.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8A81CD668C6E4425A7BE6CF31AEF6178"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Subsection (k)(1)(B) applies to the estimate under clause (i) relating to health professional volunteers to the same extent and in the same manner as that subsection applies to the estimate under that subsection relating to officers, governing board members, employees, and contractors of entities described in subsection (g)(4).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BC58DCF68744AEAA33B2CB61FEBA300"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Transfers</header><text>Not later than December 31 of each fiscal year, the Secretary shall transfer from the fund under subsection (k)(2) to the appropriate accounts in the Treasury an amount equal to the estimate made under subparagraph (B) for the calendar year beginning in that fiscal year, subject to the extent of amounts in the fund.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6334AEBB0124AD8B9FB65BDF5A88CD2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definition of service unit</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>Service unit</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1603">25 U.S.C. 1603</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA849E51224FF4CF9813AFA943334B5B3"><enum>(6)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to inhibit the authority of an Indian tribe to enter into or maintain a compact or contract under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HD87F3C41B4F1423BA1F2AFE546B9E5AE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Effective dates</header>
 <subparagraph id="HFAB7AFD754F84CB293C75FF88D65EB6D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), this subsection shall take effect on October 1, 2019.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03B0006B05174DA2BF25E8F94DA09503"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Regulations, applications, and reports</header><text>Effective on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Restoring Accountability in the Indian Health Service Act of 2017</short-title>, the Secretary may—</text>
 <clause id="HE49C43BCD81E4B6BA1B1D4824C2AF080"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prescribe regulations for carrying out this subsection; and</text> </clause><clause id="HD3147B1BCF4549F997FAD91AF69ABEC0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>accept and consider applications submitted under paragraph (3)(C)(i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H01F77A4D0C7A4F8ABAF2FA70945ECEEF"><enum>104.</enum><header>Clarification regarding eligibility for Indian Health Service loan repayment program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 108 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1616a">25 U.S.C. 1616a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H68502F15EE714620932EE610CF1DAB8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (B) of subsection (b)(1) to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE8D9DB5BB7844DDB966262DC34A0A07E" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H6FC016EF1BF14AF2BF00753571A23191"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have—</text> <clause id="HB794464AC75A46F4A2AB49EA8D648254"><enum>(i)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0B308CB85E2243B28E2F0BD6C6894240"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a degree in a health profession; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB30ADE5BA0F049D9A92B25F348A33410" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a license to practice a health profession in a State; or</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H19A9E3AC92154CDDA42C320E293B7A0E"><enum>(ii)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2D038E7B053E42FD94CF84CC41208DCC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a degree in business administration with an emphasis in health care management (as defined by the Secretary), health administration, hospital administration, or public health; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0879DCF0ACB047A88E703097F09FDF7B" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a license or certification to practice in the field of business administration, health administration, hospital administration, or public health in a State, if the Secretary determines such license or certification necessary for the Indian health program to which the individual will be assigned;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DB016D8FBA24603AE568D1D1B58BB35"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending clause (iii) of subsection (f)(1)(B) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0BBCD2E03E594CCE8C4228CA96A340A1" style="OLC"> <clause id="HB732B9634F55445B85465D88689FA6DF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to serve for a time period (referred to in this section as the <quote>period of obligated service</quote>) equal to—</text>
 <subclause id="HAB1EECF5130A4BBA8BA67BFA0B389912"><enum>(I)</enum><text>2 years or such longer period as the individual may agree to serve in the full-time practice of such individual’s profession in an Indian health program to which the individual may be assigned by the Secretary; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFF9DF1CCE767491EB6D2342A6D114908"><enum>(II)</enum><text>4 years or such longer period as the individual may agree to serve in the half-time practice of such individual’s profession in an Indian health program to which the individual may be assigned by the Secretary;</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE47A60435A140028F1E54DAC155747B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(2)—</text> <subparagraph id="H3CD1B7A4B6FF4A209E33880636EE77FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (B) as subparagraph (C); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA091D6CB22384050B20E3A5AD93F3677"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="H5EC88C608E8F46D48198E25C87FA915A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking the first sentence of the matter preceding clause (i) and inserting the following: <quote>In the case of an individual who contracts to serve a period of obligated service under subsection (f)(1)(B)(iii)(I), for each year of such obligated service, the Secretary may pay up to $35,000 (or an amount equal to the amount specified in section 338B(g)(2)(A) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254l-1">42 U.S.C. 254l–1(g)(2)(A)</external-xref>)) on behalf of the individual for loans described in paragraph (1). In the case of an individual who contracts to serve a period of obligated service under subsection (f)(1)(B)(iii)(II), for each year of such obligated service, the Secretary may pay up to $17,500 on behalf of the individual for loans described in paragraph (1)</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2B98C906FDDC4C538567A1BF0745AC07"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>In making a determination</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16109A1B47604E9F8467D14B07DBDAB2" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H23770E4E630D4DCC8931F6A5A4A9AD04"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In making a determination under this paragraph</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HFE04E18FD1D3455690E089850771E7D7"><enum>105.</enum><header>Improvements in hiring practices</header>
 <subsection id="HC2E6CECB401048428FC6D166A6ECDAE1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title VI of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1661">25 U.S.C. 1661</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03A257FF33BF43B2A5A4B4AFCA1E924E" style="OLC">
						<section id="HFB0688B558BC4EE2B66F5EFC39CB2FDA"><enum>605.</enum><header>Improvements in hiring practices</header>
 <subsection id="H299DF93A55C04088815F6E5FB98ABB76"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Direct hire authority</header><text>The Secretary may appoint, without regard to subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (other than sections 3303 and 3328 of such title), a candidate directly to a position within the Service for which the candidate meets the job description of the Office of Personnel Management.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H202B65C59EA44160A253B4668F5CFCC0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tribal notification</header><text>Before appointing, hiring, promoting, transferring, or reassigning a candidate to a Senior Executive Service position or the position of a manager at an Area office or Service unit, the Secretary shall provide notice to each Indian tribe located within the defined geographic area of such Area office or Service unit, as the case may be, of the content of an inclusion in an employment record under section 606(j).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2E681C66AE0D48918CE287473AA850C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (c) of section 2 of the Act of December 15, 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5117">25 U.S.C. 5117</external-xref>) is amended by adding the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H306072524F9342EAA6CFEAF32D455B96" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H9373D1F582EB432ABB541B446D045983"><enum>(3)</enum><header>IHS waivers</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall seek from each Indian tribe concerned, a waiver of Indian preference laws for a personnel action that is with respect to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H922E588EEA2F49FAB2689031D1DD8BC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an Indian Health Service unit in which 20 percent or more of the positions in the Service unit are not filled by a full-time employee of the Indian Health Service for a period of 6 months or longer; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4EDD77A4EB96446CBD0EF1ADAE8AD0BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a former employee of the Indian Health Service or a formal tribal employee who was removed from such former employment within, or demoted for performance or misconduct that occurred during, the 5-year period the date of such personnel action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="H9616E125160144E9930DBF9677AD7734"><enum>106.</enum><header>Removal or demotion of Indian Health Service employees based on performance or misconduct</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VI of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1661">25 U.S.C. 1661</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by section 105, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H238BFA1D3B72485D864056D279BBEB6D" style="OLC">
					<section id="H128A0C34BEDC446CBFEC9211B6884F4C"><enum>606.</enum><header>Removal or demotion of Service employees based on performance or misconduct</header>
 <subsection id="H93D79679054D44428D8FB067AA5B546D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section and section 607:</text> <paragraph id="H571EEA4D0AF0481599BA8EF2C98A4AC3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Employee</header><text>The term <term>employee</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2105 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H5FD4E6986CB04E74A76096526308EF55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Manager</header>
 <subparagraph id="H452401F3575F49B6AABDFDD7F8C55D48"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>manager</term> has the meaning given the term <term>management official</term> in section 7103(a) of title 5, United States Code.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1208C9612E1A43E1A8AC4384D6D503FB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>manager</term> includes, as employed at any facility of the Service—</text>
 <clause id="H7ADE3893157B40EEB0E4BBC7AD433D48"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a chief executive officer;</text> </clause><clause id="HA28A9D781B5A4D71A03EA73DFB0B689C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a chief medical officer; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H669E168999A54E67B574E6C7F36FC200"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a department director.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD15B2C66CF3E4D2BB0695411A0752677"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Misconduct</header><text>The term <term>misconduct</term> means neglect of duty, malfeasance, or failure to accept a directed reassignment or to accompany a position in a transfer of function.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDBFC01670F5643959CF5C03296B11383"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Personnel action</header><text>The term <term>personnel action</term> means a removal, transfer, or reduction in grade under subsection (b)(2).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B84E55D7F6A4297B3B560F45A688439"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3B98AEB64734EC5BD1CDAD338841A61"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Senior executive</header><text>The term <term>senior executive</term> means a career appointee (as that term is defined in section 3132(a) of title 5, United States Code).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H28831EFB74194EA497418417B21A7B3C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Senior Executive Service position</header><text>The term <term>Senior Executive Service position</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3132(a) of title 5, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA17383A27C54BCD9FA2E2D5ACD9CD87"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Supervisor</header><text>The term <term>supervisor</term> has the meaning given the term in section 7103(a) of title 5, United States Code.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBDA61B70D5AC4A699D92B4043E3C4B47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Removal based on performance or misconduct</header>
 <paragraph id="HC343D565724D4C8EA5D5C1A1A589C9E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (4), the Secretary may remove an employee of the Service from the position the employee occupies if the Secretary determines the performance or misconduct of the employee warrants removal.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6CD4237E9DEE4428BE26FAA54DFFA18E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Action</header><text>If the Secretary removes an employee under paragraph (1), the Secretary may—</text> <subparagraph id="HD6E34B8A65164549B16B9B028C7B1DCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>remove the employee from the civil service (as defined in section 2101 of title 5, United States Code);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF7FD133066643C2B76F07723ACF01CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an individual described in paragraph (3), transfer the individual from the Senior Executive Service position to a General Schedule position at any grade of the General Schedule for which the individual is qualified and that the Secretary determines is appropriate; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H488D8B8885CE41A0821A84A60F4BC435"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of a manager or supervisor, reduce the grade of the manager or supervisor to any other grade for which the individual is qualified and that the Secretary determines is appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H836528F847884E8CAF4A8843295F9DD0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Individual described</header><text>An individual referred to in paragraph (2)(B) is a senior executive that—</text> <subparagraph id="HD86D13BC0BB74C4F8F44B21FA5422501"><enum>(A)</enum><text>previously occupied a permanent position within the competitive service (as that term is defined in section 2102 of title 5, United States Code); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE30DB2F06FEF4CECA15A3EA91CECD391"><enum>(B)</enum><text>previously occupied a permanent position within the excepted service (as that term is defined in section 2103 of title 5, United States Code).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H17300673D1D14607B17433FD35485521"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Due process</header><text>Before an employee may be subject to a personnel action, the Secretary shall provide to the employee—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1CB55F2139F1425BADB3D5D0926455ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less than 10 days before the personnel action, written notice of the proposed personnel action; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D1DE977E4924D80A1DF178AD7AD2109"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an opportunity and reasonable time to answer orally or in writing.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H586EB178FF5E4F72A7C44116798B8EE4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pay of certain individuals</header> <paragraph id="H036E195C9CD74C978CE0EE9DDF7C80D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including the requirements of section 3594 of title 5, United States Code, any individual transferred to a General Schedule position under subsection (b)(2)(B) or subject to a reduction in grade under subsection (b)(2)(C) shall, beginning on the date of the transfer, receive the annual rate of pay applicable to the position.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H04138C40194A4169ACBF2C58ED883DE5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD63B8F3BEE224DF3ACD9CDF3B428EEDD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An individual transferred to a General Schedule position under subsection (b)(2)(B) or subject to a reduction in grade under subsection (b)(2)(C)—</text>
 <clause id="H4734EEF3E2D14AFCB88B0C963557906A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may not be placed on administrative leave or any other category of paid leave during the period during which an appeal (if any) under subsection (e)(2)(A) is ongoing; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB3FD6E96870A47B2B6118EF45A03C47A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may only receive pay if the individual—</text> <subclause id="H6802F8783A724185B17DAB421E93C9E9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>reports for duty; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1E758F1C1A114B1DBDAE5610C2F4D0BB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>performs a primary duty or an alternative primary duty, as each term is described in section 551.104 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B8D39A582E14F508F1F0A61850CB1C2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure to report</header><text>If an individual transferred to a General Schedule position under subsection (b)(2)(B) or subject to a reduction in grade under subsection (b)(2)(C) does not report for duty, pursuant to subsection (f)(3)(B), the individual shall not receive any increase in rate of pay or other benefit.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3E2D89E57E90414CB42DB3EE4B5A7475"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice to Congress</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary takes a personnel action, the Secretary shall submit, in writing, a notice of the personnel action and the reason for the personnel action to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEBA3F882B7D74230A5FCA8B53E9FF4A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H07CB91B58470488B8C2827CF03BC992E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E70AA499B8840B9A426A70FC2B764AB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE357187BD0764B769121DA2B9A632133"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7930805C54834A15ADE8C7C7DA77732B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Inspector General of the Department.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDE3F10154C8B44579C5E5386CA035E38"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Procedure</header> <paragraph id="H19F92F84CF804069A9683B64AD05E728"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inapplicability</header><text>The procedures under chapters 43 and 75 of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to a personnel action.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H4C5CF31469D24E4B9BCC7E9B7F0862DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appeal</header>
 <subparagraph id="H93102D22979D402D80642D003065A51B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B) and subsection (f), an employee subject to a personnel action may appeal the personnel action to the Merit Systems Protection Board under section 7701 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H125A7BFF00AF4A9D936203D9B331B041"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>An appeal under subparagraph (A) may only be made if the appeal is made not later than 7 days after the date of the personnel action.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B03F6ACAC7D424D8BCD2B160EC787F8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Expedited review by administrative law judge</header>
							<paragraph id="HBF58CB93D2D44E908F43B9BE22A784AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <subparagraph id="HABA98681316D4841AA01A6DC7F31D2EC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Referral</header><text>On receipt of an appeal under subsection (e)(2)(A), the Merit Systems Protection Board shall refer the appeal to an administrative law judge pursuant to section 7701(b)(1) of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H671EB0A452D2408F88C6251A3A23B3AA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Expedition</header><text>The administrative law judge to whom an appeal is referred under subparagraph (A) shall—</text> <clause id="HA4F49817E44847ABAC9A0EA5D6779F0C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>expedite the appeal under section 7701(b)(1) of title 5, United States Code; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDCADC84985BF437C9CD56A1E4DF7EEC4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>issue a decision in each case not later than 21 days after the date of the appeal.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB96C9DC6AC694C7693E1BD3780D161C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Finality</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including section 7703 of title 5, United States Code, the decision of an administrative law judge under paragraph (1) shall be final and shall not be subject to any further administrative appeal.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H9105B30D2C634B17A799BFF047E36526"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Failure to issue decision</header>
 <subparagraph id="H68D3448EBA164AAB82BF654520EDD23E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any case in which an administrative law judge fails to issue a decision in accordance with the 21-day requirement described in paragraph (1)(B)(ii), the personnel action shall be treated as final.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B0652251C2549FB81D9340C56571297"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Transparency</header><text>In any case in which a personnel action is treated as final under subparagraph (A), the Merit Systems Protection Board shall, not later than 14 days after the date on which the personnel action becomes final, submit a letter explaining the reasons why a decision was not issued in accordance with the 21-day requirement described in paragraph (1)(B)(ii) to—</text>
 <clause id="H7EE756A5964748339D31FB1102EBA67C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate;</text> </clause><clause id="H33D3160B6A454CB6AB66C382727FC5DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDAF7C71690CB4A5683FD1A7DB0C94C51"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</text> </clause><clause id="H3F4D1B3EA2A747ADA4D96D7B8EA56D33"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H495671625697407389275552F44D21A0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Restriction</header><text>The Merit Systems Protection Board or an administrative law judge may not stay any personnel action.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9AA96D6017D4CB89AC2907760FC2A4F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Cessation of pay increases and benefits</header><text>During the period beginning on the date on which an employee appeals a removal from the civil service under subsection (e)(2)(A) and ending on the date on which the removal becomes final, the employee may not receive any—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H03564EC61CB34BE79995A96F39DD23E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increase in rate of pay; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43E74BDB694B476CA2D871888736276E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>award, bonus, incentive, allowance, differential, student loan repayment, special payment, or other benefit.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H218FA49193764BFC828CA62F79E49C2C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall provide such information and assistance as may be necessary to ensure an appeal under this subsection is expedited to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H514F5910F08A4DE2A6EE38382C6E0850"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Merit Systems Protection Board; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D911EDD3DEF4D5ABBE505773DB73602"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any administrative law judge to whom an appeal under this section is referred.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE50A3F78BC34318A5111A84ADDF3B12"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Employment record transparency</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the employment records for any employee subject to a personnel action, regardless of whether that personnel action is final, include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3A0D08F8C31248E3887E5B7421410328"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a notation that the employee was subject to a personnel action; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1AB909A647C4DDE9E9F94D97CFCC965"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the disposition or status of the personnel action or any appeal of the personnel action under this section.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H975A8AADBDF048229CB29B5F02B02D29"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Relation to title 5, United States Code</header>
 <paragraph id="H2D3F0C4A8DB440188EB2552CC699F4CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Additional authority</header><text>The personnel action authorities provided to the Secretary under this section are in addition to the authorities provided under chapters 43 and 75 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H186F1B795131447480133E963E383F20"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Removal of senior executives</header><text>Section 3592(b)(1) of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to a personnel action.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section id="HC9191AA2F6804FDAAB42DF7D1A31EFE6"><enum>107.</enum><header>Standards to improve timeliness of care</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title IV of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1641">25 U.S.C. 1641</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEBA4CD3F237949C09076326239021C05" style="OLC">
					<section id="HBA790FD3F4BF45FF9C9799B3AEF683A6"><enum>412.</enum><header>Standards to improve timeliness of care</header>
 <subsection id="H52FB3B5E64834809912AAAE59268B49F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Restoring Accountability in the Indian Health Service Act of 2017</short-title>, the Secretary, acting through the Service, shall—</text> <paragraph id="HD2F2CA6EC30A4173B78237BE54884B56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish, by regulation, standards to measure the timeliness of the provision of health care services in Service facilities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C6B451C0B3D43969F543979C43BC61E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide such standards to each Service unit.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBB17582F9F6A43188543D9D98C55F410"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Service, shall develop a process for each Service unit to submit to the Secretary data with respect to the standards established under subsection (a)(1).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H32F6CBDAC98340E0862AACF26970F74A"><enum>108.</enum><header>Tribal culture and history</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 113 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1616f">25 U.S.C. 1616f</external-xref> ) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2395280475904EBD85313911D1976E9E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1E34ED893C424E1EB75375B68BA66493"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>a program</quote> and inserting <quote>an annual mandatory training program</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EBC9DF3436A4322B5BAB048AF667825"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>appropriate employees of the Service</quote> and inserting <quote>employees of the Service, locum tenens medical providers, and other contracted employees who work at Service hospitals or other Service units and whose employment requires regular direct patient access</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5BFF6AE7C804E04A6BFAA286719887F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HECCBA9E2258E4BCD8B4B5B1F3C71F66F" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H2EF8E3B89C3C426B9B626E1FCCBFDA98"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, beginning with the year of the date of enactment of the <short-title>Restoring Accountability in the Indian Health Service Act of 2017</short-title>, each employee or provider described in subsection (a) who enters into a contract with the Service on or after the date of such implementation shall, as a condition of employment, annually participate in and complete such training program. For purposes of the preceding sentence, participation in such training program may not be considered complete for the year involved until the individual satisfies each requirement, including testing, if applicable, of the training program for such year, as specified by the Secretary.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H1F9C925D9DE14877AC084B44EBF1D114"><enum>109.</enum><header>Staffing demonstration project</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VIII of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1671">25 U.S.C. 1671</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07E49BEB3F9A43169524FA621C059726" style="OLC">
					<section id="HEDCAF0A846674B629A462E6BAE839ED2"><enum>833.</enum><header>Staffing demonstration project</header>
 <subsection id="H3F83C929CD3746389617621A9CFC93D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Service, shall establish a demonstration project that authorizes the Service to provide federally managed Service units with additional staffing resources with the goal that the resources become self-sustaining.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC692A822466246FA975AF5BA85C5CEA4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>In selecting Service units for participation, the Secretary shall consider whether a Service unit services an Indian tribe that—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HC95B06CD300540A7BCB8EEE2C31F1AB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has utilized or contributed substantial tribal funds to construct a health facility used by the Service or identified in the master plan for the Service unit;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7686D7D8BBED4480BB89B5E32E2D6601"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is located in a State or States with Medicaid reimbursements plans or policies that will increase the likelihood that the staffing resources provided will be self-sustaining; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H25B96DD220304466AEE76FDDE80F7CC2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is operating a health facility described in paragraph (1) under historical staffing ratios that have not been equalized or updated by the Service or any other Service program to reflect current staffing needs.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H870E3815C4614863B95288FC8DA67E1B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Staffing resources provided to a Service unit under this section shall be for a duration that the Secretary, in consultation with the applicable Indian tribe, determines appropriate, except that each staffing position provided shall be for a period of not less than 3 fiscal years.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA375DF636868460CB070E7329AEB1A84"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the Secretary ends the demonstration project under this section, the Secretary shall prepare and submit a report to the Committee on Indian Affairs and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, and the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, regarding the project, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEE7E49A9AEA14212B290A7DB76453DAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>whether the staffing resources resulted in additional revenue for the Service unit sufficient to maintain the staff on a permanent basis;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9ED44B0D38034943BB92C702DFA5565F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the levels to which the staffing resources reduced the unmet staffing need for the Service unit; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H566ED62E27264E569390E97995693378"><enum>(3)</enum><text>whether the demonstration project could be deployed to reduce unmet staffing needs throughout the Service.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HC48096AE60F44267831A0F3F94C5935D"><enum>110.</enum><header>Rule establishing tribal consultation policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VIII of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1671">25 U.S.C. 1671</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by section 109, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H68514FD9BE49452F88911A32DF65BF83" style="OLC">
					<section id="HB51BA21527CE4605ACBF1301ABD9148A"><enum>834.</enum><header>Rule establishing tribal consultation policy</header>
 <subsection id="H46C7A95623B24FB48B24502E5FE311BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the Restoring Accountability in the Indian Health Service Act of 2017, the Secretary shall establish, through the negotiated rulemaking process described in subsection (b), a rule establishing a tribal consultation policy for the Service.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H002535721DDA4689A994E16373D8265A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Negotiated rulemaking</header><text>Before publishing a proposed rule described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall follow the provisions of subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Negotiated Rulemaking Act of 1990</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAB944A784B734E9EB7977ECF00D6DE75"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents of tribal consultation policy</header><text>The policy established under the rule described in subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H4D6E38C71B12487C9DF45295AABE0BBE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>update, and replace, the tribal consultation policy established under Circular No. 2006–01 of the Service, or any successor policy; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF18E69E06C74405AAD7B0424FE21C39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HF09497C0B6144AC8BEAE1796B9650D03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A process for determining when the Service will notify Indian tribes, and a description of how the Indian tribes should be notified.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F477DB13E1644628132661F1C17A9B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A determination of what actions or agency decisions by the Service will trigger a requirement for meaningful consultation with Indian tribes.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69262EDCA60C40DD8261311600B474FF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A determination of what actions constitute meaningful consultation with Indian tribes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section></title><title id="HE10B1DFEDC464B5FAE4CB8CD817A36AF"><enum>II</enum><header>Employee protections</header> <section id="H470FD33D4C3941FABEB93CACA67B4906"><enum>201.</enum><header>Right of Federal employees to petition Congress</header> <subsection id="H627DC126642E4302801F9D1B25E1B30A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Adverse action for violation of right To petition Congress</header><text>Section 7211 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD977DBC878984CCBBDD216DCA089849E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The right of</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In general</header-in-text>.—The right of</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E034DE29FE24A489AF8A62D0744EE06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E36AD22EB574025BD45742B4D55D891" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H7B897FFF920842A9B160107C18C73C11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adverse action</header><text>An employee who interferes with or denies a right protected under subsection (a) shall be subject to any adverse action described in paragraphs (1) through (5) of section 7512, in accordance with the procedure described in section 7513 and any other applicable procedure.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6DF5B4519114792A654A19D6FC39638"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Electronic notification of right of employees of Indian Health Service</header>
 <paragraph id="HB4D8F2C78F8F4581B80DA0F6DC7D6B41"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), acting through the Director of the Indian Health Service, shall, in accordance with paragraphs (2) through (6), provide to each employee of the Indian Health Service, and electronically post, a memorandum providing notice of the right to petition Congress under section 7211 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A3C2589388149269E37466DFC3972F9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The memorandum described in paragraph (1) shall include the following statement: <quote>It is a violation of section 7211 of title 5, United States Code, for any Federal agency or employee to require a Federal employee to seek approval, guidance, or any other form of input prior to contacting Congress with information, even if that information is in relation to the job responsibilities of the employee. A Federal employee found to have interfered with or denied the right of another Federal employee under such section shall be subject to an adverse action described in paragraphs (1) through (5) of section 7512 of title 5, United States Code, including a suspension for more than 14 days without pay.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD10198AFA9A24FF9B5B8CB856C24275E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit the memorandum described in paragraph (1) to the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Inspector General</quote>) for approval.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99621B5DECB8469B96B8FD8920532809"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Approval or disapproval</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the submission of the memorandum under paragraph (3), or a revised memorandum under paragraph (6), the Inspector General shall approve or disapprove the memorandum or revised memorandum, as the case may be.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFFC0A473E5114FA48A2E24FB77E638E0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>In the case of an approval under paragraph (4), not later than 30 days after such approval, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5EC682DE948E4CDC89AFFB74448C552D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide to each employee of the Indian Health Service an electronic copy of the approved memorandum; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71C7D5B6CF3445AA9A655CBA60D3C5DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>post such memorandum in a clear and conspicuous place on the website of the Indian Health Service for a period not less than 120 days.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H974FC6F3CE954A07A49AE91F82945D01"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Revised memorandum</header><text>In the case of a disapproval under paragraph (4), not later than 15 days after such disapproval, the Secretary shall submit a revised memorandum to the Inspector General for approval under paragraph (4).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1E80F3D222BB45C491CBCA89F07D6B03"><enum>202.</enum><header>Fiscal accountability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VI of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1661">25 U.S.C. 1661</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by sections 105 and 106 is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B9003B7ABEC44A6BCB48D3116140BE7" style="OLC">
					<section id="HFE4A9AA34FD24604B09D16859396F321"><enum>607.</enum><header>Fiscal accountability</header>
						<subsection id="H97AE00055E484DD7AC761AACC99E682A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Management of funds</header>
 <paragraph id="HBF8453EAE6BB486B82D31CCFCD669B79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Secretary fails to submit the professional housing plan under section 301(a) of the <short-title>Restoring Accountability in the Indian Health Service Act of 2017</short-title> or the staffing plan under section 301(b) of that Act, the Secretary may not receive, obligate, transfer, or expend any amounts for a salary increase or bonus of an individual described in paragraph (2) until the professional housing plan or staffing plan, as the case may be, is submitted.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H538B9741D228441599D4292973F6A567"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individual described</header><text>An individual described in this paragraph is an individual employed in a position in the Service that is a position—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6A79E4581D9A46FC8D693593A4548874"><enum>(A)</enum><text>described under sections 5312 through 5316 of title 5, United States Code;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB62C74D2CAD42C28D64617105EA40FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>placed in level IV or V of the Executive Schedule under section 5317 of title 5, United States Code;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7F95C61BACA49DB8E13208ABF8E0B8E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as a limited term appointee, limited emergency appointee, or noncareer appointee in the Senior Executive Service, as defined under paragraphs (5), (6), and (7), respectively, of section 3132(a) of title 5, United States Code; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A9C82B1B1D144E8B607896939F74DEE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>under section 213.3301 or 213.3302 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H33EF1EC08A8E41D89BFCB248FB657E37"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prioritization of patient care</header> <paragraph id="H1573B8D417454B15B1ABCFB268C33AF0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall use amounts available to the Indian Health Service that are not obligated or expended, including base budget funding and third party collections, during the fiscal year for which the amounts are made available, and that remain available, only to support patient care by using such funds for the costs of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H80D762314FA4470ABE62A4E18BBAF364"><enum>(A)</enum><text>essential medical equipment;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CEBCC243BED447183861499E4F4322E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>purchased or referred care; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3444CAC477B64FDA9597A406487D5EA2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>staffing.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1298CB11B2364013BE6AB2F6A5D564A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>In using amounts under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall ensure that, in any case where the amounts were originally made available for a particular Service unit, such amounts are used to benefit Indians served by that Service unit.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA76966FBE9442F3A383E1BE3B7F30BD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Restrictions</header><text>The Secretary may not use amounts described in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H9D6D7AB18E0B40479ECA69C232753757"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to remodel or interior decorate any Area office; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H947A936A59714A0AB47D3EFF49A75982"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to increase the rate of pay of any employee of an Area office.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5A5C8C85F04B4BEC84E0A946667CD976"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Spending reports</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the end of each quarter of a fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit a report describing the authorizations, expenditures, outlays, transfers, reprogramming, and obligations of each level of the Service, including the headquarters, each Area office, each Service unit, and each health clinic or facility, to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDDE972ADEED547B397B3956C1C3A2B3B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each Indian tribe;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H05834DFBBEC84699BFD5942A42ED6C8B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the Senate—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8BB2696528EE46CEAC18161297EA1EC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Indian Affairs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9189F89EAFE347469432989BAAE8EBCA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0ED5DC64D4349E4BAF1D765638B2C2A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8362ADC7B4E4F98AD9D76932648FB8A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on the Budget; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H427B16DE7AFD48F69B5835434817F6C2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the House of Representatives—</text> <subparagraph id="HBD1710E17FF04F5CB167A40BE45D5DBD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6024EA1DA6D45C5A57F8BBB64F14543"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACEC5955CB2A4D2687855AFCC0D4FC0D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C39012994AE49ABB1F6F3F54E21BF77"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on the Budget.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H261888A03A3B4AEFA9E1F803FAE6983C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Status reports</header> <paragraph id="H3C6D2EC7DE104D5BA728FFD5CC4E5AD4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), not later than 180 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Secretary shall provide to each entity described in paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (c) a report describing the safety, billing, certification, credential, and compliance statuses of each facility managed, operated, or otherwise supported by the Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0F05D46112C4C909493F813DCC167DE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>With respect to any change of a status described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall immediately provide to each entity described in paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (c) an update describing such change.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H339D5BFBF8B54A3B8C5F0C776D16874C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>This section may not be construed to inhibit the authority of an Indian tribe to enter into or maintain a compact or contract under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref> et seq.).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="HF54B2D2AEF6941C49CDC382A667A0B50" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <section id="HB1CC6BBAF4AF441DBA421976D2216E91"><enum>301.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph id="H97097561176A4A8EA386B062E41754B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H95522D25EF7947CFBDA4E3BA9F4A9FAF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Service</header><text>The term <term>Service</term> means the Indian Health Service.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H52B7FADCD8DD43BF849D5B85A6B6C0AC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Service unit</header><text>The term <term>Service unit</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1603">25 U.S.C. 1603</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="H5EC34B06E1ED4A878675588DEC9EDF22"><enum>302.</enum><header>Reports by the Secretary of Health and Human Services</header>
 <subsection id="HC9C0638832BA40298EA2E6EEFF9F95E4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>IHS Professional housing plan</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall develop, make publicly available, and submit to Congress and the Comptroller General of the United States a written plan to address the professional housing needs of employees of the Service that comports with the practices and recommendations of the Government Accountability Office relating to professional housing.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3B1BD62E08A347B5A625D93D2AD19DE0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan relating to IHS staffing needs</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall develop, make publicly available, and submit to Congress and the Comptroller General of the United States a written plan to address staffing needs in the Service that comports with the practices of the Government Accountability Office relating to workforce planning.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE819AC40FA634BDDAE71763298915D99"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Indian Health Care Improvement Act report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and each year thereafter for a period of 5 years, the Secretary shall develop, make publicly available, and submit to Congress a report on the data submitted under section 412(b) of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act, as amended by section 107.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H36860E1CF2644579BF779C903A73C4A9"><enum>303.</enum><header>Reports by the Comptroller General</header>
				<subsection id="H5E64E8015F86455B87B7A43513D45D15"><enum>(a)</enum><header>IHS Housing needs report</header>
 <paragraph id="HA861C8048EE04430BE58DDBFF9199992"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Comptroller General of the United States receives the professional housing plan under section 302(a), the Comptroller General shall develop and submit to Congress a report on the professional housing needs of employees of the Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE3978AC5F9CE429CA4C5A4CE53E58A0D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H827F8293821747488DCDE73037E03EB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An evaluation of any existing, as of the date of the report, assessments and projections for the professional housing needs of employees of the Service, including discussion and conclusion as to whether existing assessments and projections accurately reflect the professional housing needs of employees of the Service.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC09A164D5DEC45B3B5C0E9FAE22B95A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An assessment of the professional housing needs of employees of the Service for each Service area (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1603">25 U.S.C. 1603</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57068FA9EC7E4990A67B159AC9CE4B74"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of the professional housing plan developed by the Secretary under section 302(a).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H340F6B74678F475DBB9ED160F1168474"><enum>(b)</enum><header>IHS staffing needs report</header> <paragraph id="H248830DDC9B64319A526EDBAE6DA4218"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Comptroller General receives the report under section 302(b) of this Act, the Comptroller General shall prepare and submit to Congress a report on the staffing needs of the Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4DFD98330D3429A9327FFDB61406C80"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H73AF884095F64070B54DDE9BAA6E3736"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the number and type of full-time positions needed at each facility of the Service and the amount of funds necessary to maintain such positions.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D068A1267ED4F219B520D3B94A32375"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An assessment of the use of independent contractors, including the number of independent contractors hired to fill vacant full-time positions and amounts spent on independent contractors who provide health care services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52449818A75A47EB9D70F61655785838"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of the staffing plan developed by the Secretary under section 302(b).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C02CE5EB1864F70A9C2EE615B42AE24"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Whistleblower protections report</header> <paragraph id="H3A37D70013C842808E77A3AEAFAB2DE4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall develop and submit to Congress a report on the efficacy of existing protections for whistleblowers in the Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D6CF5592C1E4080965E9FEDFC084A87"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HA98100F17EFD4862B49A481CC85D96D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A discussion and conclusion as to whether the Service has taken proper steps to prevent retaliation against whistleblowers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEDA84D505BE416C8A722E729A8538F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If applicable, any recommendations for changes to the policy of the Service with respect to whistleblowers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC60076A5CBE1475182C0DB54C8D30D39"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A discussion and conclusion as to whether the official email accounts of employees of the Service are appropriately monitored.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0FC6E38D292B4E97857FB04BBD42ACDC"><enum>304.</enum><header>Inspector General reports</header>
				<subsection id="H296CD29EB5D0483587216460E2339F13"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Patient care reports</header>
 <paragraph id="H0ECFA9DB3C3340008AE7B9CFF99E5D44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services shall develop and submit to Congress and the Service a report on patient harm events occurring in Service units and deferrals and denials of care of patients of the Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BECFBD0FBAE42CCB65CB8100C4AFB92"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H0C77E934AA87490AADDF1AA066FBCD34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An evaluation of the number and kind of events that contribute to patient deaths in a Service unit and recommendations regarding reducing the number of patient deaths.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE7C838DBAE545B9A7A8834C2D8A95FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An evaluation of the Service’s tracking and reporting of, and response to, patient harm events and recommendations regarding how to improve such tracking, reporting, and response.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41F974B547E840A6B8F119FDA0F4A09B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The effects of deferrals and denials of care on patients of the Service, including patient outcomes, and recommendations regarding how to reduce deferrals and denials of care.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31AFAA88572342CC84D3712AD73AB1C1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting systems audit</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Inspector General shall—</text> <paragraph id="H8082E45AEC3048C38F77408BFFC1FEEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct an audit of reporting systems of the Service, as of the date of enactment of this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBFC204AB446045B285353C988744729F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide to the Service recommendations and technical assistance regarding implementation of improved reporting systems, procedures, standards, and protocols.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6A3D80D3FBEB4D0A87D0529241A47D5C"><enum>305.</enum><header>Transparency in CMS surveys</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1880 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395qq">42 U.S.C. 1395qq</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB4C83D46BEFE4892A7F40CDB0C9AB295" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H73FBDA84C1D54CC2995AD53F410E705A"><enum>(g)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF6B1453FC0DF4F6A99483A09300ECD25"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not less frequently than once every 2 years, the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services shall conduct surveys to assess the compliance of each hospital or skilled nursing facility of the Indian Health Service with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H37296F420DD94E5E99BF6203A08871B8" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 1867; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04FEE2A268D742E8A8A46855D94CF0FB" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conditions of participation in the program under this title.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEAA89835BF5428DBB8C30EBEDAAABCF" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Each survey completed under this subsection shall be posted on the Internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services. Such posting shall comply with the Federal regulations concerning the privacy of individually identifiable health information promulgated under section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="H7B6637BD32064DC1982FF74712CE4BFF"><enum>IV</enum><header>Technical amendments</header>
 <section id="H7D3F884B179A45FB88F133114AC4E688"><enum>401.</enum><header>Technical amendments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1601">25 U.S.C. 1601</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1B9E5E036C2A4A8E9DAAA2712C25E7FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>contract health service</quote> each place such term appears (regardless of casing and typeface and including in the headings) and inserting <quote>purchased/referred care</quote> (with appropriate casing and typeface); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCCD258978C9B486CA1B893A9E0594513"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>contract health services</quote> each place such term appears (regardless of casing and typeface and including in the headings) and inserting <quote>purchased/referred care</quote> (with appropriate casing and typeface).</text>
				</paragraph></section></title></legis-body></bill>


