<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H59D6803B17D34F6D852B786D22A2E1CF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2145 IH: No Russia Exemptions for Oil Production Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2145</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170425">April 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit licenses or other authorization for United States persons to engage in activities
			 relating to deepwater, Arctic offshore, or shale projects that have the
			 potential to produce oil in the Russian Federation, or in maritime area
			 claimed by the Russian Federation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5EB0FAB38E6F477F8D369ADA53867B76" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA711E65E34354C11985BE801FA464072" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Russia Exemptions for Oil Production Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>No REX Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H463A0CBF1D5246BBBDC6DA7620A5FDD0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on licenses or other authorization for United States persons to engage in activities relating to certain projects to produce oil in the Russian Federation</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H5EEA05A9EC8E4FC19FB30FC5C943C4FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective as of the date of the enactment of this Act—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H01152E7EDBCB421AABC222D243421CD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of the Treasury, acting directly or through any specifically designated person, agency, or instrumentality, may not provide a license or other authorization pursuant to Directive 4 under Executive Order 13662 to engage in any of the activities prohibited under such Directive; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H125CE02B641B497BAE69F88C54B1A844"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any license or other authorization provided before such date of enactment by the Secretary of the Treasury, acting directly or through any specifically designated person, agency, or instrumentality, pursuant to Directive 4 under Executive Order 13662 to engage in any of the activities prohibited under such Directive shall have no force or effect.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3648F259F54849BCA0887B5A92211C23"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>Directive 4 under Executive Order 13662</quote> means Directive 4 of September 12, 2014, under Executive Order 13662 of March 20, 2014 (79 Fed. Reg. 16169; relating to Blocking Property of Additional Persons Contributing to the Situation in Ukraine) or any successor Directive or other Executive action.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


