<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H57A208B4EE2D4AF7B23606C348CD87D6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2459 IH: Transnational Criminal Organization Exploitation Threat Assessment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2459</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170516">May 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a threat assessment regarding the exploitation by transnational criminal organizations
			 of the unaccompanied alien children services program within the United
			 States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4A783D24D42C46739E3A2A1FF552F3EB" style="OLC">
 <section id="H973F587880C942BEAADC325D65FDAD83" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transnational Criminal Organization Exploitation Threat Assessment Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H37A89E9665224EE698E786245B530992"><enum>2.</enum><header>Threat assessment</header> <subsection id="H879DA35BDF0A44D2A00755C46849A66F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security, shall conduct a threat assessment of the exploitation by transnational criminal organizations of the unaccompanied alien children services program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H154D23D669D34EA4A138389330410A24"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In preparing the threat assessment required under subsection (a), the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security shall consult with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Attorney General, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Director of National Intelligence, and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, to ensure that such threat assessment is informed by current information about homeland security threats posed by transnational criminal organizations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD570C9B3A54944E9AE739B46DE122C38"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>Upon completion of the threat assessment required under subsection (a), the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall make a determination if any changes are required to address security vulnerabilities identified in such assessment that are exploited by transnational criminal organizations in the unaccompanied alien children services program. If changes to the unaccompanied alien children services program are required, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall direct the Department of Homeland Security component agencies, including U.S. Customs and Border Protection and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, to address such vulnerabilities, as appropriate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBE468EF9C4A743179BB47911B94D133D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon completion of the threat assessment required under subsection (a), the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security shall disseminate such threat assessment to Federal partners, including the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Attorney General, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Director of National Intelligence, and State and local partners, including State, local, and regional fusion centers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF81ADF9EFE0E47A7BBD8B7A74AB3DE9F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H97473C9D09EA420BA738CD956567A0DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Transnational criminal organization</header><text>The term <quote>transnational criminal organization</quote> means a group of persons that includes one or more foreign persons that engages in an ongoing pattern of serious criminal activity involving the jurisdictions of at least two foreign countries and that threatens the national security, foreign policy, or economy of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H11DA35EC566C487B975238CABF5BA369"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unaccompanied alien children services program</header><text>The term <quote>unaccompanied alien children service program</quote> means the program described in section 462 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/279">6 U.S.C. 279</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

