<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB45409F602E4417DA4035B9607C34642" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3651 IH: To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a feasibility study on renovating or replacing the Lyndon B. Johnson Tropical Medical Center with a new or updated facility.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-08-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3651</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170811">August 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a feasibility study on
			 renovating or replacing the Lyndon B. Johnson Tropical Medical Center with
			 a new or updated facility.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1BB9CD787D9647B2A81A7D5F87FC6559" style="OLC">
		<section id="H5D2BB80A45F3408CA80A6F56DDDFCB0E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>GAO feasibility study on renovating or replacing the Lyndon B. Johnson Tropical Medical Center with
			 a new or updated facility</header>
 <subsection id="H31BC13C7F16A4969BD636237294A1BF6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall conduct a study to evaluate the feasibility of, and costs to the Federal Government and local government associated with, renovating or replacing the Lyndon B. Johnson Tropical Medical Center with a new or updated facility.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3D19FA99E4D04D309B227FC1FB3C0991"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report containing the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a). Such report shall include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7D2F0CB1555D47DB9E50980C35533508"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The cost to equip the facility with everything necessary to meet relevant care standards required by the Department of Veterans Affairs, Department of Defense, and Department of Health and Human Services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H378951E6D0B34278A6825B17D6B28C15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The cost of renovations as compared to the cost of an entire replacement of the facility.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D62AC553E344A54BE48C398CEE3A262"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The cost of expansions and renovations necessary to meet the healthcare demands of the territory.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA025286C313249F488CC2B9FD0832429"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The feasibility of making the center a teaching hospital.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB378082D9B0943DA89E08A813187DB05"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The ability to include a research center at the facility for studying tropical diseases.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96FA2254DF964445B2BBB6FC08557639"><enum>(6)</enum><text>How improvements to the facility compare to the long term cost of off-island care.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA2C1A54C2D14EBFA9BA8365095AF21E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The feasibility and cost of a program that would help pay for medical students to perform their residency at the facility.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED3681A5DD5A4A5884DB09155CE73B2D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The suitability of the location for a new facility.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

