<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7BE943122A744FD188DFC04BA2427B54" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3838 IH: Trust Preferred Securities Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3838</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170926">September 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000614">Mr. Duffy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000388">Mr. Kelly of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001045">Mr. Harper</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000491">Mr. Lucas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the appropriate Federal banking agencies to treat certain non-significant investments in
			 the capital of unconsolidated financial institutions as qualifying capital
			 instruments, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA6CD8D678DB5418295A0FE8F557F38A0" style="OLC">
 <section id="H78323C885F9D45F2A3826D07539D9D3A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Trust Preferred Securities Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2DE3525FE257461589B141D459D7FCE1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of certain non-significant investments in the capital of unconsolidated financial institutions</header> <subsection id="H1DD5A45392624D88BCB7213D7E2673C1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 18 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1828">12 U.S.C. 1828</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB2129F455321403CAA851A61A2930F93"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by moving subsection (z) so that it appears after subsection (y); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9158943C2F8C42D1AF7F0D840DDBB8EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7382559DB66742D6B38FCF4DE7537943" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HAB11DB5C0D244EC1874BB73AE85300A4"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Treatment of non-Significant investments in the capital of unconsolidated financial institutions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the final rules titled <quote>Regulatory Capital Rules: Regulatory Capital, Implementation of Basel III, Capital Adequacy, Transition Provisions, Prompt Corrective Action, Standardized Approach for Risk-weighted Assets, Market Discipline and Disclosure Requirements, Advanced Approaches Risk-Based Capital Rule, and Market Risk Capital Rule</quote> (78 Fed. Reg. 62018; published Oct. 11, 2013, and 79 Fed. Reg. 20754; published April 14, 2014) and any other regulation which incorporates a definition of the term <quote>non-significant investments in the capital of unconsolidated financial institutions</quote>, the appropriate Federal banking agencies shall provide that investments in trust preferred securities (pooled and individual instruments) by a depository institution or a depository institution holding company shall not be subject to deduction from the regulatory capital of such depository institution or depository institution holding company or any depository institution holding company of such an institution, provided such investments were held prior to July 21, 2010.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF378D558485948EAA4647851D3619575"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendment to Basel III Capital Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 3-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and the Comptroller of the Currency shall amend the final rules titled <quote>Regulatory Capital Rules: Regulatory Capital, Implementation of Basel III, Capital Adequacy, Transition Provisions, Prompt Corrective Action, Standardized Approach for Risk-weighted Assets, Market Discipline and Disclosure Requirements, Advanced Approaches Risk-Based Capital Rule, and Market Risk Capital Rule</quote> (78 Fed. Reg. 62018; published Oct. 11, 2013, and 79 Fed. Reg. 20754; published April 14, 2014) to implement the amendments made by this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


