<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2297FC54B1DD41248C9E00325AC5417A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1912 IH: Black Lung Benefits Improvement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1912</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170405">April 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure that claims for benefits under the Black Lung Benefits Act are processed in a fair and
			 timely manner, to better protect miners from pneumoconiosis (commonly
			 known as <quote>black lung disease</quote>), and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB011D9F3E33C4D369CBF28E6A78EAE9A" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC8552161828249EF9316BE1EBC9F13C0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Black Lung Benefits Improvement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section commented="no" id="H55B3870E825E46D18BE048F4BE731BEA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
			<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
				<toc-entry idref="HC8552161828249EF9316BE1EBC9F13C0" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H55B3870E825E46D18BE048F4BE731BEA" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HE5BE5F9276CD482F8FCE8089390A38A7" level="section">Sec. 3. Findings.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HEE23562F621B477A9C8C364FEEF582D7" level="title">Title I—Black lung benefits</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H520F57829656499086DD5F37AD2C05DF" level="part">Part A—Improving the process for filing and adjudicating claims for benefits</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H60D00B86F1714FF9B860F715C29A30D8" level="section">Sec. 101. Mandatory disclosure of medical information and reports.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HBFA45AD0948A4C309C9095EE24034FBE" level="section">Sec. 102. Attorneys’ fees and medical expenses payment program.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HA70F922774754B6F8F5A2C66612AF0A2" level="section">Sec. 103. Clarifying eligibility for black lung benefits.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H458B4CE300E049488DF4D0C32D514528" level="section">Sec. 104. Restoring adequate benefit adjustments for miners suffering from black lung disease and
			 for their dependent family members.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H4D6A1537099D44F2B6D3AD51AC8AC7A4" level="section">Sec. 105. Treatment of evidence in equipoise.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HCC0F06799DCA43F9B489CDE547B59B03" level="section">Sec. 106. Providing assistance with claims for miners and their dependent family members.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H778327BFF705454ABF61A842AEC2B59F" level="section">Sec. 107. False statements or misrepresentations, attorney disqualification, and discovery
			 sanctions.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HB2C32C8547C041FE92CB32BDE4B31A16" level="section">Sec. 108. Development of medical evidence by the Secretary.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H975A1DF633504D14A962BA84F8CA25E9" level="section">Sec. 109. Establishment of pilot program to provide impartial classifications of chest radiographs.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H49E0FADE1510496D83BAC7011C74CEBB" level="section">Sec. 110. Medical evidence training program.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H938048B3C53B4523B159D781474F4390" level="section">Sec. 111. Technical and conforming amendments.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H7314D7CD0FE146148A9F8721182B28C4" level="section">Sec. 112. Readjudicating cases involving certain chest radiographs.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H10E597B859DB4E7E8AB1C19B85EEA6A8" level="section">Sec. 113. Disclosure of employment and earnings information for Black Lung benefits claims.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HE02937B0C7034508AF352B8C0F0E71B0" level="part">Part B—Reports To improve the administration of benefits under the Black Lung Benefits Act</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H41FFAC9DF929461B92AC524BE6080F46" level="section">Sec. 121. Strategy to reduce delays in adjudication.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H8B1A0BD1A5EF4223B9C1A54ACDF7ADD1" level="section">Sec. 122. GAO report on black lung program.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H45E3091B1318410C95E35631DE9DFDC9" level="title">Title II—Standard for respirable dust concentration</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H14A720409E304711BB36CCD8A3B4011C" level="section">Sec. 201. Standard for respirable dust concentration.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HC7EA7B06F56144FD931B9A9C12259AEF" level="title">Title III—Establishing the Office of Workers' Compensation Programs</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H3EFF35BCEE274FCC8B8A3AF959BB4CEA" level="section">Sec. 301. Office of Workers' Compensation Programs.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H596F7706CB6B4DBD84B7CDF0A0FBBC5B" level="title">Title IV—Severability</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HCB5F6B9208FD492087C8BABA9990EA73" level="section">Sec. 401. Severability.</toc-entry></toc>
 </section><section commented="no" id="HE5BE5F9276CD482F8FCE8089390A38A7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H4D2A0399DB814CACB43549C0DAE30BB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/901">30 U.S.C. 901</external-xref> et seq.) was enacted to provide health care and modest benefits to coal miners who develop pneumoconiosis (referred to in this section as <quote>black lung disease</quote>) resulting from exposure to coal dust during their employment. Yet the determination of a claimant's eligibility for these benefits often requires complex, adversarial litigation. Resource disparities between coal companies and such claimants are widespread within the statutory and regulatory framework of such Act. Comprehensive reforms are necessary to ensure that coal miners are not at a disadvantage when filing claims for benefits.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H26FE3C0C071D4C3A929DEBBEE78F6369"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Government Accountability Office has found that many claimants under the Black Lung Benefits Act are not equipped with the medical and legal resources necessary to develop evidence to meet the requirements for benefits. Miners often lack complete and reliable medical evidence, consequently increasing the risk that the individuals who review claims for benefits will be presented with insufficient medical evidence. Similarly, without better options for legal representation, significant numbers of such claimants proceed with their claims through a complex and potentially long administrative process without resources that Department of Labor officials and black lung disease experts note are important for developing evidence and supporting their claims. Only 33 percent of claimants are represented by an attorney during the initial claims determination. Absent efforts to remedy administrative problems and address structural weaknesses in the process for obtaining benefits, claimants with meritorious claims will not receive benefits.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H28C85133815A44A28DB9DCF51771F09B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Full exchange and disclosure between the parties of relevant medical information is essential for fair adjudication of claims under the Black Lung Benefits Act, regardless of whether the parties intend to submit such information into evidence. Records of adjudications reveal that some mine operators’ legal representatives have withheld relevant evidence from claimants, administrative law judges, and, in some cases, even their own medical experts. In several cases, the disclosure of such evidence would have substantiated a miner’s claim for benefits. Withholding medical information can endanger miners by depriving them of important information about their own health and the potential need to seek medical treatment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C040CF224B24E6F91F7194FB2D382BC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Given the remedial nature of the Black Lung Benefits Act, when an adjudicator determines that evidence is evenly balanced, it is appropriate for any resulting doubt to be resolved in favor of the claimant. The Supreme Court vacated this longstanding legal principle, not on substantive grounds, but because its application conflicted with the requirements of another statute. Such principle needs to be reinstated in the Black Lung Benefits Act because it provides fairness and improves the administration of benefits.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2DD48E38DCC4C17B70F09285BFA378F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Physicians who read lung x-rays as part of pulmonary assessments used in proceedings for claims under the Black Lung Benefits Act are required to demonstrate competency in classifying chest radiographs by becoming certified as B Readers by the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (referred to in this section as <quote>NIOSH</quote>). However, investigations have uncovered that there are NIOSH-certified B Readers who have systematically misclassified chest radiographs while employed by coal operators or their law firms for the purpose of opposing claims under such Act. In response, the Department of Labor has directed claims examiners <quote>not to credit negative chest x-ray readings for pneumoconiosis</quote> by one widely used physician employed at a prominent medical center unless the conclusions of such physician <quote>have been rehabilitated</quote>. Where chest radiographs are needed to establish entitlement to benefits, claimants should have access to accurate interpretations so as to ensure the fair adjudication of such claims.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H44642147700442B4BB42E7722B8A04B3"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As of the date of enactment of this Act, more than one year has passed since survivors were denied benefits on claims under the Black Lung Benefits Act that involved the consideration of chest radiograph interpretations rendered by a certain physician whose interpretations have since been determined by the Department of Labor to be generally not worthy of credit. Such survivors should be permitted to file a new claim for benefits under such Act. However, a survivor is effectively barred from filing a new claim one year after a decision regarding such benefits is final, constituting an injustice that merits a remedy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H559F079370AC49AB936BFD979AA702FA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Between the calendar years 2004 and 2014, a reduction in the number of administrative law judges in the Department of Labor, coupled with a large increase in the number of cases filed under the Black Lung Benefits Act, cuts to nondefense discretionary spending, furloughs resulting from sequestration, and the 16-day shutdown of the Federal Government during the calendar year 2013, has created extensive delays in adjudicating claims under such Act and numerous other labor and employment laws. Due to the imbalance between resources and caseloads, a typical claim under such Act remains unresolved for an average of nearly 2 years prior to a decision by an administrative law judge. These delays directly and severely impact the lives of workers throughout the United States, placing an undue financial and emotional burden on the affected individuals and their families.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E3BBDE603E9402497822D9B94C44900"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Contrary to the intent of Congress, benefits payments under the Black Lung Benefits Act do not automatically increase with the rising cost of living. Benefit payments are tied to the monthly pay rate for Federal employees in grade GS–2, step 1. In several of the fiscal years prior to the enactment of this Act, there was a pay freeze for Federal employees, which had the effect of eliminating cost-of-living adjustments for miners, surviving spouses, and dependents under the Black Lung Benefits Act during such years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD6CB6353C25B4197A6440A510FCDEF77"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A competent assessment of medical information and testimony, which often involves multiple physicians disputing a diagnosis, is necessary in determining whether to award benefits under the Black Lung Benefits Act. To ensure that a determination regarding a claim for benefits under such Act is fair and accurate, regular training is needed regarding—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCE3A71D3FD594317BD14F03CA7730BE8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>developments in pulmonary medicine relating to black lung disease;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBED20CF5B580465696C4E6EC125A244B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>medical evidence necessary to sustain claims for such benefits; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B061B9EF55B4BD286DA99CBA4E6FCC5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the proper weight to be given to conflicting evidence.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD814CF005BE9477CA4262E181B4E4BC3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Black lung disease has been the underlying or contributing cause of death of more than 76,000 miners since 1968. After decades of decline, the incidence of coal miners with black lung disease is on the rise. According to NIOSH, miners are developing advanced cases of the disease at younger ages. In response, the Department of Labor has taken important steps to combat the disease, including promulgating a rule that reduces the allowed concentration of coal dust and eliminates weaknesses in the current dust sampling system. Retrospective studies should be continued to determine whether revisions to the standards are necessary to eliminate the disease.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8EC605EB89F94E8CB504B40337270082"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To eliminate an avoidable delay in evaluating claims under such Act, the Department of Labor’s Inspector General has recommended legislation that would authorize the Department of Labor to have electronic access to miners’ earning records held by the Social Security Administration.</text>
			</paragraph></section><title id="HEE23562F621B477A9C8C364FEEF582D7" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Black lung benefits</header>
			<part id="H520F57829656499086DD5F37AD2C05DF" style="OLC"><enum>A</enum><header>Improving the process for filing and adjudicating claims for benefits</header>
 <section id="H60D00B86F1714FF9B860F715C29A30D8"><enum>101.</enum><header>Mandatory disclosure of medical information and reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part A of the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/901">30 U.S.C. 901</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1049C7B31D6462BB38AEC9317A3F62D" style="OLC">
						<section id="H0A7978A3637246B5ACA74B94833B4A05"><enum>403.</enum><header>Mandatory medical information disclosure</header>
 <subsection id="H3E9B0D0A10614539A5E3D2CF87084055"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text>In any claim for benefits under this title, an operator that requires a miner to submit to a medical examination regarding the miner’s respiratory or pulmonary condition shall, not later than 21 days after the miner has been examined, deliver to the claimant a complete copy of the examining physician’s report. The examining physician’s report shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6FE19279263C44D1806B20074AC8480B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be in writing; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD26547667AE745CBBDCC698AA654D07A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>set out in detail the findings of such physician, including any diagnoses and conclusions, the results of any diagnostic imaging tests, and any other tests performed on the miner.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H28037086532649788054DC43BE0D8E66"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any claim for benefits under this title, each party shall provide all other parties in the proceeding with a copy of all medical information developed regarding the miner’s physical condition relating to such claim, even if the party does not intend to submit the information as evidence. Such medical information shall include the opinion of any examining physician, and any examining or nonexamining physician’s interpretations of radiographs or pathology.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7B3D9649E34D4B6684FAAC30E982D7EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall promulgate regulations regarding the disclosure of medical information under this section, and such regulations may establish sanctions for noncompliance with this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HBFA45AD0948A4C309C9095EE24034FBE"><enum>102.</enum><header>Attorneys’ fees and medical expenses payment program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part A of the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/901">30 U.S.C. 901</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by section 101, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEDF1650840B54F919025D8C862CFD05D" style="OLC">
						<section id="H49CD2019046C4DCE948670E8E0E81BBA"><enum>404.</enum><header>Attorneys’ fees and medical expenses payment program</header>
							<subsection id="HEA579F84A88E4007B27DA287DADEDDA4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program established</header>
 <paragraph id="HB59E729307364355A8B05A57562A8F86"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Black Lung Benefits Improvement Act of 2017</short-title>, the Secretary shall establish a payment program to pay attorneys’ fees and other reasonable and unreimbursed medical expenses incurred in establishing the claimant’s case, using amounts from the fund, to the attorneys of claimants in qualifying claims.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E3322FF94484EB5A2ABA2C020F61564"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifying claim</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A qualifying claim for purposes of this section is a contested claim for benefits under this title for which a final order has not been entered within one year of the filing of the claim.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H938111583ADB4F03BE0E6BDD39401DBD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of payments from the fund</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, amounts in the fund shall be available for payments authorized by the Secretary under this section.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H907F43859BB8403F9A1A8E18B119A9D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payments authorized</header>
 <paragraph id="HBFB2B71A278B49C2A8762C565424AB02"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Attorneys’ fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a claimant for benefits under this title obtains a proposed decision and order from a district director with an award of benefits for a qualifying claim, or an award for a qualifying claim before an administrative law judge, the district director may approve attorneys’ fees for work done before such director in an amount not to exceed $1,500 and an administrative law judge may approve attorneys’ fees for work done before such judge in an amount not to exceed $3,000. The Secretary shall, through the program under this section, pay such amounts approved.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H28273EE9ECD24B239BFA629667669DF0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Medical expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a claimant for benefits under this title obtains a proposed decision and order from a district director with an award of benefits for a qualifying claim, or an award for a qualifying claim before an administrative law judge, such district director and administrative law judge may each approve an award to the claimant’s attorney of reasonable and unreimbursed medical expenses incurred in establishing the claimant’s case in an amount not to exceed $1,500. The Secretary shall, through the program under this section, pay such amounts approved.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADCD9FB953C8482B8932A5A0C3F75604"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Maximum</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The program established under this section shall not pay more than a total of $4,500 in attorneys’ fees nor more than $3,000 in medical expenses for any single qualifying claim.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H64DE3EE7D99840878D67F931855AE44F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reimbursement of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which a qualifying claim results in a final order awarding compensation, the liable operator shall reimburse the fund for any fees or expenses paid under this section, subject to enforcement by the Secretary under section 424 and in the same manner as compensation orders are enforced under section 21(d) of the Longshore and Harbor Workers’ Compensation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/921">33 U.S.C. 921(d)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H848C324A3054430EB2A3B20949ABEFBA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional program rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall limit or otherwise affect an operator’s liability for any attorneys’ fees, medical expenses, or other allowable and unreimbursed expenses awarded by the district director or an administrative law judge that were not paid by the program under this section. Nothing in this section shall limit or otherwise affect the Secretary's authority to use amounts in the fund to pay approved attorneys’ fees in claims for benefits under this title for which a final order awarding compensation has been entered and the operator is unable to pay.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H24530DC2D15C4ADA9B9E6B8ECF480F33"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No recoupment of attorneys’ fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any payment for attorneys’ fees or medical expenses made by the Secretary under this section shall not be recouped from the claimant or the claimant’s attorney.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HA70F922774754B6F8F5A2C66612AF0A2"><enum>103.</enum><header>Clarifying eligibility for black lung benefits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 411(c) of the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/921">30 U.S.C. 921(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraphs (3) and (4) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA5F91D43307543F58A69850DF685BF38" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HADB4F8D996564910B904D712011F623C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If x-ray, biopsy, autopsy, or other medically accepted and relevant test or procedure establishes that a miner is suffering or has suffered from a chronic dust disease of the lung, diagnosed as complicated pneumoconiosis or progressive massive fibrosis (pneumoconiosis that has formed an opacity, mass, or lesion whose greatest diameter exceeds 1 centimeter), then there shall be an irrebuttable presumption that such miner is totally disabled due to pneumoconiosis, that the miner’s death was due to pneumoconiosis, or that at the time of death the miner was totally disabled by pneumoconiosis, as the case may be. A chest radiograph, which yields one or more large opacities (whose greatest diameter exceeds 1 centimeter), and would be classified in category A, B, or C in the International Classification of Radiographs of Pneumoconioses by the International Labor Organization, shall be sufficient to invoke the presumption, in the absence of more probative evidence sufficient to establish that the etiology of a large opacity is not pneumoconiosis.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H97D332393E7A477988BADC904FC47221"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a miner was employed for 15 years or more in one or more coal mines, and if there is a chest radiograph submitted in connection with the claim under this title of such miner or such miner’s surviving spouse, child, parent, brother, sister, or dependent and it is interpreted as negative with respect to the requirements of paragraph (3), and if other evidence demonstrates the existence of a totally disabling respiratory or pulmonary impairment, then there shall be a rebuttable presumption that such miner is totally disabled due to pneumoconiosis, that the miner’s death was due to pneumoconiosis, or that at the time of death the miner was totally disabled by pneumoconiosis. In the case of a living miner, a spouse's affidavit may not be used by itself to establish the presumption under this paragraph. The presumption under this paragraph may be rebutted only by establishing that such miner does not, or did not, have pneumoconiosis, or that no part of such miner’s respiratory or pulmonary impairment or death was caused by pneumoconiosis.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</section><section id="H458B4CE300E049488DF4D0C32D514528"><enum>104.</enum><header>Restoring adequate benefit adjustments for miners suffering from black lung disease and for their
 dependent family members</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 412(a) of the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/922">30 U.S.C. 922(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDAE721A8C7414FE98DD009403CFEBEEB" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H59E04E64127742A2B43C4D41BA9EA3B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the case of total disability of a miner due to pneumoconiosis, the disabled miner shall be paid benefits during the disability—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H264FEF5C5C2A45FFBCF6F699DC1D6780"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for any calendar year preceding January 1, 2015, at a rate equal to 37<fraction>½</fraction> percent of the monthly pay rate for Federal employees in grade GS–2, step 1;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD3D73CCA89842EBA6082FBA6553B257"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for the calendar year beginning on January 1, 2015, at a rate of $7,980 per year, payable in 12 equal monthly payments; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC34F85B5F5C24BC69D9749ADEDC9EFB8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for each calendar year thereafter, at a rate equal to the amount under subparagraph (B) increased by an amount equal to any increase in the annual rate of the Consumer Price Index for Urban Wage Earners and Clerical Workers, as published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H4D6A1537099D44F2B6D3AD51AC8AC7A4"><enum>105.</enum><header>Treatment of evidence in equipoise</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 422 of the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/932">30 U.S.C. 932</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H058FC7DA654441A8ACA747B434D7A92B" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H7FD94604AA194E97AA5BCACF54910A54"><enum>(m)</enum><text>In determining the validity of a claim under this title, an adjudicator who finds that the evidence is evenly balanced on an issue shall resolve any resulting doubt in the claimant’s favor and find that the claimant has met the burden of persuasion on such issue.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HCC0F06799DCA43F9B489CDE547B59B03"><enum>106.</enum><header>Providing assistance with claims for miners and their dependent family members</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 427(a) of the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/937">30 U.S.C. 937(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the analysis, examination, and treatment</quote> and all that follows through <quote>coal miners.</quote> and inserting <quote>the analysis, examination, and treatment of respiratory and pulmonary impairments in active and inactive coal miners and for assistance on behalf of miners, spouses, dependents, and other family members with claims arising under this title.</quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="H778327BFF705454ABF61A842AEC2B59F"><enum>107.</enum><header>False statements or misrepresentations, attorney disqualification, and discovery sanctions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 431 of the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/941">30 U.S.C. 941</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H160EF968AFAD47A494EAAFB921561DF8" style="OLC"> <section id="H294F6F3799AA4F9E946C858D866452B8"><enum>431.</enum><header>False statements or misrepresentations, attorney disqualification, and discovery sanctions</header> <subsection id="HF468E4FC28D24EAEA0F1390A7C476B91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No person, including any claimant, physician, operator, duly authorized agent of such operator, or employee of an insurance carrier, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB9F648D70BD14947953D7FBB47EB3873"><enum>(1)</enum><text>knowingly and willfully make a false statement or misrepresentation for the purpose of obtaining, increasing, reducing, denying, or terminating benefits under this title; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H54A46E3A429F4E059421B1F3602B8B67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>knowingly and willfully threaten, coerce, intimidate, deceive, or mislead a party, representative, witness, potential witness, judge, or anyone participating in a proceeding regarding any matter related to a proceeding under this title.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H22242CE70D134E35B8A898E714724AFD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fine; imprisonment</header><text>Any person who engages in the conduct described in subsection (a) shall, upon conviction, be subject to a fine in accordance with title 18, United States Code, imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H75FC05A51BF544DEA2C6E4FDB41EB4DA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prompt investigation</header><text>The United States Attorney for the district in which the conduct described in subsection (a) is alleged to have occurred shall make every reasonable effort to promptly investigate each complaint of a violation of such subsection.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H2FF5475BB0ED4D74AA7FF98ADC3B546A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Disqualification</header>
 <paragraph id="HDFDD00C77E77456CA2426FB277D164A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An attorney or expert witness who engages in the conduct described in subsection (a) shall, in addition to the fine or imprisonment provided under subsection (b), be permanently disqualified from representing any party, or appearing in any proceeding, under this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C6CCDC701754E14B1C7FC61260E25DE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Attorney disqualification</header><text>In addition to the disqualification described in paragraph (1), the Secretary may disqualify an attorney from representing any party in any administrative proceeding under this title for either a limited term or permanently, if the attorney—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6EB8D59FBC4F4744A84D0756693B8DD5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>engages in any action or behavior that is prejudicial to the fair and orderly conduct of such proceeding; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1F1770A74EE4FFE8005CD8A6F41010C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is suspended or disbarred by any court of the United States, any State, or any territory, commonwealth, or possession of the United States with jurisdiction over the proceeding.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B6082F197B9438FB819E5C6CD7FA8A3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Discovery sanctions</header><text>An administrative law judge may sanction a party who fails to comply with an order to compel discovery or disclosure, or to supplement earlier responses, in a proceeding under this title. These sanctions may include, as appropriate—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3ED37917110D4C59B440985F173E97FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>drawing an adverse inference against the noncomplying party on the facts relevant to the discovery or disclosure order;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2D1550DBC104128902257BB3C4067E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>limiting the noncomplying party’s claims, defenses, or right to introduce evidence; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9C314EAF1B74014AEC4BDE460CE3E6C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>rendering a default decision against the noncomplying party.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2387E0AA3E443B29CAF16DCFD6B647E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall promulgate regulations that—</text> <paragraph id="H3E249924D3BF48F98217CC6DB0777B64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide procedures for the disqualifications and sanctions under this section and are appropriate for all parties; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDACA828CE5D743C5AAE5BDA2137951A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>distinguish between parties that are represented by an attorney and parties that are not represented by an attorney.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HB2C32C8547C041FE92CB32BDE4B31A16"><enum>108.</enum><header>Development of medical evidence by the Secretary</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part C of the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/931">30 U.S.C. 931</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84D9709C5BBF4D079C29EB5A7E056B1C" style="OLC">
						<section id="H9C87D2734AD744469BBEF0FD1C615E69"><enum>435.</enum><header>Development of medical evidence by the Secretary</header>
 <subsection id="H81C90AD101EA4E6A8B1965DD8882FCAA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Complete pulmonary evaluation</header><text>Upon request by a claimant for benefits under this title, the Secretary shall provide the claimant an opportunity to substantiate the claim through a complete pulmonary evaluation of the miner that shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE8AA9B9354BE47C19EA784549A572550"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an initial report, conducted by a qualified physician on the list provided under subsection (d), and in accordance with subsection (d)(5) and sections 402(f)(1)(D) and 413(b); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6928BDD760BF474B9A3F47D4638AF7AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the conditions under subsection (b) are met, any supplemental medical evidence described in subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF45B4BA14EDD44AAB2FC61030AFA6336"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Diagnosing complicated pneumoconiosis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In diagnosing whether there is complicated pneumoconiosis as a part of a medical examination conducted under subsection (a), the Secretary shall authorize a high-quality, low-dose or standard computerized tomography scan where any or a combination of the following is found:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HF10BAFB59F6C4B07BF20A03084C5C8E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any certified B reader of a chest radiograph associated with an exam conducted under section 413(b) finds advanced pneumoconiosis (ILO category 2/1 or greater).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE43BB50036DB467595B6EFFCD580B1B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any certified B reader of a chest radiograph associated with an exam conducted under section 413(b) finds a coalescence of small opacities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H59AB78B76F93449A86510E1F4DC750F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any certified B reader of a chest radiograph associated with an exam conducted under section 413(b) has a reasonable belief that there may be a large opacity in the upper lungs that has been obscured by bony structures.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4559E52B67164DC39E5671FD68899E13"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conditions for supplemental medical evidence</header><text>The Secretary shall develop supplemental medical evidence, in accordance with subsection (d)—</text> <paragraph id="H7EF8E4477D154072812FE1182AC740F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for any claim in which the Secretary recommends an award of benefits based on the results of the initial report under subsection (a)(1) and a party opposing such award submits evidence that could be considered contrary to the findings of the Secretary; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA40BA2F5F594C6EB8D40807FF0549DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for any compensation case under this title heard by an administrative law judge, in which—</text> <subparagraph id="H6578296861F44A0F88491A00747AA3EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary has awarded benefits to the claimant;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFC5B707DE0047F9A5FD850C9D1072B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the party opposing such award has submitted evidence not previously reviewed that could be considered contrary to the award under subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H680E7918A3564CB6990E4AFF003D01E5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the claimant or, if the claimant is represented by an attorney, the claimant’s attorney consents to the Secretary developing supplemental medical evidence.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEA871CC67A644256B816C424A4171066"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Process for supplemental medical evidence</header>
 <paragraph id="HB9B3264CA1DA479C98D3DD053C234C9D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided under paragraph (2), to develop supplemental medical evidence under conditions described in subsection (c), the Secretary shall request the physician who conducted the initial report under subsection (a)(1) to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC4D7E1ABAC0D4FF48D245C679CC67990"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review any medical evidence submitted after such report or the most recent supplemental report, as appropriate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD196E8E0CC0D4FEE9DA5895D318457DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>update his or her opinion in a supplemental report.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1295123D42E446A987797C83E6F622BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternative physician</header><text>If such physician is no longer available or is unwilling to provide supplemental medical evidence under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall select another qualified physician to provide such evidence.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD7B0B9804CA0417B902AEE0918F80FE8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Qualified physicians for complete pulmonary evaluation and protections for suitability and
			 potential conflicts of interest</header>
 <paragraph id="H09BAA57F90E74E3BB704FEB16522FA5E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified physicians list</header><text>The Secretary shall create and maintain a list of qualified physicians to be selected by a claimant to perform the complete pulmonary evaluation described in subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF06BAC1DB62F40D0B547E4E1DA0222FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary shall make the list under this subsection available to the public.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF718221EBA56472986780B74B9B72FF0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual evaluation</header><text>Each year, the Secretary shall update such list by reviewing the suitability of the listed qualified physicians and assessing any potential conflicts of interest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C134A81BD1D47B1B28258A84A22392D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Criteria for suitability</header><text>In determining whether a physician is suitable to be on the list under this subsection, the Secretary shall consult the National Practitioner Data Bank of the Department of Health and Human Services and assess reports of adverse licensure, certifications, hospital privilege, and professional society actions involving the physician. In no case shall such list include any physician—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H047D540DA2DE480E80464302C3754734"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who is not licensed to practice medicine in any State or any territory, commonwealth, or possession of the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDFB915649294A8FA480CB7916DC90BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whose license is revoked by a medical licensing board of any State, territory, commonwealth, or possession of the United States; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83693A2D510646E5847B6A8F6ABB6682"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whose license is suspended by a medical licensing board of any State, territory, commonwealth, or possession of the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H40EE2B2679C647E7B88C48A979CBCF26"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Conflicts of interest</header><text>The Secretary shall develop and implement policies and procedures to ensure that any actual or potential conflict of interest of qualified physicians on the list under this subsection, including both individual and organizational conflicts of interest, are disclosed to the Department, and to provide such disclosure to claimants. Such policies and procedures shall provide that, unless the claimant knowingly and with the benefit of full disclosure waives the following limitations, a physician shall not be used to perform a complete pulmonary medical evaluation under subsection (a) that is reimbursed pursuant to subsection (g), if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9AECA86C3E554A62B38609396A8FAD59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such physician is employed by, under contract to, or otherwise providing services to a private party opposing the claim, a law firm or lawyer representing such opposing party, or an interested insurer or other interested third party; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48B271BE321D4901914E487702F5653F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such physician has been retained by a private party opposing the claim, a law firm or lawyer representing such opposing party, or an interested insurer or other interested third party in the previous 24 months.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9E6C36A74A542BB8F661C4687AE6A36"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Record</header><text>Upon receipt of any initial report or supplemental report under this section, the Secretary shall enter the report in the record and provide a copy of such report to all parties to the proceeding.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF3B3E4B6F514E179A494B6220DBAD31"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Expenses</header><text>All expenses related to obtaining the medical evidence under this section shall be paid for by the fund. If a claimant receives a final award of benefits, the operator liable for payment of benefits, if any, shall reimburse the fund for such expenses, which shall include interest.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</section><section id="H975A1DF633504D14A962BA84F8CA25E9"><enum>109.</enum><header>Establishment of pilot program to provide impartial classifications of chest radiographs</header>
 <subsection id="HCB7C3FB4CA9344AABCA3EFC4247169BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part C of the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/931">30 U.S.C. 931</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by section 108, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23D4813CB7B84F5B92F8384E77D5201C" style="OLC">
							<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4FF970A771134F55AB4DB5B7A0C12977"><enum>436.</enum><header>Establishment of pilot program to provide impartial classifications of chest radiographs</header>
 <subsection id="HF91B23563C9145969C4877075E573ABF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H5B2CEA90BB5146CC8853040C08B36456"><enum>(1)</enum><header>B Reader</header><text>The term <term>B Reader</term> means an individual who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H941533341902448090087C3B0505588F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has a valid license to practice medicine in not less than one State, territory, commonwealth, or possession of the United States; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA79965324BF4FF497CFAD973EBD8153"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has demonstrated a proficiency, through an examination administered by the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, in classifying chest radiographs for findings consistent with pneumoconiosis using the International Classification of Radiographs of Pneumoconioses by the International Labor Organization (ILO).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC943DFB8FB9E46488D8091593002D9E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>B Reader Panel</header><text>The term <term>B Reader Panel</term> means a panel of not less than 3 B Readers selected by the Director exclusively from the B Reader Panel Pool.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB456A72D9074285931C901C080FADEC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF66FEC10E68E434897F5760788FD5917"><enum>(4)</enum><header>ILO classification</header><text>The term <term>ILO classification</term> means the standardized categorization of chest radiographs for findings consistent with pneumoconiosis using the International Classification of Radiographs of Pneumoconioses by the International Labor Organization.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D2C300CD6564BE79BD3EED75B30EE5C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>B Reader Panel Pool</header><text>The term <term>B Reader Panel Pool</term> means the group of physicians included in the pool described in subsection (c).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDFF9A070421944A79FE5970D0919EB6C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>B Reader Panel Program</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H535D3D8D703D4EE894DCBB59CB2E6A6F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment of pilot program</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA665B11D3F4A4CD3A201E1D8D4449C94"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall establish, in the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, a pilot program to be known as the <quote>B Reader Panel Program</quote>. The B Reader Panel Program shall establish B Reader Panels that—</text>
 <clause id="H78B47E7D9E5141D09963928119418872"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are operated in a manner to assure accurate ILO classifications, which may be used for claims for benefits described in subparagraph (C);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD4187F23695D4B8B84D0032CACCAE931"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>only classify chest radiographs; and</text> </clause><clause id="HE62FBB49A5B445AEB4420DA0A61E410B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>classify all appearances described in the International Classification of Radiographs of Pneumoconiosis or illustrated by the ILO Standard Radiographs.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H89ED0734CC904C0A92EB9BE211ED6793"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The B Reader Panel Program established under this section shall be conducted for a duration of one year, beginning after the issuance of necessary protocols and interim final rules under subsection (h).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5CC7C50CDFCF4482ADC3FAF7293B3B58"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A chest radiograph classification may only be requested under this section for a claim for benefits under this title where the presence or absence of complicated pneumoconiosis or progressive massive fibrosis (large opacities greater than or equal to category A of the ILO classification) is in fact at issue.</text>
										</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA50A2488BFBD4A87A438869577A3A033"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program personnel matters</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C53B75DA73349D981369C2F4716B974"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director may hire such personnel as are necessary to establish, manage, and evaluate the B Reader Panel Program, including a B Reader Program Director described in subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB327D4520D8C46338DEF99B05D97E4C9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>B Reader Program Director</header><text>The B Reader Program Director shall be a physician who is a B Reader and has documented expertise in ILO classifications.</text>
										</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD64150FA5340461D9A0D24B0075AD5DA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Staff</header>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4EDC0C29EFE2499291E5A2D97ADB6959"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In procuring the services of B Readers for this section, the Director may hire Federal personnel, contract for services, or both.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD68D08B54819488CB129C9A5AB268505"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The Director shall establish compensation rates for B Readers who are hired under contract.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2FF35DC8DFC64E8C8DC5D6AA6CF2F5C5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ethics policy</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H227721E54FE84F60A7D859D45A4E8803"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Code of ethics</header> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFDC3A8A819F44592B5891F43A553BFCA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to maximize the quality, objectivity, and confidence in ILO classifications under this section, the Director shall establish a binding code of ethics to which all B Readers in the B Reader Panel Pool shall agree to in writing and adhere.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H258C25D033C343E0A75D01CBF930E5B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The code of ethics shall include—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H60D8EE3983F64E8F95E80EE6469BC761"><enum>(I)</enum><text>definitions and stipulations of procedures dealing with actual and apparent conflicts of interest and the appearance of bias or lack of sufficient impartiality;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1DDB4384EC7345CDB44A124068F4E4BE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a requirement that each such B Reader submits a conflict of interest disclosure statement to the Director and annually updates such statement; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A02915ED67C49A495E3C380339122B0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>requirements for the content of the conflict of interest disclosure statements required under subclause (II).</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H89088C2D4F70456CB0547759EC219213"><enum>(B)</enum><header>B Reader ethics officer</header><text>The Director shall designate an employee of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health as the B Reader Ethics Officer whose responsibilities shall include—</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BB7AFB9D3084F00BDE83EE5CC969442"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reviewing all conflict of interest disclosures of B Readers on the B Reader Panel Pool;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H24BC507A9C6441C59F9F4F3284422644"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>investigating the validity of such disclosures;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H20732C68E37648B2A837FCE708F7FDF6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>maintaining a list of such B Readers who fail to disclose a conflict of interest;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B11799E2FF0429196C0908D69F9689D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>addressing complaints about incomplete or inaccurate conflict of interest disclosures;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H09B5FD2379E8435C9D26674ECC6BC847"><enum>(v)</enum><text>assessing whether any such B Reader has been improperly assigned to a panel due to a conflict of interest; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF05A573C6C5C4F8E87BF81923D091D96"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>assuring full transparency of conflict of interest disclosures to the public.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD66759BCF0614F9D911A1E2F4606D9A7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Quality assurance program</header> <subparagraph id="H8CE448CA087542BCADF40ADC0302620B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Protocols</header> <clause id="H5527ABCB316E4D19994D4CDEEFEE6DBC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Director shall establish a quality assurance program consisting of protocols to ensure that the results produced by B Reader Panels meet or exceed standards of performance required for accuracy and consistency.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H567FDF98062945E4BA7E668E16B631B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Protocols</header><text>The protocols under this subparagraph shall include protocols—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H52DCA0AAA9084045B24F8C6E6DB505AD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for each B Reader to prepare an individual ILO classification report for each chest radiograph; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H92F8B304D82E436B997D6AACE175224F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for the preparation of a final ILO classification report for the chest radiograph.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H3F86C8DFB75F4C03B5A00AD8975A303E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Additional reviewers</header><text>If individual ILO classifications reported by each B Reader of a B Reader Panel diverge from each other by more than an acceptable variance, as determined by protocols established under subsection (h), the Director shall assign additional B Readers to the applicable B Reader Panel or convene an additional B Reader Panel, as the Director determines necessary, to assure that the ILO classification report of the initial B Reader Panel is accurate and scientifically valid.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAEA7190118D6452380F299D0191322A2"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Use of known positive and negative x-rays as a quality control tool</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The quality assurance program under this paragraph shall use pre-read radiographs, for which ILO classifications have been previously established as external standards, with sufficient frequency in order to assure that B Readers on B Reader Panels read radiographs that are borderline positive or negative for complicated pneumoconiosis or progressive massive fibrosis (large opacities greater than or equal to category A of the ILO classification) with accuracy and consistency.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7AE1080BDA884ECCA00B88AE888BFFB7"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Blind readings</header><text>In reading a radiograph to make an ILO classification, a B Reader shall be blinded from the origin of the radiograph.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H57A8FBCBF26B43CBB5FBA9EBABEC5CA4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Continuous improvement</header><text>The Director shall establish a process for providing feedback to B Readers in the B Reader Pool with respect to their performance in providing ILO classifications and provide suggestions for improvement.</text>
										</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB0D84317B4443FEBF7EF202E6AED480"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Creation and maintenance of B Reader Panel Pool</header>
 <paragraph id="H3C97469BF0DC4A1EBB609181F30AD1A6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Director shall establish a B Reader Panel Pool to be used for the B Reader Panel Program under this section. The Director shall solicit and select physicians who are B Readers for inclusion in the B Reader Panel Pool.</text>
									</paragraph><paragraph id="HCAA3ABC1326F4BA6A5541EB3B9B2B1BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection and retention for B Readers on B Reader Panel Pool</header>
 <subparagraph id="H222699817DA5497CA8637D1D9D9C5DC0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall establish and disclose criteria by which B Readers are selected and retained within the B Reader Panel Pool, including minimum standards of performance described in subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A5C74159E78410D94603669404A3C03"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Minimum standards of performance</header><text>The minimum standards of performance for inclusion in the B Reader Panel Pool shall include requiring the B Reader to make radiograph classifications consistent with ILO classification criteria that are consistently within acceptable norms, as established by the Director.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DC5D9FB238647B29480BB95C379E483"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Considerations for selection</header><text>In selecting a B Reader to be included in the B Reader Panel Pool, the Director shall—</text> <clause id="HBD198BBE463B4F809BF7DE29486FE903"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assess, to the maximum extent practicable, the prior performance of the B Reader in making ILO classifications;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA3950FC3772540DCB3426D660AF537F1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consult the National Practitioner Data Bank of the Department of Health and Human Services for information on physician suitability; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8EE40FBFEF7E4A7F86DA7C3BDF692E77"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>assess reports of adverse licensure, certifications, hospital privilege, and professional society actions involving the B Reader.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAD737DE39E64D218F3A3BD2F3882CAE"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Monitoring</header><text>The Director shall monitor ILO classifications conducted under this section to determine if any B Reader included in the B Reader Panel Pool demonstrates a pattern of providing ILO classifications that are erroneous or not consistently within the acceptable norms, as established by the Director.</text>
										</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H91CAB99074C44786A38568F82D71BCAC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Process for removal</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE012BCAA09B744099DA9EE36F8D2168B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall be authorized to suspend or remove any B Reader from the B Reader Panel Pool for—</text>
 <clause id="HDC5D086BFEE9431AA7FC9333144E9CF4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consistently failing to meet the minimum standards of performance under paragraph (2)(B);</text> </clause><clause id="H17A158CF1B7F4534A9B97C995D48599F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>breaching the code of ethics under subsection (b)(3)(A); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1F8EAF253E49475EBDA0D088384BCF7D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>other disqualifying conduct, as established by rule or policy.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H083798D9641243CDA50173C4CB1B1799"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Director shall provide a process for a B Reader who is aggrieved by a decision of the Director under subparagraph (A) to seek review by the Secretary of Health and Human Services. The review by such Secretary shall not stay the suspension of the B Reader during the pendency of the review.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF255D57F5D34620A3A5002459691025"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>The Director shall make publicly accessible—</text> <subparagraph id="HB8A71501AD274288BA4717FC03245B69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the names and qualifications of the B Readers included in the B Reader Panel Pool;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8345710108EA484C99451B40F84A8189"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the names of B Readers who have been suspended or removed from the B Reader Panel Pool and the reasons for such suspension or removal;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H332DDF1518764BD0911BBCBCD0CAAF61"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the conflict of interest disclosure statements required under subsection (b)(3)(A)(ii)(II); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE2A50D3AE2D47A6BA614C89714E0306"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any pertinent information which the Director determines necessary to assure transparency and program integrity.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8334AEAE90074ABEB96CEBBC8F50D161"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligibility To request ILO classifications</header><text>Each of the following individuals may request an ILO classification under this section:</text> <paragraph id="HB14D67B3FCAD4769A74B676AA185B9FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Claimants or operators, or their authorized representatives, in a claim for benefits that meets the requirements of subsection (b)(1)(C).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H776FD647C1C84281B96E185825ED003F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Individuals defined as adjudication officers by regulations of the Secretary.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF4CF72ECD8B44786AEC996C789704B68"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Timing of reports</header><text>Following the receipt of a written request for the classification of a chest radiograph, the Director shall provide a report conducted by a B Reader Panel—</text>
 <paragraph id="H004F3044B72A4E709552110643C19710"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for digital chest radiographic images, within 45 days; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F8FC25179B6490E954B807D9678398B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for film-based chest radiographs, within 90 days.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F29E8B93D134698896C290C6F51EA52"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Testimony</header>
 <paragraph id="HC5293E97AE4D47D1AB31B606CD29F4F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Availability of director or designee</header><text>The Director, or a designee of the Director, shall be available to respond to interrogatories or appear and testify about a B Reader Panel's conclusions or the process by which B Reader Panels classify radiographs in a case under subsection (b)(1)(C), upon the request of a party to such case.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEAFAAEB40C914C0C986EE86964F63DA1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interrogatories and subpoenas for B Readers</header><text>To the extent that additional information is reasonably necessary for the full development of evidence pertaining to a B Reader Panel Report in a case under subsection (b)(1)(C), a B Reader of a B Reader Panel—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H048ED52EBAFE490A84A62063A3F07EEB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may be required to respond to interrogatories with respect to the ILO classification provided by the B Reader in the case, only if so ordered by an administrative law judge; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7942470A22E4E50BC22A3EE7201A81D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not be required to appear and testify under subpoena, unless the party making such request demonstrates to an administrative law judge that—</text>
											<clause id="H13FB147ADD074C11AAB7BF2E173CC66A"><enum>(i)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE2896639D037412AADB33A7A07CD27F9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the B Reader Panel Report is incomplete or lacks information that is reasonably necessary for such full development; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H078611C9E45548E4A5EC342620E79D36" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if responses to interrogatories were ordered, the responses are unclear or incomplete; or</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HFD82D6A7A2AB49AC8465CF55769718B1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>there is an extraordinary circumstance in which additional information that is reasonably necessary for such full development is otherwise unavailable from the Director and can only be provided by such B Reader.</text>
											</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79576009EF5A4621BD748BDBD9DC6FB8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header>
 <paragraph id="H20A88BB26D8746DEB35DFF29DB97CB17"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Funds necessary to establish and operate the B Reader Panel Program under this section shall be paid as an administrative cost from the fund. The Director shall consult with the Secretary on allocations of funds in establishing such program.</text>
									</paragraph><paragraph id="H5566579E32FF4E58BB17A50636B9FA8B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Costs of reports for B Reader Panels</header>
										<subparagraph id="H5BCDAB5C481649BDA64CBD77107F0947"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Fees</header>
 <clause id="H606A64A97E3E4453BE2FBF3345B7A307"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall establish a fee for a B Reader Panel Report in accordance with clause (ii). Such fee shall be payable by the party requesting such report. No fee shall be charged if the request for such ILO classification is made by an individual defined as an adjudication officer by regulations of the Secretary.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H15BFCFEA5C174A2BBCC00570368F099A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The amount of a fee under clause (i) shall not exceed the direct cost of hiring the B Readers of the B Reader Panel that made the ILO classification.</text>
											</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5FFB3B140814056AE9BFF55B8514B34"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Legal costs</header>
 <clause id="HAA03E41BA0B54471948822143B96267C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health shall use amounts in the fund to pay for all costs related to the appearance and responses to interrogatories of the Director or a designee of the Director, or a B Reader of a B Reader Panel, in a proceeding under this section.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC1A711FA8E454FECB945EBCA02976DE8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Representation of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health</header><text>The General Counsel of the Department of Health and Human Services shall, in consultation with the Solicitor of Labor, represent the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health in any proceeding under this section, which costs shall be payable from the fund.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2AB20DD3605C4B5C8C53184878154392"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Protocols and interim final rules</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Black Lung Benefits Improvement Act of 2017</short-title>, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue protocols and promulgate interim final rules, as necessary, to commence the implementation of this section.</text>
								</subsection><subsection id="HED65AADA0B4643F6A4DCE2E7F6549221"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header>
 <paragraph id="H09FDE03753854B00A14490487A83EE90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the completion of the pilot program under this section, the Director shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, prepare and submit a report to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives that includes the information in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCDDAB7C17A0941DAB607ED3D88984855"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under this subsection shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H9E1DDFFE4FD34077ABCC3AD64EC6E93C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of B Reader Panels established under this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BD473D3C2AC4A1B9AD9D8BDDA714FD9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of B Readers participating in the pilot program under this section;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE09E02C9F3948A092323D48C6ADD41B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the effectiveness of the quality assurance program under subsection (b)(4);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29895870717C45C5878E9F4EEB5904DF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the accuracy of the ILO classifications conducted by B Readers under this section;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5618206A3B1842C890502FE27A47D510"><enum>(E)</enum><text>challenges in the administration and implementation of such pilot program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C3D41F179CA4517A5366EB4AA2666CB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the costs and revenues of such pilot program;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEA8453C51EF4CEFAB84A309F02D83F7"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of the pilot program on the claims-adjudication process;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0EA9A8BEBB4492F94C6CFE4F2709B04"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a recommendation on whether the pilot program under this section should extend beyond the one-year duration under subsection (b)(1)(B); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D356CED04444540BEB585A10AD99D6D"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for any necessary modifications to such pilot program, if the Director recommends such an extension.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H93A49C0F486C4C699AD9624578D24B3F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment related to deposit of fees</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9501">Section 9501(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9501">26 U.S.C. 9501(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1E67064569B4A01A69802C7ABF6EFD7" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H4B0474E36C1B4BCD964D7956B2E52E6A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Certain fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts collected as fees authorized under section 436(g)(2)(A) of the Black Lung Benefits Act.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section><section id="H49E0FADE1510496D83BAC7011C74CEBB"><enum>110.</enum><header>Medical evidence training program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part C of the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/931">30 U.S.C. 931</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by sections 108 and 109, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAB2C093185148F5A9FB2C4C9FD8E10A" style="OLC">
						<section id="HA60F079E02AA481F809747A9CBAFB622"><enum>437.</enum><header>Medical evidence training program</header>
 <subsection id="H1F7F287E6BFC47CABCA30BEFBE646005"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Black Lung Benefits Improvement Act of 2017</short-title>, the Secretary, in coordination with the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, shall establish and implement a training program, to provide education on issues relating to medical evidence relevant to claims for benefits under this title, to each of the following individuals who engage in work under this title:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6BAB7821413B47D7B4847A4A6C079FBE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>District directors.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B22AB7A3A854BEE9B673AAC84AEF71F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Claims examiners working under such directors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H22F8932AB7B346EFB0127003D9140F8C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Administrative law judges and attorney advisors supporting such judges.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC831990972D649CBA60E6F43F82060C5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Members of the Benefits Review Board established under section 21(b) of the Longshore and Harbor Workers' Compensation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/921">33 U.S.C. 921(b)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A3CDC7C57714D5FA540FA35978D1336"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training program topics</header><text>The training program under this section shall provide an overview of topics that include—</text> <paragraph id="HDDCB2051D4064FD3A0C55D55F0B29505"><enum>(1)</enum><text>new developments in pulmonary medicine relating to pneumoconiosis;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9F51A58AC124EEA954A240DD3503B0E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>medical evidence, and other relevant evidence, sufficient to support a claim for benefits under this title; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5AE1A50DEF2E45D4AA55BA569D9873B6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>weighing conflicting medical evidence and testimony concerning eligibility for such benefits.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H55E416298C62464899D648E699E1AC57"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Timing of training</header> <paragraph id="H15137D230B544984849F625A020F4B92"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Individuals hired or appointed prior to the Black Lung Benefits Improvement Act of 2017</header><text>Any district director, claims examiner, administrative law judge, attorney advisor supporting such judge, or member of the Benefits Review Board described in subsection (a)(4), who was hired or appointed prior to the date of enactment of the <short-title>Black Lung Benefits Improvement Act of 2017</short-title> shall complete the training program under this section not later than 60 days after the establishment of such program under subsection (a) and not less than annually thereafter.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99B8140241DE4C0798DE90301614982F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individuals hired or appointed after the Black Lung Benefits Improvement Act of 2017</header><text>Any district director, claims examiner, administrative law judge, attorney advisor supporting such judge, or member of the Benefits Review Board described in subsection (a)(4), who is not described in paragraph (1) shall complete the training program under this section prior to engaging in any work under this title and not less than annually thereafter.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section commented="no" id="H938048B3C53B4523B159D781474F4390"><enum>111.</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/901">30 U.S.C. 901</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H89911957C6054BADB5CCD272094D8A73"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 401(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/901">30 U.S.C. 901(a)</external-xref>), by inserting <quote>or who were found to be totally disabled by such disease</quote> after <quote>such disease</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF61C81EF9D734D54A94173675965C11B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 402—</text> <subparagraph id="H84602027DBF742F0968AEE3ADBEB6579"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCDABFF7429DA462BA9F6BFA69CD016AF" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H062080C766CB4D2EB062832DD2DC856B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a spouse who is a member of the same household as the miner, or is receiving regular contributions from the miner for support, or whose spouse is a miner who has been ordered by a court to contribute to support, or who meets the requirements of paragraph (1) or (2) of section 216(b) of the Social Security Act or paragraph (1) or (2) of section 216(f) of such Act. An individual is the <term>spouse</term> of a miner when such individual is legally married to the miner under the laws of the State where the marriage was celebrated. The term <term>spouse</term> also includes a <quote>divorced wife</quote> or <quote>divorced husband</quote>, as such terms are defined in paragraph (1) or (4) of section 216(d) of such Act, who is receiving at least one-half of his or her support, as determined in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary, from the miner, or is receiving substantial contributions from the miner (pursuant to a written agreement), or there is in effect a court order for substantial contributions to the spouse’s support from such miner.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0719EA9EE48C47D79C991B5BD2619956"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subsection (e) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4746FB7BDA440C79C14E457EF7E6768" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H692363743FB841C7A9BDC199DB416C7E"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>surviving spouse</term> includes the spouse living with or dependent for support on the miner at the time of the miner’s death, or living apart for reasonable cause or because of the miner’s desertion, or who meets the requirements of subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), or (E) of section 216(c)(1) of the Social Security Act, subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), or (E) of section 216(g)(1) of such Act, or section 216(k) of such Act, who is not married. An individual is the <quote>surviving spouse</quote> of a miner when legally married at the time of the miner’s death under the laws of the State where the marriage was celebrated. Such term also includes a <quote>surviving divorced wife</quote> or <quote>surviving divorced husband</quote>, as such terms are defined in paragraph (2) or (5) of section 216(d) of such Act who for the month preceding the month in which the miner died, was receiving at least one-half of his or her support, as determined in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary, from the miner, or was receiving substantial contributions from the miner (pursuant to a written agreement) or there was in effect a court order for substantial contributions to the spouse’s support from the miner at the time of the miner’s death.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H031CC4903DB544A582B9390EB4F0C5AA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (g)—</text> <clause id="HD8AC8AF24D754B179147897D36C459D5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(B)(ii), by striking <quote>he ceased</quote> and inserting <quote>the individual ceased</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDA913BE91D5A4FA38A2E4FC12E3E1394"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the matter following paragraph (2)(C), by striking <quote>widow</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>surviving spouse</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38EDC242CF3C40D6A438AC3E8340FD60"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (h), by striking <quote>Internal Revenue Code of 1954</quote> and inserting <quote>Internal Revenue Code of 1986</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDCDCC1D5C3946CFAC65FAF24EE3F46F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in subsection (i), by striking <quote>Internal Revenue Code of 1954</quote> and inserting <quote>Internal Revenue Code of 1986</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H95B7FE67132441CC96F4743F5A462DE6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 411 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/921">30 U.S.C. 921</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC486500611794707BDD7850C626AADD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H266D24771868403EAB30063EFF2DB247" style="traditional"> <subsection id="H08890832D43743EFA8B86727E8F0B94F"><enum>(a)</enum><text>The Secretary shall, in accordance with the provisions of this title, and the regulations promulgated by the Secretary under this title, make payments of benefits in respect of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8C0B3C4AEDF347B4802F89BA66F63C07"><enum>(1)</enum><text>total disability of any miner due to pneumoconiosis;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H41F9A577B604448282D9DAA51CD28C36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the death of any miner whose death was due to pneumoconiosis;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70239AB4D04B4F2AB070AE7DD9EF44FA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>total disability of any miner at the time of the miner’s death with respect to a claim filed under part C prior to January 1, 1982;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8E82393499D4362B621A6B45ED64297"><enum>(4)</enum><text>survivors’ benefits for any claim filed after January 1, 2005, that is pending on or after March 23, 2010, where the miner is found entitled to receive benefits at the time of the miner’s death as a result of the miner’s claim filed under part C; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A56B91864574174819AA4AB658E88FA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>survivors’ benefits where the miner is found entitled to receive benefits at the time of the miner’s death resulting from the miner’s claim filed under part C before January 1, 1982.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D4D8CE684084A44966451620A6A43D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <clause id="H26A65BBCFA404A3A8E0AB15A7EDBA7B5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>his pneumoconiosis</quote> and inserting <quote>the miner’s pneumoconiosis</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H32DB54173B3B457395FBBF69E0AE896A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>his death</quote> and inserting <quote>the miner’s death</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB4CC5121CDE4C5D8BB9A5C8D03876F2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 412 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/922">30 U.S.C. 922</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCD28B774570D41229AB5A83161FF460C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="HBDD90A1F5B134CC291CE0ED9B43C7E04"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text>
								<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H051A70C74F544A84BE94C4CF7A0E2DDD" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H9340459A529D44739DE8AC38FD46B490" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In the case of a surviving spouse—</text> <subparagraph id="HAE441CD7DC554427B03D5C8A88457801"><enum>(A)</enum><text>of a miner whose death is due to pneumoconiosis;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DFFC12A84B248BB998655968B9DFA24"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a claim filed after January 1, 2005, and that is pending on or after March 23, 2010, of a miner who is found entitled to receive benefits at the time of the miner’s death as a result of the miner’s claim filed under part C;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE59EDCDDBC647029CF4DAEBC6C596CD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>of a miner who is found entitled to receive benefits at the time of the miner’s death as a result of the miner’s claim filed under part C before January 1, 1982; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDD7335F4C5FA43939568BBE38CDB0D2B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in a claim filed under part C before January 1, 1982, of a miner who was totally disabled by pneumoconiosis at the time of the miner’s death,</text>
										</subparagraph></paragraph><quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="subsection">benefits shall be paid to the miner’s surviving spouse at the rate the deceased miner would receive
			 such benefits if he were totally disabled.</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause id="HC94A9EF0D06D43D8A571C849915D34BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <subclause id="H9F6C3D15286B4095B4E2D0D56FACF4EC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(3) In the case</quote> and all that follows through <quote>section 411(c)</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>(3)(A) In the case of the child or children of a miner described in subparagraph (B)</quote>;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H71E1C999DBBB412DA6E1BC306F9EEF76"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>he</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>the child</quote>;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HE269D5E4E78F4FA99981497D7C9CD03D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by striking <quote>widow</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>surviving spouse</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3497842E11C3476E83AB03857BA5F45D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF85B939877C04795B45BB595EDCEEF2F" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HBBB6AD63074B457699CBC8C17BE763BD" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Subparagraph (A) shall apply in the case of any child or children—</text>
 <clause id="H326E6E63001A4D2D996CBF1B6E3CAEAB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>of a miner whose death is due to pneumoconiosis;</text> </clause><clause id="H1E66C2ED79F7437CBF8F89779DAD5174"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a claim filed after January 1, 2005, that is pending on or after March 23, 2010, of a miner who is found entitled to receive benefits at the time of the miner’s death as a result of the miner’s claim filed under part C;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H08469CC164614F09A2A2F25455AC105B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>of a miner who is found entitled to receive benefits at the time of the miner’s death as a result of the miner’s claim filed under part C before January 1, 1982;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H504E8DEE03A5422CB0847B5901340C25"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in a claim filed under part C before January 1, 1982, of a miner who was totally disabled by pneumoconiosis at the time of the miner’s death;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD164DD63F2804CD880FD4C19DE83AFFD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>of a surviving spouse who is found entitled to receive benefits under this part at the time of the surviving spouse’s death; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7153618C7B554F37B84F8DC011C6D4FB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>entitled to the payment of benefits under paragraph (5) of section 411(c).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subclause></clause><clause id="H62D868E6E7654CB98CFF8F2DB0145D52"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text>
 <subclause id="HC68223C36DF84B9F8C6EEFC6C1A754F9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking the first sentence and inserting the following: <quote>In the case of the dependent parent or parents of a miner who is not survived at the time of death by a surviving spouse or a child and (i) whose death is due to pneumoconiosis, (ii) in a claim filed after January 1, 2005, that is pending on or after March 23, 2010, who is found entitled to receive benefits at the time of his the miner’s death as a result of the miner’s claim filed under part C, (iii) who is found entitled to receive benefits at the time of his death as a result of the miner’s claim filed under part C before January 1, 1982, or (iv) in a claim filed under part C before January 1, 1982, who was totally disabled by pneumoconiosis at the time of the miner’s death; in the case of the dependent surviving brother(s) or sister(s) of such a miner who is not survived at the time of the miner’s death by a surviving spouse, child, or parent; in the case of the dependent parent or parents of a miner (who is not survived at the time of the miner’s death by a surviving spouse or child) who are entitled to the payment of benefits under paragraph (5) of section 411(c); or in the case of the dependent surviving brother(s) or sister(s) of a miner (who is not survived at the time of the miner’s death by a surviving spouse, child, or parent) who are entitled to the payment of benefits under paragraph (5) of section 411(c), benefits shall be paid under this part to such parent(s), or to such brother(s), or sister(s), at the rate specified in paragraph (3) (as if such parent(s) or such brother(s) or sister(s), were the children of such miner).</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE14C5D62897F42E1BDB1522E68948AA5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the fourth sentence—</text> <item id="HBF0ABC58E5084133942F16A1FB08E6EC"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>by striking <quote>brother only if he</quote> and inserting <quote>brother or sister only if the brother or sister</quote>; and</text>
 </item><item id="H1CD5D4D17CC64BA09C0CFF0C76304EBA"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>by striking <quote>before he ceased</quote> and inserting <quote>before the brother or sister ceased</quote>; and</text> </item></subclause></clause><clause id="HDE67A7869F24491B90D5848D07281B62"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>prescribed by him</quote> and inserting <quote>prescribed by such Secretary</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B1D444AEAF640238E7660B9F0D3DFAA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <clause id="HDBB35C0AC3CF49089B6690F124946E6C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>his</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>such miner’s</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC72C04805E8940D9851C81C7D41C5FD4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>widow</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>surviving spouse</quote>; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD9BD0B34CC8453283A88174A14BF117"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>Internal Revenue Code of 1954</quote> and inserting <quote>Internal Revenue Code of 1986</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA17A3543DA55472191AB5124385E7F0F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 413 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/923">30 U.S.C. 923</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H5D8E80EF61EF44F388FA9F95EF0C305B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <clause id="HB97B7D0C42CB4730A069A7C02824B718"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>his wife’s affidavits</quote> and inserting <quote>affidavits of the miner’s spouse</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="HC2C2CFB1BAE34C26AF4CD1B4DD00B242"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the ninth sentence, by striking <quote>widow</quote> and inserting <quote>surviving spouse</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H116455397AF34A339E21A340D7DBBA2E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking the last sentence; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD76907DF2EF741BDA3448BBBBB71E997"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>his claim</quote> and inserting <quote>the claim</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE8039209E7E74AF39424B58FC14CE46B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in section 414 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/924">30 U.S.C. 924</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H23284946221841679D3D2B0525677E1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <clause id="H2C8A8B107EEC4691934DD6A0DF04B981"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>widow, within six months after the death of her husband</quote> and inserting <quote>surviving spouse, within six months after the death of the miner</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H02BC9E2F87564678A09F78AF140B62FB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(C), by striking <quote>his</quote> and inserting <quote>the child’s</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC37CB1046605417E9A23C11BF6AEF759"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text> <clause id="HCFF66A5834A0462D8E950589F45E96F8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>widow</quote> and inserting <quote>surviving spouse</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0714DF84520B44E5AC0D310F944BCE8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>his death</quote> and inserting <quote>the miner’s death</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H070B51F570B34F64936E2C2C3BCB15AE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in section 415(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/925">30 U.S.C. 925(a)</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE391988F3BCA4E9B94AA0313A905C724"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Internal Revenue Code of 1954</quote> and inserting <quote>Internal Revenue Code of 1986</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74641B9A97F74C83AC03F9013CC6B494"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
 <clause id="HE51794AC191C45C6963946C4FCD7AEAB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>he</quote> and inserting <quote>such Secretary</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H9881765880F744CF8A6590E1E5177169"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>him</quote> and inserting <quote>such Secretary</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF9C8583FEFB4680AC68C906AFAEFE4C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in section 421 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/931">30 U.S.C. 931</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H486FCA0D30594751B52F1AA52C533502"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>widows</quote> and inserting <quote>spouses</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD47559E231B14338B329890B07DB69D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)—</text> <clause id="H9F1F7C22E8C842A99E9FDE6DB2C3D5AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>he</quote> and inserting <quote>such Secretary</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDC1FAF815DAE40BFB30DA1ED3890DE70"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by striking <quote>promulgated by him</quote> and inserting <quote>promulgated by such Secretary</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE14E98F17F21421E877AD66E5E716091"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in section 422 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/932">30 U.S.C. 932</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H58A09406DA784FB39EE1D357E7D43DD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="HA996401C4A684545A57930731DC51CA7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Internal Revenue Code of 1954</quote> and inserting <quote>Internal Revenue Code of 1986</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAD512CCEE2DC4809979C82022EDDA04C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>he</quote> and inserting <quote>such Secretary</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0830A34D10C4D9CB04D62A636406F3C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (i)(4), by striking <quote>Internal Revenue Code of 1954</quote> and inserting <quote>Internal Revenue Code of 1986</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB3D27F8BA9B4C1C8B6C5B95BB9BAD32"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (j), by striking <quote>Internal Revenue Code of 1954</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Internal Revenue Code of 1986</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD88E0E9D19874005B7FCCD92A0036107"><enum>(10)</enum><text>in section 423(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/933">30 U.S.C. 933(a)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>he</quote> and inserting <quote>such operator</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F7C9C7FA3CF4C2582B7555BA71F6222"><enum>(11)</enum><text>in section 424(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/934">30 U.S.C. 934(b)</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H102DCE6A92D24D54AAB9DD1D8114C7C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter following subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1), by striking <quote>him</quote> and inserting <quote>such operator</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D75B4AC31724D98A9F935893B662C4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>Internal Revenue Code of 1954</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Internal Revenue Code of 1986</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF3FBE5A796E4FDBA07623FEDC6D9F22"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>Internal Revenue Code of 1954</quote> and inserting <quote>Internal Revenue Code of 1986</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H610E9457771A4BF7ABEB452893C3F7A7"><enum>(12)</enum><text>in section 428 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/938">30 U.S.C. 938</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="HAFC2BEB94D5140B4B74B8AB152380806"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>him</quote> and inserting <quote>such operator</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H463B9D1DCF08466085593E208CA2E589"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <clause id="H42AABB0419304B289529AB358A1129FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>he</quote> and inserting <quote>the miner</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1BBB93B75D444515AA2073874FCD131F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the third sentence, by striking <quote>he</quote> and inserting <quote>the Secretary</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="H537D4918E9C24DD78D58211B74565B60"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the ninth sentence—</text>
 <subclause id="HC12E6078B5EF40218C8150F8F6E84D47"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>he</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>the Secretary</quote>; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H930524461BC545F9BEDF82FB2B2737A0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>his</quote> and inserting <quote>the miner’s</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HE943B0474775430AABE4D858486A9AE4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the tenth sentence, by striking <quote>he</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>the Secretary</quote>; and</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9931586BB2C14BD0B3817361D9F6454E"><enum>(13)</enum><text>in section 430 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/940">30 U.S.C. 940</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB95316D9908C46019BC366BB66179B5D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>1977 and</quote> and inserting <quote>1977,</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H060052DBB3194537B79C64FD69539BEF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>1981</quote> and inserting <quote>1981, and the Black Lung Benefits Improvement Act of 2017, and any amendments made after the date of enactment of such Act,</quote>.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H7314D7CD0FE146148A9F8721182B28C4"><enum>112.</enum><header>Readjudicating cases involving certain chest radiographs</header>
 <subsection id="HBB1D604D96F2429CB6555A70A3538AAD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HB9BBBD4C49C24BB287C469F5A4A12B41"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered chest radiograph</header><text>The term <term>covered chest radiograph</term> means a chest radiograph that was interpreted as negative for simple pneumoconiosis, complicated pneumoconiosis, or progressive massive fibrosis by a physician with respect to whom the Secretary has directed, in writing and after an evaluation by the Secretary, that such physician’s negative interpretations of chest radiographs not be credited, except where subsequently determined to be credible by the Secretary in evaluating a claim for benefits under the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/901">30 U.S.C. 901</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H018BD49276224B13A6F561300E059990"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>The term <term>covered individual</term> means an individual whose record for a claim for benefits under the Black Lung Benefits Act includes a covered chest radiograph.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H93FA2CF6E445458896A7E35B62D7745B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered survivor</header><text>The term <term>covered survivor</term> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="H1A3AFDBC68734E63A7888094A9DF3DE2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a survivor of a covered individual whose claim under the Black Lung Benefits Act was still pending at the time of the covered individual’s death; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03E5449ADE094824971465CB178E7A6E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who continued to seek an award with respect to the covered individual’s claim after the covered individual’s death.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A88C89FB9914018B8CD9A644F9F04DF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Claims</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered individual or a covered survivor whose claim for benefits under the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/901">30 U.S.C. 901</external-xref> et seq.) was denied prior to the enactment of this Act may file a new claim for benefits under this Act not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H69BA3D02228D4B228E9F5957CD67A518"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Adjudication on the merits</header>
 <paragraph id="H58E3E9FBCFFC4F17BAAAFBBDB2703672"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any new claim filed under subsection (b) shall be adjudicated on the merits and shall not include consideration of a covered chest radiograph.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H11B9BCF8EA874C7D9EEC93B587CCE84A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered survivor</header><text>Any new claim filed under subsection (b) by a covered survivor shall be adjudicated as either a miner’s or a survivor’s claim depending upon the type of claim pending at the time of the covered individual’s death.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEB4B623029E24399B9FB385CBCC61AD9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Time of payment</header>
 <paragraph id="HC346D7310DBF4E1B9CDC91B6CBAFCF25"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Miner’s claim</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a claim, filed under subsection (b) and adjudicated under subsection (c) as a miner’s claim, results in an award of benefits, benefits shall be payable beginning with the month of the filing of the denied claim that had included in its record a covered chest radiograph.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H31BF6C490C8741E681FF39C9026806FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Survivor’s claim</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a claim, filed under subsection (b) and adjudicated under subsection (c) as a survivor’s claim, results in an award of benefits, benefits shall be payable beginning with the month of the miner’s death.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D1A8038F8F547909529941EC8C7883C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Contributing impact</header><text>The Secretary shall have the discretion to deny a new claim under subsection (b) in circumstances where the party opposing such claim establishes through clear and convincing evidence that a covered chest radiograph did not contribute to the decision to deny benefits in all prior claims filed by the covered individual or the covered survivor.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7E7F848ED81C46AD8E2E0BE4379AD6DB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation on filing of new claims</header><text>A new claim for benefits may be filed under subsection (b) only if the original claim was finally denied by a district director, an administrative law judge, or the Benefits Review Board established under section 21(b) of the Longshore and Harbor Workers' Compensation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/921">33 U.S.C. 921(b)</external-xref>).</text>
					</subsection></section><section id="H10E597B859DB4E7E8AB1C19B85EEA6A8"><enum>113.</enum><header>Disclosure of employment and earnings information for Black Lung benefits claims</header>
 <subsection id="H02B21EEDE88E454DBE5BE07E16A6F8B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Tax return information</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">Section 6103(l)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H997A13E22D604E548E60F8DDDFC8A604" style="OLC">
							<paragraph id="H187E2017A4FF4BE6A63D79EDE8B0C951"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Disclosure of return information to Department of Labor to carry out Black Lung Benefits Act</header>
 <subparagraph id="H21662B1CCB384935860DFCD8827AEC62"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commissioner of Social Security shall, on written request with respect to any individual, disclose to officers or employees of the Department of Labor return information from returns with respect to net earnings from self-employment (as defined in section 1402) and wages (as defined in section 3121(a) or 3401(a)) for employment for each employer of such individual.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H412EBF9463E14963902A73896D994F57"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Restriction on disclosure</header><text>The Commissioner of Social Security shall disclose return information under subparagraph (A) only for purposes of, and the extent necessary in, carrying out the proper administration of the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/901">30 U.S.C. 901</external-xref> et seq.).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9868A3F41D5047398D97DC40DCDB909A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Social security earnings information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 552a of title 5, United States Code, or any other provision of Federal or State law, the Commissioner of Social Security shall make available to the officers and employees of the Department of Labor, upon written request, the Social Security earnings information of living or deceased individuals who are the subject of a claim under the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/901">30 U.S.C. 901</external-xref> et seq.), which the Secretary of Labor may require to carry out such Act. Such information shall be made available in electronic form.</text>
					</subsection></section></part><part id="HE02937B0C7034508AF352B8C0F0E71B0" style="OLC"><enum>B</enum><header>Reports To improve the administration of benefits under the Black Lung Benefits Act</header>
				<section id="H41FFAC9DF929461B92AC524BE6080F46"><enum>121.</enum><header>Strategy to reduce delays in adjudication</header>
 <subsection id="H37E0B041DE224EF3A9B7AA74C71E7278"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Education and the Workforce and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a comprehensive strategy to reduce the backlog of cases pending on such date of enactment before the Office of Administrative Law Judges of the Department of Labor.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H745D1C6091564D378E6933C6B71F9403"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of strategy</header><text>The strategy under this section shall provide information relating to—</text> <paragraph id="H6EA84C51FA2242DF9D344F46D688197C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the current and targeted pendency for each category of cases before the Office of Administrative Law Judges of the Department of Labor;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H90FFFD69C8AF486B9AF9E8451245F3E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of administrative law judges, attorney advisors supporting such judges, support staff, and other resources necessary to achieve and maintain the targeted pendency for each category of such cases;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05BC92F5A5664C34BD8FA6357FE2B405"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the necessary resources to improve efficiency and effectiveness, such as equipment for video conferences, training, use of reemployed annuitants, and administrative reforms;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7FED359E04E542729987CAC11C0EBB1E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the impact of sequestration, furloughs, and the Federal Government shutdown, which occurred from October 1 to October 16, 2013, on increasing administrative burdens and the backlog of cases pending before such office; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25216D7B5986476E88A0D924FAD07B8C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>with respect to claims filed under the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/901">30 U.S.C. 901</external-xref> et seq.), the necessary resources needed to reduce the average pendency of cases to less than 12 months from the date of receipt of the case to the date of disposition of such case.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6DA99EA6AD8843068DFDF57AC7DF6346"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In preparing such strategy, the Secretary of Labor shall consult with organizations that have ongoing interactions with the Office of Administrative Law Judges of the Department of Labor, including organizations that represent parties in cases under the Black Lung Benefits Act, the Longshore and Harbor Workers' Compensation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/901">33 U.S.C. 901</external-xref> et seq.), and Federal statutes regarding whistleblowers, wages and hours for employees, and immigration.</text>
					</subsection></section><section id="H8B1A0BD1A5EF4223B9C1A54ACDF7ADD1"><enum>122.</enum><header>GAO report on black lung program</header>
 <subsection id="H6CD0B42A00834AB4B406093BE4100684"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives a report on any barriers to health care faced by coal miners with pneumoconiosis.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2F69529118EC473096C7749990A9C840"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H28A813010A654C17B6CCE84D9AFB04DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of possible barriers to health care under the Black Lung Benefits Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/901">30 U.S.C. 901</external-xref> et seq.) and the degree to which any barriers impact the ability of miners with legitimate medical needs, particularly such miners in rural areas, to access treatment for pneumoconiosis;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46488F4D4EEC449481E04CC376DD03A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations necessary to address issues, if any, relating to patient access to care under such Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H055FBD93B20348ADB88915B65F0F156C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an evaluation of whether the benefit payments authorized under such Act, as amended by this Act, are sufficient to meet the expenses of disabled miners, surviving spouses, dependents, and other family members entitled to receive benefits under the Black Lung Benefits Act.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection></section></part></title><title id="H45E3091B1318410C95E35631DE9DFDC9" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Standard for respirable dust concentration</header>
 <section id="H14A720409E304711BB36CCD8A3B4011C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>201.</enum><header>Standard for respirable dust concentration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 202 of the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/842">30 U.S.C. 842</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB418BBF4EE7F40CAB53609E1969E7725" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H710E2BDC515A4FC6A6A07F07B6F3F86C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reports</header>
						<paragraph id="HF9512E36034448288693BD81FE7E007C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Retrospective study</header>
 <subparagraph id="H54B6B3528C824E59B1F74FD526DE6CB6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on August 1, 2021, the Secretary shall conduct a retrospective study to assess the effectiveness of the Mine Safety and Health Administration’s final rule entitled <quote>Lowering Miners’ Exposure to Respirable Coal Mine Dust, Including Continuous Personal Dust Monitors</quote> (published May 1, 2014; 79 Fed. Reg. 24813), the data regarding the use of continuous personal dust monitors, and the rising number of cases of progressive massive fibrosis (PMF) to determine whether to—</text>
 <clause id="HD02AC53A82E0451EB519DD0BB693AAF2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>lower the applicable standard for respirable dust concentration to protect the health of miners;</text> </clause><clause id="HF4C9180A3345493EA3F53D8963EB893A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">lower the 100 μg/m<superscript>3</superscript> standard for quartz (crystalline silica) in respirable dust to better protect miners’ health;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD0C65DFD0FF04500809FE3B03408DA32"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>increase the frequency for taking samples of respirable dust concentration, using continuous personal dust monitors;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H042FD78EE23D4110BA6900501C646C7B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>modify the engineering controls and work practices used by mine operators to comply with the applicable standard for respirable dust concentration; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB0BCF80D172C4CDA92C545DC94B28CED"><enum>(v)</enum><text>convert samples taken for shifts that are greater than 8 hours to an 8-hour equivalent concentration to more accurately assess the conditions of miners working on longer shifts.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H337189D900384F1989437D17913975B0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Completion deadline</header><text>By August 1, 2022, the Secretary shall complete the study required by subparagraph (A) and report the findings of such study to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DB7F8A05FBA4555B113DC215552C59E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent studies</header><text>By August 1, 2025, and every 3 years thereafter, the Secretary shall conduct a new study as described in paragraph (1)(A) and report, by not later than one year after the commencement of the study, the findings of such study to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H394D6EB775E04514B20C5DDF7A74B13B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Revised standards</header><text>If any report of the Secretary under this subsection concludes that the applicable standard for respirable dust concentration should be lowered to protect the health of miners, or that the incidence of pneumoconiosis among coal miners in the United States, as reported by the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health, has not been reduced from such incidence prior to the implementation of the most recent applicable standard for respirable dust concentration, the Secretary shall, consistent with the requirements of this section and section 101, accordingly revise such standard and any applicable sampling or testing procedures not later than 24 months after the publication of such report of the Secretary under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title commented="no" id="HC7EA7B06F56144FD931B9A9C12259AEF" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Establishing the Office of Workers' Compensation Programs</header>
			<section commented="no" id="H3EFF35BCEE274FCC8B8A3AF959BB4CEA"><enum>301.</enum><header>Office of Workers' Compensation Programs</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H9DABBCF4CE514D75AD6A508B869DA994"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There shall be established, in the Department of Labor, an Office of Workers' Compensation Programs (referred to in this section as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text>
				</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H7CBB985B65944E709C441ED560714EAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Director</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H8110C7E3506A4F8189D65B1FD9CE5BB3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office shall be directed by a Director for the Office of Workers' Compensation (referred to in this title as the <quote>Director</quote>) who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3A63F3C6C8AB4373855E4DA091192770"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Director shall carry out all duties carried out by the Director for the Office of Workers' Compensation as of the day before the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD76042D79B154CFCBE2D4284DE24CEA7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The functions of the Office on and after the date of enactment of this Act shall include the functions of the Office on the day before the date of enactment of this Act, including all of its personnel, assets, authorities, and liabilities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H329E18EBC2524FB7BD95AC73CFA39BBE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>References to Bureau of Employees' Compensation</header><text>Reference in any other Federal law, Executive order, reorganization plan, rule, regulation, or delegation of authority, or any document of or relating to the Bureau of Employees' Compensation with regard to functions carried out by the Office of Workers' Compensation Programs, shall be deemed to refer to the Office of Workers' Compensation Programs.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="H596F7706CB6B4DBD84B7CDF0A0FBBC5B" style="OLC"><enum>IV</enum><header>Severability</header>
 <section id="HCB5F6B9208FD492087C8BABA9990EA73"><enum>401.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be invalid, the remainder of this Act, or an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision to other persons or circumstances, shall not be affected.</text>
			</section></title></legis-body></bill>


