<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2DE4EEC4344B43F3BA2A9499011A4961" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1388 IH: Clean Legislating and Ethical Accountability Now Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1388</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170307">March 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enact House Resolution 895, One Hundred Tenth Congress, (establishing the Office of Congressional Ethics) into permanent law.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC264C6166EC04D5EA38880022F1135E0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H27730B3D62C342A3951566AABB98730A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Clean Legislating and Ethical Accountability Now Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CLEAN Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9518BE5F75094CDF8D74B8BD5BBCD871" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enacting House Resolution 895 into permanent law</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">House Resolution 895, One Hundred Tenth Congress, is hereby enacted into permanent law, except that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2D5329920CBD4BAABA2D77C5495D27EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Office of Congressional Ethics shall be treated as a standing committee of the House for purposes of section 202(i) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4301">2 U.S.C. 4301(i)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H60D612804A9C42F3B6A31B943D242855"><enum>(2)</enum><text>references to the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct shall be construed as references to the Committee on Ethics;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3C2B3BB0A6564431BA70267EA5DBAD6D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the second sentence of section 1(b)(6)(A) shall not apply;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE150548FFE9461280B07B5855465BDB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>members subject to section 1(b)(6)(B) may be reappointed for a second additional term;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83232DCFB01E4232B5E9F156F9B47DA0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any individual who is the subject of a preliminary review or second-phase review by the board shall be informed of the right to be represented by counsel and invoking that right should not be held negatively against them; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9B35ED4ADA94D7CB3D2E250C21C6D0D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Office may not take any action that would deny any person any right or protection provided under the Constitution of the United States; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD06334F841BD4AFEAC0E6F1F6BA9D83E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Office of Congressional Ethics shall have the same subpoena power as a standing committee of the House of Representatives has under clause 2(m) of rule XI of the Rules of the House of Representatives and all references to the committee or to the chair of the committee in such clause shall be deemed to be references to the Office of Congressional Ethics or to the cochairmen of the board for purposes of this paragraph.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

