<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H661AFB64AA8C407EAD70A88F2223EA51" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2376 IH: Drug Diversion and Counterfeit Crackdown Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2376</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170504">May 4, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to protect and strengthen the drug supply chain in the United States by closing several statutory gaps in the penalty provisions of such Act that apply to drug diversion and counterfeiting.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC272774828DA46CB89328CDDE785197C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4BBD1E5180634EB1826445B3C1859D5F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Drug Diversion and Counterfeit Crackdown Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5039E25134F746E28C05075EB7A80BA7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H19BEDA5C16944336BAD71423CED6A352"><enum>(1)</enum><text>there should not be differing penalties under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/301">21 U.S.C. 301</external-xref> et seq.) for illegally diverting drugs into the United States that arbitrarily turn on the location where the drugs were initially manufactured;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H994ACB7D3D2C4D05BFFE761BAFB13F02"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such disparity should be addressed by providing the same penalties for diverting drugs made outside the United States and intended for a foreign market as the penalties that exist for diverting drugs made inside the United States and intended for a foreign market;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H16A5C0270A3442338FCDF7F8055C1EB2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>there should not be unequal treatment of counterfeiting and diversion, enabling criminal enterprises to exploit statutory loopholes and jeopardize patient and consumer safety without fear of significant penalties; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF19BB08440374103905A7ADFBFDFF304"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such unequal treatment should be addressed by increasing the penalties for counterfeiting to match the penalties for diversion.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H8814683AAB204C25B3997613A140D596"><enum>3.</enum><header>Protecting and strengthening the drug supply chain</header> 
<subsection id="H40C562A5FDD04B61BD43711559B6FE06"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Diverted drugs</header><text>Paragraph (1) of section 801(d) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/381">21 U.S.C. 381(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2A641AB7333841E19B96405856224B89"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(d)(1) Except as</quote> and inserting <quote>(d)(1)(A) Except as</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H876A3EA1D9414725BCAC25B2F8595E36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE7A8ACD78F4F47DE86D502C0B6EC8D91" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H1F7E05AF16054805A23ABE363578AE69" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as authorized by the Secretary in the case of a drug that appears on the drug shortage list in effect under section 506E, no drug that would be subject to section 503(b), and which is manufactured outside the United States and intended by the manufacturer or labeled to be marketed outside the United States, may be imported into the United States for sale or commercial use.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H367C024DE4A142808A51F6FCDD80B8DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Counterfeit drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (b) of section 303 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/333">21 U.S.C. 333</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6E5C10FB9CE446A48A5109B76A6EEB53" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H206F834387AA4627B5608C096D2D097A" indent="up1"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (a), any person who violates section 301(i)(3) by knowingly selling or dispensing, or holding for sale or dispensing, a counterfeit drug shall be imprisoned for not more than 10 years or fined in accordance with title 18, United States Code, or both.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

