<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H25DF8FEDDE9142DFBFDFE91707AEBCA4" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3376 IH: Jobs Now Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3376</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170724">July 24, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000537">Mr. Clyburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to create a pilot program to award grants to
			 units of general local government and community-based organizations to
			 create jobs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3509DE0B53354453BBF796618E117628" style="OLC">
 <section id="H93ED22B065BE42B88C15A7116A9801D0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Jobs Now Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section commented="no" id="HBD1F38833D8C4F199413AB34C50C5E8F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants to units of general local government</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subtitle D of title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3221">29 U.S.C. 3221</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding after section 172 the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H55F5611DDCA74FFEB4EE99589246E8E5" style="OLC">
				<section commented="no" id="H18E387CA550E4B7BA3BFBD62C0C4B5D8"><enum>173.</enum><header>Pilot program</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H7E86DFC7510447CE8BD3D3B8B2CA73AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 181(e), from the amounts appropriated under <internal-xref idref="H73C5C8D7FFAA4E46A244EE015EEA969B" legis-path="173B.(h)">subsection (h)</internal-xref>, the Secretary shall carry out a 2-year pilot program to award grants, on a competitive basis, to units of general local government or community-based organizations to retain, employ, or train employees providing a public service for a unit of general local government.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H10C1F40CC4E34B9381041F9884B8E735"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Unit of general local government defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>unit of general local government</term> means any general purpose political subdivision of a State, or the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the freely associated states of the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, or the Republic of Palau, that has the power to levy taxes and spend funds, as well as general corporate and police powers.</text>
					</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H5E39797FD62E48EFAADD9C08A3F69615"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header>
						<paragraph commented="no" id="H3514DA7E03444DB1AD5E3C141B99313A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required uses</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H76467DFC0E4348FC9BC69FE3106B4BFB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), a unit of general local government or community-based organization shall use not less than 50 percent of the grant funds received under this section to—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H1073021C96E0436BB4629A4EFA7FD003"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a unit, retain employees of such unit who are providing a public service for the unit and who would otherwise be laid off as a consequence of budget cuts; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HC7BFBED1B93D43B28B59E448E307B7EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an organization, retain employees of the organization who are providing a public service for the unit in which the organization is located and who would otherwise be laid off as a consequence of budget cuts.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4088175B3FF8424BA826B62A1B9DC590"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a case in which 50 percent of a grant amount received under this section would exceed the amount needed for a unit or organization to retain the employees described in subparagraph (A), the unit or organization may use only the amount needed to retain such employees for such purpose.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4444D7E7879542B1840AD513B88142D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorized uses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After using grant funds received under this section in accordance with paragraph (1), a unit of general local government or community-based organization may use any remaining grant funds provided under this section to—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H7C6461494CDD4B1C83D3D35F5098AFF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a unit of general local government—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H1773D367DBBF40E3B9BF2B98ADED06C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employ individuals in new positions providing a public service for the unit; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H12E9B7F08F734D7B9262AC2684251065"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>train individuals for new public service positions for the unit; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2D16736207CB4925A0C766724AFC051C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a community-based organization—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H957D805E547E4B249073B9B50EBE3021"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employ individuals in new positions that would provide a public service for the unit in which the organization is located or services in the private sector; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HC0C1D5BE74F84B4493117FD8682A3B04"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>train individuals for any such positions.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H66D2CA546EF4443C8D460FCF090DDCD7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority for certain individuals</header><text>The Secretary shall encourage each unit of general local government and each community-based organization receiving a grant under this section to use such grant funds to retain, employ, or train—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H19FC43CC6D8640BCB0204A5BAFF34489"><enum>(1)</enum><text>veterans;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDE38B5BDEC1F4CA4B18CEF6322D78AAC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals with disabilities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H68EDC99E6A124FC9938BBB73E1897A35"><enum>(3)</enum><text>individuals who are receiving unemployment benefits; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8FD667DD79BD41E98B604DFBAABCA592"><enum>(4)</enum><text>dislocated workers.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HACA7F048FF1D4B42BC666407348032B8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority for certain units and organizations</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H94BB78FDFBF441EF915AEC37D2192952"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Units</header><text>In awarding grants to units of general local government under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to units of general local government with high unemployment, foreclosure, and poverty rates as compared to other units of general local government applying to receive a grant under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H10BCB5B7F40B453ABB8253F56DE36A6A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Organizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants to units of general local government under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to community-based organizations located in units of general local government with high unemployment, foreclosure, and poverty rates as compared to other units of general local government applying to receive a grant under this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H16B39A6836924235AC427DEE8A50A70A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Each unit of general local government or community-based organization desiring to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD991CCAF8B64450EA4902B17C3037404"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the first appropriation of funds under <internal-xref idref="H73C5C8D7FFAA4E46A244EE015EEA969B" legis-path="q:H55F5611DDCA74FFEB4EE99589246E8E5:173B.(g)">subsection (h)</internal-xref>, the Secretary shall submit to Congress, a report on—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H54E096E0BB284CBC9F2135AC9ED18838"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number and percentage of individuals hired or trained, and the number and percentage of employees of units retained, as a result of a grant under this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H67A0355E5A804339A2EC9C59EBFD280A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>best practices in carrying out a grant program to hire, train, or retain employees of units of general local government.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H73C5C8D7FFAA4E46A244EE015EEA969B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000,000 to carry out this section for fiscal years 2018 and 2019.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


