<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD0D9A4FC527F4414ABA7D799CF3CF9F5" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3039 IH: San Gabriel Mountains Forever Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3039</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170623">June 23, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate certain Federal lands in the State of California as wilderness areas and as components
			 of the National Wilderness Preservation System, to designate portions of
			 the San Gabriel River and Little Rock Creek in that State as components of
			 the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H01C6CA85A8354494BA0D259A1925CA82" style="OLC">
		<section id="HB34AE7B292BA4F1E8A07CFD088FA1430" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; definitions</header>
 <subsection id="HFF4659B437F748A997D7EA193A906384"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>San Gabriel Mountains Forever Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HD28EFA4DAF3D4F6F8C98C072E7424147"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="HFE1F674D66A648AEB48068D96EBF7A73"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1DA750FB94E4BB79C66EB1DEDB8AC5F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of California.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9E9271D625BA4A8AA75DA8BC45EBCD5E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of wilderness, Angeles National Forest, California</header>
 <subsection id="HB490031B6A4B428CA19CB511BA712DFF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.), the following National Forest System lands in the State are designated as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB2D89586EBBB461E91987003E0000F0C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Condor peak wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land in the Angeles National Forest, comprising approximately 8,417 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Condor Peak Wilderness—Proposed</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Condor Peak Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2841E3CD7AF448787121675D75E2283"><enum>(2)</enum><header>San gabriel wilderness additions</header><text>Certain Federal land in the Angeles National Forest, comprising approximately 2,027 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>San Gabriel Wilderness Additions</quote> and dated _____, which is incorporated in, and considered to be a part of, the San Gabriel Wilderness designated by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/90/318">Public Law 90–318</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note; 82 Stat. 131).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3AA4356705464635AEF6A5DD1CB595F5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sheep mountain wilderness additions</header><text>Certain Federal land in the Angeles National Forest, comprising approximately 13,851 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Sheep Mountain Wilderness Additions</quote> and dated _____, which is incorporated in, and considered to be a part of, the Sheep Mountain Wilderness designated by section 101(a)(29) of the California Wilderness Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/425">Public Law 98–425</external-xref>; 98 Stat. 1623).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB60FB69CD8BC4A7B86FE93ADD09AE8A5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Yerba buena wilderness</header><text>Certain Federal land in the Angeles National Forest, comprising approximately 6,774 acres, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Yerba Buena Wilderness—Proposed</quote> and dated _____, which shall be known as the Yerba Buena Wilderness.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H48A852C0DD8E4B41A97CCF4C0E2D3E39"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Map and legal description</header>
 <paragraph id="HBE2ED3E831114E338A3D19E1FBE87261"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall file a map and a legal description of the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by subsection (a) with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H118B626AD0B5494CB1BF0DFE443E64BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6577F8D53A9453FA44A5B00518C4228"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H463AD3347712431697FDCE84D82D5D05"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct any clerical and typographical errors in the map and legal description.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFFCDF60B19B74799AD8E9E5DC9FD46B6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The map and legal description filed under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9DFF0F91F3394CAF86B4460785A10964"><enum>3.</enum><header>Administration of wilderness</header>
 <subsection id="HB1A03EFC68DC4B178D1F77A88987D643"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by section 2 shall be administered by the Secretary in accordance with this section and the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.), except that any reference in the Wilderness Act to the effective date of that Act shall be considered to be a reference to the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H6F12ED4B3F874F2F9E180E12CC73E1A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fire management and related activities</header>
 <paragraph id="HFFB64328163942C79FCE84D4564C4178"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may take such measures in a wilderness area or wilderness addition designated by section 2 as are necessary for the control of fire, insects, and diseases in accordance with section 4(d)(1) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(1)</external-xref>) and House Report 98–40 of the 98th Congress.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0A01D51D1E24932ADC8C795089A83B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funding priorities</header><text>Nothing in this Act limits funding for fire and fuels management in the wilderness areas or wilderness additions designated by section 2.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2324984F0AF749FA8EC7D1CF9471502D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Revision and development of local fire management plans</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall amend the local fire management plans that apply to the land designated as a wilderness area or wilderness addition by section 2.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDBD968D66D194A8B974D8A1905E7196C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Consistent with paragraph (1) and other applicable Federal law, to ensure a timely and efficient response to fire emergencies in the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by section 2, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA7EA360D70694B8185A207B7FBB13484"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, establish agency approval procedures (including appropriate delegations of authority to the Forest Supervisor, District Manager, or other agency officials) for responding to fire emergencies; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AE574C978BA48E38CEE968E15A42510"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enter into agreements with appropriate State or local firefighting agencies.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8568935AF0CA4AE3B07A60DFA25CC5CE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grazing</header><text>The grazing of livestock in the wilderness areas or wilderness additions designated by section 2, if established before the date of enactment of this Act, shall be administered in accordance with—</text>
 <paragraph id="H85C0EA1223B545A5992DD9B091E51ECE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 4(d)(4) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(4)</external-xref>); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5546FAEB0B24E6E8436C1DBF77B90FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the guidelines set forth in Appendix A of the report of the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the House of Representatives accompanying H.R. 2570 of the 101st Congress (H. Rept. 101–405).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H05FA5FEAE11544848AB1C61E0EE68B61"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header>
 <paragraph id="HB2608CE76A2B46E496BAC52B27974E58"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with section 4(d)(7) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(7)</external-xref>), nothing in this Act affects the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the State with respect to fish and wildlife on public land in the State.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H674F9045103546FA86D97EB6AABBB509"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management activities</header>
 <subparagraph id="H4BAA7E496E9F4710B4EE7074D14F3289"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In furtherance of the purposes and principles of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.), the Secretary may conduct any management activities that are necessary to maintain or restore fish and wildlife populations and habitats in the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by section 2, if the management activities are—</text>
 <clause id="H0125B610FB384D75AF5E788C8D88D5B4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consistent with relevant wilderness management plans; and</text> </clause><clause id="H4B7CD29C18CF4ACAB748A38C9E5753A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>conducted in accordance with appropriate policies, such as the policies established in Appendix B of House Report 101–405.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0AF44DC8C944A27B35263D446DF7D11"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>Management activities under subparagraph (A) may include the occasional and temporary use of motorized vehicles, if the use, as determined by the Secretary, would promote healthy, viable, and more naturally distributed wildlife populations that would enhance wilderness values while causing the minimum impact necessary to accomplish those tasks.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3B718635AC44E02B53005D1675D0BAA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Existing activities</header><text>Consistent with section 4(d)(1) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(1)</external-xref>) and in accordance with appropriate policies, such as those established in Appendix B of House Report 101–405, the State may use aircraft (including helicopters) in the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by section 2 to survey, capture, transplant, monitor, and provide water for wildlife populations, including bighorn sheep.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D05378025C54061A337226BAE6F25CF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Buffer zones</header>
 <paragraph id="HAE68A039177246D0B1A9AFC52CBB9CB9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Congress does not intend for the designation of wilderness areas or wilderness additions by section 2 to lead to the creation of protective perimeters or buffer zones around each wilderness area or wilderness addition.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D49546A8EE94E108EF3D4BB7F3BFAFD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities or uses up to boundaries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The fact that nonwilderness activities or uses can be seen or heard from within a wilderness area or wilderness addition designated by section 2 shall not, of itself, preclude the activities or uses up to the boundary of the wilderness area or addition.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE768DCEC3D70482BA063C9D53115793D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Military activities</header><text>Nothing in this Act precludes—</text> <paragraph id="H6C71488F3BE04E10B9352040679FF366"><enum>(1)</enum><text>low-level overflights of military aircraft over the wilderness areas or wilderness additions designated by section 2;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9BB250223088445EAC0685DE43325755"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the designation of new units of special airspace over the wilderness areas or wilderness additions designated by section 2; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC95990B91B042748BDBEB56245DE133"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the use or establishment of military flight training routes over wilderness areas or wilderness additions designated by section 2.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE524C43A61048C8BEFF7BF2B3DB38C3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Horses</header><text>Nothing in this Act precludes horseback riding in, or the entry of recreational or commercial saddle or pack stock into, an area designated as a wilderness area or wilderness addition by section 2—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1CAE3C34A5DA465BB7F205845ACF354F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in accordance with section 4(d)(5) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(5)</external-xref>); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3961B41ABA544DA0BF8B91CF5FD8DC40"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to any terms and conditions determined to be necessary by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H341A81FFD1054933ADDFD60CA9DFCFCC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Law enforcement</header><text>Nothing in this Act precludes law enforcement and drug interdiction efforts within the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by section 2 in accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6B7B914C942341EABAD6B4D5C5D1FCF0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by section 2 are withdrawn from—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE8454C9A05004E94AA1746807871A527"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8E861D0368347F39900105D65DA3A87"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H85114397129C43C68689DBE720F0D32E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>operation of the mineral materials and geothermal leasing laws.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A38039F7B3443D4ACF8F9BF9C443AF5"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Incorporation of acquired land and interests</header><text>Any land within the boundary of a wilderness area or wilderness addition designated by section 2 that is acquired by the United States shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA25C9BEFBC15438BAD87CBD53C55A8FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>become part of the wilderness area in which the land is located; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA943A1F644894CE49F1D6200168B56A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be managed in accordance with this section, the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.), and any other applicable law.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7AD86EF19874C958B56352E0EB710AA"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Climatological data collection</header><text>In accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.) and subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may authorize the installation and maintenance of hydrologic, meteorologic, or climatological collection devices in the wilderness areas or wilderness additions designated by section 2 if the Secretary determines that the facilities and access to the facilities are essential to flood warning, flood control, or water reservoir operation activities.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H63E332422C664034BECD624EB9252FD9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Designation of wild and scenic rivers</header>
 <subsection id="H94AF197057F747BA97926022E6AE465F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>Section 3(a) of the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1274">16 U.S.C. 1274(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H2B9F22833A734AD191C57E37B0B6BC2E" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H792A83495B3F4BFCAF1D084BA0D25167"><enum>(213)</enum><header>East fork san gabriel river, California</header><text>The following segments of the East Fork San Gabriel River, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture in the following classes:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAA860D17A06B41C0AE13B890A62C6D40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 10-mile segment from the confluence of the Prairie Fork and Vincent Gulch to 100 yards upstream of the Heaton Flats trailhead and day use area, as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6544BBC778CA4712B45C7415D396BB3B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 2.7-mile segment from 100 yards upstream of the Heaton Flats trailhead and day use area to 100 yards upstream of the confluence with Williams Canyon, as a recreational river.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H01E6FAB316A444538171582406F20C5C"><enum>(214)</enum><header>North fork san gabriel river, California</header><text>The 4.3-mile segment of the North Fork San Gabriel River from the confluence with Cloudburst Canyon to .25 miles upstream of the confluence with the West Fork San Gabriel River, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture as a recreational river.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D48F3EBA9A6444498ED0C187377F330"><enum>(215)</enum><header>West fork san gabriel river, california</header><text>The following segments of the West Fork San Gabriel River, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture in the following classes:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA64479E82A7640E2A37B28471079776A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 6.7-mile segment from 0.25 miles downstream of its source near Red Box Gap in section 14, T2N, R12W, to the confluence with the unnamed tributary .25 miles downstream of the power lines in section 22, T2N, R11W, as a recreational river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53C31DDEDF41402B872F640CE95DA71D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 1.6-mile segment of the West Fork from 0.25 miles downstream of the powerlines in section 22, T2N, R11W, to the confluence with Bobcat Canyon, as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H14948ED09352404E9922B61B61019E37"><enum>(216)</enum><header>Little rock creek, California</header><text>The following segments of Little Rock Creek and tributaries, to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture in the following classes:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD4C7D94279A24E02B50CF2BEC27891A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 10.3-mile segment from its source on Mt. Williamson in section 6, T3N, R9W, to 100 yards upstream of the confluence with the South Fork Little Rock Creek, as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E28B197437548C38B44A289629A6EC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 6.6-mile segment from 100 yards upstream of the confluence with the South Fork Little Rock Creek to the confluence with Santiago Canyon, as a recreational river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H750B3F99773D4BF597DD8C80864567E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 1-mile segment of Cooper Canyon Creek from .25 miles downstream of Highway 2 to 100 yards downstream of Cooper Canyon Campground, as a scenic river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H854A69CEA6134BB78692002CA30B15AA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The 1.3-mile segment of Cooper Canyon Creek from 100 yards downstream of Cooper Canyon Campground to the confluence with Little Rock Creek, as a wild river.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F914A20ABC64DCB80809B93B3E52AC3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The 1-mile segment of Buckhorn Creek from 100 yards downstream of the Buckhorn Campground to its confluence with Cooper Canyon Creek, as a wild river.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HBC74E6CE60B848C989A34D10D7AEDE73"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Water resource facilities and water use</header>
				<paragraph id="H08AABF66C91D4C54B4225EFA58B9879D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Water resource facilities</header>
 <subparagraph id="H4602090685BF4BC3B7C4572B64075C65"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>water resource facility</term> means—</text> <clause id="HD6229E06DB7C46639278A3045ECFB307"><enum>(i)</enum><text>irrigation and pumping facilities, dams and reservoirs, flood control facilities, water conservation works, including debris protection facilities, sediment placement sites, rain gauges and stream gauges, water quality facilities, recycled water pumping, conveyance distribution systems, and treatment facilities, aqueducts, canals, ditches, pipelines, wells, hydropower projects, and transmission and other ancillary facilities; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB6EE13212F234D6CADED73D7D7F21621"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other water diversion, storage, and carriage structures.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E60D229CFFF44A0A039175F9295992E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No effect on existing water resource facilities</header><text>Nothing in this section shall alter, modify, or affect—</text>
 <clause id="HF80042F23DE04B2DAA273DDD5866FFC5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the use, operation, maintenance, repair, construction, reconfiguration, expansion, or replacement of a water resource facility downstream of a wild and scenic river segment designated by this section, provided that the physical structures of such facilities or reservoirs shall not be located within the river areas designated in this section; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFDEA3A1A63A94FF29CCDB2C455FB625B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>access to a water resource facility downstream of a wild and scenic river segment designated by this section.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H072D6F36FA2A46B9A0864228569CAA9B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No effect on new water resource facilities</header><text>Nothing in this section shall preclude the establishment of new water resource facilities (including instream sites, routes, and areas) downstream of a wild and scenic river segment designated by this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H060F16D1A05748EB835507870C036C8A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Any new reservation of water or new use of water pursuant to existing water rights held by the United States to fulfill the purposes of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1271">16 U.S.C. 1271</external-xref> et seq.) shall be for non-consumptive instream use only within the segments designated by this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF81D7CACCA2C4F8BBD8DF201B37DB912"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Existing law</header><text>Nothing in this section affects the implementation of the Endangered Species Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H757530C188FD4DE1AFE5C172527A3023"><enum>5.</enum><header>Water rights</header>
 <subsection id="H018CC534D3714E24982DDF814D2DEC07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statutory construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act and no action to implement this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H4EE8918CD78648B79AE1E0F1DD05705E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall constitute or be construed to constitute either an express or implied reservation of any water or water rights or authorizing an expansion of water use pursuant to existing water rights held by the United States with respect to the land designated as a wilderness area or wilderness addition by section 2 or land adjacent to the wild and scenic river segments designated by the amendment made by section 4;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2051B7A3DA0040E7B91263866EFDD52F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall affect, alter, modify or condition any water rights in the State existing on the date of enactment of this Act, including any water rights held by the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD31052A849D148CC9E49236B61D36B47"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall be construed as establishing a precedent with regard to any future wilderness or wild and scenic river designations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2B381D76FAD41339BD36AC5442665F9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>shall affect, alter, or modify the interpretation of, or any designation, decision or action made pursuant to, any other Act; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB79C961E5B6462AAFA08AA6E5EE1AF7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>shall be construed as limiting, altering, modifying, or amending any of the interstate compacts or equitable apportionment decrees that apportion water among and between the State and other States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E9715B5889740879A69C0352C7F56A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State water law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall comply with and follow the procedural and substantive requirements of the law of the State in order to obtain and hold any water rights not in existence on the date of enactment of this Act with respect to the wilderness areas and wilderness additions designated by section 2, and the wild and scenic rivers designated by the amendment made by section 4.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


