<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H417917C8069F48B9B754995609138F1C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 50 IH: Unfunded Mandates Information and Transparency Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 50</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170103">January 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for additional safeguards with respect to imposing Federal mandates, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H97B00A73656C4EEDADDD85AAD08ADE35" style="OLC">
 <section id="H272050C1A5C0467892C3D9C108B99AD8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Unfunded Mandates Information and Transparency Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBD5C496B632D4BD8AD20DC6097021763"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC9CF2BCB3FAF48258AB73ED7875DF99E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve the quality of the deliberations of Congress with respect to proposed Federal mandates by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF5BFE4C589704E7A92EE8FE553AA0CEC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing Congress and the public with more complete information about the effects of such mandates; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACE0B3DCEB7C443D956A51E3F3483D78"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensuring that Congress acts on such mandates only after focused deliberation on their effects; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA86EE35051CE44049B973D5380A48BB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to enhance the ability of Congress and the public to identify Federal mandates that may impose undue harm on consumers, workers, employers, small businesses, private property owners, and State, local, and tribal governments.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="H2A2DA2736ABD40E7B52AC4A96C2B576E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Providing for Congressional Budget Office studies on policies involving changes in conditions of
 grant aid</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 202(g) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/602">2 U.S.C. 602(g)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D0AB6798B5F4FA98559D4976CA8D7CC" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H39C9918388684B2AB17D07A815C9033B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional studies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the request of any Chairman or ranking member of the minority of a Committee of the Senate or the House of Representatives, the Director shall conduct an assessment comparing the authorized level of funding in a bill or resolution to the prospective costs of carrying out any changes to a condition of Federal assistance being imposed on State, local, or tribal governments participating in the Federal assistance program concerned or, in the case of a bill or joint resolution that authorizes such sums as are necessary, an assessment of an estimated level of funding compared to such costs.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H77C7D8671806409D9E7BE433CF6B2C1F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Clarifying the definition of direct costs to reflect Congressional Budget Office practice</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 421(3) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/658">2 U.S.C. 658(3)(A)(i)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF53D7D04C469444E86453F7D2315F7A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(i), by inserting <quote>incur or</quote> before <quote>be required</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H64E7AD085F2842C789119FE0266FD631"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting after <quote>to spend</quote> the following: <quote>or could forgo in profits, including costs passed on to consumers or other entities taking into account, to the extent practicable, behavioral changes,</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HC11D1C980CBD4A879BE4E923621551EC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Expanding the scope of reporting requirements to include regulations imposed by independent
 regulatory agencies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of section 421 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/658">2 U.S.C. 658</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>, but does not include independent regulatory agencies</quote> and inserting <quote>, except it does not include the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Open Market Committee, or the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="HFC053D53AE5A4931A622EE69CDAF17D1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Amendments to replace Office of Management and Budget with Office of Information and Regulatory
 Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/4">Public Law 104–4</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1511">2 U.S.C. 1511 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H962D05138614492B81977208B1920C44"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 103(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1511">2 U.S.C. 1511(c)</external-xref>)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2E6D358D4CE6495881ED46F198C7EA97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Office of Management and Budget</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B7EB3C5CE6E4308BC8A8AB1A39A7835"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Director of the Office of Management and Budget</quote> and inserting <quote>Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H17C272BE85A1432DA3194A0D04A5E31D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 205(c) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1535">2 U.S.C. 1535(c)</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H763440BDE265404189DB77075A5DA1E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">OMB</header-in-text></quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84495988A7ED4E10953663F236B80423"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Director of the Office of Management and Budget</quote> and inserting <quote>Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H56507475E7634CE6AF2789905B78559A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 206 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1536">2 U.S.C. 1536</external-xref>), by striking <quote>Director of the Office of Management and Budget</quote> and inserting <quote>Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H09B23914D459441BAFA9501ED58AAC2B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Applying substantive point of order to private sector mandates</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 425(a)(2) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/658d">2 U.S.C. 658d(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8C36D0C23732433F998A2CB75B9C567B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Federal intergovernmental mandates</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal mandates</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8496A1AB675E46EFAD1313662592C044"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or 424(b)(1)</quote> after <quote>section 424(a)(1)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HEC708F9367B844D7812A0A6D582B56CB"><enum>8.</enum><header>Regulatory process and principles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 201 of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1531">2 U.S.C. 1531</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7D49323FAA644AF9A6D0FF1F6A8AC08" style="OLC">
				<section id="H636289B3D5374AECAB3C2BCFC8F982ED"><enum>201.</enum><header>Regulatory process and principles</header>
 <subsection id="H8ECE47E28CD4447E913CAFBBC1A5976A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agency shall, unless otherwise expressly prohibited by law, assess the effects of Federal regulatory actions on State, local, and tribal governments and the private sector (other than to the extent that such regulatory actions incorporate requirements specifically set forth in law) in accordance with the following principles:</text>
 <paragraph id="H287CF2A7F2B34F78AE52B0050F0624F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agency shall identify the problem that it intends to address (including, if applicable, the failures of private markets or public institutions that warrant new agency action) as well as assess the significance of that problem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D018FA015D74D86ABA715C4426B7C79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Each agency shall examine whether existing regulations (or other law) have created, or contributed to, the problem that a new regulation is intended to correct and whether those regulations (or other law) should be modified to achieve the intended goal of regulation more effectively.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC4AC004FD967455FA8D2E2F6939DB3BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Each agency shall identify and assess available alternatives to direct regulation, including providing economic incentives to encourage the desired behavior, such as user fees or marketable permits, or providing information upon which choices can be made by the public.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE99F16C32A904B3AAA0BB2E028D96D0A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>If an agency determines that a regulation is the best available method of achieving the regulatory objective, it shall design its regulations in the most cost-effective manner to achieve the regulatory objective. In doing so, each agency shall consider incentives for innovation, consistency, predictability, the costs of enforcement and compliance (to the government, regulated entities, and the public), flexibility, distributive impacts, and equity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB20C40FB40B43B793E7425A53334FB2"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agency shall assess both the costs and the benefits of the intended regulation and, recognizing that some costs and benefits are difficult to quantify, propose or adopt a regulation, unless expressly prohibited by law, only upon a reasoned determination that the benefits of the intended regulation justify its costs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46667A1E6285404794F5F8EEDF441E60"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Each agency shall base its decisions on the best reasonably obtainable scientific, technical, economic, and other information concerning the need for, and consequences of, the intended regulation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H04D922CEB5074DF08F272C387D6E18CD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Each agency shall identify and assess alternative forms of regulation and shall, to the extent feasible, specify performance objectives, rather than specifying the behavior or manner of compliance that regulated entities must adopt.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03E0B48B5BD142D9923A9020822040B2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Each agency shall avoid regulations that are inconsistent, incompatible, or duplicative with its other regulations or those of other Federal agencies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H66FBA3B893E44CA9ADA7ACD14032831B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Each agency shall tailor its regulations to minimize the costs of the cumulative impact of regulations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E7EA9118BEF4C169D43354976FDB207"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agency shall draft its regulations to be simple and easy to understand, with the goal of minimizing the potential for uncertainty and litigation arising from such uncertainty.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H81FE04BDC4CE4508B78D86AB9178A719"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulatory action defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>regulatory action</term> means any substantive action by an agency (normally published in the Federal Register) that promulgates or is expected to lead to the promulgation of a final rule or regulation, including advance notices of proposed rulemaking and notices of proposed rulemaking.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HBD8985A49A494C8E9EB81F86A123D46B"><enum>9.</enum><header>Expanding the scope of statements to accompany significant regulatory actions</header>
 <subsection id="H88901072FF5B4C0DAC827A4A113A4C94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) of section 202 of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1532">2 U.S.C. 1532</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11BD4489ACD240A8A0138E6F96C5DE62" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H624E2FA414434C389545B5B22A3DF21F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless otherwise expressly prohibited by law, before promulgating any general notice of proposed rulemaking or any final rule, or within six months after promulgating any final rule that was not preceded by a general notice of proposed rulemaking, if the proposed rulemaking or final rule includes a Federal mandate that may result in an annual effect on State, local, or tribal governments, or to the private sector, in the aggregate of $100,000,000 or more in any 1 year, the agency shall prepare a written statement containing the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H16F581C8C7514BF29FB7DDAE74F89767"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The text of the draft proposed rulemaking or final rule, together with a reasonably detailed description of the need for the proposed rulemaking or final rule and an explanation of how the proposed rulemaking or final rule will meet that need.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5625D2BCDC974AB39AC94C271C2B1D60"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the potential costs and benefits of the proposed rulemaking or final rule, including an explanation of the manner in which the proposed rulemaking or final rule is consistent with a statutory requirement and avoids undue interference with State, local, and tribal governments in the exercise of their governmental functions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3DFC89FF0B4E4F21810B3200B8E46041"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A qualitative and quantitative assessment, including the underlying analysis, of benefits anticipated from the proposed rulemaking or final rule (such as the promotion of the efficient functioning of the economy and private markets, the enhancement of health and safety, the protection of the natural environment, and the elimination or reduction of discrimination or bias).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H42BAC0EFFF264D9981D64B3404EACDAA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A qualitative and quantitative assessment, including the underlying analysis, of costs anticipated from the proposed rulemaking or final rule (such as the direct costs both to the Government in administering the final rule and to businesses and others in complying with the final rule, and any adverse effects on the efficient functioning of the economy, private markets (including productivity, employment, and international competitiveness), health, safety, and the natural environment).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFCC0136EBEE04D749FE5CA14E134B321"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Estimates by the agency, if and to the extent that the agency determines that accurate estimates are reasonably feasible, of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAAFEAF816D30410AB40CA5365E39C838"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the future compliance costs of the Federal mandate; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DEBF3AEF7834B8D98B140EBAF47051F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any disproportionate budgetary effects of the Federal mandate upon any particular regions of the Nation or particular State, local, or tribal governments, urban or rural or other types of communities, or particular segments of the private sector.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H377D64B3BB094370912CF8F8803E32FB"><enum>(6)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H498286EDE73F4C3BAF5529D5D750343F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A detailed description of the extent of the agency’s prior consultation with the private sector and elected representatives (under section 204) of the affected State, local, and tribal governments.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD3DCCB20B70443CA9353A51E4A471F6" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A detailed summary of the comments and concerns that were presented by the private sector and State, local, or tribal governments either orally or in writing to the agency.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78B84455B8894ECFADB406B53D28F578" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A detailed summary of the agency’s evaluation of those comments and concerns.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H59B399F2E4214D1788C34B10E5E2384F"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A detailed summary of how the agency complied with each of the regulatory principles described in section 201.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HECA00A8C066F4055A39B137D8F06FD85"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the effects that the proposed rulemaking or final rule are expected to have on private property owners, including the use and value of affected property.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H24D650F1221545CCAB6B2BB8EABE669F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement for detailed summary</header><text>Subsection (b) of section 202 of such Act is amended by inserting <quote>detailed</quote> before <quote>summary</quote>.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HF9E8221CA1DC44F5BA88899CEE7BC37B"><enum>10.</enum><header>Enhanced stakeholder consultation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 204 of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1534">2 U.S.C. 1534</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1AB5180A707E4484A329FA701675DF02"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and private sector</header-in-text></quote> before <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">input</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DAA6D3E2A8E40BD8BBC9936CCFE6CD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEBACE49D650349ECBBBA2070075F4D40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, and impacted parties within the private sector (including small business),</quote> after <quote>on their behalf)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H292E7DD2B8544936932E8AAD2E15187F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Federal intergovernmental mandates</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal mandates</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H81672DE617B44C26824661441814E74C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by amending subsection (c) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAD052008F72F44A695AAC4B898C210EA" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H030792EF7DFB4DD9A0DE9186EFEB0814"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>For appropriate implementation of subsections (a) and (b) consistent with applicable laws and regulations, the following guidelines shall be followed:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7B3A991397234CB2A8B8B19B5D381796"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Consultations shall take place as early as possible, before issuance of a notice of proposed rulemaking, continue through the final rule stage, and be integrated explicitly into the rulemaking process.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC876EA531234BCA9C23B63D9F3B8CD6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Agencies shall consult with a wide variety of State, local, and tribal officials and impacted parties within the private sector (including small businesses). Geographic, political, and other factors that may differentiate varying points of view should be considered.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF82C3C5D5BA4F808F6242B93D828B8F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Agencies should estimate benefits and costs to assist with these consultations. The scope of the consultation should reflect the cost and significance of the Federal mandate being considered.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6535AA48800449BAA59419C20541D6F5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Agencies shall, to the extent practicable—</text> <subparagraph id="HDEF26AC304F24A2F9EC3352246164A2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>seek out the views of State, local, and tribal governments, and impacted parties within the private sector (including small business), on costs, benefits, and risks; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3E86759C3244455860BCC70E76AD37A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>solicit ideas about alternative methods of compliance and potential flexibilities, and input on whether the Federal regulation will harmonize with and not duplicate similar laws in other levels of government.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9705AFBD51F447C9B464F30E56635BDC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Consultations shall address the cumulative impact of regulations on the affected entities.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8ED06F7A3078424EA1B500505E1DA1C9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Agencies may accept electronic submissions of comments by relevant parties but may not use those comments as the sole method of satisfying the guidelines in this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H1AEB07174C75465BBE7F1C0F5F2831C0"><enum>11.</enum><header>New authorities and responsibilities for Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 208 of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1538">2 U.S.C. 1538</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H494D40111DED4EAB9307302503693F54" style="OLC">
				<section id="HFA3630AB556C475FB6DF06BCEAD6EC14"><enum>208.</enum><header>Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs responsibilities</header>
 <subsection id="H9AA552F1B24D41C88DACA37D3772ED78"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs shall provide meaningful guidance and oversight so that each agency’s regulations for which a written statement is required under section 202 are consistent with the principles and requirements of this title, as well as other applicable laws, and do not conflict with the policies or actions of another agency. If the Administrator determines that an agency’s regulations for which a written statement is required under section 202 do not comply with such principles and requirements, are not consistent with other applicable laws, or conflict with the policies or actions of another agency, the Administrator shall identify areas of non-compliance, notify the agency, and request that the agency comply before the agency finalizes the regulation concerned.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H094D126C631146609F8A29C1C8E97552"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual Statements to Congress on Agency Compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs annually shall submit to Congress, including the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives, a written report detailing compliance by each agency with the requirements of this title that relate to regulations for which a written statement is required by section 202, including activities undertaken at the request of the Director to improve compliance, during the preceding reporting period. The report shall also contain an appendix detailing compliance by each agency with section 204.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HEE0EB68358BA44239143DED97E8DB4FD"><enum>12.</enum><header>Retrospective analysis of existing Federal regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/4">Public Law 104–4</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1511">2 U.S.C. 1511 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6C2980E0389941DFAB3A60ED23C9DA0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 209 as section 210; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF158CE736AD49E48E885BA9763A2AB5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 208 the following new section 209:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H147D1C4F7AF14F33922A12246F627853" style="OLC"> <section id="HBF716884E00B4CE4A95C11F29B76FF06"><enum>209.</enum><header>Retrospective analysis of existing Federal regulations</header> <subsection id="H37F3992AB54446DDA93783C437835C0F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the request of the chairman or ranking minority member of a standing or select committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate, an agency shall conduct a retrospective analysis of an existing Federal regulation promulgated by an agency.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB573AEE06D6C411EA129D1C1A07CFE84"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agency conducting a retrospective analysis of existing Federal regulations pursuant to subsection (a) shall submit to the chairman of the relevant committee, Congress, and the Comptroller General a report containing, with respect to each Federal regulation covered by the analysis—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8CE56BB111424CFC87D6F32384FA3710"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a copy of the Federal regulation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB7877301FA04D6C830460290C79FE03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the continued need for the Federal regulation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9FF8772898244EEBABF0B2EE63D96EA5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the nature of comments or complaints received concerning the Federal regulation from the public since the Federal regulation was promulgated;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2A99700C92FC4ADA8CF691916B0A61CB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the extent to which the Federal regulation overlaps, duplicates, or conflicts with other Federal regulations, and, to the extent feasible, with State and local governmental rules;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71D284FF0F1D41209E8EA9FCD1BA2119"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the degree to which technology, economic conditions, or other factors have changed in the area affected by the Federal regulation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3739B25BE0454226967E9DF0616B02B9"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a complete analysis of the retrospective direct costs and benefits of the Federal regulation that considers studies done outside the Federal Government (if any) estimating such costs or benefits; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF25B2B2478D47F8A481FB394EA85DE8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any litigation history challenging the Federal regulation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="H3623866C302241E48DBF809E8753AB26"><enum>13.</enum><header>Expansion of judicial review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 401(a) of the Unfunded Mandates Reform Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1571">2 U.S.C. 1571(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HE6FE55486308434AA6B1A92ED3D8B182"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraphs (1) and (2)(A)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H90E5D9B303F2428C882BCEF0FB38291E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>sections 202 and 203(a)(1) and (2)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>sections 201, 202, 203(a) (1) and (2), and 205 (a) and (b)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3A5E8EBF3ADA4DACB49B3B9B8856C1B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>only</quote> each place it appears;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB3EDA0E0B9C84CAB9695AF08825CC697"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(B), by striking <quote>section 202</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting the following: <quote>section 202, prepare the written plan under section 203(a) (1) and (2), or comply with section 205 (a) and (b), a court may compel the agency to prepare such written statement, prepare such written plan, or comply with such section.</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7C50D17CF77A4B67B6F62DE2D9EDAF28"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>written statement or plan is required</quote> and all that follows through <quote>shall not</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>written statement under section 202, a written plan under section 203(a) (1) and (2), or compliance with sections 201 and 205 (a) and (b) is required, the inadequacy or failure to prepare such statement (including the inadequacy or failure to prepare any estimate, analysis, statement, or description), to prepare such written plan, or to comply with such section may</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


