<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H313207F4B2D041A78FF9703836E1234A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3558 IH: Improve Access to Care for Our Female Veterans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3558</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001284">Mrs. Brooks of Indiana</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001202">Mrs. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make certain improvements relating to inspections of
			 Department of Veterans Affairs medical facilities and improving care for
			 women.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H17D99970BE204B01A9810F692DCF18A1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H28FA248F254D4CB89D11CF50106ADED5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improve Access to Care for Our Female Veterans Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF1B11966C5B0467E91CAD7CA1F4DA314"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="H5594BE80B98B4314ADDF0B101E4A218F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="H75CB10CE566541189D6F5BD869A4B5A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Veterans Affairs has policies in place to help ensure the privacy, safety, and dignity of women veterans when they receive care at its medical facilities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3C57C8AD28F436F912B92BDCBE87DE0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A Government Accountability Office report found many instances of noncompliance with such policies.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7F018D748A4473A8AF5560F21A9D388"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Women veterans are the fastest growing cohort within the veteran community.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C98882FE84F4323A3394332B4CCE7A9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Women serve in every branch of the Armed Forces and represent nearly 15 percent of the members of the Armed Forces currently serving on active duty and 18 percent of members of the National Guard and reserve components.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1BB4B3188D7342E79D3ADEA945CE445B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The number of women veterans using the medical care provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs is expected to increase dramatically.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B304B33CC704F8AA2549FF6BD719CC0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H3DD5DC70D00447569256DA5ABC827A40"><enum>(1)</enum><text>female veterans are put at risk by a system that is currently designed for men; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F722896813049B2A980AA0B8F52F98C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Department of Veterans Affairs should follow through with commitments to ensure female veterans can access services tailored to their needs.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6AB131BD9A3A4B4F98F8AFB7C0789779"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improvement of inspections of Department of Veterans Affairs medical facilities and improvement of
			 care for women provided by Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
 <subsection id="HAC3ED57BC6A144B98BF63A0CE447098C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Improvement of inspections process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall strengthen the environment of care inspections process and oversight of such process by—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2EB4D9FEB0734B1FACB7AF068FDC9911"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expanding the list of requirements that facility staff inspect for compliance to align with the women's health handbook of the Veterans Health Administration;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE4BE12EDC3D84662B17ECE70D34D1D88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensuring that all patient care areas of Department medical facilities are inspected as required;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2124693D8DE5439BB759C6A57252BC33"><enum>(3)</enum><text>clarifying the roles and responsibilities of Department medical facility staff responsible for identifying and addressing compliance; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H32A87014AA30492A9CB5C2B0D6A0E96F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establishing a process to verify that noncompliance information reported by facilities to the Veterans Health Administration central office is accurate and complete.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAAD43915E8CE46A5B174767A36A388D6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Improvement of care for women</header>
 <paragraph id="H7C87DD8A2E7D4CCA9DDEEB888F21CD3F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Monitoring of sex-specific care services</header><text>To improve care for women veterans, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall monitor women veterans' access to sex-specific care services under current and future community care contracts. Such monitoring shall include an examination of appointment scheduling and completion times, driving times to appointments, and reasons appointments could not be scheduled with community providers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H44AEDC924ADC454C8DB629F686CB7636"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H1950269B8E564307A6EFE398AA64A903"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <quote>sex-specific care services</quote> means mammography, maternity care, and gynecology.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6BCD700299A418EB779F2431C6FA169"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>community care contract</quote> means an agreement described in section 101(d) of the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/146">Public Law 113–146</external-xref>).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


