<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H887E9ABF24D14C1A809DA97074E31B4D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3410 IH: Stop Infant Mortality And Recidivism Reduction Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3410</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170726">July 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enhance public health and safety by improving the effectiveness and efficiency of the Federal
			 prison system for incarcerated pregnant women and mothers by establishing
			 a pilot program of critical-stage, developmental nurseries in Federal
			 prisons for children born to inmates, with risk and needs assessments, and
			 risk and recidivism reduction.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2B53F3D144594D9E99665C611389C078" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCA863CC026144C79BFC203140D04E2EA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Infant Mortality And Recidivism Reduction Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SIMARRA Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF65A4C2AACA941BCBFAC00404948220D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Prisons (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>) shall establish a pilot program (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) in accordance with this Act to permit women incarcerated in Federal prisons and the children born to such women during incarceration to reside together while the inmate serves a term of imprisonment in a separate housing wing of the prison.</text>
 </section><section id="H8031DA444E7F491993AD8AB5E76A5A64"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of the Act are to—</text> <paragraph id="H185B97AD29DB4778B2212DA49CE3E60F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prevent infant mortality among infants born to incarcerated mothers and greatly reduce the trauma and stress experienced by the unborn fetuses of pregnant inmates;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8893D7F0411C4D8FB51CB4CECB45EAA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduce the recidivism rates of federally incarcerated women and mothers, and enhance public safety by improving the effectiveness of the Federal prison system for women as a population with special needs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C8F8D147FE9424EAFDC27B6667BDFD1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish female offender risk and needs assessment as the cornerstones of a more effective and efficient Federal prison system;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H27BA550326414868BCBD8322CC0E8727"><enum>(4)</enum><text>implement a validated post-sentencing risk and needs assessment system that relies on dynamic risk factors to provide Federal prison officials with a roadmap to address the pre- and post-natal needs of Federal pregnant offenders, manage limited resources, and enhance public safety;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE17440F03924CB78395273E49809AAD"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">perform regular outcome evaluations of the effectiveness of programs and interventions for federally incarcerated pregnant women and mothers to assure that such programs and interventions are evidence-based and to suggest changes, deletions, and expansions based on the results of such evaluations; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B68252BB27B4806B33CEE14543B0845"><enum>(6)</enum><text>assist the Department of Justice to address the underlying cost structure of the Federal prison system and ensure that the Department can continue to run prison nurseries safely and securely without compromising the scope or quality of the Department’s critical health, safety and law enforcement missions.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H2D269C5B08A54E22A1297029A3EB9F69"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duties of the Director of Federal Bureau of Prisons</header>
 <subsection id="H9E822E69A42148088F13B8DC3FAB17AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall carry out this section in consultation with—</text> <paragraph id="H814B645EDF9A4EAFBAED5865277B7146"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a licensed and board-certified gynecologist or obstetrician;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H22611FD2C13E42FC88B5CA0B6BB58F4E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HADDACACEC1F541158A3F1B87C8297123"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Director of the Office of Probation and Pretrial Services;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4611A793F782434EB2942EA6DC398DA7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Director of the National Institute of Justice; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8312D3B2490E4DBAB2B5AE5AAD5F774F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Director of the U.S. Department of Health &amp; Human Services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H76E83E78979D48328D2ABD40E5466505"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Director shall, in accordance with subsection (c)—</text> <paragraph id="H5B5A94DB7701430790AD558232E24275"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop an offender risk and needs assessment system particular to the health and sensitivities of federally incarcerated pregnant women and mothers in accordance with this section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC604DB6F3F7C4793AC3E66D8E8D7294B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop recommendations regarding recidivism reduction programs and productive activities in accordance with section 9;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F4AE66E2D6445869F63B892F4EEE5F1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conduct ongoing research and data analysis on—</text> <subparagraph id="HD4FE34622AF54168B95A7EDE68EF388D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the best practices relating to the use of offender risk and needs assessment tools particular to the health and sensitivities of federally incarcerated pregnant women and mothers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACFC7C5EEF3148AAA67A46DBA3D57F6B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the best available risk and needs assessment tools particular to the health and sensitivities of federally incarcerated pregnant women and mothers and the level to which they rely on dynamic risk factors that could be addressed and changed over time, and on measures of risk of recidivism, individual needs, and responsivity to recidivism reduction programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBAFC6446F42452297D55E2DE3306B88"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the most effective and efficient uses of such tools in conjunction with recidivism reduction programs, productive activities, incentives, and rewards; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B2C7714B6884A2EA6F0CEF481DE1EE3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>which recidivism reduction programs are the most effective—</text> <clause id="HA174E1FF2F3146C49B66D5C06A14229A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for federally incarcerated pregnant women and mothers classified at different recidivism risk levels; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H95B40C0ACB524E56B316644F4D0F94F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for addressing the specific needs of federally incarcerated pregnant women and mothers;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C729C98CC7C4B8B9DA1153B70255194"><enum>(4)</enum><text>on a biennial basis, review the system developed under paragraph (1) and the recommendations developed under paragraph (2), using the research conducted under paragraph (3), to determine whether any revisions or updates should be made, and if so, make such revisions or updates;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H57955E83BA274161BD08E814632672D4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>hold periodic meetings with the individuals listed in subsection (a) at intervals to be determined by the Director; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B3AAEF533DE457F870F8AC88F820827"><enum>(6)</enum><text>report to Congress in accordance with section 9.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09A631384A1B4617A12F0DCEEF80EDCA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Methods</header><text>In carrying out the duties under subsection (b), the Director shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H300410AB0C2147D1B5091E76CE330AA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult relevant stakeholders; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAD46D130FE0444C8E6737E52741496D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make decisions using data that is based on the best available statistical and empirical evidence.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF55F106AE57944CE90C390BB83A97A1A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An inmate may apply to participate in the Program if the inmate—</text> <paragraph id="H6F099095E92E4EC9A26B12DAA5E2CACC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is pregnant at the beginning of the term of imprisonment; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8708ABEE930B4F468A3787BB1875A9A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is in the custody or control of the Federal Bureau of Prisons.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HEEC5519F871F48A9957975F8F7426FE3"><enum>6.</enum><header>Program terms</header> <subsection id="H5532D3ED4FA542E79A68128C92689756"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Term of participation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To correspond with the purposes and goals of the program to promote bonding during the critical stages of child development, an eligible inmate selected for the Program may participate in the Program, subject to section 7, for the shorter of the inmate’s term of imprisonment or 30 months.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H286DECC6978645CCB66912DDFFEA4350"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inmate requirements</header><text>For the duration of an inmate’s participation in the Program, the inmate shall agree to—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H5D9ECFDBD2EA485DA9F6789E456FF118"><enum>(1)</enum><text>accept the responsibility of child-rearing;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB0F2D274E0248A1A82EC66E0F4487BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">participate in any educational or counseling opportunities established by the Director, including topics such as child development, parenting skills, domestic violence, vocational training, or substance abuse;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H327CA9DF9B2E46F2A812D1C4DEAC296D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>abide by any court decision regarding the legal or physical custody of the child;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CDDD6B0B1E6471381B20897695351D8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transfer to the Federal Bureau of Prisons any child support payments for the infant of the participating inmate from any person or governmental entity; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8DABC94DE38241FF89496FEDC949277F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify a person who has agreed to take custody of the child if the inmate’s participation in the Program terminates before the inmate’s release.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9CF8CD6D5F614843BDA6FE9BC62E6616"><enum>7.</enum><header>Termination of participation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An inmate’s participation in the Program terminates upon the earliest of the following to occur:</text> <paragraph id="HADB124F46565477196D87D6D8E13B328"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The inmate is released from prison.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99868B9FF81F497197CBDA59E59A3F79"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The infant fails to meet any medical criteria established by the Director or the Director’s designee along with a collective determination of the persons listed in section 4(a).</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HDBBBEC723D0D476291950CA331E6AE94"><enum>8.</enum><header>Continuity of care</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director shall take appropriate actions to prevent detachment or disruption of either an inmate’s or infant’s health and bonding-based well-being due to termination of the Program.</text>
		</section><section id="HA3069F07FFAF46D8A09EB1FD8A351BC3"><enum>9.</enum><header>Reporting</header>
 <subsection id="HE568FA145CAB4CCDB7D5731B8AD06B72"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act and once every year thereafter for 5 years, the Director shall submit a report to the Congress with regards to progress in implementing the Program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7BE0620629DA43C88716AFEF053307B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the termination of the Program, the Director shall issue a final report to the Congress that contains a detailed statement of the Director’s findings and conclusions, including recommendations for legislation, administrative actions, and regulations the Director considers appropriate.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H07D30A281E184409BC9D176226E0B302"><enum>10.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To carry out this Act, there is authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


