<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H28A6A37FC0254A138776D93BB26E18C4" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3897 EH: Gold Star Family Support and Installation Access Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3897</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for the issuance of the Gold Star Installation Access Card to the surviving spouse, dependent children, and other next of kin of a member of the Armed Forces who dies while serving on certain active or reserve duty, to ensure that a remarried surviving spouse with dependent children of the deceased member remains eligible for installation benefits to which the surviving spouse was previously eligible, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H18A3D644084D4D608786E2BEAE49EC89" style="OLC"><pagebreak/>
<section id="H4FBDDF8B78ED4A0589C016B9A6841CE0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gold Star Family Support and Installation Access Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H9462AD6BF3334AF78A65939AA6DA031A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7824151F348C471BA958159C833A3A5B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Since World War I, the gold star symbol has been used by American families to honor members of the Armed Forces who have given their lives in service to the Nation.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H9036FAB32E094D2BBED41D083B97FACF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Surviving families of deceased members of the Armed Forces confront many challenges, often made worse by policies that fail to compassionately honor the memory of their loved one’s service and sacrifice to the Nation.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC900281CBA224FE4AB7EE871190B62D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>There is an obligation to ensure that the Gold Star family connections to the military community remain an eternal bond providing strength and comfort to surviving family members and to those still serving.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H476E84054DBC456CB7063251F3C5E6DA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Individual military services have recognized the need to provide installation access to Gold Star families to attend memorial events, visit gravesites, and access other benefits for which family members are eligible and entitled.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H970526D060584AC1AB072C31C68F0B42"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Surviving families of deceased members of the Armed Forces relocate to other parts of the country, often far away from the service installation where their loved one last served.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA9FB0BE325F4E15AE40044C869A1C46"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Current Department of Defense policy rescinds on-base benefits to surviving spouses of deceased service members who remarry, even when dependent children under the guardianship of the surviving spouse remain eligible for benefits, effectively rendering these benefits inaccessible by the children of the deceased member.</text> </paragraph></section> 
<section id="HF9C17E89C4DD4B90B15CF2D77487486F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Issuance of Gold Star Installation Access Cards</header> 
<subsection id="H8CD564E9B7754EB3B7E1F1636F128745"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Issuance and conditions on use</header> 
<paragraph id="H611463E6C56B4F81B7EDAB98BFD44BFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/57">Chapter 57</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1126">section 1126</external-xref> the following new section:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H44A1B78A6755414A8D1B24C13058A57B" style="USC"> <section id="HB74B8E4259CB466B94CD56B21013C271"><enum>1126a.</enum><header>Gold Star Installation Access Card: issuance and protections</header> <subsection id="HDFE7DC13AA4C4177918552FE1344D888"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Issuance to Gold Star surviving spouse and dependent children of deceased member required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary concerned shall provide for the issuance of a standardized Gold Star Installation Access Card to the widow and dependent children of a deceased member of the armed forces described in section 1126(a) of this title to facilitate their ability to gain unescorted access to military installations for the purpose of attending memorial events, visiting gravesites, and obtaining the on-installation services and benefits to which they are entitled or eligible.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H8E3C4D44DED14BF99CACB4795195631A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Issuance to other next of kin authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the discretion of the Secretary concerned, the Secretary concerned may provide the Gold Star Installation Access Card to the parents and other next of kin of a deceased member of the armed forces described in section 1126(a) of this title.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H7409B640CBEB497081F8DD22A76B3727"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Service-Wide acceptance of access card</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretaries concerned shall work together to ensure that a Gold Star Installation Access Card issued by one armed force is accepted for access to military installations under the jurisdiction of another armed force.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H878C726EF88C4D4988D85B2B483BC5A4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Protection of installation security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing, issuing, and accepting the Gold Star Installation Access Card, the Secretary concerned may take such measures as the Secretary concerned considers necessary—</text> <paragraph id="HC4E4EC4025D845FE8A31F2B84C245B5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prevent fraud in the procurement or use of the Gold Star Installation Access Card;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0B9379F3E8DE4D0BA784754F9B4A7A9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to limit installation access to those areas of the installation that provide the services and benefits for which the recipient of the Gold Star Installation Access Card is entitled or eligible; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D696B5499E2444282B39B9E70BFA8CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure that the availability and use of the Gold Star Installation Access Card does not adversely affect military installation security.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB5C2FA5217774FAFBACB27281ABA4555"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Gold Star Installation Access Card for the widow and dependent children of a deceased member of the armed forces shall remain valid for the life of the widow or child, regardless of subsequent marital status of the widow, subject to periodic renewal as determined by the Secretary concerned to ensure military installation security.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE4E854F9A00B41C6842173124B39235E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1126">section 1126</external-xref> the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0C68834B58D433EA3CCA002A6DD3453" style="USC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">1126a. Gold Star Installation Access Card: issuance and protections.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD3A886B91C024B109BFE5F45BA856F5C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability of current definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1126(d) of title 10, United States Code is amended by striking the matter preceding paragraph (1) and inserting the following: <quote>In this section and section 1126a of this title:</quote>.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="HA69DD7157B174700903188087A1F5C75"><enum>4.</enum><header>Extension of commissary and exchange benefits for remarried spouses with dependent children</header> <subsection id="HF539EB99F6114E9389BF1C7E56571AB3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1062 of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H360C46509CD04D999A4EF9644AE99A88"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretary of Defense</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC9BB299B7A64E76AAA311F18BEA245D" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H3AEE9F4B6AAA48C58F76B1904244000E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Certain unremarried former spouses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE747A25816684C61A7AC7C36320E045B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H08B68C7F6BB3464DA55F3BDDFC991248" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H805DF24F26CB49A8AC9E8D6ED69C7223"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certain remarried surviving spouses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to provide that a surviving spouse of a deceased member of the armed forces, regardless of the marital status of the surviving spouse, who has guardianship of dependent children of the deceased member is entitled to use commissary stores and MWR retail facilities to the same extent and on the same basis as the unremarried surviving spouse of a member of the uniformed services.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE9FD82B0EA3E44559F6884B303F5CB1F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 1062 of title 10, United States Code, is further amended—</text> <paragraph id="H26B75774F4EA4D9CB0C73E3D8D524BE2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>commissary and exchange privileges</quote> and inserting <quote>use commissary stores and MWR retail facilities</quote>; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H39797361084942549211AD78CBFC64CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC25852B914F74460AB31CA9DF38261C1" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HC6664E2FF3594E65AA9A34801062B401"><enum>(c)</enum><header>MWR retail facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>MWR retail facilities</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1063(e) of this title.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB5F95F9E69A64A969CBA69C023C47037"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="HA529F9E5D0F747C1B11B3E3DB412396B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Section heading</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The heading of section 1062 of title 10, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B6AA3BAEAB643DEB060182B5F72150B" style="USC"> <section id="H01C5D790225E4079BFD3E16EB2BE2BDE"><enum>1062.</enum><header>Certain former spouses and surviving spouses</header></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H556211410F1341C79C2ECCA063796DC7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/54">chapter 54</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 1062 and inserting the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91408B67241E4A83A77C2825CD185F39" style="USC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">1062. Certain former spouses and surviving spouses.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20171107" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives November 7, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> 
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> 
</bill> 


