<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H30655E6590A4443CB658F353D07C0850" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4679 IH: Ensuring Equal Access to Treatments Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4679</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171218">December 18, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000578">Mr. Reichert</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for improvements to coverage and payment
			 under the Medicare program for new drugs, devices, and technology.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF1544433E6604866AF9334CC50E4CF98" style="OLC">
 <section id="H301B03448DBA42AD9082E2BB103D0265" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Equal Access to Treatments Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDB59B498A0C846E2A8744697D241DA5E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Coverage and payment for new drugs, devices, and technology under the Medicare program</header> <subsection id="H3895379D587B455283C3CEB3D750A397"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Improvements to NTAP payment adjustment under the inpatient prospective payment system</header> <paragraph id="H20A19127E094418D8578B3568D70E0C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payment for costs of new technologies</header><text>With respect to hospital discharges occurring on or after October 1, 2018, for which payment is made under section 1886(d) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)</external-xref>), in calculating the amount of the additional payment for a new medical service or technology under paragraph (5)(K) of such section with respect to such a discharge, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall apply section 412.88 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H89E640A3D3834F2397BCB80C6A0270F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as if the reference to <quote>50 percent</quote> each place it appears in such section were a reference to <quote>75 percent</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1B6CA8D7711F4739BD50A6398AA85161"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as if paragraph (b) of such section did not include <quote>Unless a discharge case qualifies for outlier payment under § 412.84.</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEFC2C6F10CA4FBE8CA004C525BFE55F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Revision to the cost threshold</header><text>Section 1886(d)(5)(K) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(5)(K)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HA68C4A4FFAD14756A8D70E6178270029"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text>
 <clause id="HDBCBF359DE754A29905B1027D79DB75F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>75 percent</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>50 percent</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H4D5D4DAFAD2249FF97F4370C39C1FA59"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subclause (II), by striking <quote>not less than two years and not more than three years</quote> and inserting <quote>five years</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB7D8ED27A5D4AAEBFC74DCF7A4FB847"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>International Classification of Diseases, 9th Revision, Clinical Modification (‘‘ICD–9–CM’’)</quote> and inserting <quote>International Classification of Diseases, 10th Revision, Clinical Modification (‘‘ICD–10–CM’’)</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4050D31E17A44EA5A3D3717970EF3502"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Revision to the commencement of the period for collection of cost data for new technologies</header><text>Section 1886(d)(5)(K)(ii)(II) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(5)(K)(ii)(II)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>the later of the date that is the date of the clearance or approval by the Commissioner of Food and Drugs of the service or technology or</quote> after <quote>beginning on</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H40702DA40028490D8CB20B5B6A75E1EF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Permitting appeals of ntap determinations</header>
 <subparagraph id="H53AD9201FC0F43E2A3907D2FB5F038DB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1886(d)(5)(K) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(5)(K)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H16E53E76E99C441DADA384C829993FD0" style="OLC">
							<clause id="HC3DE017E1F3645CCA0F7E4AE326CD963" indent="up3"><enum>(x)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF64AC1CCCEF04C77B103F9E3C10F2F43"><enum>(I)</enum><text>An individual or entity that submits an application for additional payment under this subparagraph for a new technology shall be entitled to administrative review of an adverse determination by the Secretary with respect to such application.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6DBDE86FA920470BB0A9A83F53502286" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The Secretary shall establish a process for administrative review for purposes of subclause (I). Under such process, administrative review shall be conducted by the Departmental Appeals Board of the Department of Health and Human Services. Under such process, the Departmental Appeals Board shall complete administrative review within 90 days of the date of receipt of the request for such review.</text>
								</subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3564E1A56CE642E9A7E31C826A5EA032"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 1886(d)(7)(B) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(7)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>but not including a denial by the Secretary of an application for additional payment under paragraph (5)(K)</quote> after <quote>paragraph (4)(D)</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3136813468E04B94A5BB81F17A07F32D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Requiring new DRG codes for new technologies coming off of new technology add-on</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1886(d)(5)(K)(ii)(IV) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(5)(K)(ii)(IV)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or existing</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C7D0181209440ED83A6440A1178FE8D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Limit on aggregate annual adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1886(d)(5) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(5)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H60B142C905CA484AAB0104480AD3A49C" style="OLC">
						<subparagraph id="H1C8DAF816CD64D1CB216E0AA1B0969FE"><enum>(M)</enum><header>Limit on aggregate annual adjustment</header>
 <clause id="H9CFBB6BCCF0D403AA7C4B27FF1E47427"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total of the additional payments made under subparagraphs (K) and (L) for covered services furnished for discharges in a fiscal year (as estimated by the Secretary before the beginning of the fiscal year) may not exceed the applicable percentage (specified in clause (ii)) of the total program payments estimated to be made under this subsection for all covered services furnished for discharges in that fiscal year. If this clause is first applied to less than a full fiscal year, the previous sentence shall apply only to the portion of such fiscal year.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6FAB4901973F46AA99BB99499C4E0CE5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), the term ‘<quote>applicable percentage</quote>’ for fiscal year 2019 and each subsequent fiscal year, is a percentage specified by the Secretary up to (but not to exceed) 2.0 percent.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA8682FAD7A3E4B4388F331C05C725A01"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Uniform prospective reduction if aggregate limit projected to be exceeded</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary estimates before the beginning of a fiscal year that the amount of the additional payments under subparagraphs (K) and (L) for the fiscal year (or portion thereof) as determined under clause (i) without regard to this clause will exceed the limit established under such clause (i), the Secretary shall reduce pro rata the amount of each of the additional payments under this paragraph for that fiscal year (or portion thereof) in order to ensure that the aggregate additional payments under subparagraphs (K) and (L) (as so estimated) do not exceed such limit.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF6E548763334DE4AB450FE95EED8C9F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by paragraphs (2), (3), (4), (5), and (6) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply with respect to hospital discharges occurring on or after October 1, 2018, for inpatient hospital services for which payment is made under section 1886(d) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA23F107370B54EB285043EF204526480"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Improvements to payment adjustment under the Medicare outpatient prospective payment system for
			 certain drugs and devices eligible or previously eligible for pass-Through</header>
				<paragraph id="H1E15ABCEAF2846F59555E8ADFD08A491"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requiring separate ambulatory payment classification for certain drugs and devices previously
 eligible for pass-through payments</header><text>Section 1833(t) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(t)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H7C6868E7FD6E45909283EA0C8DE53C4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
 <clause id="H4678B29D27EB4AF9AA8362C052360031"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </clause><clause id="H58BEA20E6CCA4374999EA2B7CA517A06"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HECCF578A38FE4A36BD8099644853AF98"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8117824A279B46FD98EE9883B11C9117" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H40DEF5C7E97247238907A58BD21D9A6F"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary shall create additional groups of covered OPD services that classify separately procedures and services that employ medical devices and drugs described in a subparagraph of paragraph (22), in accordance with such paragraph.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33F0F3D2BC9E4D219FEB84E3FF882E42"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE234D2167E2846028E8CE89CDB49A4D3" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H8F0CB8D1A98F4853986E27BE40436CA6"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Separate additional payment groups for certain drugs and devices previously eligible for pass-through payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (2)(I), the following shall apply:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEC3D55AB8DB7455AA21A1BF7563DA285"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For payments under this subsection for services furnished on or after January 1, 2020, the Secretary shall, in accordance with subparagraph (B), create additional groups of covered OPD services to classify separately from other covered OPD services the following:</text>
 <clause id="H38E516939AB04847B5DC2DE658125FE8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Existing pass-through drugs and devices</header><text>Medical devices and drugs that met the requirements of paragraph (6)(A)(iv) and were receiving payment under paragraph (6) by reason of satisfying such requirements beginning on or after the date of enactment of this paragraph.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H23A350C4FD5F4BAAA10D1E8D1707B244"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Retired pass-through drugs and devices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Medical devices and drugs that had met the requirements of paragraph (6)(A)(iv) and were receiving payment under paragraph (6) by reason of satisfying such requirements before the date of enactment of this paragraph but after January 1, 2010.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C7EDC49EE8D4A65AFC001D0B8F9351E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="HA269A1DE0D6344AFBBA1D43ACF859139"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">bundle procedures and services that employ a device to which such subparagraph applies with all relevant diagnostic tests and surgical procedures, as applicable;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA005A7E58ACE41F7806FAA6CB58CDA18"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">bundle procedures and services that employ a drug, with respect to which payment is not made on or after the date specified in subparagraph (A) in accordance with the methodology under section 1847A and to which such subparagraph applies, with all relevant diagnostic tests and surgical procedures, as applicable; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1EA4DE1E151B4F1DB71EE11FD702BD47"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>include such relevant diagnostic tests and surgical procedures in more than one group created under such subparagraph, as necessary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1BDF0BA08A04CA0BE856EB59A588C1A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Revision to pass-through period under OPPS</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1833(t)(6) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(t)(6)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H044C18E8A85144099593D70175078EF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(iii), by striking <quote>at least 2 years, but not more than 3 years</quote> and inserting <quote>5 years</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4333EF92A504E6580AC8927EBDEA8B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (C)(i), by striking <quote>at least 2 years, but not more than 3 years</quote> and inserting <quote>5 years</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F95F8ED2A3840188075F2BB995354BF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appeals process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1833(t)(6) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(t)(6)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H370AB42F0CD8452BB0147C80DCBFE940" style="OLC">
						<subparagraph id="H9E006E3DBC964E2C982F866B0116A727"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Appeals process</header>
 <clause id="HA6450BF8B5EC4BE79C01275D924EC693"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An individual or entity that submits an application for additional payment under this paragraph for a new technology shall be entitled to administrative review of an adverse determination by the Secretary with respect to such application.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE5B16B93EA7140DDB79A8620426C9014"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Process</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a process for administrative review for purposes of clause (i). Under such process, administrative review shall be conducted by the Departmental Appeals Board of the Department of Health and Human Services. Under such process, the Department official involved shall complete administrative review within 90 days of receipt of a request for such review.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7131B2A34F4444FA8440C4BF53B2F33F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by paragraphs (2) and (3) shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act and shall apply with respect to items and services furnished on or after January 1, 2020.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


