<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H131EA28CB3D3405C8FB2377AD64E1F31" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4169 IH: Protecting Seniors Access to Proper Care Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4169</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171031">October 31, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001158">Mr. Marchant</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000465">Mr. Ferguson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to remove the enrollment restriction on certain
			 physicians and practitioners prescribing covered outpatient drugs under
			 the Medicare prescription drug program.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4654775C64BE41CB9172094AC7D82BCB" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3130194EC360470A847D35D7D69DFDAA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Seniors Access to Proper Care Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD988738C2A3B4D3DBBBEDCD0BF9B32E9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Permitting certain non-enrolled physicians or practitioners to prescribe covered outpatient drugs under medicare part d</header> <subsection id="H4832700432474955A029191AE5974650"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1860D–4 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-103">42 U.S.C. 1395w–103</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HEEC1A928CEE145B289C7EEB48C2AE256" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H501BE1DC6D394288A0D872A25F6CA791"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Removal of enrollment restriction</header>
 <paragraph id="H16068BB6366C479D867623AE2FC108F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this title or section 6405(c) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act shall be construed as authorizing the Secretary to require, as a condition of payment by a PDP sponsor for a covered part D drug that is prescribed by an applicable physician or practitioner who is authorized under State law to prescribe such drug, that such applicable physician or practitioner be enrolled under section 1866(j).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7242C7955BD54238908B3CF27A3916A9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable physician or practitioner defined</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <quote>applicable physician or practitioner</quote> means an eligible professional described in section 1848(k)(3)(B) (other than a physician described in section 1861(r)(1))—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE0A28F8160904C419AA51631C6B99525"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who—</text> <clause id="HEDFE503CFF3B4E2A924AAE36B1FE6331"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not excluded under this title or title XI;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H80FAB49F854C485F82F297F3D8B395E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not barred from participating in the program under this title for a period of time following a revocation under section 424.535(c) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA40E758F505241A19DC404475E030DBA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>meets other criteria similar to clauses (i) and (ii) that may be specified by the Secretary; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H542D702F81C8461AAEA8B33B8A8F593C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who prescribes a low volume (as determined by the Secretary) of such drugs to individuals enrolled in plans under this part.</text>
							</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">In determining low volume under subparagraph (B), the Secretary may determine low volume
			 differently based on the specialty of the applicable physician or
			 practitioner.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H84AB78D151F242B5B1056C35F3EE6FFA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date and enforcement delay</header>
 <paragraph id="HCFC8C9F76B824548B6EC090AB6DE6EC7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to covered part D drugs prescribed on or after January 1, 2019.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA15E228A951249C59026719D0B4B1115"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delay in enforcement of enrollment requirement until low volume exemption is implemented</header><text>The Secretary shall continue not to enforce the enrollment requirement under clauses (ii) through (v) of section 423.120(c)(6) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, until section 1860D–4(m), as added by subsection (a), takes effect.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


