<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H31CF1CCFB5C34D83A3491325D2BD05F1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4205 IH: Financial Institution Examination Responsiveness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4205</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171101">November 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000598">Mr. Rothfus</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000569">Mr. Luetkemeyer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1978 to establish a
			 three-judge independent examination review panel.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H522C5293841A4EF49760CD0537ED396A" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA095A36B35AE4BE8AD161628CBEC8CEB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Financial Institution Examination Responsiveness Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H33B9C0F978014146873ED088A7341701"><enum>2.</enum><header>Timeliness of examination reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/3301">12 U.S.C. 3301</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HAF49A0AC6F454E5B891334033285BBEC" style="OLC">
				<section id="H32591645CD0A431DB7C17C4C23AA659C"><enum>1012.</enum><header>Timeliness of examination reports</header>
					<subsection id="H86000C8E26DE4D4F8BD0FC9A0BAFC1F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="H2A27CC9F45FA4BC193BBB410012482CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Final examination report</header><text>A Federal financial institutions regulatory agency shall provide a final examination report to a financial institution not later than 60 days after the later of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBF34B11C65C94398BAAA37B65EBEAFDF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the exit interview for an examination of the institution; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7D4B747EEFF414AADA4052B90383FDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the provision of additional information by the institution relating to the examination.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H54122922F64A4085944E3EECB149B392"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exit interview</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an examination of a financial institution by a Federal financial institutions regulatory agency, if the financial institution is not subject to a resident examiner program, the exit interview for such examination shall occur not later than the end of the 9-month period beginning on the commencement of the examination, except that such period may be extended by the Federal financial institutions regulatory agency by providing written notice to the financial institution describing with particularity the reasons that a longer period is needed.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC6AD586C3B0841089C3A4C9AF21AF879"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Examination materials</header><text>Upon the request of a financial institution, the Federal financial institutions regulatory agency shall include with a final examination report an appendix listing all examination or other factual information relied upon by the agency in support of a material supervisory determination.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HC1D2310AE7224C46B99B58E10025D605"><enum>3.</enum><header>Independent Examination Review Panel</header>
 <subsection id="HEB641BFD7CBD4E138A031CD443ABBDB5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/3301">12 U.S.C. 3301</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by section 2, is further amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H63496C73EED3406AA1D129D682ABA778" style="OLC">
					<section id="H72FF0860DE0E4FDFBC1C908CDD84555B"><enum>1013.</enum><header>Independent Examination Review Panel</header>
						<subsection id="H1D558D1A624E44268050281AD159EADB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="HDD3F02EBC8D142A1B94E00E85587CFFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the executive branch the Independent Examination Review Panel (in this section referred to as the <quote>Panel</quote>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6194C425890A4D7C87D3A39A4053E625"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Judges</header><text>The Panel shall consist of three judges, appointed as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="H26F024ECF4174CDC8CB26704B523F827"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One judge appointed by the Council with extensive financial institutions regulatory agency experience.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4EE8F1C79FF247298BD3AB7942A28592"><enum>(B)</enum><text>One judge appointed by the Securities and Exchange Commission with legal and public accounting experience.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB78A4E0A441454C8896A1F4248A62F1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>One judge appointed by the Council, selected from candidates with private sector senior management-level experience with legal or public accounting background and recommended to the Council by a financial institution or a financial institution trade association.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H14497169377C4207B39131398D1D8DCF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Terms</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3A17C1160A0D486FB543AA194D4DFDF9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each judge appointed to the Panel shall serve for a term of 3 years, except as provided in subparagraph (B). No judge may be appointed to serve more than 2 terms.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC3E71A544BD40A183FE4BD03D06FE95"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Terms of initial appointees</header><text>Of the judges first appointed to the Panel—</text> <clause id="H4D80CFEB65014B6AAC783488C69D03D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the judge appointed pursuant to paragraph (2)(A) shall be appointed for a term of 1 year;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4CF7DBF388C34E98A79B94FADBA9737A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the judge appointed pursuant to paragraph (2)(B) shall be appointed for a term of 2 years; and</text> </clause><clause id="H6859A28AB200492D9598FEDCB0BDF665"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the judge appointed pursuant to paragraph (2)(C) shall be appointed for a term of 3 years.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCC226D317AA4BA4A7C0438C1E2BE449"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Requirements for appointment</header><text>An individual appointed under subparagraph (B) or (C) of paragraph (2) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HD1BE85A8D7D54BB19D979F58F4402154"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be a licensed attorney and a certified public accountant authorized to practice under the laws of a State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any other territory or possession of the United States; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47126D6D5B3E4CF499EE727A11C372B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have relevant subject matter education and work-related experience, including working knowledge of generally accepted accounting principles, as determined by the entity making the appointment.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF525E316CAC8403CACFB08D026E06BCA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Panel shall have exclusive jurisdiction of an appeal of a final material supervisory determination of a Federal financial institutions regulatory agency. The Panel shall determine the merits of the appeal, after an opportunity for a hearing on the record.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5CC4A7935851464DBFDAA2D3E0E12904"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Standard of review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In an appeal heard by the Panel under this section, the Panel may not defer only to the opinions of an examiner or a Federal financial institutions regulatory agency, but shall independently determine the appropriateness of the Federal financial institutions regulatory agency’s decision based upon the relevant statutes, regulations, judicial precedents, and previous decisions of the Panel.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="HCDBC6E76B5B34B1DBB65CCA49716C416"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HE7C23857A8504488BE5A2BC8C77DE2BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A financial institution seeking an appeal under this section shall file a written notice with the Panel within 30 days after receiving the final material supervisory determination from the agency, or within 270 days after receiving the final examination report, whichever occurs first.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5245A2EE7F241BA8639C481C4C401EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of notice</header><text>The written notice shall identify the final material supervisory determination that is the subject of the appeal and a statement of the reasons why the financial institution believes such determination should be modified.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6CE39A2DD2C448D6ABD3B3478F601A1D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Information To be provided to institution prior to hearing before the Panel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any information relied upon by a Federal financial institutions regulatory agency in a final examination report that is not in the possession of a financial institution requesting an appeal under this section may be requested by the financial institution and, if requested, shall be delivered promptly by the agency to the financial institution.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFF32B2F4E7B34CC5888BFC96D63A49D2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Hearing</header><text>If a financial institution requests a hearing before the Panel in connection with an appeal by the financial institution under this section, the hearing shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8438C6A453D34EA7A357866CF0AB926B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">take place not later than 60 days after the date on which the notice of the appeal was received by the Panel, except the Panel in its discretion or upon good cause shown may extend the hearing by up to 60 days; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H67A31C12158944949579D86239D766DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be conducted pursuant to the procedures set forth under sections 556 and 557 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H34BA819992EB4696A18C7B0A2C42DBB6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Decision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A decision by the Panel on an appeal under this section shall be made not later than—</text> <paragraph id="H577A762C434340DF97E4FC025D18FDE9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>60 days after the date on which the notice of appeal is filed with the Panel; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7474926FA8D4095AAE021296C0B8F58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>30 days after the date on which a hearing under subsection (f) has concluded, if a hearing is requested by the financial institution.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC8E49602EDA147709E28BD76F3EE3629"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Right to judicial review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A financial institution and the Federal financial institution regulatory agency that made the material supervisory determination appealed under this section shall have the right to petition for review of the decision of the Panel under this section by filing a petition for review not later than 60 days after the date on which the decision was made in the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit or the circuit in which the financial institution is located.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H4DE72C217FFA40ECA1C8384E2B9D11AD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reports and publication</header>
 <paragraph id="HCE2FF5FED0E44E00A2CB46FE45A89770"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Panel shall, within 90 days of the end of each calendar year, report final decisions made under subsection (g) during such calendar year to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives. Such reports may not contain confidential or privileged information shared by financial institutions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H07E6B04628454793A32CC4B367E614C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Any report submitted under paragraph (1) shall be made available on the Council’s website in such a manner that such reports may serve as precedent for future disputes.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3964098F779D4DC59ABF987BEFEAB1D1"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Expenses</header>
 <paragraph id="H23DCCF7721134BCEA25A5639B587C831"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The reasonable costs and expenses incurred by the Panel shall be paid by the Council.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3404258C81C44564AF8524CA15993B59"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Salaries</header><text>Compensation for the judges appointed to the Panel under this section shall be determined by the Council and based upon the fair market value of the level of service and time provided considering the training, knowledge, and experience needed to properly and professionally carry out the duties required.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEDE5AED2447A42A7B47B5EF0094CB5D3"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Retaliation prohibited</header><text>A Federal financial institutions regulatory agency may not—</text> <paragraph id="HD829FC84D541423FAECB18D2DEFED406"><enum>(1)</enum><text>retaliate against a financial institution, including service providers, or any institution-affiliated party, for exercising appellate rights under this section; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H919E7E905CED458299B3D74D2478B421"><enum>(2)</enum><text>delay or deny any agency action that would benefit a financial institution or any institution-affiliated party on the basis that an appeal under this section is pending under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H537A380778784BF9A9AF56A7C58F4160"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>Section 1003 of the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/3302">12 U.S.C. 3302</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H64A4D73F1F7C43638A426B6AFE7A35D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>and</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD08E00C88006415EBCD93076B0D6944A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3236CF7011142CEBD4B83184A2AB4D2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC69F4C8AD34B496D93A4E1447AAE3F47" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HBA122E142F994630ABF22EE1318743F3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <quote>material supervisory determinations</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 309(f) of the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4806">12 U.S.C. 4806(f)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H620378B6A9D246C6BA81F02708B4B1FD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Timeliness of required permission, regulatory, and reporting guidance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/3301">12 U.S.C. 3301</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by section 3, is further amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HA2127A4B94EF4B5F82966941042F51F5" style="OLC">
				<section id="H68B250A67C4D4D55BC2FA96D7F02BE73"><enum>1014.</enum><header>Timeliness of required permission, regulatory, and reporting guidance</header>
 <subsection id="H53BFF94DAE9443C990F20254747FE471"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Request for permission or guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A financial institution may request a written determination by a Federal financial institutions regulatory agency of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3FC3D7D0147F47D2A60FFDAA2142C481"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the agency’s permission to take an action where permission is mandated by regulation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBCFB7548F1E04062987829239BC449AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the agency’s interpretation of a law or regulation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F5B580861A34D91ABC839EE8EE81A09"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the agency’s interpretation of generally accepted accounting principles or accounting objectives, standards, and requirements under section 37 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0BD6BEEC5B0844EBA44D8B6E17A0F4BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of request</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A request made under subsection (a) shall be in writing and contain all the information needed to communicate to the Federal financial institutions regulatory agency the following:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HC7FCB7FDBA604D2D9C066F44EE68D1A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The nature of the request.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9237C8A461EE4BB981E4E70D0735E598"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Applicable facts relating to the matter.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4E7AAF8268584137AFBEF282B509602D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Applicable law, regulation, or generally accepted accounting principles relating to the matter.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA00172AD3B6D45B0ACF81256AEB658E2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Discussion relative to the nature of the request summarizing the financial institution’s position or summary of the request.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6BBBD210A3145F6ACB654153D99EE92"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Response to request</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal financial institutions regulatory agency receiving a request under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H2FB906E54CC840E4B6D526446162AD8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>within 60 days of receiving the request—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBD1458686EB2430EB61E329399C986C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide the financial institution making the request with written notification that the agency received the request and stating whether the request contains the information required under subsection (b); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E7BEECA2F144C22891EB4D5E3041301"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the request does not contain the information required under subsection (b), provide the financial institution with an explanation of what information is missing; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50E7457E99FD4BE8BF3FC19627D55B2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>within 120 days of receiving the request, if the request contains the information required under subsection (b), make a determination on the request and provide the financial institution with a written notice of such determination.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD5161BE564B14E58999D6087544A463C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 1013(b), the following actions are deemed a final agency material supervisory determination:</text>
 <paragraph id="H07C65A80F85941699C10D16A1994AF88"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any determination made under subsection (c)(2).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7D94DDC6405401192F4CCD32885C2D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any failure by a Federal financial institutions regulatory agency to comply with a deadline required by this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2CAE7E147C6E43CFBC6F4A6BA4D25C50"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any determination by a Federal financial institutions regulatory agency under subsection (c)(1)(B) that a request does not contain the information required under subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4B68F12CE66A423E94CB71E83B249FB1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports and publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Federal financial institutions regulatory agency shall, within 120 days after making a determination under subsection (c)(2), publish a summary of the determination, in order to offer guidance to the applicable industry. The summary may not contain confidential or privileged information about the financial institution, financial institution clients, or agency personnel.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


