<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB6557599A32146A48D5380638C41343B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4720 IH: Abby Honold Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4720</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171221">December 21, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001078">Mrs. Handel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster of New Hampshire</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Office on Violence Against Women to improve the handling of crimes of domestic
			 violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking by incorporating a
			 trauma-informed approach into the initial response to and investigation of
			 such crimes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF53C8F0C0C134A3EB899DF74D95CA4FA" style="OLC">
 <section id="HFCC9E04A88574CEDAA0B11EFAF4B79A2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Abby Honold Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5C0E073AFE604A918139B7D12B451733"><enum>2.</enum><header>Demonstration program on trauma-informed training for law enforcement</header> <subsection id="H2D509E96FA1744B48DFEBB8299FCDC30"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="H49D8D9058A1145FC99A81C08920C1095"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Attorney General</term> means the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA9F39DDA720245BD84A1BDB49FB5D0C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>covered individual</term> means an individual who interfaces with victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HABB520A94DCA46ABA84FC21A342DEB1E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual working for or on behalf of an eligible entity;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED207D9B26D6426486D1FA5BD52D0781"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a school or university administrator; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DEC5F77F75E4AAF8637BF0689201425"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an emergency services or medical employee;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2547F4C44F964BCC83D3E961ED425B1D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>demonstration site</term>, with respect to an eligible entity that receives a grant under this section, means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEF194773553D41F395A5932E14CDF6BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the eligible entity is a law enforcement agency described in paragraph (4)(A), the area over which the eligible entity has jurisdiction; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38C936D83C764BC69856D0068BA795FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the eligible entity is an organization or agency described in paragraph (4)(B), the area over which a law enforcement agency described in paragraph (4)(A) that is working in collaboration with the eligible entity has jurisdiction; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H49761A30153849CAA2CD73E6C3052F01"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H8588FA92ACA3438D96ED8CEB3BEB91B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State, local, territorial, or tribal law enforcement agency; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA72CD561E220430CB00641C9E137FDFA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a national, regional, or local victim services organization or agency working in collaboration with a law enforcement agency described in subparagraph (A).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDFA93B8D9C8241249196481E0BD701C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header>
 <paragraph id="H1BC3DB0FA1E9492E8CC5C9975C3DA5D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall award grants on a competitive basis to eligible entities to carry out the demonstration program under this section by implementing evidence-based or promising policies and practices to incorporate trauma-informed techniques designed to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF36034C054214A83A9C48EADE97F9BF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prevent re-traumatization of the victim;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD98F963B906E4AAFB3804BE7877DE174"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that covered individuals use evidence-based practices to respond to and investigate cases of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAE8C9B19D864AF99A01A245697E4712"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve communication between victims and law enforcement officers in an effort to increase the likelihood of the successful investigation and prosecution of the alleged crime in a manner that protects the victim to the greatest extent possible;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAFC3EA0A864408CAA23F439F3E04399"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase collaboration among stakeholders who are part of the coordinated community response to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CB6A12C3C8C4A6599B89C06D98C95E9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>evaluate the effectiveness of the training process and content by measuring—</text> <clause id="H72CF029941F34CC395FAB11858C217C4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>investigative and prosecutorial practices and outcomes; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H62DAC59A6C3F48CA998BF60582F144A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the well-being of victims and their satisfaction with the criminal justice process.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7FC2F01E62D40D48600C9E2A54019E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The Attorney General shall make grants under this section for each of the first 2 fiscal years beginning after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E8F8B6408594618B7CC116466B815F8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Award basis</header><text>The Attorney General shall award grants under this section to multiple eligible entities for use in a variety of settings and communities, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H68CAD0C1C8844574A61EBB9C1CF2E101"><enum>(A)</enum><text>urban, suburban, tribal, remote, and rural areas;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3E7C55303C547F6ACCF09892D032B46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>college campuses; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49F3F27C1A1644F5B9BF2C998862BB67"><enum>(C)</enum><text>traditionally underserved communities.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2ABCDA126BC345DABFE18167FA2E82AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H145FA3942C26408A8F3917331DC03A6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">train covered individuals within the demonstration site of the eligible entity to use evidence-based, trauma-informed techniques throughout an investigation into domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking, including by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H71C53F13557F4BDBA97C61E6E51F1452"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conducting victim interviews in a manner that—</text> <clause id="HCD97939FFF8B48FCBE5F368A4F16FB59"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">elicits valuable information about the domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFDA4B2C5297F42DD94262E6C26D1C4D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>avoids re-traumatization of the victim;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FEAE5A617974A4EBDE3DAC29D8C02D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conducting field investigations that mirror best and promising practices available at the time of the investigation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46E85841D26D4BBA8DFE602BADAB7660"><enum>(C)</enum><text>customizing investigative approaches to ensure a culturally and linguistically appropriate approach to the community being served;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D521750076F4B32AACB80D95C3AA5F5"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">becoming proficient in understanding and responding to complex cases, including cases of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking—</text>
 <clause id="H9B819B0A690A45BFAD3EA49FE4EE00CB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitated by alcohol or drugs;</text> </clause><clause id="H08D1CCE0DFB64C50AEC17A6396D9AE8F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">involving strangulation;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H828A931F2B314CB4B3D21E306D9F3CE8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>committed by a non-stranger;</text> </clause><clause id="HBD841572E6514C41A4FFF1FAE886A676"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>committed by an individual of the same sex as the victim;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC20E8E3337784A72963D45A510E6CDE3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>involving a victim with a disability;</text> </clause><clause id="HBD96292707D84575B5771C458723A061"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>involving a male victim; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA0279E9E73304F449FE75C8E391C1868"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>involving a lesbian, gay, bisexual, or transgender (commonly referred to as <quote>LGBT</quote>) victim;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B887B9ADDEF4FED8AE80BFC7B572629"><enum>(E)</enum><text>developing collaborative relationships between—</text>
 <clause id="HA9B3369961A44B59AA7DC9A80509C008"><enum>(i)</enum><text>law enforcement officers and other members of the response team; and</text> </clause><clause id="HE1F77E8D4A52430B9CBAA5B1342B3349"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the community being served; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1D9C31C47FC4866B674AC56F00F25E6"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing an understanding of how to define, identify, and correctly classify a report of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE77A25E877F343ADBE04B7A67ED2822B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promote the efforts of the eligible entity to improve the response of covered individuals to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking through various communication channels, such as the website of the eligible entity, social media, print materials, and community meetings, in order to ensure that all covered individuals within the demonstration site of the eligible entity are aware of those efforts and included in trainings, to the extent practicable.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF893B5FAC6324982AB6CA92DF0EDA217"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Demonstration program trainings on trauma-Informed approaches</header>
				<paragraph id="H231C7E986A3C44639CB936596A504773"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Identification of existing trainings</header>
 <subparagraph id="H33301EA07ED846B0B9341C51142D9E11"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall identify trainings for law enforcement officers, in existence as of the date on which the Attorney General begins to solicit applications for grants under this section, that—</text>
 <clause id="HAEB804E62EA64588832EE330839BA98E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employ a trauma-informed approach to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1C8797F97C4C4DD8994396CC1FD9E250"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>focus on the fundamentals of the—</text> <subclause id="H991D151AAA1F471CB845AA4BED907C85"><enum>(I)</enum><text>neurobiology of trauma; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB52E95BBDE3C470E851FD5D387A699AC"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">impact of trauma on victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H660CDF6D682946FE996A017CB9A41225"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall select 1 or more of the approaches employed by a training identified under subparagraph (A) to test within the demonstration site of the eligible entity.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H41AF218668DB4DCF823F537D53CAB638"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall consult with the Director of the Office for Victims of Crime in order to seek input from and cultivate consensus among outside practitioners and other stakeholders through facilitated discussions and focus groups on best practices in the field of trauma-informed care for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36A063D4C9D44E5EBAF34DF3F9526488"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General, in consultation with the Director of the National Institute of Justice, shall require each eligible entity that receives a grant under this section to identify a research partner, preferably a local research partner to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF78415530D3A41BBAAE617CDAD3D67DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>design a system for generating and collecting the appropriate data to facilitate an independent process or impact evaluation of the use of the grant funds;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DADCCBF3A9349F298A8EDC37A41CE7D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>periodically conduct an evaluation described in paragraph (1); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9CA80F5D32C945E5BE7A799403696A17"><enum>(3)</enum><text>periodically make publicly available, during the grant period—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC7616E69D57A47FFA8AA549E6C30D0C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>preliminary results of the evaluations conducted under paragraph (2); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H412B2D5D67D54C5EB69FE95E76E19DE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations for improving the use of the grant funds.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA60A0DF902234BEFB7AD1F88E8E3AC51"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>The Attorney General shall carry out this section using amounts otherwise available to the Attorney General.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


