<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H81FDF8ACBA8245BE931B150CD9EB603E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3102 IH: To amend title 10, United States Code, to improve the provision of naturalization assistance to members of the uniformed services, including new recruits, who are not citizens of the United States, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3102</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20170628">June 28, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000132">Mr. Vela</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to improve the provision of naturalization assistance to members of the uniformed services, including new recruits, who are not citizens of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H9468DBC29D5A4FBB87BAD7253927B2F1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA77AEEF095E246D999E31AD497D173B2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Establishment of Office of Service Member Naturalization and designation of naturalization offices on certain military installations</header> 
<subsection id="H425DFE649C874DB89F6F5C152A48E9DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/80">Chapter 80</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1566a">section 1566a</external-xref> the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H50AC4C8AF0D2439180940BC67AB90CA4" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H6F0518A6DC4349B89670BA97D67C2056"><enum>1566b.</enum><header>Naturalization assistance: Office of Service Member Naturalization and installation naturalization offices</header> <subsection id="HFE8D3C52468747A9B9880D51DF7DB525"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Office of Service Member Naturalization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall establish an office in the Department of Defense, to be known as the <quote>Office of Service Member Naturalization</quote>, whose mission shall be—</text> 
<paragraph id="H71055FCF05A7464B90029B06CFA26D37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to identify members of the uniformed services, including new recruits, who are not citizens of the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H82C6E4273A9E485FACEB190F53A7E654"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to inform such members of the availability of naturalization assistance to facilitate such members in becoming citizens; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H350E1BD4BBA3403493D3577ED08D99D9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to help such members complete the naturalization process before their separation from the uniformed services; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H22D96AF564B241A0A8FA11AA9AA4E1B6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to coordinate points-of-contact at military installations to ensure that personnel who are responsible for assisting members through the naturalization process successfully complete their assignments.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF3AFF15AADAF4C9DA268654F6A6A05EF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation of installation naturalization offices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense under subsection (e), the Secretaries of the military departments shall designate naturalization offices—</text> <paragraph id="HDBC0883F0A834295BE006B1AE06513D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on military installations under their jurisdiction at which the initial entry training program for new recruits for the uniformed services is conducted; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1A48D35E2E3D4A90A566EB5FA9E82520"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on such other military installations as the Secretary concerned shall determine are best located to provide access to naturalization assistance for members of the uniformed services who are not citizens of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H344151269A6D4D9097C73B94E956B800"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Types of naturalization assistance</header> <paragraph id="H5CA5C9F60EDD4076A71604A11D15F01B" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A naturalization office shall make available Form N–400, Application for Naturalization, and Form N–426, Request for Certification of Military or Naval Service.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86E05B67F8B9443BA6F8BF61935FFDA1" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A naturalization office shall assist members of the uniformed services, including new recruits, who are not citizens of the United States in completing the process to become a citizen of the United States. If, through no fault of the member, a member whose service has been honorable is unable to complete the naturalization process before separation from the uniformed services, the naturalization office shall continue to work with the member until completion of the naturalization process.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H977A6DBEFBB44FD3A9820B2F62A777DB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability to other elements of the uniformed services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Department of the Navy, the Secretary of Health and Human Services with respect to the commissioned corps of the Public Health Service, and the Secretary of Commerce with respect to the commissioned corps of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall carry out this section in the case of members of the uniformed services under their jurisdiction.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H78EB44D7D3904068844985AA38BD3401"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretaries referred to in subsection (d), shall prescribe regulations relating to the administration of the requirements of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection id="H7B825EDC13134F9C9B7A9BB47870D386"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 80 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1566a the following new item:</text> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry bold="off" level="section"><quote>1566b. Naturalization assistance: Office of Service Member Naturalization and installation naturalization offices.</quote>.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8B8FC9E5150C4B31BA3CFB43C710A481" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improved provision of applications for naturalization and forms for certification of military or naval service at Military Entrance Processing Command Centers</header> 
<subsection id="HD1690C62AEEE4C5ABD60DCB7B499E362"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Duty To provide materials</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1790 of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3F94ED422AA143718A89DF3E5EF249DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Using funds</quote> and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1C385BEFC0384438AAE073CB1276AE84" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HF499F2A3FDE7427D8E3D32FBA9E879CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reimbursement of Homeland Security processing and adjudication costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Using funds</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H39BEAB60F6AE44F2B21678326C78783B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after the section heading the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1D68862E0A3F43869FD0E4740C8E8222" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H030684C78E5042658E50B02EED54DCE7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Provision of naturalization applications and service certification forms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness shall ensure that each Military Entrance Processing Station provides the Form N–400, Application for Naturalization, and Form N–426, Request for Certification of Military or Naval Service, to new recruits for the uniformed services who are processed at the center and are not citizens of the United States.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H28C2EB1C82164F5182FA8588AC7124CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text>Section 1790 of title 10, United States Code, as amended by subsection (a), is further amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H023D94EEAD1C41A3A9F23C29E80D1CA9" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H8ADA174F7FE046278F1CB0EA4D9FB7E7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Through December 31, 2021, the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness shall submit to the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives, and the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and the House of Representatives an annual report specifying—</text> <paragraph id="H5CE9B85248B7469890956E519B8997A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of members of each uniformed service who received the naturalization materials described in subsection (a) at Military Entrance Processing Stations and installation naturalization offices during the year covered by the report; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4BC24C27FE2142E189F67BDDC8B4A5E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of reimbursement provided under subsection (b) to the United States Citizenship and Immigration Services during the year covered by the report.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

