<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE6D515EE98104CE0943838E2A93EF350" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3028 IH: Bolstering Returning American Veterans Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3028</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170622">June 22, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000475">Mr. Trott</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide
			 training for school certifying officials.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3CC9768619EF440B978924B2F7C17D49" style="OLC">
 <section id="H987DE63E53EF4E629C99A2BE44D94503" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bolstering Returning American Veterans Education Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BRAVE Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HCFA9C9D1FD5B48C085B11CFBC9561DA8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs provision of training for school certifying officials</header> <subsection id="H593D9DBB3CBD45E0B8D1666205C04A35"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/36">chapter 36</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/3674A">section 3674A</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19F484B04DBC438A9C6FBCDA7E94E5DB" style="USC">
					<section id="H0D5671BC5D66426FA96A900A518FCC95"><enum>3674B.</enum><header>Training for school certifying officials</header>
 <subsection id="HFC963986AC1546FC841CE8BDB961D532"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Training curriculum</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the National Association of State Approving Agencies, State approving agencies, the National Association of Veterans’ Program Administrators, and school certifying officials, shall establish and provide a standard training curriculum for school certifying officials regarding administrative responsibilities relating to the educational assistance programs of the Department.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8E5BAB9795B847F4A35D16F820EED439"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The training curriculum required under subsection (a) shall include training related to each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H5013770433744A4F85CDB3E63505DFB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Certification and recertification for the educational assistance programs of the Department.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4124609041AD4B638ABA0CB36105FAE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Certification and recertification for tutoring assistance and meeting the voluntary requirements of Executive Order 13607.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3AA0406A8E194EB3B530FDD1748A017A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Standards and process for establishing and maintaining the approval of courses of education for purposes of the educational assistance programs of the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H51B8A3AD1A1941F58A6BE43F888C78AD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Yellow Ribbon G.I. Education Enhancement Program under section 3317 of this title.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6405D43F554A40EEAB592385D0556B35"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The calculation and distribution of payments under the educational assistance programs of the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB1234626A33342FEB9554F518869C634"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Common ways to assist individuals entitled to educational assistance under the laws administered by the Secretary in using such entitlement.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H591B35B0387F4EAC847F4971B6D1A9E5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Provision of training</header><text>The training curriculum required by subsection (a) shall be provided through an internet website or taught at a conference sponsored by the Department.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H291FA462DDF84F8AA07235EFE5E04D82"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirements for officials</header><text>The Secretary shall require, as a condition of the approval of a course of education under this chapter, that the school certifying official of the educational institution offering such course—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC1C93510A43444E087517F030C89498B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>completes the training curriculum required under subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H730AF87B9C9F4347BF7F7328E19D0A51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by not later than 30 days after first being designated as a school certifying official; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE084D8F05AD34881A293C4C76D1C87F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less often than once during every subsequent two-year period; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D4E597919D74946B79FA3BB200A9377"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon completion of the training cur­ric­u­lum, earns a score of at least 75 percent on a multiple choice exam designed to test the knowledge of the official with the subjects covered in the training curriculum.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8DB6980847D34ED8BBEE88DF914F0004"><enum>(e)</enum><header>School certifying official defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>school certifying official</quote> means an official of an educational institution designated to sign or report Department enrollment certifications, certifications of change in student status, certifications of delivery of advance payments, certifications of pursuit, attendance, flight training, on-the-job or apprenticeship training (as applicable), or other certifications of enrollment or to sign the school portion of the application and enrollment certification for individualized tutorial assistance.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEFEBCFCFB29C45C4B066B1D3A6E3380F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 3674A the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3196855BC7F2413DB90B2FB1EE1DAFBE" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">3674B. Training for school certifying officials.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


