<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC99B35A6A8644F1E821736C1502FD20E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2425 IH: Public Lands Telecommunications Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2425</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170516">May 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support the establishment and improvement of communications sites on or adjacent to Federal
			 lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the
			 Secretary of Agriculture through the retention and use of rental fees
			 associated with such sites, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H26F5FA7ABB3443C291EF75749312A74C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4379FE9398F742009EDFB20A2FB58B48" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Lands Telecommunications Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2EA246AEDF024714B243119E232D4B33"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB8A7A4300C2741658B8BCABA2E56D27B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Communications site</header><text>The term <quote>communications site</quote> means an area of Federal lands designated for telecommunications uses.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF518A2693D6D4F88B38E2BE74A7B1E5E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Communications use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>communications use</quote> means the placement and operation of infrastructure for wireline or wireless telecommunications, regardless of whether the use of radio frequencies by such telecommunications is pursuant to a license issued by the Federal Communications Commission or on an unlicensed basis in accordance with the regulations of the Commission. The term includes ancillary activities directly related to such placement and operation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H753F632DA120419C92DD31002DA6CE99"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Communications use authorization</header><text>The term <quote>communications use authorization</quote> means a right-of-way, permit, or lease granted, issued, or executed by a Federal land management agency for the primary purpose of authorizing the occupancy and use of Federal lands for communications use.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4BC667ED793438FB0890957355EEF58"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal land management agency</header><text>The term <quote>Federal land management agency</quote> means the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the Bureau of Land Management, the Bureau of Reclamation, and the Forest Service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A856975D5FA4C068F6BD8DA3930C768"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal lands</header><text>The term <quote>Federal lands</quote> means lands under the jurisdiction and management of a Federal land management agency.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H081F0415996046CF9BCC75550AD6B780"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rental fee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>rental fee</quote> means the fee collected by a Federal land management agency for the occupancy and use authorized by a communications use authorization pursuant to and consistent with authorizing law.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H3202B21D7D4242EA9024BBEE5120FE91"><enum>3.</enum><header>Retention of rental fees associated with communications use authorizations on Federal lands and
			 Federal land management agency support for communication site programs</header>
 <subsection id="HEFA9CB314FB342EAB28C51CCE92B9FE9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Special account required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall establish a special account in the Treasury for each Federal land management agency for the deposit of rental fees received by a Federal land management agency for communications use authorizations on Federal lands granted, issued, or executed by the Federal land management agency.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2D2B1C14A6994BA186F59D9A1BC77DE7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deposit and Retention of rental fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rental fees received by a Federal land management agency shall—</text> <paragraph id="HE1312DFABAB84B07A398B734BFD1A5ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be deposited in the special account established for that Federal land management agency; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H159343B895BC45338BC76F72252EFA0A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>remain available for expenditure under subsection (c), to the extent and in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriation Acts.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H378EBCCA55A94F729B4598902F7E0392"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expenditure of retained fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts deposited in the special account for a Federal land management agency shall be used for Federal land management agency activities related to communications sites, including the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HDB67F8AE2DC740AABD11FD0FC5AF6DAD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Administering communications use authorizations, including cooperative agreements under section 4.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H32BE60EFC78A4B25A5F5C00F1EC41F3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Preparing needs assessments or other programmatic analyses necessary to designate communications sites and authorize communications uses on or adjacent to Federal lands.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H02CB49EB1FCA4EECA6D0490AA478C570"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing management plans for communications sites on or adjacent to Federal lands.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H003F5D0A542041B48391C6893B79A282"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Training for management of communications sites on or adjacent to Federal lands.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H65F9FE80F7FC459D89CCCD4EBB59DFED"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Obtaining or improving access to communications sites on or adjacent to Federal lands.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52D00673CAF9428185FA0E55CF42AFFE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No effect on other fee retention authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act shall not limit or otherwise affect fee retention by a Federal land management agency under any other authority.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HF58EAD623A644F539C3A37259694CE28"><enum>4.</enum><header>Cooperative agreement authority</header>
 <subsection id="H071F67CCC8484FB68215662388446509"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Department of the interior</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior may enter into cooperative agreements to carry out the activities described in section 3(c).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H748A319FED3743C3B2B54560BF1EEEEF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Forest service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, may enter into cooperative agreements to carry out the activities described in section 3(c).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


