<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD6FF4D3C09584120A4A0AB7810D40F09" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 960 IH: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the tax-exempt financing of certain government-owned buildings.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 960</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170207">February 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000017">Mr. Zeldin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001073">Mr. Hurd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000586">Mr. Renacci</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the tax-exempt financing of certain
			 government-owned buildings.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB3F126DB6433433CBF4706619C6B6A5F" style="OLC">
		<section id="H996FE969AA2848B6B0A12F3DBB6DB30F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Tax-exempt financing of qualified government buildings</header>
 <subsection id="HD2DB71AA30EF49B78D311B4BA94EBF4C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/142">Section 142(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of paragraph (14), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (15) and inserting <quote>, or</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H25CA554BF72441CF9AE8E58A1F82368C" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H75197C38BEA548DF8BDCCBD2D041052E"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">qualified government buildings.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6699505B8EBB464BBFE57A8630AAACF1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified government buildings</header><text>Section 142 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02091F23A9C545A59B9BEA0B6AEF87C2" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HBB5F8B3C3A194A268695225CC5AA7844"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Qualified governmental buildings</header> <paragraph id="HEC59D9EAC25D4D38BD0DD981026F66DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a)(16), the term <quote>qualified governmental buildings</quote> means any building or facility that consists of one or more of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEB979031FC6A410798044EB6DBA99B99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An elementary school or a secondary school (within the meanings given such terms by section 14101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/8801">20 U.S.C. 8801</external-xref>), as in effect on the date of the enactment of this subsection).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H870FE0A9475E41A6ACE64D13CB30A590"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Facilities of a State college or university used for educational purposes.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC946E024F3E6456FAB825ACE932E56C3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A library maintained for, and open to, the general public.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4423B853B3F540C88B4F363BDE1170E5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A Court of law.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B2AFA3E619B4A2D86B1CE633EA5F978"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A hospital, health care facilities, laboratory facilities or research facilities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DCA064639284F6ABDBCF2518EE11AA7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Public safety facilities (including police, fire, enhanced 911, emergency or disaster management, and ambulance or emergency medical service facilities and jails and correctional facilities).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06A076E35FD24CC282F2A9B0FE0FDCA0"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Offices for employees of a governmental unit.</text> </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Such term shall include any equipment, functionally related and subordinate facility, or land (and any real property rights appurtenant thereto) with respect to any such building or facility.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24AAE931D72548E880A4E9F248FD3ABA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specifically excluded facilities</header><text>Such term shall not include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE34C24A42E1745308CDC9CB970561333"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a building or facility the primary purpose of which is one of the following: retail food and beverage services, or the provision of recreation or entertainment, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92E0599962384AB1B4AE65AA7AE31C4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any building or facility that includes any of the following: any private or commercial golf course, country club, massage parlor, tennis club, skating facility (including roller skating, skateboard, and ice skating), racquet sports facility (including any handball or racquetball court), hot tub facility, suntan facility, racetrack, convention center, or sports stadium or arena.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1C915E673B940FD92D34EFCE1794EC0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National limitation on amount of tax-exempt financing for qualified governmental building</header>
 <subparagraph id="HED216FA0E48F4C6884F192BA01719816"><enum>(A)</enum><header>National limitation</header><text>The aggregate amount allocated by the Secretary under subparagraph (C) shall not exceed $5,000,000,000.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A166B1037E3462AB0BF716CAF2331AA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Enforcement of national limitation</header><text>An issue shall not be treated as an issue described in subsection (a)(16) if the aggregate face amount of bonds issued pursuant to such issue for any qualified governmental building (when added to the aggregate face amount of bonds previously so issued for such facility) exceeds the amount allocated to such qualified governmental building under subparagraph (C).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B3A13D6C3104159A06CDBEF92585346"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Allocation by the Secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall allocate a portion of the amount described in subparagraph (A) to a qualified governmental building if the Secretary determines that—</text>
 <clause id="H292AC10D30AE44098BAD04086F90A34A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the application for financing of such qualified governmental building meets the requirements set forth in subparagraph (D), and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H22EA3D84861949A49ED64B9067545255"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of the allocation requested, if allocated by the Secretary, would not cause the national limitation set forth in subparagraph (A) to be exceeded.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6549BAD0C0F4CBD9588ED777864D38C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Applications For Financing</header><text>An application for financing a qualified governmental building meets the requirements of this subparagraph if such application includes—</text>
 <clause id="H99AAE0852BE14C10B8AA3BCF8E52ECF9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of the allocation requested,</text> </clause><clause id="H83A67A21797849E08FFC604421A7BFDC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the name of the governmental unit that will own the project, together with complete contact information,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H98C42FAE23B14D6B856907F00E028959"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of the project as a whole and the proposed organizational and legal structure of the project,</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC293616F947A40ABB934CC4061BCE94C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a timeline showing the estimated start and completion dates for each major phase or milestone of project development and an indication of the current status of milestones on this timeline, including all necessary permits and environmental approvals,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H08D5D5E2EB4E493FB20D188F900366BF"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a statement of anticipated sources and uses of funds for the project, and</text> </clause><clause id="HE449AA02CF8E467DBBDD06553894A257"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the following declaration signed by an individual who has personal knowledge of the relevant facts and circumstances: <quote>Under penalties of perjury, I declare that I have examined this document and, to the best of my knowledge and belief, the document contains all the relevant facts relating to the document, and such facts are true, correct, and complete.</quote>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D435C4D2D754D69B839437BCCAE3011"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Use of allocation in a timely manner</header><text>If, following an allocation by the Secretary under subparagraph (C), bonds are not issued in the amount of such allocation after the date that is 2 years after the date of such allocation, then the unused portion of the allocation shall be withdrawn, unless the Secretary, upon a showing of good cause by the applicant, grants an extension of such date.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H145F79625EB84EA1AAF2271411C6A715"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exception for current refunding bonds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (4) shall not apply to any bond (or series of bonds) issued to refund a bond issued under subsection (a)(16) if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE10F423A501C47588DE0C1B09BC9C55B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average maturity date of the issue of which the refunding bond is a part is not later than the average maturity date of the bonds to be refunded by such issue,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F3ED72653EB47A6B61E18880C7AE39D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of the refunding bond does not exceed the outstanding amount of the refunded bond, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10454121B93644A28F9FB423F82E7E89"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the refunded bond is redeemed not later than 90 days after the date of the issuance of the refunding bond.</text>
							</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">For purposes of subparagraph (A), average maturity shall be determined in accordance with section
 147(b)(2)(A).</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87E90B7119B54DC099EDBC48252EA535"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Office space</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (b)(2) shall not apply with respect to any qualified governmental building.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H828F23B6E57B41E6A804BF7E9DD938E7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>No depreciation or investment credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No depreciation, amortization, or business credit under section 38 shall be allowed with respect to any facility described in subsection (a)(16) which has been financed by the net proceeds of the issue for so long as such bonds are outstanding.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0513A8F0C5344D4C9538EEB2FA9BD7EE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Governmentally owned requirement</header><text>Section 142(b)(1)(A) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>or (12)</quote> and inserting <quote>(12), or (16)</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H1642F90895814AF0A2C4A4E09B802A6F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exemption from volume cap on private activity bonds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 146(g)(3) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>or (15)</quote> and inserting <quote>(15), or (16)</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H17C2E8D41F0942F5B0F2C96F5FD4DBF2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to bonds issued after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


