<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H24F827E8F81649A0B5F13AFCEAC5DFD0" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1086 IH: Preserving Public Access to Federal Buildings Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1086</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170215">February 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require executive agencies to notify the public and consider public comment before relocating an
			 office of the agency that has regular contact with the public, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8DCFEC2C956249CFA0B185F323C2DE3C" style="OLC">
 <section id="HBE52D56548B84A7BB8D539364AEEC523" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preserving Public Access to Federal Buildings Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF4D1F6F7D5B34C32A2C2D29C016A6F1A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirements relating to relocation of certain federal offices</header> <subsection id="H777FDE8750D9442DB60AFC17A158F334"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An executive agency shall provide notice to the public and an opportunity for public comment before relocating an office of the agency if the office has regular contact with the public.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCD258CC4B1904DE0A7B9DB7517D4806F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered relocations</header><text>Subsection (a) shall apply to—</text> <paragraph id="H7F167F8473584A5D8CB20D15BA60CD05"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a relocation proposed by an executive agency; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A2C8C5A41BF4B199661996C3902DE23"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a reassignment of office space of an executive agency by the Administrator of General Services.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H788DAA425200474BBED246F07C53A782"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Initial determination and plan</header> <paragraph id="H396D497E054C46C6B323C95517E1E3BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before an executive agency provides notice of the relocation of an office under subsection (a), the agency shall determine if the agency expects the relocation to impact the ability of the office’s clientele to access services provided by the office.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H44304BBDD6324B0F9263B76FC6053678"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the agency determines under paragraph (1) that such relocation is expected to have such impact, the agency shall develop an initial plan to address the impact.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3423A5572C2F4CFBB20631B2AE4B6DAB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice and comment</header>
 <paragraph id="H1FF9F079B8D74B089690F32C6BE802CF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Recipients</header><text>In providing notice of the relocation of an office under subsection (a), an executive agency shall ensure that the notice is received by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB412BF317E654FDBB100F91D63B76550"><enum>(A)</enum><text>entities that regularly serve the clientele of the office, including nonprofit organizations and advocacy groups;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCD2841772E64DAFB3E5307F9EC0BBD7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">local media outlets;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42F59DE93FB24CF0843CFF1CFB98108B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Members of Congress that represent the area where the office is located; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3935EA343DF840AA8E793C944E924897"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EAFD7633E4D4ABDAE997068F4AC7927"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content</header><text>If an initial plan was developed under subsection (c)(2), the notice shall include a description of the initial plan.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H48BA3BF235044970BA6CC774E2995B8B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Substantial public interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, after an executive agency provides notice of the relocation of an office under subsection (a), the relocation receives substantial public interest, the agency shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB51483884E4B4962AE6CCB41AC2FDB1D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct an in-depth evaluation of the potential impact of the relocation on the ability of the office’s clientele to access services provided by the office, particularly with respect to minority groups, persons with disabilities, the elderly, and the economically disadvantaged;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E08C3ECF3F044DBAE4A9A411E14AD79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop a plan to address such impact or revise an initial plan developed under subsection (c)(2); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H840096ECFCAA40FA91C25396116C71AB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publish the results of the evaluation and a description of the plan on the public website of the agency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H54F41D0049864A198B9EDB5F0188AFD4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Guidance on terms</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Administrator of General Services and the Federal Real Property Council, shall issue guidance for agencies on the meaning of each of the terms <quote>regular contact with the public</quote> and <quote>substantial public interest</quote> for purposes of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9ED0F5AFD85C45C79544BEA701214ED0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Executive agency defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>executive agency</quote> means—</text> <paragraph id="HA9998BDF46804B7E9606DED677E85E84"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an executive department or independent establishment in the executive branch of the Government; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H40840FB3391944FBB4FAC6723230E445"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a wholly owned Government corporation.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H124B5430A85347C186FBE12527F2BFF4"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall apply to the relocation of an office of an executive agency initiated on or after the date that is 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


