<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H34D52E5D6C99409B89FA6F1880D6D00A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2846 IH: Federal Agency Customer Experience Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2846</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170608">June 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the collection of voluntary feedback on services provided by agencies, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H238317698B6C4D3E9B9722460A62C0F0" style="OLC">
		<section id="H3452DAA303544F69A81572539F3DA0F0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Agency Customer Experience Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H688F3BFCC42145F992C9434EAC2F854B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="H8B3D7CF56FAE48E492D19304A84254BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCFBDA1F4933F4C7982B91386B28F76FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal Government serves the people of the United States and should seek to continually improve public services provided by the Federal Government based on customer feedback;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3DD1E637116F4A1D996D524C428679BD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the people of the United States deserve a Federal Government that provides efficient, effective, and high-quality services across multiple channels;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8362C641EF744B6D80FB3978B7EBF450"><enum>(3)</enum><text>many agencies, offices, programs, and Federal employees provide excellent service to individuals, however many parts of the Federal Government still fall short on delivering the customer service experience that individuals have come to expect from the private sector;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9E9056E85034F49AB56075528B0F686"><enum>(4)</enum><text>according to the 2016 American Customer Satisfaction Index, the Federal Government ranks among the bottom of all industries in the United States in customer satisfaction;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6178361BA6A64EC1B613E2D2A99C27FC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>providing quality services to individuals improves the confidence of the people of the United States in their government and helps agencies achieve greater impact and fulfill their missions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BA7AB3B93584110B1B70A5DDEC0AEBD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>improving service to individuals requires agencies to work across organizational boundaries, leverage technology, collect and share standardized data, and develop customer-centered mindsets and service strategies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1995959F625B4A3FA697F7BD83B78F7C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that all agencies should strive to provide high-quality, courteous, effective, and efficient services to the people of the United States and seek to measure, collect, report, and utilize metrics relating to the experience of individuals interacting with agencies to continually improve services to the people of the United States.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H00C69EA5B9994F93AB78B751EC10CA2E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H7A0C831BD7644BBC8539F14E5873FA51"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of General Services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E4CF79FBFA3486FBCA8F559F6FAD4D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F733B1319FE4B0291E07F3FD570CE90"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered agency</header><text>The term <term>covered agency</term> means an agency or component of an agency that is required by the Director to collect voluntary feedback under section 6, based on an assessment of the components and programs of the agency with the highest impact on or number of interactions with individuals or entities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3BB96AAC5FF4F898DDD7EDCDF444267"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B5B15C5E1B64C8FA7B26BD6B8A6ADE2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Voluntary feedback</header><text>The term <term>voluntary feedback</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code, as added by section 4 of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HD0FC2B3DEB9742789641FE4953364B53"><enum>4.</enum><header>Application of the Paperwork Reduction Act to collection of voluntary feedback</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>), is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HEE2E682034EC4FE8972FD2E8814A8DAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 3502—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF3B7CFC4836E4323ABB22F251C04D2BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (13)(D), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10F5AC64C39A4689A390FDB3E454B85A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (14), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D60EC0D8F464F26B2CF4F3119C1B044"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H497A8DD7EC6140899F32D217F45E8C78" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HD66C39849671485CAA999D99032AC7BD"><enum>(15)</enum><text>the term <term>voluntary feedback</term> means any submission of information, opinion, or concern that is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3726887E7DAF49EA87E0C1EE91F2F564"><enum>(A)</enum><text>voluntarily made by a specific individual or other entity relating to a particular service of or transaction with an agency; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66DE3F04A7A3406EA015CFD45115214D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specifically solicited by that agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H88334AC007E14CF79211A35B5353036E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 3518(c)(1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6FAE848014C04AB08E409E748CA9CD91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H810BDD9E278C43E888AD97B03295E8AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE78AAED5A464207A205B6D12D4905D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA99F7C4C01641E28303A8A87CCBA778" style="OLC"> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC152DCC7E3D14950B30225760385B995" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by an agency that is voluntary feedback.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HF456B13207684680B406C4C92725D536"><enum>5.</enum><header>Guidelines for voluntary feedback</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Each agency that solicits voluntary feedback shall ensure that—</text> <paragraph id="H5BD9FAEDBC0342EFA5280DE9C995E04E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>responses to the solicitation of voluntary feedback remain anonymous and shall not be traced to specific individuals or entities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0298BA1E57034175919F0FE85EA24D16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>individuals who decline to participate in the solicitation of voluntary feedback shall not be treated differently by the agency for purposes of providing services or information;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3F7B53776FE7404782F8F645A6DE85B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the solicitation does not include more than 10 questions;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4CCAE4BD6EFA4BEF9010E3825923D454"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the voluntary nature of the solicitation is clear;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDB31A8AA74045A1BE540166007C9CB5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the proposed solicitation of voluntary feedback will contribute to improved customer service;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H02BB261A93AF44A281870A32C658194A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>solicitations of voluntary feedback are limited to 1 solicitation per interaction with an individual or entity;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45CF9681C86246DEA4E42DBB0FDAE4C4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, the solicitation of voluntary feedback is made at the point of service with an individual or entity;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H80EECC1DB71E4F56878F654917E68DF5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>instruments for collecting voluntary feedback are accessible to individuals with disabilities in accordance with section 508 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794d">29 U.S.C. 794d</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F504D4E3D7B46B5AA8DA8003D0F8E82"><enum>(9)</enum><text>internal agency data governance policies remain in effect with respect to the collection of voluntary feedback from individuals and entities.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H26A5EA21B5574BFBAE1F7D6F3C8F234D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Customer experience data collection</header>
 <subsection id="HCE089F1D743F44C3AE40D762CE1BF881"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Collection of responses</header><text>The head of each covered agency (or a designee), assisted by and in coordination with the Chief Performance Officer or other senior accountable official for customer service of the covered agency, shall collect voluntary feedback with respect to services of or transactions with the covered agency.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H980B8FF5313D45FA9BD5873CD0C406B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content of questions</header>
 <paragraph id="H2CFDE7A188E64DA7B340EDFA72768020"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Standardized questions</header><text>The Director, in coordination with the Administrator, shall develop a set of standardized questions for use by covered agencies in collecting voluntary feedback under this section that address—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H48B2E2780CB6420AA9E768376CEBDA72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>overall satisfaction of individuals or entities with the specific interaction or service received;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC305A016B514071B2EC5DDF298DF582"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the extent to which individuals or entities were able to accomplish their intended task or purpose;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1504540AF3074E0FA5519F502F9390BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the individual or entity was treated with respect and professionalism;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5AD4BCD681347D082AEA0BB59409BF5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether the individual or entity believes they were served in a timely manner; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2314FAE9936F472B8A67548E7F85B66A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any additional metrics as determined by the Director, in coordination with the Administrator.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF952F6D404494AFE97CE015CBF195CF8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional questions</header><text>In addition to the questions developed under paragraph (1), the Chief Performance Officer or other senior accountable official for customer service at a covered agency may develop questions relevant to the specific operations or programs of the covered agency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDE082B5BEDD149F08309B376A8301782"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text>To the extent practicable—</text> <paragraph id="HC69F7FF5EEB745CEB1A87F4486238891"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each covered agency shall collect voluntary feedback across all platforms or channels through which the covered agency interacts with individuals or other entities to deliver information or services; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H50E1940ECC114FD8A79B1FE2E03429F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>voluntary feedback collected under this section shall be tied to specific transactions or interactions with customers of the covered agency.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B4A3A0E3ECE4FD4BA8F33EA6F25841B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header>
				<paragraph id="H57602AA41A3C4E9585C15240A20AF94B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual report to the Director</header>
 <subparagraph id="H956D901EAC6D41BEAE26AB823FCF89DD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, each covered agency shall publish on the website of the covered agency and submit to the Director, in a manner determined by the Director, a report that includes the voluntary feedback required to be collected under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DA0B4BBCF734B248867B8525CC01767"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Centralized website</header><text>The Director shall—</text> <clause id="HC89E08954A5F4CCBBDB4ECB6E8C5A547"><enum>(i)</enum><text>include and maintain on a publicly available website links to the information provided on the websites of covered agencies under subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H38D30B0AA01B4E15824C62B86C6415BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for purposes of clause (i), establish a website or make use of an existing website, such as the website required under section 1122 of title 31, United States Code.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD152732ED401499CBDE20340C583FB20"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aggregated report</header><text>Each covered agency shall publish, on a regular basis, an aggregated report on the solicitation of voluntary feedback sent to individuals or entities, which shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBE78C74402D64C7C861437158C675EFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the intended purpose of each solicitation of voluntary feedback conducted by the covered agency;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5337F65C8C9349C5A824E1AA9FAE956F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the appropriate point of contact within each covered agency for each solicitation of voluntary feedback conducted;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA9E5081B6E24C118405E92DB7B376C2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the questions or survey instrument submitted to members of the public as part of the solicitation of voluntary information; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC38F969A7FD9452FAA0FEF157161BA44"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of how the covered agency uses the voluntary feedback received by the covered agency to improve the customer service of the covered agency.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4DC88EFC57294ADF99E36B196CD30018"><enum>7.</enum><header>Customer experience scorecard report</header>
 <subsection id="H33FC0EC0E9DC497ABCD78341098403ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 15 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 10 years, the Comptroller General of the United States shall make publicly available and submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives a scorecard report assessing the quality of services provided to the public by each covered agency.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC6654A2B06CD4CEA8DC1F66E7285E508"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H334A13FD7B0A47F09AD163F80B0A11FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of the information required to be published by covered agencies under section 6(d); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H193205D542A64300942E410D26A5B9E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an analysis of administrative and legislative barriers to improving service delivery by covered agencies.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


