<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9275EE59463B4BE5B2F7A18FCD024575" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2077 IH: Restoring the Patient’s Voice Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2077</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to require a group health plan (or
			 health insurance coverage offered in connection with such a plan) to
			 provide an exceptions process for any medication step therapy protocol,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HEC7FB4709AA24BB9813ACF22B6840E53" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF5852EC11F854CAF839DEB10A062B936" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restoring the Patient’s Voice Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6B656ABCA0EB4FCE8038800222153355"><enum>2.</enum><header>Required exceptions process for medication step therapy protocols</header> <subsection id="HFC73FB75994A416285D5983EECFD2C19"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 is amended by inserting after section 715 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1185d">29 U.S.C. 1185d</external-xref>) the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H5867E24AD82D490D90BABCFD24181E4F" style="OLC">
					<section id="H1DA9EAF494AE46FCB8C55FBD08C11181"><enum>716.</enum><header>Required exceptions process for medication step therapy protocols</header>
 <subsection id="H613D3C8BEC064CD7B833EB27A635A2D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a group health plan (or health insurance coverage offered in connection with such a plan) that provides coverage of a prescription drug pursuant to a medication step therapy protocol, the plan or coverage shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H48D08B36A9624966B189599421BB401A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>implement a clear process for a participant or beneficiary (or the prescribing health care provider) to request an exception to such medication step therapy protocol; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF139E4F45E649BB9B3F0A676930D07A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if such a request demonstrates through supporting documentation that any of the circumstances listed in subsection (b) exists, authorize coverage for the prescription drug without regard to such medication step therapy protocol.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCFC97463F1B84F66B61D80AC916904C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expedited approval</header><text>The circumstances warranting an exception to a medication step therapy protocol, pursuant to a request under subsection (a), are any of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HFF38AF8D7CB94A63A80A866658D5F669"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The treatment otherwise required under the protocol, or a drug or drugs in the same pharmacological class, are contraindicated or have been ineffective in the treatment of the disease or condition of the participant or beneficiary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8F790F264554330A5E99C2EE6A3BCA2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The treatment otherwise required under the protocol is reasonably expected to be ineffective based upon—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0B2BEC7C9B4B4A8BAEF4D3421F76F7F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the known physical or mental characteristics of the participant or beneficiary, including medical history; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD766F4134C3F44619F835184B7885FDC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the known characteristics of such treatment.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H43174A49FE774A81820ADDE71759026C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The treatment otherwise required under the protocol will cause or is likely to cause an adverse reaction or other physical harm to the participant or beneficiary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1C719209A3A42B3998BB7FDBB23C4AF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The treatment otherwise required under the protocol is not in the best interest of the participant or beneficiary, based on medical necessity, because the participant or beneficiary’s use of such treatment is expected to decrease the participant or beneficiary’s ability—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBA41AC4047BD48CAB37DE7979E83729B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to achieve or maintain reasonable and safe functional ability in performing daily activities or occupational responsibilities; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B102768239A475488AE82493179ADBB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to adhere to the treatment plan as defined by the prescribing health care provider.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A295C8F8AA54932A20984E45C2965E7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The participant or beneficiary is stable for his or her disease or condition on the prescription drugs selected by the prescribing health care provider.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF3BA8160D88543DFA0ECD70F18844BC9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clear process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The process required by subsection (a)(1) shall make information regarding such process readily available on the website of the group health plan, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H29E3EE025BC94483A729F47FBB113D92"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the requirements for requesting an exception to a medication step therapy protocol pursuant to this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB8825B9E990841D7A8BA1236C1DBB2E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any necessary forms and contact information.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H12ADEE19CAF14574A972AEB929140FED"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Timing for granting exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The process required by subsection (a)(1) shall provide for the disposition of requests received under such paragraph in accordance with the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD177A0CD4B2240EC953F6AD91ACCCD4A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Such a request shall be granted as quickly as the disease or condition of the participant or beneficiary requires, but no later than 3 days after the day of receipt of the request.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA8050EFCCD14ADA8C3B4888BA9FCAFB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For circumstances in which the applicable medication step therapy protocol may seriously jeopardize the life, health, or ability to regain maximum function of the participant or beneficiary, such a request shall be granted—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H888196032FCE4466BA5F56F0810013CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on an expedited basis; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD808203DCE17481A8C5B4DE7DD2E4023"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no later than 24 hours after receipt of such request.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H07C948DE20C54C7B915FB4388D1A4634"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Medication step therapy protocol</header><text>In this section, the term <term>step therapy protocol</term> means a protocol or program that establishes a specific sequence in which prescription drugs that—</text> <paragraph id="HFF1D3E130DD947D5AD3DAA453BFEFB36"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are for a specified disease or condition, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7C2C9E58D7342E694263AFE32F44EFD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are medically necessary for a particular patient,</text> </paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">are covered under a pharmacy or medical benefit by a group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage.</continuation-text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HE6B67F4629CA41F5B1EE1C76BA2148C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical correction; clerical change</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1001">29 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 714 the following new items:</text>
				<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
					<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 715. Additional market reforms.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 716. Required exceptions process for medication step therapy protocols.</toc-entry></toc>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC4EA4BD52FD74E47B1FA91352233F940"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) applies to plan years beginning no sooner than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


