<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H03C7E9EC948C42B8B146C5F564F13B75" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 941 IH: 12 Carrier Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 941</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170207">February 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001062">Mr. Conaway</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To increase the number of operational aircraft carriers of the Navy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H47BB06B5865447988B41EEEF6F242E05" style="OLC">
 <section id="H039A73B4A78242E8A6447F35989CB328" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>12 Carrier Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD647DB37DFD047D48612B3056666FC51"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="H92C8E698019044EEAA49F052E69296AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1546335411F24CD993866E38BFBFA92A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The aircraft carrier can fulfill the Navy’s core missions of forward presence, sea control, ensuring safe sea lanes, and power projection as well as providing flexibility and versatility to execute a wide range of additional missions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HECEA4B70098241DAA9EB2BECEA92F810"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Forward airpower is integral to the security and joint forces operations of the United States. Carriers play a central role in delivering forward airpower from sovereign territory of the United States in both permissive and nonpermissive environments.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E85F1B36CD44754B9198D5008CABD4C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Aircraft carriers provide our Nation the ability to rapidly and decisively respond to national threats, as well as conducting worldwide, on-station diplomacy and providing deterrence against threats to the United States allies, partners, and friends.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H11290CA707084D2B87D7AD3DA0D9156A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Since the end of the cold war, aircraft carrier deployments have increased while the aircraft carrier force structure has declined.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF53C541742094C76AED5E5162D5C64E7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Considering the increased array of complex threats across the globe, the Navy aircraft carrier is operating at maximum capacity, increasing deployment lengths and decreasing maintenance periods in order to meet operational requirements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H79D9324D6DB94794A1EEE776780D3042"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To meet global peacetime and wartime requirements, the Navy has indicated a requirement to maintain two aircraft carriers deployed overseas and have three additional aircraft carrier capable of deploying within 90 days. However, the Navy has indicated that the existing aircraft carrier force structure cannot support these military requirements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3196EDCF39794EAB8F3D950CB47AD881"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Despite the requirement to maintain an aircraft carrier strike group in both the United States Central Command and United States Pacific Command, the Navy has been unable to generate sufficient capacity to support our combatant commanders and has developed significant carrier gaps in these critical areas.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD3DAB9065584A94AAC515509A637194"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Because of continuing use of a diminished aircraft carrier force structure, extensive maintenance availabilities result which typically exceed program costs and increase time in shipyards. These expansive maintenance availabilities exacerbate existing carrier gaps.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC33E37BF69448BD921451032193D811"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Because of maintenance overhaul extensions, the Navy is truncating basic aircraft carrier training to expedite the deployment of available aircraft carriers. Limiting aircraft carrier training decreases operational capabilities and increases sailor risk.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H47912B3386A84C3A8D48D9C9A99E8624"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Despite the objections of the Navy, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics directed the Navy on August 7, 2015, to perform shock trials on the U.S.S. Gerald R. Ford (CVN–78). The Assistant Deputy Chief of Naval Operations for Operations, Plans and Strategy indicated that this action could delay the introduction of the U.S.S. Gerald R. Ford (CVN–78) to the fleet by up to two years, exacerbating existing carrier gaps.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E1D3FC95F854D5E976A0DD265282686"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Navy has adopted a two-phase acquisition strategy for the U.S.S. John F. Kennedy (CVN–79), an action that will delay the introduction of this aircraft carrier by up to two years, exacerbating existing carrier gaps.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B59F38629204F56A8E2BD27AC7EA917"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Developing an alternative design to the Ford-class aircraft carrier is not cost beneficial. A smaller design is projected to incur significant design and engineering cost while significantly reducing magazine size, carrier air wing size, sortie rate, and on-station effectiveness among other vital factors when compared to the Ford-class. Furthermore, a new design will delay the introduction of future aircraft carriers, exacerbating existing carrier gaps and threatening the national security of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0178F3015A4940818914DB214B05ACBF"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The 2016 Navy Force Structure Assessment states <quote>A minimum of 12 aircraft carriers are required to meet the increased warfighting response requirements of the Defense Planning Guidance Defeat/Deny force sizing direction.</quote></text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF9E06D380A7C42989DF351BCC57FC8D9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HC282FDDF3ED94E6E9DC785AD6B7C3799"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States should expedite delivery of 12 aircraft carriers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H233F5568485542A9BD7F1ECB8F0B021E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an aircraft carrier should be authorized every three years;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E68865E4FBE4B599F72F8372470D759"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shock trials should be conducted on the U.S.S. John F. Kennedy (CVN–79), as initially proposed by the Navy;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC16A2B3989C4CBDA37E69A5A1B487B8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">construction for the U.S.S. John F. Kennedy (CVN–79) should be accomplished in a single phase;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H683BE32765DC4ABFA92CC822F29C0B5D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States should continue the Ford-class design for CVN–81; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H692C5AC51EEC45E6ADFAABB76434D37B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>bulk procurement initiatives for CVN–80 and CVN–81 should be pursued.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H21851C8DC26F47DD95F3004D2FC755AC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Shock trials for CVN–78</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 128(b)(1) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/92">Public Law 114–92</external-xref>; 129 Stat. 751) is amended by striking <quote>prior to the first deployment of such ship</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H462210370D8E487A936108B768AAB77A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Increase in number of operational aircraft carriers of the Navy</header>
 <subsection id="HB15603C5C6344C1CA5946E60D30D2633"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Increase</header><text>Section 5062(b) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>11 operational aircraft carriers</quote> and inserting <quote>12 operational aircraft carriers</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HAEE51AA74DA44D3AB06275D6ACD1E3F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on September 30, 2023.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


