<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H589F3C9B09084034BB7FBA6B2231D546" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2626 IH: Strong Visa Integrity Secures America Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2626</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170524">May 24, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001073">Mr. Hurd</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 and the Immigration and Nationality Act to improve visa
			 security, visa applicant vetting, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4D11D4A9302248809BF933AC19D459CA" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF4A05CD832CA49B5920AFC372C8EC9DC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strong Visa Integrity Secures America Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H55C148FD342440D788E43801BC60258E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Visa security</header> <subsection id="H97F9AEEDB2114ED5A0DAC646C85EB981"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Visa security units at high-Risk posts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of section 428(e) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/236">6 U.S.C. 236(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H22C5DDFD6974432E85456544EACD4A5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0F7B4B3EA0A45F08F7572CC40AE881D" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HF77A4A19CF3A4F3997A2EBB551040138"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBED9B924505046C3BCDF941876B85791"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0FDBB22A9B0408B98DEF688F3284D45" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H17BA51BA9BF041DBB8132C2E55558318"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Risk-based assignments</header> <clause id="HBC86069E6F104B42A0279EACA29B3CDA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall assign, in a risk-based manner, and based on the criteria described in clause (ii), employees of the Department to not fewer than 30 diplomatic and consular posts at which visas are issued.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H11A9292B9CE74AC8959209F2940698CC"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Criteria described</header><text>The criteria referred to in clause (i) are the following:</text> <subclause id="HCF20A4D9741A44FE84FE384C269307AD"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of nationals of a country in which any of the diplomatic and consular posts referred to in clause (i) are located who were identified in United States Government databases related to the identities of known or suspected terrorists during the previous year.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0D7FC105844A487F92AE1CEA61CDBFDE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The level of cooperation of such country with the counterterrorism efforts of the United States.</text> </subclause><subclause id="HC59764385CE54A78BA00BE6D10ECDC6E"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information analyzing the presence, activity, or movement of terrorist organizations (as such term is defined in section 212(a)(3)(B)(vi) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)(B)(vi)</external-xref>)) within or through such country.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H5B5C28F18EFF40E5B0182CEC054EE6D2"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of derogatory Security Advisory Opinions issued by the Visa Security Advisory Opinion Unit pursuant to paragraph (10) regarding nationals of a country in which any of the diplomatic and consular posts referred to in clause (i) are located.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF54C298FAA2E421B94913F08BC3D934B"><enum>(V)</enum><text>The adequacy of the border and immigration control of such country.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H7EF9464DA8FE4645BE0FEEB216147355"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Any other criteria the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H2BE9BACD1D184E4C8EDD47CAE060051E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The assignment of employees of the Department pursuant to this subparagraph is solely the authority of the Secretary and may not be altered or rejected by the Secretary of State.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0595DFEE3F694B70B616883DDB3D136F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Counterterror vetting and screening</header><text>Paragraph (2) of section 428(e) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H82675390612E4D228B4E4195E8DD412C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (D); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H202DD6986001447684C839AB6C98F794"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (B) the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86C52B51CB5C411C9CEF7A406F3CBACC" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HD34D8A356025431DB9A521BFEC2A7F6C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Screen any such applications against the appropriate criminal, national security, and terrorism databases maintained by the Federal Government.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9CC8917BCF7444BA8189D77B809640C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Training and hiring</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of section 428(e)(6) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by—</text> <paragraph id="H88DBB52B83744A64872B827A666F4E2E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>striking <quote>The Secretary shall ensure, to the extent possible, that any employees</quote> and inserting <quote>The Secretary, acting through the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, shall provide training to any employees</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB92B3211580431088ADF1A1FFD8500C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>striking <quote>shall be provided the necessary training</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H71A3611CFF4648A89070AEAAB6DBF2C6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Pre-Adjudicated visa security assistance and Visa Security Advisory Opinion Unit</header><text>Subsection (e) of section 428 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8DC141838BF24858BC045127BDD283A2" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H17F97349757A46FB9236553294BC101F"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Remote pre-adjudicated visa security assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the visa-issuing posts at which employees of the Department are not assigned pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary shall, to the greatest extent possible, in a risk-based manner, and in consultation, where appropriate, with the Secretary of State, assign employees of the Department to remotely perform the functions required under paragraph (2) for such posts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H87488512DD6C4C409573880156ED07AC"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Visa Security Advisory Opinion Unit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish within U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement a Visa Security Advisory Opinion Unit to respond to requests from the Secretary of State to conduct a visa security review using information maintained by the Department on visa applicants, including terrorism association, criminal history, and other relevant factors, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H9FC54F6EFA5841E2AD59767E33574162"><enum>3.</enum><header>Electronic passport screening and biometric matching</header>
 <subsection id="H21A244D1837F4A5ABE1FF43E46231A0E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle C of title IV of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/231">6 U.S.C. 231</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new sections:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8FE831991778492FB327C67A5B1C181A" style="OLC">
					<section id="HC2AA9EB7759D47999AD04FA616C50B4A"><enum>434.</enum><header>Electronic passport screening and biometric matching</header>
 <subsection id="H96939FC49AE4424D9BD43FE03730763E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA3CF0C64463C4842A0F36FD3272603DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">screen electronic passports at airports of entry by reading each such passport’s embedded chip; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HECC68A8B039C4295BEECEFFEB3122075"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the greatest extent practicable, utilize facial recognition technology or other biometric technology, as determined by the Commissioner, to screen travelers at United States airports of entry.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6CB1C8508394E4081CA68AB7F8CADB6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header>
 <paragraph id="HE316FC1E49A94A81A028F624CD583722"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Electronic passport screening</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of subsection (a) shall apply to passports belonging to individuals who are United States citizens, individuals who are nationals of a program country pursuant to section 217 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1187">8 U.S.C. 1187</external-xref>), and individuals who are nationals of any other foreign country that issues electronic passports.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H725FEE846BAB4F81A0C26C8CB1198EC8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Facial recognition matching</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of subsection (a) shall apply to individuals who are nationals of a program country pursuant to section 217 of the Immigration and Nationality Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2F074F7A0D69439C8A0F4D0CF2C36F12"><enum>435.</enum><header>Continuous screening by U.S. Customs and Border Protection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall, in a risk-based manner, continuously screen individuals issued any visa, and individuals who are nationals of a program country pursuant to section 217 of the Immigration and Nationality Act, who are present, or will soon be arriving, in the United States, against the appropriate criminal, national security, and terrorism databases maintained by the Federal Government.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB615246577424A999F910CA424C57B11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 433 the following new items:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H66F21D8313FC496494AEC160819397F4" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 434. Electronic passport screening and biometric matching.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 435. Continuous screening by U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="H1545E87CABC942FCAA2A2FAE32BC5273"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reporting of visa overstays</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/173">Public Law 105–173</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1376">8 U.S.C. 1376</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2F6D9AC7E30A4DEBB10E6F00001A2084"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H12AA5CD2B8EC46AF85395EA11CF3174A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> and inserting <quote>Secretary of Homeland Security</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE57CE028DE94C4AA989CE9941225905"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, and any additional information that the Secretary determines necessary for purposes of the report under subsection (b)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE01AAB329A9645E49F575E869A9515B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending subsection (b) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAD80232572349EEA4EABD9CF6E0D1CD" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HB8187FB7146141B2BE1AB959A3549A11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than June 30, 2017, and not later than June 30 of each year thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report providing, for the preceding fiscal year, numerical estimates of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1EEB91C547DB4EFA9B329B7025BFEF6C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for each country, the number of aliens from the country who are described in subsection (a), including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAAC98DA2E3DF4A15B1D4809A3CD1BF7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total number of such aliens within all classes of nonimmigrant aliens described in section 101(a)(15) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA5C6A577F0F4A4B8019E9E3730C263D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of such aliens within each of the classes of nonimmigrant aliens, as well as the number of such aliens within each of the subclasses of such classes of nonimmigrant aliens, as applicable;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H633548A1D06640508D3E01CE2037D46A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each country, the percentage of the total number of aliens from the country who were present in the United States and were admitted to the United States as nonimmigrants who are described in subsection (a);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2446EED4EE9B4C7786E3882C8A4ED10E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of aliens described in subsection (a) who arrived by land at a port of entry into the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H19F46EA8F48B49849A6A5F3BDA9251F2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number of aliens described in subsection (a) who entered the United States using a border crossing identification card (as such term is defined in section 101(a)(6) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(6)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HD8D92C8444654597AE4DAFC4D0C818AB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Student and exchange visitor information system verification</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that the information collected under the program established under section 641 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1372">8 U.S.C. 1372</external-xref>) is available to officers of U.S. Customs and Border Protection conducting primary inspections of aliens seeking admission to the United States at each port of entry of the United States.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


