<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5AA38B707C3E4BF99B1CB3D01E07C15E" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3262 RH: Grow Our Own Directive: Physician Assistant Employment and Education Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 192</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3262</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–267]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170717">July 17, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster of New Hampshire</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>July 28, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on July 17, 2017</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program to provide educational
			 assistance to certain former members of the Armed Forces for education and
			 training as physician assistants of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to
			 establish pay grades and require competitive pay for physician assistants
			 of the Department, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HVR00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H74ABD75ED1F24B669E383C7FCA3047AE" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="H868199DF1CFD4EEA9F30D125869CF8B1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Grow Our Own Directive: Physician Assistant Employment and Education Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3177F8BDE4E64CD2996629A04D0399DF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program to provide educational assistance to physician assistants to be employed at the Department of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="HB9D9B8E4FD094535881CA1CB561312DE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program</header> <paragraph id="H2DBE6F3F45294B00B91C1E2D0221089D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a pilot program to be known as the <quote>Grow Our Own Directive</quote> or <quote>G.O.O.D.</quote> pilot program (in this section referred to as the <quote>pilot program</quote>) to provide educational assistance to certain former members of the Armed Forces for education and training as physician assistants of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86E7E84BA2124EB5A23502788424F53C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information on pilot program</header><text>The Secretary shall provide information on the pilot program to eligible individuals under subsection (b), including information on application requirements and a list of entities with which the Secretary has partnered under subsection (g).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0020697ABE1949EDB9C5244A44FE6281"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible individuals</header><text>An individual is eligible to participate in the pilot program if the individual—</text> <paragraph id="HF425C99023054E9783070782D22DA969"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has medical or military health experience gained while serving as a member of the Armed Forces;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H081E26EA36284D15A76C8FB14BFA0899"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has received a certificate, associate degree, baccalaureate degree, master’s degree, or postbaccalaureate training in a science relating to health care;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D965194C7D845399E2818950D51BD2B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not eligible to participate in educational assistance under chapter 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, or 35 of title 38, United States Code, or chapter 1606 or 1607 of title 10, United States Code;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46D7B1CB865241A3A46144F7EC56F43D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>has participated in the delivery of health care services or related medical services, including participation in military training relating to the identification, evaluation, treatment, and prevention of diseases and disorders; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A08453FF09C430CB37D9293AC68CE47"><enum>(5)</enum><text>does not have a degree of doctor of medicine, doctor of osteopathy, or doctor of dentistry.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA765AE9C3A674BCABF21E05E1521216D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The pilot program shall be carried out during the five-year period beginning on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H86BAE25F6E6449738E4F5A22831F851F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection</header>
 <paragraph id="HFC51609B51094E6794D385CF46556AF2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall select not less than 250 eligible individuals under subsection (b) to participate in the pilot program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35F13085ABE44DE0844238CF81118370"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Priority for selection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting individuals to participate in the pilot program under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall give priority to the following individuals:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A05525B14E340C2AD5389881A4069A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals who participated in the Intermediate Care Technician Pilot Program of the Department that was carried out by the Secretary between January 2011 and February 2015.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52AB67711D5C40C39672DDBC0C8059DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Individuals who agree to be employed as a physician assistant for the Veterans Health Administration at a medical facility of the Department located in a community that—</text>
 <clause id="HF14280B26C85458BB859A2BA58660D7F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is designated as a medically underserved population under section 330(b)(3)(A) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254b">42 U.S.C. 254b(b)(3)(A)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFF1225359FDA46FFACF405FA9AF04E08"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is in a State with a per capita population of veterans of more than 9 percent according to the National Center for Veterans Analysis and Statistics and the United States Census Bureau.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H25CC162C457B4CC38E2BF62AD926350D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Educational assistance</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB7B6B06A08F445699ADAA44911D8C23"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary shall provide educational assistance to individuals participating in the pilot program, including through the use of scholarships, to cover the costs to such individuals of obtaining a master's degree in physician assistant studies or a similar master's degree.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1260EA148E014C06B29DBEB3A193B84C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of existing programs</header><text>In providing educational assistance under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall use the Department of Veterans Affairs Health Professionals Educational Assistance Program under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/76">chapter 76</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, and such other educational assistance programs of the Department as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE992800E66B4E6F899CC8B54CB0464C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of scholarships</header><text>The Secretary shall provide not less than 35 scholarships under the pilot program to individuals participating in the pilot program during each year in which the pilot program is carried out.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20092E38E6D148D3BE7CB8D0D0D727B8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Period of obligated service</header>
 <paragraph id="H093537E2C7594A3CB2A3F33AF2154943"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall enter into an agreement with each individual participating in the pilot program in which such individual agrees to be employed as a physician assistant for the Veterans Health Administration for a period of obligated service specified in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24C026F2D30D4D3C8530A3D6C7681838"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period specified</header><text>With respect to each individual participating in the pilot program, the period of obligated service specified in this paragraph for the individual is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H198D7923D1B745D48FD2A1347AF7AEBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the individual is participating in the pilot program through a program described in subsection (e)(2) that specifies a period of obligated service, the period specified with respect to such program; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7292A1B4E03E45E98A12CDAE3CA5E3BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the individual is participating in the pilot program other than through a program described in such subsection, or if such program does not specify a period of obligated service, a period of three years or such other period as the Secretary considers appropriate for purposes of the pilot program.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1A8B1ED4A0FF40588B1836014596C86F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Breach</header>
 <paragraph id="HE478EAE7EFD04E1C9BB5EF0B79043BDD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Liability</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), an individual who participates in the pilot program and fails to satisfy the period of obligated service under subsection (f) shall be liable to the United States, in lieu of such obligated service, for the amount that has been paid or is payable to or on behalf of the individual under the pilot program, reduced by the proportion that the number of days served for completion of the period of obligated service bears to the total number of days in the period of obligated service of such individual.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD820922B4929404D8193193F20C7EC42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If an individual is participating in the pilot program through a program described in subsection (e)(2) that specifies a period of obligated service, the liability of the individual for failing to satisfy the period of obligated service under subsection (f) shall be determined as specified with respect to such program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H30651FE4F72E4197B875192437DC5B83"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Mentors</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that a physician assistant mentor or mentors are available for individuals participating in the pilot program at each facility of the Veterans Health Administration at which a participant in the pilot program is employed.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4AD85BF0C6184399AEE1CFA2ED6F1A28"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary shall seek to partner with the following:</text> <paragraph id="HD1629478A1CC467984A4509DF1B3861B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not less than 15 institutions of higher education that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H261D0E7FD4C14BD481C2629B6834BA45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>offer a master's degree program in physician assistant studies or a similar area of study that is accredited by the Accreditation Review Commission on Education for the Physician Assistant; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2305E7E9A9914D9A95509086809D39E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>agree—</text> <clause id="H883E3E1A37B145A1A553E7259D231CD8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to guarantee seats in such master's degree program for individuals participating in the pilot program who meet the entrance requirements for such master's degree program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCE7EE4875823482E87555CDB3D634B7F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to provide individuals participating in the pilot program with information on admissions criteria and the admissions process.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA1DCE0069504286830D7FC7A907EEA4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Other institutions of higher education that offer programs in physician assistant studies or other similar areas of studies that are accredited by the Accreditation Review Commission on Education for the Physician Assistant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B96A81EF6394B3EAEEB84123D1AEC7B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Defense.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB431068997544A608BC62268D3A4EDC3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Veterans' Employment and Training Service of the Department of Labor.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23C4F4D7E7654544BCF2417B053DCCB3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Programs carried out under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/41">chapter 41</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, for the purpose of marketing and advertising the pilot program to veterans and members of the Armed Forces who may be interested in the pilot program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H375168C6EC3743F0BB723BAE4C7912C9"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Administration of pilot program</header><text>For purposes of carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary shall appoint or select within the Office of Physician Assistant Services of the Veterans Health Administration the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H9A9463503D7F4B1491AEA0B12F4E7E04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A Deputy Director for Education and Career Development of Physician Assistants who—</text> <subparagraph id="H7851758CD925412292C6403D6E29927D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a physician assistant, a veteran, and employed by the Department as of the date of the enactment of this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC88EACD1621F43418E64F6653B672198"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is responsible for—</text> <clause id="HF45B249C009747069A85DE27C824BBEB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>overseeing the pilot program;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAA72E2FA231A4C9DADB3F1DED22DC9AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recruiting candidates to participate in the pilot program;</text> </clause><clause id="HDF1D6AB6BA524DA9BC7B1F26C66A77C9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>coordinating with individuals participating in the pilot program and assisting those individuals in applying and being admitted to a master's degree program under the pilot program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4775A6013A9646F0B4016D4F51975A0B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>providing information to eligible individuals under subsection (b) with respect to the pilot program; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H898EA65FE5EA4EBF8B7101CB6405D1BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may be employed in the field at a medical center of the Department.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BE5CEEEB44E46A682F8E3C3881A028F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A Deputy Director of Recruitment and Retention who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFFE712F8DCE647A38A5B5955EC94C402"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a physician assistant, a veteran, and employed by the Department as of the date of the enactment of this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H077042E6F3DF4404A5554CD582BECC54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is responsible for—</text> <clause id="H7A098CB0D4804EACBFA9CAD11D2F0AFE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identifying and coordinating the needs of the pilot program and assist the Secretary in providing mentors under subsection (h) to participants in the pilot program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H11BB23E0CF134EC98A0187D82FC3B0FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>coordinating the staff of facilities of the Veterans Health Administration with respect to identifying employment positions and mentors under subsection (h) for participants in the pilot program; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H41B24C88872848B788AA60D271D3BB5A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be employed in the field at a medical center of the Department.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DA0E518139B4EF4ABBB45DF2549D594"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A recruiter who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H37D002663C434B8A9F0CE77904B27908"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reports directly to the Deputy Director of Recruitment and Retention; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1A6E72B7A9B439685D6E8DE04ABBA0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>works with the Workforce Management and Consulting Office and the Healthcare Talent Management Office of the Veterans Health Administration to develop and implement national recruiting strategic plans for the recruitment and retention of physician assistants within the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H93018200F9464A8BA1D5B55BD2752F47"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An administrative assistant, compensated at a rate not less than level GS–6 of the General Schedule, or equivalent, who assists with administrative duties relating to the pilot program in the Office of Physician Assistant Services and such other duties as determined by the Secretary to ensure that the Office runs effectively and efficiently.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB8C2EC5B7B434CBB818818040C9EF1BD"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <paragraph id="H44DF94583838486C86F5E555E293C1C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in collaboration with the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall submit to Congress a report on the pilot program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB84943550C1424AA5586E84CBC273A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H6212BC4A6C074E38924B482CB1E94718"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The extent to which the pilot program is effective in improving the ability of eligible individuals under subsection (b) to become physician assistants;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90E7E82FC20143559F98B46620C127B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An examination of whether the pilot program is achieving the goals of—</text> <clause id="H66C2A99D02004BD0A725B2B85079A883"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enabling individuals to build on medical skills gained as members of the Armed Forces by entering into the physician assistant workforce of the Department; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H034003D5B3814573B7E24E0F5F7258AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>helping to meet the shortage of physician assistants employed by the Department.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A6FF74053E54E8D9C0AEF60E410078D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An identification of such modifications to the pilot program as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services consider necessary to meet the goals described in subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C19DF6422FA4506B275E7E350E5503D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An assessment of whether the pilot program could serve as a model for other programs of the Department to assist individuals in obtaining certification and employment in other health care fields.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8906991F2E0649DC8154824E00E1E7D9"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Source of amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than $8,000,000 of the amount necessary to carry out the pilot program shall be derived from amounts appropriated to the Department of Veterans Affairs before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H1AEBA3AB7E194E84AE9C19488D92E3AF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of standards for the Department of Veterans Affairs for using educational assistance
			 programs to educate and hire physician assistants</header>
 <subsection id="H4A74DF0711D243A9BB0D2CD22EF7E794"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish standards described in subsection (b) to improve the use by the Department of Veterans Affairs of the Department of Veterans Affairs Health Professionals Educational Assistance Program under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/76">chapter 76</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, and other educational assistance programs of the Department, including the pilot program under section 2, to educate and hire physician assistants of the Department.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H85143E0BC3734D5C829539D8753667B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Standards</header><text>The standards described in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph id="HA8617FB306F24704BDA6839886E5C86A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Holding directors of medical centers of the Department accountable for failure to use the educational assistance programs described in subsection (a) and other incentives—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1C892C8714F14265800685E82157F278"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to advance employees of the Department in their education as physician assistants; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A0D3B3A69EF45BF9509C46BB76269D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to improve recruitment and retention of physician assistants.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8B270011AA3459B9F23A0A2CB84A8A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Ensuring that the Department of Veterans Affairs Education Debt Reduction Program under subchapter VII of chapter 76 of such title is available for participants in the pilot program under section 2 to fill vacant physician assistant positions at the Department, including by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD47040DC2DEA4A58894C3E3DAEB94FD6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>including in all vacancy announcements for physician assistant positions the availability of the Education Debt Reduction Program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3215520F72B84D63A837287EE2A57872"><enum>(B)</enum><text>informing applicants to physician assistant positions of their eligibility for the Education Debt Reduction Program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF4E00B1088A4E639765D8DAB25C459B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Monitoring compliance with the application process for educational assistance programs described in subsection (a) to ensure that such programs are being fully utilized to carry out this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5C3895DA49E94FA49E9092816AFB2E4F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Creating programs, including through the use of the Department of Veterans Affairs Employee Incentive Scholarship Program under subchapter VI of chapter 76 of such title, to encourage employees of the Department to apply to accredited physician assistant programs.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDB0CC8F239534457B448AFB762ED6E09"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as the Secretary considers appropriate to carry out this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HD5CB31EE9D8142DDB27747E907326360"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of pay grades for physician assistants of the Department of Veterans Affairs and
			 requirement to provide competitive pay</header>
 <subsection id="HBED7A8C872004C89B7D5EC22E0E1C7D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of pay grades</header><text>Section 7404(b) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HVR00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED52AF6D0BF144B3B072D084B965BC8B" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> <toc changed="added" committee-id="HVR00" reported-display-style="italic"> <toc-entry bold="off" level="section">PHYSICIAN ASSISTANT SCHEDULE</toc-entry> <toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Physician Assistant IV.</toc-entry> <toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Physician Assistant III.</toc-entry> <toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Physician Assistant II.</toc-entry> <toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Physician Assistant I.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H525FE81C1E4E467295FA694ECF78FCC4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Competitive pay</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7451(a)(2) of such title is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB91F645E93F84B0EB756800FE0780F5E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (B) as subparagraph (C);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H41E60701D2204ACB847109D96348B236"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following new subparagraph (B):</text>
					<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HVR00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2B25D4654734633A845A7A53AFD0153" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H44F184B508924AD19D1F402CE3966118"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Physician assistant.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H550DC654F414480A90FC60FDBB27B614"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), as redesignated by paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and registered nurse</quote> and inserting <quote>registered nurse, and physician assistant</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H81376F9DFEF54D32B075337E065E7B30"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National strategic plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H98C0738778D8467FB06C111CDD05A01F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall implement a national strategic plan for the retention and recruitment of physician assistants of the Department of Veterans Affairs that includes the establishment and adoption of standards for the provision of competitive pay to physician assistants of the Department in comparison to the pay of physician assistants in the private sector.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF5A329A629746868ADBE66B41967FFB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the implementation of the national strategic plan under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H301CD404852F469BBE6BD3492B5E50BC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Extension of requirement for collection of fees for housing loans guaranteed by secretary of
 Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3729(b)(2) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4418E03CF50244068D5D39A043D2F22C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8E7F3DBBADBE4D72A884A89DBF4BCE62"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2024</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCF2F46A30CD4E759614D06653012A91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2024</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H177B5914CACF4C52A4A5611B836C6D98"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <subparagraph id="H934EFB28757046AA95355DD4F1CAC608"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2024</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F392378A32B4B3EA0C3E88D3D14BC21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2024</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E3425CB2D394578B7D424B1CD0BFF26"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H248ABD9B7B64445481DF014ED50550DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2024</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00425B901A644CD2A078A73869CC5B80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2024</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B1B4B43ACD44B6FBE1B7219C48C00DD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)—</text> <subparagraph id="HA3C2C611C1C84DCD8707D1AC08981234"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2024</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H435544C04AD443D9B91F14166A3DB9BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (ii), by striking <quote>September 30, 2024</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2024</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body> <endorsement display="yes"> <action-date>July 28, 2017</action-date> <action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement> </bill> 

