<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCA16AF351A724455AA8450646E97FECD" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 580 IH: Muhammad Ali Legacy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 580</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170113">January 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program to preserve the legacy and ideals of Muhammad Ali and promote global
			 respect, understanding, and communication, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA21F00D08C6A4811A74AA3D0228D2454" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE5DD1DB6EFAE41E096566EADA794D12C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Muhammad Ali Legacy Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H616ABD561D414B01A36E9710BEE4E4B2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text>
 <paragraph id="H490D9B80625A456DA38189188B876B56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to preserve the legacy and ideals of Muhammad Ali, who dedicated his life to fostering international friendship and to service to those in need, both in the United States and around the world;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4209794BD4A44D24B8805F240288F9C5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to promote global respect, understanding, and communication; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H48138AE650334CBFA5DBACDD1AED1995"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to foster the next generation of world leaders who will work toward these goals.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H0D78B90CF09A4D6894BC7CFDCE8D0ECF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Muhammad Ali legacy grant program</header>
 <subsection id="H782436720B7B422A841CD205B2C4AF03"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>The Secretary of State shall award grants, on such terms and conditions as the Secretary may determine, to one or more eligible organizations that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF08B1BC7E0E546D49893489A1E034767"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are established to promote global respect, understanding, and communication and to encourage character and leadership development worldwide; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4CC23FA66D334B9384D81C4B64264E48"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demonstrate a commitment to preserving the legacy of Muhammad Ali.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13DB54F5F1A841E2B4FE29A0D453AA9A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant agreement</header><text>Each organization awarded a grant under this section shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary of State. Each such agreement shall require the organization—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2F8CEFB65E9A4E4EA7802EAD2E22FC6A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to develop and provide educational programming to prepare prospective leaders in foreign countries to make a profound contribution to global society, including programming that includes peace building, conflict resolution, violence prevention, character education, and education about world cultures, religions, and languages;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7144B34756C24F6B936182D074810FF0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to act as a global gathering place—both online and in person—for negotiation and mediation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB03FA0CE58C44848A62C59AA4619B7D8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to utilize technology and the Internet to empower people in foreign countries, including adults, young people, educators, and civic, community, religious, and corporate leaders, to dialogue on common interests and concerns, share information, and engage in cross-cultural learning, including by utilizing diverse and multi-layered connections such as videoconferencing, Web-based forums, and other modes of communication;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H06DE5F98823F4310AEFE732625BEE65D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to partner with and build a network of organizations and schools already working with adults, young people, educators, and civic, community, religious, and corporate leaders, as well as the Department of State, to reach many people worldwide as quickly as possible;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35C514E913534FC6AA73F1546DEFD636"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to place a special emphasis on providing a positive, productive path for young people to combat the pull of radicalism, terrorist networks, and organized crime;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B5E084D5D2047CA8BF897CFC9CA1AC2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to support a Web site providing resources, in a variety of languages, to further the programs and activities described in paragraphs (1) through (5) by making such programs and activities accessible to the general public and able to be utilized by educators to integrate into the classroom; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6CF16B47D2D74D3596821922EE42C32B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to submit for each fiscal year for which the organization receives funds from a grant awarded under this section, a report to the Secretary of State that contains—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4291F78AB7ED4CC09700012F9FC30FFE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the programs and activities supported by the funding;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9507D9EFD3B842E7A46BFA78C4671A81"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the audited financial statement of the organization for the preceding fiscal year;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC3650177F984949805B78AF3F93846D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a plan for the programs and activities to be supported by the funding as the Secretary may require; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC95A0399A66647A9800B23E357C0CB38"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an evaluation of the programs and activities supported by the funding as the Secretary may require.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H125132154DAB4BC295D8E62695C393AA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible organization defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>eligible organization</term> means an organization that is exempt from tax under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">26 U.S.C. 501(c)(3)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD7AE8EDCC6C049919002AF66EF36C611"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $5,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2020.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


