<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFFF8ACC12DFD428F9550054E09089AFA" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4224 IH: Sustainable Fishing Workforce Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4224</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171102">November 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the temporary entry into the United States of alien crewmen employed on longline
			 fishing vessels originating in Hawaii, to ensure that such aliens receive
			 reasonable wages and working conditions, and to provide for appropriate
			 enforcement and oversight of fishing companies employing such aliens.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H002FA8D3C4E54690B18DBFEC541661EB" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7C11220CEF53408589A1C121192EABE7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sustainable Fishing Workforce Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE558DB37819C471A9B8FBA42DE9C4254"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF4BCBFB647F54F46903BB96529D6664C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Association of employers</header><text>The term <term>association of employers</term> means any nonprofit or membership association of owners, charterers, or managing operators of a longline fishing vessel, or the legal representative of any such individual or entity, that has its home port or an operating base in the State of Hawaii.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BFB498552A74340B4C69061DAF5037B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>D–3 nonimmigrant</header><text>The term <term>D–3 nonimmigrant</term> means a nonimmigrant described in section 101(a)(15)(D)(iii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 3(a)(2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB6B85C76B6354EE9BB8DE2C6400E5B07"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Employer</header><text>The term <term>employer</term> means the owner, charterer, or managing operator of a longline fishing vessel, or the legal representative of any such individual or entity, that has its home port or an operating base in the State of Hawaii.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE89FA4C721E54141ACE9ED1638882CC4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Longline fishing vessel</header><text>The term <term>longline fishing vessel</term> means a vessel which—</text> <subparagraph id="H84EA818CEA284D5AA8BCF0DA53138947"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is operating in accordance with section 8103(b)(2)(B) of title 46, United States Code;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE21C5A1D0E524D96AD05919FF15AF0CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has its home port or an operating base in the State of Hawaii; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F606CF6B7934882925B3D14B6407556"><enum>(C)</enum><text>uses pelagic longline (as defined in section 600.10 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations) in its fishing operations.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H15406EA04F44468C9A0545B457EAF261"><enum>3.</enum><header>Nonimmigrant visa for alien crewmen on fishing vessels operating out of Hawaii</header>
 <subsection id="HEA411B1AE55948D7A6FB938EE7E2FDFE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 101(a)(15)(D) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(D)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H56FD91A44F694A5090CF62FBA2B817B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H982611C9EDB24C90AF49ACC05EE3CD7B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9CB7CC7942AA42FBACC7CC12839C205B" style="OLC"> <clause id="HC2329E32A43E4376903FB23FE3DA0159" indent="up2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an alien crewman serving in good faith as such in any capacity required for normal operations and service aboard a longline fishing vessel having its home port or an operating base in Hawaii who intends to land temporarily in Hawaii solely in pursuit of work as a crewman and to depart from Hawaii with the vessel on which the crewman arrived or some other vessel or aircraft;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF3959F071E0F4D898D0527F71875E740"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of departures</header><text>In the administration of section 101(a)(15)(D) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by subsection (a), an alien crewman shall be considered to have departed from Hawaii, Guam, or the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands after leaving the territorial waters thereof, without regard to whether the alien arrives in a foreign state before returning to Hawaii, Guam, or the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFA419762679E461E973CF3A1D0E3BDB5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A visa issued to an alien crewman under section 101(a)(15)(D)(iii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA63EE201E8774C4182F910F2472EA95F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall remain in effect during the 3-year period beginning on the date on which the visa is issued by the Secretary of State; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8CB34D60DEA4B6DAB2395D8E666FCB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may be renewed for successive 3-year periods under the same terms and conditions applicable to the issuance of a new visa to a nonimmigrant under such section.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H26C654116C004469813466A2D72CFA2A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effect of termination of employment on visa status</header>
 <paragraph id="HA4A9495149BF47F49A91EAE0DC930ED5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided under paragraph (2), a D–3 nonimmigrant whose employment is lawfully terminated by his or her employer, or by an association of employers, before the end of the period described in subsection (c) shall depart the United States not later than 10 days after the effective date of such termination. The employer or association of employers, as applicable, shall pay for the cost of transportation and subsistence necessary to return the alien to his or her country of origin.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H286343ABADFE41F8B17B97951B9C2495"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Change in employment</header><text>An employer or association of employers may employ a D–3 nonimmigrant described in paragraph (1) or a D–3 nonimmigrant who amicably terminates employment with another employer if the employer or association—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4911CD101EEB4DAB999803021389661F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enters into a written agreement with the D–3 nonimmigrant that complies with the requirements under section 4; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70E6A2A605E54802BAC68E90991CAD77"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submits a copy of such agreement to the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Labor, and such State and local entities as may be required for compliance with State and local licensing and oversight of the employer.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2EF0E1ADE23B4258AC4249F6105FFDD5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Petition requirements and employer responsibilities</header>
			<subsection id="H3AD985D8835849DFB97B72008AA4E20E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Petition</header>
 <paragraph id="H668E690AEB804F2AB9B72CF11B93B018"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An employer or association of employers may not employ an alien crewman on a longline fishing vessel unless—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8E31A1514956485F8E2BBFD2711EB98C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the employer or association has filed a petition with the Secretary of State to employ the alien as a D–3 nonimmigrant on a longline fishing vessel; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EDADDC65FD34DB492C94A289395D7EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of State has approved the petition.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2981F542FE0741D49E6E9FAE2C532298"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form; contents</header><text>The petition required under paragraph (1) shall be in such form as determined by the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, and shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0DF54595A30D46ECA7AEFE4DAED1E460"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name, contact information, and mailing address of the place of business of—</text> <clause id="H17914407EC244EF8989A5F8C9FB39833"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the employer; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H326B38C7BE7743CEA13FF46B00366EA9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the petition is submitted by an association of employers, the employers that are members of the association;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2895D553D76549F59AE1852489009912"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an attestation that workers who will be issued visas under section 101(a)(15)(D)(iii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 3(a), are being employed in accordance with section 8103(b)(2)(B) of title 46, United States Code;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EECD4C4F73F49FD87D8E0C22E22DA63"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of visas sought by the employer or association of employers;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CF1B87403874C84B7634E036782A477"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the name, place of business, and description of services provided by any foreign third party engaged by the employer or association of employers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03870E72C0D041AEAC7352ED26D5AAEF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary of State deems necessary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4107220FF90C42AF80B38FA5A081374C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Visa issuance</header><text>Upon receipt of a completed petition from an employer pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary of State is authorized to issue the requested number of D–3 nonimmigrant visas to aliens to meet the employer’s need.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HB4A90A1F85834BDC888EF424B27975AA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Role of associations of employers</header>
 <subparagraph id="HCBED373CCF3441688266C8177383734C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Filing by associations of employers</header><text>A petition to employ an alien or aliens as D–3 nonimmigrants under this subsection may be filed by an association of employers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB30026110A8F442796CF5347849F4FCF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of associations acting as employers</header><text>If an association is a joint or sole employer of D–3 nonimmigrants, the visas issued pursuant to an approved petition submitted by the association under this subsection may be used for the certified job opportunities of any of its members and such workers may be transferred among its members.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AED6F15EA9A4841B0F7EE924FFD8C02"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Transitional visas</header>
 <subparagraph id="HECC7C27D031A42A28BF42DBC0CA76A2B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Employers or associations of employers shall petition the Secretary of State for temporary nonimmigrant visas for all alien crewmembers employed by the employer or association as of the date of the enactment of this Act. The Secretary of State shall issue such temporary visas to such alien crewmembers in accordance with this paragraph.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDBB5D7ABA6E4E66B69E89E40E6143F6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>National security reviews</header>
 <clause id="H8CADE750CB0C44F481B1D7BD213798A1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the presence of alien crewmembers for whom D–3 nonimmigrant visas are sought under this subsection does not pose a national security threat.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H96B0DE4956F34F4383193BAE7C6B493F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Evaluations</header><text>In evaluating the potential national security threat of alien crewmembers under this subparagraph, the Secretary may—</text>
 <subclause id="H2855291899A9427B9F08967C190B539A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>conduct individual or group interviews of alien crewmembers in Hawaii; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H42559AB40A2246B58DC650C03C6F4AB3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>take any other action the Secretary determines necessary to determine whether alien crewmembers pose a national security threat.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H5DEAB0F3982C49A6AFD63E0766657D9A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Action</header><text>If the Secretary determines that an alien crewmember poses a national security threat, the Secretary shall take appropriate action in accordance with Federal law.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFF08C55E147846AC802A95831264D81E"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Expeditious reviews</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct interviews and related evaluations under this subparagraph as expeditiously as possible to minimize the disruption to the commercial fishing workforce.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76EB884B45D04D32B9C44BB4DD830717"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Period of validity</header><text>Visas issued under subparagraph (A) shall be valid for the longer of—</text> <clause id="HCE3274240AE34620848161F2A101E679"><enum>(i)</enum><text>1 year; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8D8F54C6EA334A02B921B72B2AF2E2C7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the period beginning on the date of issuance and ending 90 days after the date on which the Secretary of State issues regulations or other written guidance relating to the issuance of visas to D–3 immigrants in accordance with section 101(a)(15)(D)(iii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 3(a).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6776DF84837D46698FAAF44ABAC902A8"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Petition</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the issuance of the regulations or other written guidance described in subparagraph (C)(ii) or within an alternate timeframe determined by the Secretary of State, employers and associations of employers shall petition for D–3 nonimmigrant visas for all of their alien crewmembers, including those who were issued temporary visas under subparagraph (A). Employers or associations of employers may not seek compensation or reimbursement from D–3 nonimmigrants for costs associated with applications for transitional visas or D–3 nonimmigrant visas.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4CA558B5BA9343328786468FDF3BA177"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Labor agreements</header>
 <paragraph id="HD717CC2DB7A849708F06782CC9D469E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Components</header><text>After the approval of a petition and the issuance of D–3 nonimmigrant visas, but before proceeding on a voyage of a longline fishing vessel, an employer or association of employers shall enter into a written agreement directly with each D–3 nonimmigrant, in accordance with section 10601 of title 46, United States Code, that describes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3114B270BAF040ACBCB2C2438C8BF595"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the responsibilities of, and costs to be covered by, the employer or association of employers during the contract period;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2896A27789DC447FB3C9C13442614A9D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the job duties to be performed and the expected work during the contract period;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H867192385FAA4E20B575D402A571DB0A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms of the wage, share, or other compensation the employer or association of employers will provide to the employee during the contract period;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB568C773C9A9416BBF9C2EE78652333D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the responsibility of the employer or association of employers—</text> <clause id="HEDB123F57C354BBD83F010278C395430"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to pay for or reimburse the employee in his or her first workweek for all visa, visa processing, border crossing, and other related fees (including those mandated by the Government) incurred by the employee, other than passport expenses or other charges primarily for the benefit of the employee;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD5A0FA9AB1E347DBB9B94C8707475BD8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to pay all recruitment costs; and</text> </clause><clause id="HFDCB0AF8C35544BB916BE3CF6A4E487E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to provide, or reimburse the employee for the costs of, transportation and subsistence to and from the United States;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53FE5422CC99442E88129B8B14958806"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the terms of payment and provision or reimbursement for transportation and subsistence costs from the United States if the worker is dismissed or otherwise fails to complete contract term;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2679E6EE7E4A4ED7B6BB26EBCD486FC7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the crewmember’s rights (with respect to occupational safety and health protections)—</text> <clause id="HB4602D52653A4F04B21DBA9FB9DFE762"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to freely report any labor, safety, or health abuses without fear of retaliation;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1E7CF5C4A24042CF846E6D923C2027B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to have access to remediation, as needed;</text> </clause><clause id="H2C578E3E7D7E4A698B31E7F6334D88C5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to free and timely access to their passports or other identity documents; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1ED0B857982143B980157E32AFB84B1E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to adequate living conditions aboard the vessel, including access to food, water, medical care, and other necessary provisions;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75EB2367034B40189F157E28F79AC10D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a summary of the remedies for violations of the terms of the labor agreement available to the employee in accordance with paragraph (2); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H017A542FCA9A4F189B7EC9C4DFF13470"><enum>(H)</enum><text>other agreed terms and conditions of employment.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H26A91099D18B4E88AC5A370A48979611"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement of agreements</header><text>Employers or associations of employers and D–3 nonimmigrants have the right to avail themselves of appropriate legal recourse in the United States, including voluntary arbitration, in the event of disputes arising due to nonperformance of any provision of an agreement.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HA230AE232F994402B1AD33A88F590482"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Language barriers and recordkeeping</header>
 <subparagraph id="H37616E0D5DA747EFA6AE7E81A2F8ED17"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Employers or associations of employers shall secure such language services as may be necessary to ensure that D–3 nonimmigrants understand the terms of the labor agreement described in subsection (b) that is presented to them before embarking on their first voyage on a longline fishing vessel and may not seek compensation or reimbursement from D–3 nonimmigrants for the provision of such services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F6ED5A916344AF8AF3C88940B80F3F0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Record retention requirements</header><text>A signed copy of each labor agreement shall be kept on file by the employer in English and in the language of the D–3 nonimmigrant. Copies of signed labor agreements shall be submitted to the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Labor, and such State and local entities as may be required for compliance with State and local licensing and oversight of the employer or association of employers.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EED06C81F84465FB930C47211859F7F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Recruitment costs and oversight</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7BD2889D712945F0A0D2EE8E7464F079"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Employee reimbursement</header><text>Employers or associations of employers shall pay or reimburse each D–3 nonimmigrant, in his or her first workweek, for all visa, visa processing, border crossing, and other related fees (including those mandated by the Government) incurred by the D–3 nonimmigrant, but are not required to reimburse D–3 nonimmigrants for passport expenses or other charges primarily for the benefit of the D–3 nonimmigrants.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB08E6FA910724F2690D945556D40C611"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other costs and oversight</header><text>Employers or associations of employers may engage agents or firms in the United States or elsewhere to recruit D–3 nonimmigrants only if the employer or association—</text>
 <clause id="HB2FE8351E90746F0AFE0C40A62418098"><enum>(i)</enum><text>solely assumes all costs associated with such recruitment services, including—</text> <subclause id="HA28D33D86FEB48F7A8031E110BE53C01"><enum>(I)</enum><text>fees for the employers’ attorneys and agents;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC89D862A8A9F457DA460FB211B653A84"><enum>(II)</enum><text>placement and referral fees; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HB9A5EE042566407DBDECE64FB253B34D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>other fees required to be paid directly to the third party providing recruitment services; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H1C1F3A23A81F4DD28DD406D823D296BD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>discloses the agents or firms used for such recruitment to the Secretary of State.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAFD54A5268844BA9AE4EF105617AC53"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Report on third-party recruitment practices</header> <clause id="H14AEE5A70E574D11854A2D9FEA94B43E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall review and evaluate the laws and business practices governing third-party recruitment of workers in Southeast Asian countries to determine whether third-party recruitment firms in such countries engage in—</text>
 <subclause id="HF31CE241344A4FF5A95D1B4B97F22441"><enum>(I)</enum><text>forced labor practices, including debt bondage; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="HF3866CDD755C461CB99E230A498B32E3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>practices that violate International Labour Organization standards or other relevant standards with respect to the recruitment of workers for jobs in the United States.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H8F71654A01624E049A83A27482565050"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall submit a report to Congress that—</text> <subclause id="H506D3B60EDB9428B8F1FCE74F2F6EA5C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>summarizes the findings of the review conducted pursuant to clause (i); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA36B4EF9F0754544A5115A3211774709"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may include—</text> <item id="H9AF4D9BB2E7447F693E10F2BFF33C5D0"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>suggested legislation or other recommendations for Congress and executive branch agencies; or</text>
 </item><item id="H860A6BE114464FB88050C42565EFBEA0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>recommendations for private sector businesses regarding best practices for avoiding third-party recruitment firms in countries that the Secretary determines allow for, or engage in, forced labor practices that violate international law or other relevant standards and practices.</text>
								</item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF7E09FCDFC0A4F80B4062D74A65F5DEE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Enforcement and oversight</header>
			<subsection id="H38D8997BE18347339D1D27AB57372B0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Examinations; referrals</header>
 <paragraph id="H04337D749AEC403EAAC4BA9227238FCD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commandant of the Coast Guard, in conjunction with the Secretary of Labor, shall ensure that employers operating vessels that employ D–3 nonimmigrants are subject to regular dockside examinations not less than biennially to ensure compliance with applicable laws and regulations affecting the safety and health of seamen, including D–3 nonimmigrants, aboard longline fishing vessels that have their home port or an operating base in Hawaii.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6238EF769D314F81857D0788C6B676FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional examinations</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, in conjunction with the Secretary of Labor—</text> <subparagraph id="HAEB6B328BABA4EEAAEC669C2A64B00DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may conduct additional examinations, as they consider necessary to ensure compliance with labor agreement terms and conditions or health and safety conditions; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8AF7C8C0AD44337994FCA3F1A0B0061"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall conduct additional examinations upon receipt of information from a D–3 nonimmigrant, or from such State or local entity as may be responsible for licensing and oversight of the employer, that an employer may be violating the requirements under this Act or applicable health and safety requirements.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC3B55175D3A54F42B1B90934193800AD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties for noncompliance</header><text>The Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Homeland Security are authorized to take such actions, including imposing appropriate penalties and seeking appropriate injunctive relief and specific performance of contractual obligations, as may be necessary to ensure employer compliance with the terms and conditions of employment required under this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H68EDBE4DB32E4E09A558A0D83D61E499"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Labor are authorized to issue such regulations and written guidance as may be necessary to carry out the activities required under this Act.</text>
 </section><section commented="no" id="H2028033CB78A4B7CB1BD3962419B69F3"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act.</text> </section></legis-body></bill> 

