<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H88791337DBCC4951821C5EC3475F040D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3756 IH: Medicare Advantage Quality Expansion Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3756</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170913">September 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to exclude MA quality rating bonuses for certain
			 new entrant Medicare Advantage plans from benchmark cap.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H58349B7AEF7748ADA22B3D3640531F44" style="OLC">
 <section id="idE01FF4173A1E4DC0B6C83F93084AB110" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicare Advantage Quality Expansion Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA14604152B0E48FFB2C430F7D6BFD4C7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>MA quality rating bonuses for certain new entrant plans excluded from benchmark cap</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1853 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-23">42 U.S.C. 1395w–23</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H525C0014538A412EAC92D881382F944F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (n) by amending paragraph (4) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D6A66B4A96B48E88E599C77A12E7AAC" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H30C468677AC841B398D6EC80353E7360"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cap on benchmark amount</header> <subparagraph id="H7D3B9CDB85354451B09E94529CF3E0C9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In no case shall the blended benchmark amount for an area for a year (determined, subject to subparagraph (B), taking into account subsection (o)) be greater than the applicable amount that would (but for the application of this subsection) be determined under subsection (k)(1) for the area for the year.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60205DBC9D4C4B34AC8622BD20D5410B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Quality rating bonuses applicable to certain new entrant plans not considered in blended benchmark
			 determination</header>
 <clause id="H3FFFF9132CAB4CE999CAAB1F5E18FF68"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (o) shall not be taken into account in determining the blended benchmark for purposes of subparagraph (A) in the case of any increase under such subsection applicable to a Medicare Advantage plan that is a new entrant plan, with respect to an area, as described in clause (ii).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2786BE8DBB4C4C6D881AE686E7AA106A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>New entrant plan</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), a Medicare Advantage plan is a new entrant plan, with respect to an area, if—</text>
 <subclause id="H83174B9E228E44CD896702562A2427DD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the plan is offered in such area beginning on or after January 1, 2018, by an organization or sponsor that did not offer a Medicare Advantage plan in such area during the 3-year period preceding January 1, 2018; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H20D8A020B95F43B3835336E4B31240C2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>as of the date the plan is first offered in such area, there was not any other Medicare Advantage plan being offered in the area that was a qualifying plan (as defined in paragraph (3)(A)).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9575A77DE1074916ABA30E10A59D1BFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (o), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H380371933188480BBFC756C43D7082C3" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HC8780D52156C4DFEA26382A86BF18B8E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Increase in case of certain new entrant plans made without regard to benchmark cap</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An increase under this subsection, with respect to a new entrant plan (as described in subsection (n)(4)(B)(ii)) for an area, shall be made to the applicable percentage determined under subsection (n)(2)(B) without regard to the limitation under subsection (n)(4)(A).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


