<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H809B3D60DD9F45A5833679B600DCC95B" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1370 RH: Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign Authorization Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 92</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1370</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–143, Part I]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170306">March 6, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HHM00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>May 22, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000132">Mr. Vela</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000625">Mr. Donovan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000184">Mrs. Noem</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>
			</action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>May 22, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HHM00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>May 22, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>The <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to
			 be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 6, 2017</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to issue
			 Department of Homeland Security-wide guidance and develop training
			 programs as part of the Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign, and
			 for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H5B7B180CF64B407283DFCCE7C7E6AC21" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC30DE9A793CC467F94BC85374F456E92" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign Authorization Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H126EE04AC80F45CE95D6D8863ABC001F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enhanced Department of Homeland Security coordination through the Blue Campaign</header> <subsection id="H2ECA6DF3F163413CAF768B2BF54F4B9E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle C of title IV of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/231">6 U.S.C. 231</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC22F483DD1824B14ACFA8B626B06A6E8" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
					<section id="H9D0AEAC14D6048F6B89AB6335E4FCB25"><enum>434.</enum><header>Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign</header>
 <subsection id="H7BF6CB208EA64BDD8FA0BEBEF2B94682"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized in the Department a campaign to be known as the <quote>Blue Campaign</quote>. As part of the Blue Campaign, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H74D8520B63DC43F08A3F07F755C4875D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>issue Department-wide guidance to appropriate personnel of the Department;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4547E09305674FB8A1F7394675C0B180"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop training programs for such personnel; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA68440F6A32C420EA9EBA98366CA8AFE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate departmental efforts, including training for such personnel.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6A6FA25CFFA4F93819F919B14B383EE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance and training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Blue Campaign shall provide guidance and training to appropriate personnel of the Department regarding the following:</text>
 <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H46EA91230F3E46649D27A3B2FC74F660"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Programs for such personnel, as well as Federal, State, and local law enforcement entities, to help identify instances of human trafficking and potential connections to terrorist activities, including along the borders of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9D45451C93F46D8A101F0867AC82BB5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Systematic and routine information sharing between and among the components of the Department and the National Network of Fusion Centers regarding individuals suspected or convicted of human trafficking and patterns and practices of human trafficking and potential connections to terrorist activities, including along the borders of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2CBB883FBAA740B08B3E66E131E87BA4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Techniques to identify suspected victims of trafficking along the borders of the United States.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB3DC0AEA3654FCABF0472785DB78E1D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Techniques specifically for Transportation Security Administration personnel to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA29F302299E346689928FC33C179A838"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify suspected victims of trafficking at airport security; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C7E190F6D2943DB894017EF0FBF0F02"><enum>(B)</enum><text>serve as a liaison and resource to aviation workers and the traveling public.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A05432A8EF9469D9702C2470BC2CE5A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Utilizing resources to educate partners and stakeholders and increase public awareness of human trafficking, such as indicator cards, fact sheets, pamphlets, posters, brochures, and radio and television campaigns.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E5AEAF898604F3D909D38F2B975629C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Leveraging partnerships with governmental, non-governmental, and private sector organizations at the State and local levels to raise public awareness of human trafficking and potential connections to terrorist activities, including along the borders of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC973C2BD09B4C3996D297DE694D2032"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any other activities determined necessary by the Secretary as part of the Blue Campaign.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9CEF30C380A641A59E47EEEE7E1EC11D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>human trafficking</quote> means an act or practice described in paragraph (9) or (10) of section 103 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1A8058150A4F473E9AAFC4CAF636498E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information technology systems</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that, consistent with the Department of Homeland Security-wide guidance required under subsection (a) of section 434 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (as added by subsection (a) of this section), information technology systems utilized within the Department to record and track information regarding individuals suspected or convicted of human trafficking (as such term is defined in such section 434) are integrated with each other.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H910F66A130814BC88535D455594BA119"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall report to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate on the status and effectiveness of the Blue Campaign.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H582E8D3B6DC54576A3736AB20B8B142D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $819,000 to carry out section 434 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by subsection (a) of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7C65C566D7494B13B66FF447E0ACC940"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 433 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD236E4FE5814CB49E0169509A2E3C67" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
					<toc changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" regeneration="no-regeneration" reported-display-style="italic">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 434. Department of Homeland Security Blue Campaign.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>May 22, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HHM00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc>
		<action-date>May 22, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>The <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to
			 be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


