<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H775FF32D3B3F47EC92E0751FED3D0CE1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3392 IH: Lake Bistineau Land Title Stability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3392</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170725">July 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000299">Mr. Johnson of Louisiana</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for stability of title to certain land in the State of Louisiana, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H66B5C08F7ADF43A08EE1462AE7B7622B" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAAED51120A6549F38EC14BDC0219B6C9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lake Bistineau Land Title Stability Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC6EC63CD785C46D4BBAD804D0D5EBB85"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header> <subsection id="HBB2C92C144B44539AAF4C49B8921BCD3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H974A11127AC34A988837FD3C8BD22D52"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on December 8, 1842, the Surveyor General approved an original survey of land in northern Louisiana, which included the land surrounding Lake Bistineau;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FD70CED4963436C99DEB12E4FBF12F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>under the equal footing doctrine, the State of Louisiana was entitled to the land underlying the navigable waters in place within the boundaries of the State as of the date on which the State joined the Union;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H259208C8CD6645029166234B4717818F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the State of Louisiana delineated the ownership of the land in the State based on the Original Survey;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DB3539B992A4E25ACC0B9DACB625D42"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in 1901, the State of Louisiana—</text> <subparagraph id="HEFFDF65D72CB4225A385A9B4FF20F527"><enum>(A)</enum><text>transferred more than 7,000 acres of land to the commissioners of the Bossier Levee District through Louisiana Act Number 89 of 1892; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0D97C8B4AE8428DBAD78C9E852D8DA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conducted a survey that followed the same path around Lake Bistineau as the path included in the Original Survey;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H744FC50417D54343B8FC705818AF15D9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in 1904, the Bossier Levee District subsequently conveyed the land described in paragraph (4)(A) to private ownership;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H513FAA4AC0274BAE95D2ACE42E179551"><enum>(6)</enum><text>parcels of the land described in paragraph (4)(A) were bought and sold in good faith based on the stability of the title to the land;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63168300D2834DB78B9A8DC4D308B2C2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>on September 16, 1967, the Bureau of Land Management submitted a resurvey of the land described in paragraph (4)(A) for S30–T16N–R10W and 2 adjacent islands, which presented a new line to represent what the Bureau of Land Management surveyors believed to be the contour of Lake Bistineau as of the date on which the State of Louisiana joined the Union;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H04405004BBA948A0B741B38045DBBAE5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>on January 15, 1969, the Bureau of Land Management approved the Resurvey;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDBC4498418E645FC894BE91025F106BF"><enum>(9)</enum><text>on February 27, 1969, notice of the filing of the Resurvey was filed in the Federal Register (34 Fed. Reg. 2677), but the Bureau of Land Management has presented no records of further notice provided to the affected landowners regarding—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H98707E05AF45463496A62A27972C37D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effects of the Resurvey; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97256161066A48398957A63F6A44E7B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the right of affected landowners to contest the Resurvey;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DD9D6C2F6904FDFA5738437BDB1336B"><enum>(10)</enum><text>on September 27, 2013, the Bureau of Land Management responded to an inquiry by certain owners of land subject to the Resurvey to inform the landowners that title to the land of the landowners would <quote>appear to be still vested in the United States</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H112CC46133F54F20BD38EE3A93B622A0"><enum>(11)</enum><text>there are estimated to be more than 200 acres of, and more than 50 residential homes located on, the land subject to the Resurvey.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4A40A89D37C248EFBA7A7DBE78D8E0F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to direct the Secretary of the Interior to issue a recordable disclaimer of interest of the United States in and to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0993A576ED67405592F9552842439356"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any land described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b) of section 4 that is located outside the record meander lines described in that subsection; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H13775D34A7DA476BB0CD5952C22423D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any omitted land.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA4149A2F5F8C40329D44D262A42C55D8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD6067E8FA2354AC49E6276B9EA4CB7DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Omitted land</header><text>The term <quote>omitted land</quote> means any land in S30–T16N–R10W, including adjacent islands and the meander lines of the water body, that was in place during the Original Survey, but that was not included in the Original Survey, regardless of whether the exclusion of the land was due to gross error in the Original Survey or fraud by any individual conducting the Original Survey.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6771E92E7E0949AC9C3079DEB63337E4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Original survey</header><text>The term <quote>Original Survey</quote> means the survey of land in northern Louisiana approved by the Surveyor General on December 8, 1842.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD27488ADB74846CC8FF5A154BBE13835"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Resurvey</header><text>The term <quote>Resurvey</quote> means the document entitled <quote>Dependent Re-Survey, Extension Survey and Survey of Two Islands, Sections 17, 29, and 30</quote>, which was completed on November 24, 1967, approved on January 15, 1969, and published in the Federal Register on February 27, 1969 (34 Fed. Reg. 2677).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H068CF7DC9D6F44E29018160BA909C179"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H9E6427E8B9E14597AD9B776CA0E37E8E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Legal status of Resurvey</header> <subsection id="HAE4744FCD0464264AD32F6F19B414CD4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Resurvey—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE0684BFA4AB44D26BDD4104767058C7E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall not be considered to be, or serve as, a gross error determination; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A70E6A2F38C4FBAA5B3A04DB5917E1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall have no legal force or effect on the ownership of the land described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0953DA8274A54094AC7B9B0A17455A5F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Meander lines</header><text>The meander lines in the Original Survey are definitive for purposes of determining title to—</text> <paragraph id="HB4C0C1EC18404C4ABF9A9E6C86804DE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the land in S30–T16N–R10W; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB56E4E72EED41869D3B81BC395E538D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the 2 islands adjacent to the land described in paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE98496E5EA10466A857EDC6337631CA8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disclaimer of interest</header> <paragraph id="HD66A6125FCFF435FB72E57B2973442F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall prepare a disclaimer of interest in which the United States disclaims any right, title, or interest of the United States in and to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEE6AC135A83B4E7E9E88A4485CD6EF92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any land described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b) that is located outside the recorded meander lines described in that subsection; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50D3A6C9A7E047A385BAB28D0E42ED60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any omitted land.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E99C0FB9C0041188CD062E8DB47A6BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Filing</header><text>The Secretary shall record the disclaimer of interest prepared under paragraph (1) in the appropriate local office in the State of Louisiana in which real property documents are recorded.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A1C88BB081E4CEB853842012663A481"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The disclaimer of interest filed under paragraph (2) shall include legal descriptions of the land subject to the disclaimer of interest using the lot or tract numbers included in the Resurvey.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


