<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H338445F815554A84AC2D600C71947BF6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4622 IH: Stop Underrides Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4622</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171212">December 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reduce the number of preventable deaths and injuries caused by underride crashes, to improve
			 motor carrier and passenger motor vehicle safety, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2AFF489828BE4AB696B60317B87F75B3" style="OLC">
 <section id="H72ABC80A026F455BB179ED92145E502E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Underrides Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2B9AE866BB834CBE8BD09F582107114D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purposes</header> <subsection id="H9327234E4FB84F148A5DF6DE6219ECE2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H14B8A198B40E43E7AAF53E27F3EC1DC7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Underride crashes involving passenger motor vehicles striking and traveling underneath a truck or trailer are a significant public health and safety threat.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H90A5156FA5C24E2E8267EF76035C4379"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration has reported that hundreds of preventable fatalities and life-threatening injuries have occurred as a result of underride crashes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE7731DA5F56E44FDA97348BC5961B455"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The National Transportation Safety Board has recommended the installation of rear, side, and front underride guards on tractor-trailers to improve passenger motor vehicle safety.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3D8B66BE63F24D2F837A2B8F6C25FA96"><enum>(4)</enum><text>This bill is introduced in the memory of the thousands of victims of underride crashes, including—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HAEAF5401524F44DCAD6C4CD485272AB3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Roya Christine Sadigh, AnnaLeah Karth, Mary Lydia Karth, Roderick Cota, Moonjohn Kim, Corey Moore, Gregg Williams, Guy Champ Crawford, Carl Hall, Michael Higginbotham, Sandra Maddamma, David Mathis, Mary Katherine Mathis, James Mooney, Christopher Weigl, Bill Zink, David Magnan, Jasen Swift, Samuel Sierra, Brittany McHargue, Christopher Samuel Padilla, and Edward Hall;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6C94ED10DBE647429DAEC29EF43DE82C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>those whose catastrophic injuries dramatically changed their lives, including Julie Magnan, Nancy Meuleners, Joshua Rojas, Maiv Yang, and Anita Plantage Bomgaars; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H46F3B40FE2F346649D31410B1E3BEDBA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>those whose precious lives were cut far too short as a result of preventable underride crashes.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB356B965BD0C4E91BEE366FD4483A2EE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is—</text>
 <paragraph id="H05B8C6F1F55448F6A6B0CC76C5D67935"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to reduce the number of preventable deaths and injuries caused by underride crashes; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF137CDD727184CCD9F2B6EB1EFF21B88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to improve motor carrier and passenger motor vehicle safety.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1097287508984AFCA09F49FD5B2F240C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 30102(a) of title 49 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF4700FA1DCA44C13BDA3A4E8C531F2A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (5), (6), (7), (8), (9), (10), (11), (12), and (13) as paragraphs (6), (7), (8), (9), (10), (11), (14), (19), and (21), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF7EC8A3AEB4446F84A463A1E8310EAB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D2DCB041AF44EF993D2457947449531" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HECEF941EE0944BC494BE5D828AAD457F"><enum>(5)</enum><text><term>front underride guard</term> means a device installed on or near the front of a motor vehicle that limits the distance that a vehicle struck in the rear by the vehicle with the device will slide under the front of the striking vehicle.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H75BFD1294F5B4E4DA79292C10A16D893"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (11), as redesignated, the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80B9438D9F2C4ABDB17DD58C4D092EE6" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H22D1E67277804ED5A6B2C207E2720657"><enum>(12)</enum><text><term>passenger motor vehicle</term> has the meaning given that term in section 32101.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H193E05103A0440A7BC927347F2B170CF"><enum>(13)</enum><text><term>rear underride guard</term> means a device installed on or near the rear of a motor vehicle that limits the distance that the front end of a vehicle striking the rear of the vehicle with the device will slide under the rear of the impacted vehicle.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DAEF7AB64C5481CBB401B135F6701D0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (14), as redesignated, the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H208E6674E465402789FBEB1CEACDF184" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H3BED0F275F264613944F85D79F14E8D1"><enum>(15)</enum><text><term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3470AF59EF9942F791F1854D53458081"><enum>(16)</enum><text><term>semi-trailer</term> means a trailer, other than a pole trailer, which is designed to rest upon, or be carried by, a motor vehicle.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DF4FD2BE8F64B8F81927B8454FBDE57"><enum>(17)</enum><text><term>side underride guard</term> means a device installed on or near the side of a motor vehicle that limits the distance that the front end of a vehicle striking the side of the vehicle with the device will slide under the side of the impacted vehicle.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BE7BAC9FA6F479899F7501D362932FB"><enum>(18)</enum><text><term>single unit truck</term> means a truck with a gross vehicle weight rating greater than 10,000 pounds (excluding any attached trailer).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A1B267590EF41C197D9DDD7C4EC2397"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (19), as redesignated, the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA9A3ECBAA1E41ED9316CEC752B208DB" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HA66FE2E0C5E74EDC8AC347B396C77904"><enum>(20)</enum><text><term>trailer</term> means a vehicle, with or without motive power, which is designed—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB3B18B66D7C443FB9DEE43027B638170"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to carry persons or property; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9BC1D55363A430499662A123C8F463D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to be drawn by a motor vehicle.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HD7746CC2A6284A2C8D4060A8F7F821A4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Underride guard rulemaking</header>
 <subsection id="HD622431983324104A291D2ABB28C5401"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/301">chapter 301</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC3CA3AF754A54AB8BC43FE6E403D9866" style="USC">
					<section id="H4227CD9E75C945E88B4119658B56A08A"><enum>30129.</enum><header>Underride guards</header>
						<subsection id="H5A7F3D78BCC84332BD0C3893AC6BB78E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rear underride guards</header>
 <paragraph id="H4594CD4AD6B0424A845DD47C8E795E87"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall issue a final rule to require the installation of rear underride guards that meet the performance standards described in paragraph (2) on all trailers, semi-trailers, and single unit trucks with a gross vehicle weight rating of more than 10,000 pounds that are manufactured on or after the effective date of the rule.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H188C496586884ADEA4F155ABF79F98B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Performance standards</header><text>A rear underride guard shall be considered to meet the performance standard referred to in paragraph (1) if a passenger motor vehicle traveling at 35 miles per hour is prevented, as verified through crash testing while attached to a trailer, from moving underneath the rear of a trailer, semi-trailer, or single unit truck on which the rear underride guard has been installed after—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2A19447CDFC84F46A4760844129836B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an impact in which the passenger vehicle impacts the center of the rear of the trailer, semi-trailer, or single unit truck;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECD1526CF3EE4147AAD4D0D1CF34E4E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an impact in which 50 percent the width of the passenger vehicle overlaps the rear of the trailer, semi-trailer, or single unit truck; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7807B6764EF24BE89771D582EBFB2ABD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an impact in which 30 percent of the width of the passenger vehicle overlaps the rear of the trailer, semi-trailer, or single unit truck.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80C29F3CC9054C90BE120805192F408C"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Retrofit requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall issue a final rule requiring the installation of rear underride guards described in paragraph (1) on all trailers, semi-trailers, and single unit trucks with a gross vehicle weight rating of more than 10,000 pounds that are manufactured before the effective date of the rule required by paragraph (1).</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H9A6B70C2804643819386B417919A2410"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compliance dates</header>
 <subparagraph id="HAB1B42362B074176BF37B2D4FEA38C8A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), compliance with each of the rules issued by the Secretary under paragraphs (1) and (3) shall be required beginning 1 year after the date on which the final rule is published in the Federal Register.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADB6996A766446BBB338EB788AD44FD3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Phase-in</header><text>The Secretary may permit a phase-in period (not to exceed 2 years) for the installation of rear underride guards on trailers, semi-trailers, and single unit trucks described in paragraph (3).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H11C98B62F10D4F95AB9C2907086B054F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Side underride guards</header>
 <paragraph id="H7A7B36DBF52B4993B4F549D17F612F6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall issue a final rule requiring the installation of side underride guards that meet the performance standards described in paragraph (3) on all trailers, semi-trailers, and single unit trucks with a gross vehicle rating of more than 10,000 pounds manufactured on or after the effective date of the rule.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2ECFB2737D4E45638CF62B714693A554"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Retrofit requirements</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall issue a final rule requiring all trailers, semi-trailers, and single unit trucks with a gross vehicle rating of more than 10,000 pounds manufactured before the effective date of the rule required by paragraph (1) to be equipped with side underride guards that meet the performance standards described in paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H49ADA787957A4FBE85E6618743D0B50A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Performance standards</header><text>A side underride guard meets the performance standards described in this paragraph if the side underride guard is able to prevent intrusion from the body or frame of a vehicle described in paragraph (1) into the passenger compartment of a passenger motor vehicle that contacts the guard while traveling 35 miles per hour at any angle between 10 degrees and 90 degrees.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H90CFCFC343E04B55963D2A645BC30A12"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compliance dates</header>
 <subparagraph id="H181B9C4C75144AF5A15B387CB857890E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), compliance with each of the rules issued by the Secretary under paragraphs (1) and (2) shall be required beginning on the date that is 1 year after the respective issuance date of each such rule.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3B68B0D8EA14C0A9AEF75B75D4192B2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Phase-in</header><text>The Secretary may permit a phase-in period, not to exceed 3 years, pursuant to paragraph (2) for the installation of side underride guards on trailers and semi-trailers described in that paragraph.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H22EA1EC27EE2414ABA797ACE37F145C8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Front underride guards</header>
 <paragraph id="H59BE1FFD251E4B8BA57AB7F3B14C88E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rule required</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall issue a final rule requiring all commercial motor vehicles with a gross vehicle weight rating of more than 10,000 pounds manufactured on or after the effective date of the rule to be equipped with front underride guards.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0BF730CBD544AB085C4F3B619922419"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H356F12C30848427DB2EB524C5A033CF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>complete research on equipping commercial motor vehicles with a gross weight rating of more than 10,000 pounds with a front underride guard to prevent trucks from overriding the passenger vehicle; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9A1C1FE6E044026B50D2B72B1346354"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure and Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report on the research described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0132EF56DAC34270AD090A8EF5C98A59"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Retrofit requirements</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall issue a rule requiring all commercial motor vehicles with a gross vehicle weight rating of more than 10,000 pounds to be equipped with a front underride guard.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H2E63A913CA7C47079462D8C3851E718A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compliance dates</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2C44803166624D11B3C94E55C8740F25"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), compliance with each of the rules issued by the Secretary under paragraphs (1) and (3) shall be required beginning on the date that is 1 year after the respective issuance date of each such rule.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAC50BE8C5B04110B88BB4FD1DEA8F96"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Phase-in</header><text>The Secretary may permit a phase-in period (not to exceed 3 years) pursuant to paragraph (3) for the installation of front underride guards on commercial motor vehicles.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1B7FED5574DC4A8EAB6254CAD1A43EEA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Maintenance requirements</header>
							<paragraph id="H7A3F12A9424B4CCDAC0EC718C57B0A84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Revised standard</header>
 <subparagraph id="H05A4581BA35C4D3A90E5491CE8A0AA0D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall require that the underride guard required under this section be maintained in safe and proper operating condition to maximize its effectiveness in saving lives.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0253CA03DF564A79A4DD9D6CFA9BC6D9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Periodic inspections</header><text>The Secretary shall require periodic inspections of the comprehensive underride protection system in trailers, semi-trailers, and single unit trucks to ensure that the guards are in safe and proper operating condition, including identification of any rust, corrosion, cracked welds, cracked or fractured vertical members, cuts, or tears in any underride guard to ensure the integrity of the guard.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB1C78A776B84CACAACC82E95ABB9C1D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect of inspection results</header>
 <clause id="H48D1CB40AADD4AD5A2FDAC5A2B78AEEC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Passing</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall—</text> <subclause id="HDFB44F84B4F747D99AF11F27AE2E1C15"><enum>(I)</enum><text>authorize motor vehicles that pass the inspection described in subparagraph (B) to display a Commercial Vehicle Safety Alliance Inspection Decal, which shall be valid for 3 months; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0AA22587532B49E28C4464277636464A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>permit the reinspection of motor vehicles.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HE8DC86D3B7D94FAA8253D4B47E9B5D7F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Not passing</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text>
 <subclause id="H160C05EB33244195A60500722287F864"><enum>(I)</enum><text>require that any motor vehicle that does not pass the inspection described in subparagraph (B) be issued an Out of Service violation and bear an Out of Service Vehicle sticker; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H864BA25AAA934F7D99E725439B8E1B02"><enum>(II)</enum><text>require the vehicle owner or lessor—</text> <item id="H6384D7AD687842E6A98D90346CA24E80"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>to pay a fine; and</text>
 </item><item id="H1C8995FC9B474945AA18C2A025C6FE40"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>to repair or replace equipment, as necessary, so that the comprehensive underride protection system is in safe and proper operating condition at all times before a driver may operate the vehicle.</text>
											</item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6543676BC879452F8F71404461F9FA4B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inspections and repairs</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3765FE268CA14EB7B26804E0C6DB5F01"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Post-accident inspections</header><text>To ensure that underride guards are maintained in safe and proper operating condition at all times, the Secretary shall require—</text>
 <clause id="HE54BF0A1EE9E4632A0B463D0EEDD2DE5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the inspection of underride guards immediately following a crash that impacts an underride guard; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3C4CB33CB4964F7292A35AF1F25765BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the owner or lessor of the vehicle involved in such crash to inspect and repair or replace the underride guard so that it is in safe and proper operating condition at all times before the vehicle is allowed to be driven.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H027C7A79B67046739069FF369C14D25A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Pre-trip inspections</header><text>The Secretary shall require drivers—</text> <clause id="H960D97F5DBC34FC9BE70F78D2BBE1052"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to conduct a pre-trip inspection of the comprehensive underride protection system of their trailer, semi-trailer, or single unit truck to identify any rust, corrosion, cracked welds, cracked or fractured vertical members, cuts and tears in any underride guard, and to ensure the dimensional integrity of such guards;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE07FD7A94E064755ACE4EBA34EFC6775"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to include the results of the inspection described in clause (i) in the driver vehicle inspection report; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD88DEEC822584896B15856A5F49AC6E7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to complete any necessary repairs to, or replacement of, the underride protection system before the vehicle is operated.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2E713ACAD2CB4E21B76B1B0EEE0512F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The chapter analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/301">chapter 301</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 30128 and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HE6DF0DA8D7FC4C80BC95652CDD9ED9A9" style="USC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">30128. Vehicle rollover prevention and crash mitigation.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">30129. Underride guards.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H51AE4CF91850481CA08C45FD5995683B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rulemakings</header><text>The Secretary shall amend—</text> <paragraph id="HEE4E339EED7848148BC997FDD74D7C2F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 396.17 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, and appendix G to subchapter B of chapter III of that title, in accordance with section 30129(d)(1)(B) of title 49, United States Code (as added by subsection (a));</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA99945E0DBD14A6CB6CCC1F376BE0471"><enum>(2)</enum><text>section 398.8 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, by revising Form MCS 64 in accordance with section 30129(d)(1)(C)(ii) of title 49, United States Code (as added by subsection (a));</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H53729CACC9684E808514D8B91ED0CF90"><enum>(3)</enum><text>section 396.11 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, in accordance with section 30129(d)(2)(B) of title 49, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC7BC64B686A4021AC67E8667C8DD56C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>appendix G to subchapter B of chapter III of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations—</text> <subparagraph id="HB7BE5638B0B048418675A167B54FE7C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs 6 through 14 as paragraphs 7 through 15, respectively; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AFAD125B7F4471D845EAA4FCBFECE7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph 5 the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H835D2DB303954D27B44A0E6477F354D9" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H50E451F8E4FB4F8898770C9F94514EE3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rear impact guards and rear end protection</header><text>Any trailer or semitrailer required under section 393.86 to be equipped with a rear impact guard or rear end protection—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF8B34D0AA7784B14BC6E5871B1E0C1CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that does not meet the requirements under section 393.86;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H863EC9F6DD1B4BE38B69AB20DACF0E7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is missing or has rust, corrosion, cracked welds, cracked or fractured vertical members, or cuts or tears in any underride guard component; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AEB8E44747E4DCB84E20E0AA01CACCF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for which the dimensional integrity of the guard or protection is compromised.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H31DEAC2FD8D54D9AA3B39851D276A47E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Research and periodic review of underride guard standards</header> <subsection id="HEBD5DDF965934D43A50459951A9336C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Request for Proposals</header><text>As soon as practicable, the Secretary of Transportation shall issue a Request for Proposals for the design of 2 high capacity rear underride barrier prototypes of a generic guard (with energy absorption and without energy absorption) to prevent underride crashes and protect motor vehicle passengers against severe injury at crash speeds of up to 65 miles per hour.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD32FCB72C331429C98E8F7E2C66A916C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H34C9AFEAC75545E2818A3F06EA4459E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluate the proposals received in response to the Request for Proposals issued pursuant to subsection (a); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4CE63BA63D774D59861ADF120AE50017"><enum>(2)</enum><text>update the underride guard standards under section 30129 of title 49, United States Code, as appropriate, to provide the best underride protection that is technologically feasible.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H12A47A7F84A64056B20DCDBDE5951069"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Periodic reviews</header>
 <paragraph id="HE6CE3607141845D988F87CB361AA48F4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the underride guard standards are updated pursuant to subsection (b)(2), and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H56CF2255A0B74A208E2264BA589EA113"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct a review of underride guard standards to evaluate the need for changes in response to advancements in technology; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D7E47D5B9874EE9A7A029743CE964E0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>update such standards accordingly.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C4F707D94734891A68AA6263B3C2DCC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>After each review conducted under this section, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure and Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report on the results of the review.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFA590B59E8F9467EAA54262FFF162895"><enum>6.</enum><header>Committee on Underride Protection</header>
 <subsection id="HC0574E4474E442D7B3C56FD4980F8DF2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation shall establish the Committee on Underride Protection (referred to in this section as the <quote>Committee</quote>) to oversee the ongoing underride rulemaking process.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4C62611D0C494FFF8A7612F0D01DE826"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Representation</header><text>The Committee shall be composed of—</text> <paragraph id="H2C1839DFB9894FED8375FD6E17611D69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>truck and trailer manufacturers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB8C335AD1F9C4F899029E164F3619867"><enum>(2)</enum><text>motor vehicle engineers, including technicians who work on motor vehicle safety improvements;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA2F8509A62E4C92AF3F4CD1A00AF809"><enum>(3)</enum><text>motor vehicle crash reconstructionists;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A56C56E5681423E848C360CECA1EAE8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>traffic safety organizations;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7F809136ED234B248F70010DFF28B6A6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>public health or injury prevention professionals; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H93F080FA45C44997957B4F524A0EA12D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>at least 2 people whose families have been impacted by an underride crash.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H40E9E4DBBD6447A8B79C76F9CB557F4D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Committee shall meet—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8D6ADA1A26DB4CA2957E3F95C3A869F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>until the final rules have been issued pursuant to section 30129 of title 49, United States Code, as added by section 4—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6CFD016E1E3D4E1FB59C947FF8148A39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>monthly, via conference call; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84F3CCB049F3475C9A0EF9BC4ECF132B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>quarterly, in person, at the Department of Transportation headquarters; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AC00A0AB99F446685E91978F6FF2832"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subsequent to the issuance of the final rules described in paragraph (1), annually, at the Department of Transportation headquarters, to assess the status of underride crash protection.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F49939A0E204CF88107076A4704F489"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Committee shall submit an annual report to the appropriate congressional committees that describes the progress made by the Secretary of Transportation in meeting the rulemaking deadlines set forth in section 30129 of title 49, United States Code, as added by section 4.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HF5EC78C6F56D433BBE87BD88C60AC113"><enum>7.</enum><header>Publication of victims of truck underride crashes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation shall—</text> <paragraph id="H9549D157E5DF4B47AC8FAB584EFAB153"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publish data on victims of truck underride crashes on a publicly accessible website; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C734D6B991540AC818504E141A3261E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">update the data described in paragraph (1) not less frequently than quarterly.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

