<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD7CE89CDF6A24D078977E56217BAB4E6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4151 IH: Smart Technology for Resilient, Efficient, Economic and Reliable Transportation in Cities and Communities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4151</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171026">October 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty of Connecticut</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote the use of smart technologies and systems in communities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE76F3B523E4D419FBD25E9076F9B432D" style="OLC">
		<section id="H533D002ECC27472C875303C743A0A610" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H6DA09C4BFDC249EFAAFF1BBE1012A9CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Smart Technology for Resilient, Efficient, Economic and Reliable Transportation in Cities and Communities Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STREET Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD875EEB8CEF04DECBBA4E204D78C4BEB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> <toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> <toc-entry idref="H533D002ECC27472C875303C743A0A610" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H1F9179E8F3704447862AA555008FF3CC" level="section">Sec. 2. Purpose.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H24E57CFC21FB4866AB30AC6745E35E76" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HE87ECDCA5A064325A68546E8B019453C" level="section">Sec. 4. Smart city and community transportation resource guide.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H08BFF31A956343C3BE484A94DB7CE819" level="section">Sec. 5. Smart Cities Challenge Grant Extension Program.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HFE35A8DFD09949BEAA74C0072060EC1D" level="section">Sec. 6. GAO study.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H5F39D6E577C2459794CF70571A30AA34" level="section">Sec. 7. Standards and interoperability framework.</toc-entry> </toc> </subsection></section><section id="H1F9179E8F3704447862AA555008FF3CC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to promote smart technologies and systems to reduce transportation costs, traffic congestion, air pollution, energy use, and carbon emissions for communities of all sizes by—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDFFB918C779A4B68BCD56E177D36821A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>creating a smart city and community transportation resource guide in order to increase equity;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DDF404D59A545B4AF54239E4EE6C129"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promoting the quality and performance of smart city or community transportation technologies while protecting—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1196DFC51CA44EC4B2CA512E03AED150"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the security of data and systems; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91200BC52BD94E9195BFB84AF59D3BD0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>privacy; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1328431258C84D0497077725FF9D29CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>providing assistance to local governments interested in implementing smart city or community transportation technologies.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H24E57CFC21FB4866AB30AC6745E35E76"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HA5821DA335C54E01AAD99F10CED0B688"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Data</header><text>The term <term>data</term> includes information and images.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9A6B82AF1DF14E2C83E028787E13AA9F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Medium-sized city</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>medium-sized city</term> means a beneficiary city with a population between 200,000 and 850,000, according to the Census Bureau’s most recent annual estimates of resident population.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE681370E6FC148828D07D839C2751C9C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rural area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rural area</term> means a beneficiary jurisdiction with a population between 10,000 and 75,000 people, not located within an urbanized area or cluster, according to the Census Bureau’s most recent annual estimates of resident population.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8924064AE714279B56B93B4B4047309"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretaries</header><text>The term <term>Secretaries</term> means the Secretary, acting in coordination with—</text> <subparagraph id="H251418CBCBF14D06B26BA68F0B95AD38"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Energy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E15B6920592436E887431F0120AB06F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB004EB201D944EC88ACB62A94ED4C502"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Director of the National Science Foundation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA7A33DB915D4C3FA48A1845B6041954"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE6BEBC7C0FA4454AA43C0677AAA7D5B2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Small city</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>small city</term> means a beneficiary city with a population between 75,000 and 200,000, according to the Census Bureau’s most recent annual estimates of resident population.</text>
			</paragraph><paragraph id="HEF7C09A89574472EB78E443C6CF400A5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Smart city or community</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD44C649A3CB74C28AB7A8A18E8280A47"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>smart city or community</term> means a community in which innovative, advanced, secure, and reliable information and communication technologies and related mechanisms are applied—</text>
 <clause id="H9DBE7D224BC143A4A282BFC0836971F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to improve the quality of life for residents;</text> </clause><clause id="H6DC6EE849BB048B185C859C0A7C39FCA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to reduce resource consumption by increasing the efficiency and cost effectiveness of civic operations and services;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H87FCA801D1014FB2B6C418D0728E4206"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to promote economic growth; and</text> </clause><clause id="H6E58BE5DFD954ADB9183C64797F2D913"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to create a community that is safer and more secure, sustainable, resilient, livable, and workable.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69780650A04F420C9C2B38884B7FD65D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>smart city or community</term> includes a local jurisdiction that—</text> <clause id="H7E186F45B4344316BF8E73291B88C929"><enum>(i)</enum><text>gathers and incorporates data from systems, devices, and sensors embedded in civic systems and infrastructure to improve the effectiveness and efficiency of civic operations and services;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3E85D7844E14447BBEBEF785906C5CA2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>aggregates and analyzes gathered data;</text> </clause><clause id="H7924C4FB7A97497F9954E0AE25DC6B6E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>communicates the analysis and data in a variety of formats;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2F16EBE1BC61457D8D37EC497658C3B2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>makes corresponding improvements to civic systems and services based on gathered data; and</text> </clause><clause id="H54AE9752E1F1495A8AAE4DEC26DBB25C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>integrates measures—</text>
 <subclause id="H78D2F80446314718A199312D4A807732"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to enhance the resilience of civic systems against cybersecurity threats and physical and social vulnerabilities and breaches;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9EE6E883E10D4B52AD8FD2E0D3CB671C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to protect the private data of residents; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H05B642D42A9A40F982894B1A22302749"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to measure the impact of smart city or community technologies on the effectiveness and efficiency of civic operations and services.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H14116FD426544256AE2314EED81B6371"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Smart transportation technologies and systems</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>smart transportation technologies and systems</term> means technology and systems that provide innovative services in multiple modes of transport and traffic management to enable users to be safer, better coordinated and connected, and better informed. Such systems may also provide data to cities to assist in making effective transportation policy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF81E5B4BE0147059B2FDFDE44FFF412"><enum>(9)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HC5FA3344550D4D51B92F1D3A971177FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7058FC1130F140C8B85BE9E9058B1A08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the District of Columbia;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B559597621B44E18A60C1B7B7719AD9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBC2CC1317654FD186B481F5146D8D35"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other territory or possession of the United States.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD701BCA423D1437EA3EE3FE84D711362"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Urban area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>urban area</term> means a census-designated urban area with a population of 50,000 residents or more.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HE87ECDCA5A064325A68546E8B019453C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Smart city and community transportation resource guide</header>
			<subsection id="H686127D06C674E829377C86474016CDC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Publication</header>
 <paragraph id="H8E7CF70753864E9EA9F240F2FE60EB40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretaries, in coordination with the heads of any other applicable Federal agencies, shall create, publish, and maintain a resource guide designed to assist States, communities, and cities in developing and implementing smart city or community programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E20F9ECC599430B87151DE0FD81BC97"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information included</header><text>The Secretaries, in coordination with representatives of States, cities, communities, and industry entities, shall determine what information shall be included in the guide described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9E54418D5FF2482CBF753C2427A14203"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The guide published under subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="H24D67317857E41FDA4A3AB14AE9BB82E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be maintained electronically on a website;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6DF7ACE0721459FB45F83A2EB978567"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be provided as an electronic reference guide available to the public free of charge; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9DE9347299A04A03B27EBDF368EEAFB0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H15FBFC0081394D2BBFB1D9DB15A48137"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">available examples of local governments engaging private sector entities in order to implement smart city or community solutions, including public-private partnership models, that could be used to leverage private sector funding and reduce transportation costs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC294DB17180544DA81A9B9E251BF9A3A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>best practices and lessons learned from technology demonstrations, including return on investment and performance information to help cities decide how to initiate integration of smart technologies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H887AD5749A2144829E93F90E12B0F4D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">voluntary, industry-led, international consensus standards and best practices, in collaboration with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, for safeguarding cybersecurity and appropriate data management and data privacy; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90D1E4A0B96241EDB468B33400AB09EB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such other topics as are determined to be necessary by the Secretaries.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBFF7788536A44D3C8693B6ADD822B4FC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Existing guides</header><text>In creating, publishing, and maintaining the guide under subsection (a), the Secretaries shall consider Federal guides published before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act relating to smart city or community goals, activities, and best practices—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB96EF3E5674C40D9A128795F41B4A58E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to prevent duplication of efforts by the Federal Government; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8176CB4059F6490AA8C2088C1AB05630"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to leverage existing complementary efforts.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H08BFF31A956343C3BE484A94DB7CE819"><enum>5.</enum><header>Smart Cities Challenge Grant Extension Program</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HFE1F17E74C7A40F6AA8CEC3C2E7B041B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall develop and implement an additional round to the Smart Cities Challenge under which the Secretary shall provide grants on a competitive basis to small- and medium-sized communities to implement smart transportation proposals.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6C6F5A980A7D461AB1ADAEE4A1473C9B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall be—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HFBD4BCA3A6D744A98F0E9AF07B2A60E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a State or local government;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H79079184D3134CF4B188BCEB94F23082"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a tribal government;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9C348872D8DD42519783BBDB55F160E0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a transit agency or authority;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBC3739D7D3C7424BA8A415BB48FD4960"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a public toll authority;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6EB21D91771840558C0C635E787AC308"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a metropolitan planning organization;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC1CC7B3822B4958A4A053A99613D67D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any other subdivision of a State or local government; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA110DC8DBF746F8855772A2691C40CE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a multijurisdictional group applying through a single lead applicant.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H0F17555248624B4898228AC160E757D6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An eligible entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at the time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. An eligible entity may only submit 1 application.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE1D3EE64D6D9413A8BB40CD577548368"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In selecting eligible entities to receive grants under this section, the Secretary shall prioritize applicants that—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H1A81678780DA4979B02A4720C27A02C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify transportation challenges and describe how smart transportation technologies and systems can address such challenges;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1A4CD09D612A42AD91A25E9348632C70"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine what technologies have the most potential to address the challenges identified;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4B2069146FFC4167A6AF5DD6252A72F2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify what data may be collected and analyzed using these technologies and how such data would be used to continue to address identified transportation challenges; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3C038E81D5C54B32868CA5DA2F18A314"><enum>(4)</enum><text>comply with any other requirements that the Secretary may identify.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6817A905B7F54C468C8222800B3E84D3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Non-Federal Share</header><text>The non-Federal share of the cost of a project for which a grant is awarded under this section shall be a minimum of 25 percent of the total cost.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H45560098FCE442FDB209EE149B0D66C7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Amount of Grants</header><text>The amount of a grant awarded under this section shall be a minimum of $20,000,000 and a maximum of $40,000,000. The total amount of funds awarded under this section shall not exceed $100,000,000 for one calendar year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9E53EEA6058B473780C8953764E26A14"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022. Additionally, the Secretary may reallocate unobligated funds to carry out this section.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HFE35A8DFD09949BEAA74C0072060EC1D"><enum>6.</enum><header>GAO study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study to identify—</text>
 <paragraph id="H51CE81CA6C5E4D09B566561A0C77A47F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>financial and procurement mechanisms currently available to public and private entities to fund smart city or community activities and associated demonstration projects, including <quote>pay for performance</quote> financing that could deliver measurable and verifiable market and non-market values to smart cities or communities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H68809B7C27E449418E79DC67E9EB8EDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>new, innovative financial and procurement mechanisms under development or used experimentally that may be available, in the near term, to public and private entities to fund smart city or community activities and associated demonstration projects;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCEBA20C4D5664F82AEDA10C7694CCEB2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>barriers to creative financing solutions for those activities and projects, including procurement barriers faced by State and local governments; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H84E77D2C24C147399085AB7FC80AF593"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ways to leverage private sector investments in smart cities and communities.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H5F39D6E577C2459794CF70571A30AA34"><enum>7.</enum><header>Standards and interoperability framework</header> <subsection id="H495EDDAEF88F4C339F49CAAB39017E70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Participation</header><text>To strengthen the public-private partnership approach to smart city- or community-related standards development and interoperability, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall strongly encourage and support participation by Federal Government experts in private sector-led standards-related activities that convene smart city or community stakeholders, including representatives of applicable Federal agencies.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5D8AB329738048D0BE40B127C485B6AA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>To promote innovation and economic competitiveness and to achieve interoperability of smart city or community devices and systems, while strengthening the United States approach to private sector-led standardization activities and the participation of Federal representatives under subsection (a), the Director, in consultation with private and public sector stakeholders, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1256187487BD49CD8A2544CA6C98BB44"><enum>(1)</enum><text>survey and review domestic and international smart city or community performance standards, existing architectures, applications, and deployments, and interoperability standards;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H492FA7CA08D243EBBF747A508D339D6F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make consensus-based recommendations—</text> <subparagraph id="H68A9C8B7189C431DB06FBAFDF543FDF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to identify gaps in the smart city or community performance standards and interoperability standards under paragraph (1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44D20E1C1AB342DA938342886064FB38"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to harmonize existing standards and deployment efforts and enable greater interoperability across smart city or community technologies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H015A801596144552BC708C9D3A66ABA2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to coordinate domestic and international performance standards and interoperability standards to promote uniform performance standards and interoperability standards worldwide, including with respect to the need for testing and demonstration; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7D598D693D9480C845DCA3AB4B4B08F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>for guidelines to enable interoperability in the collection, storage, ownership, and sharing of data;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H750522E726474901886B5F9EFCAA9529"><enum>(3)</enum><text>based on the recommendations under paragraph (2), develop a consensus-based framework that includes protocols and model standards for information management, including existing guidelines, best practices, and industry consensus standards;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H92666E9728694398BA3BBFDC15ECE4AB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensure that cybersecurity and privacy are core elements of the recommended standards and interoperability standards; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2A32A913C814FC4A6F12724E5E07BC7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>lead international coordination efforts to develop industry-led, technology-neutral, voluntary, consensus-based global smart city or community performance standards and interoperability standards.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


