<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7E3909EFB8CD476190A29828109B1A23" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2115 IH: Family Notification of Death in Custody or Life-Threatening Emergency Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2115</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170424">April 24, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To encourage State, local and tribal jurisdictions to implement and enforce appropriate and
			 time-sensitive procedures to notify the next-of-kin or designated person
			 upon the death or life-threatening emergency of an individual who is in
			 the custody of law enforcement.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5EEF35A5CE124553B75DA7EBBDD2C5F7" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA76898BC229346CD804B1FEED4A6885B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Family Notification of Death in Custody or Life-Threatening Emergency Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Wakiesha’s Law</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H148F9B9F87B5473FBF4D3684D2E7D1EE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To encourage State, local and tribal jurisdictions to implement and enforce appropriate and time-sensitive procedures to notify the next-of-kin or designated person upon the death or life-threatening emergency of an individual who is in the custody of law enforcement.</text>
		</section><section id="H894194CE3D5D4F87813BFC92D55633CA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Compliance and ineligibility</header>
			<subsection id="H50FDE25570714C7D973BB17AA2C3A095"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Compliance</header>
 <paragraph id="HD09161120C164B29A0B6F5345C21B5D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal law enforcement agencies</header><text>Each Federal law enforcement agency shall take such actions as may be necessary to ensure compliance with the requirements of sections 4 and 5.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9BAC13320654F768B12419C3161208E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>States and localities</header><text>For purposes of this section, a State or unit of local government is a noncompliant jurisdiction if that State or unit of local government does not establish, implement, or enforce a law, policy, or procedure to ensure compliance with the requirements of sections 4 and 5.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0CBD5D0F74364EABA598C1D95AEC8B56"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reduction of grant funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of this Act, a State shall be subject to a 10-percent reduction of the funds that would otherwise be allocated for the fiscal year to the State under subpart 1 of part E of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3750">42 U.S.C. 3750</external-xref> et seq.), whether characterized as the Edward Byrne Memorial State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance Programs, the Local Government Law Enforcement Block Grants Program, the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program, or otherwise, if during the prior fiscal year—</text>
 <paragraph id="H39A77497AC77409BA1ED2BAD43E1B3A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the State was a noncompliant jurisdiction; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE93816C082124E4BA9E0E1BBA9A2BA26"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a unit of local government was a noncompliant jurisdiction.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF195559277154DE090ED636CDAEA4521"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reallocation of funds</header><text>Amounts not allocated accordingly to a State for failure to fully comply with this Act shall be reallocated under that program to States that have complied with this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE1C84F5668204BE4ADB5DADD7ACA87FC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Information required upon arrest or detention</header>
 <subsection id="H7B01B86C225349BEA58C606E570DAFE3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual taken into the custody of a law enforcement agency, the agency shall, at the time of taking custody, including during an arrest, during or prior to booking or intake screening as a new commitment, in transfer from another institution, as a court return, as a return from a writ, or as a holdover, obtain basic identification information for the individual, including his or her name, date of birth, and last known address, as well as ensuring that the information is accurate and complete. The individual may not be placed into any correctional institution prior to the acquisition and confirmation of such information.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4D8632728E5F4CDFABB0E05EC137561C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Emergency notification information</header><text>The receiving institution or agency shall also obtain the name, relationship, and contact information, including mailing address and one or more phone numbers, of at least one person or next-of-kin to be notified in case of death or emergency. In all instances where counsel has entered appearance on the record as a representative for the individual, the attorney listed shall by default be listed as the designated emergency contact. The attorney contact shall be provided in addition to the contact or contacts provided by the individual.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDCE9CAEEFA8C4CBBA0891D75E7DEB1DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No use in proceedings</header><text>Under no circumstances may any information obtained for the purpose of identifying a next-of-kin or designated emergency contact be used in any criminal, civil or investigative proceeding against the individual.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE59045C9360142A59531C1135B28DC04"><enum>5.</enum><header>Notification by law enforcement of family with regard to death or life-threatening emergency
			 occurring to individual in custody</header>
 <subsection id="H68C61F451C0A4A338C75596D848D224D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Death notification minimum standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual who dies while in the custody of a law enforcement agency:</text> <paragraph id="H85EC84B4E30645B6845C0EE84B603A82"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Written notification plan</header><text>A law enforcement agency shall have a written notification plan in place identifying all designated staff members who are authorized, trained and prepared to deliver notification of death to the next-of-kin or designated contact in a professional and compassionate manner.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD77592859F1541ACAA201594AD5204A2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timeframe for notification</header><text>In the event an individual dies while in the custody of law enforcement, such notification shall be delivered not later than 3 hours after the declaration of death.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H40C0B8F4D8194FE7A705F5186E8A404E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Manner of notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To minimize confusion and trauma suffered by the family or designated contact of the deceased, reasonable efforts may be taken when practical to ensure that notification is provided in-person and in a private setting.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H168F7E4E112B4C97BADCAAF2F3CCA5A1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Information required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such notification shall include the official time of death, the cause of death (if determined) and all pertinent circumstances surrounding the death, including whether the individual’s death is under investigation and the reason for opening an investigation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H36A33E25E3534720A382733FA1E17F02"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Documentation of attempts</header><text>All notification attempts shall be documented and maintained within the custodial record, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H04BA2D98F6AA4C528F6BDB6E5F25F5FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the staff name and corresponding agency or department contact information for all those responsible for carrying out the notification;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4577011C483B4A2E940F75B9ADAEF05E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date and time of successful and unsuccessful contacts;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9740B30675A3404B86F24329ADEC39B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the names and contacts to which attempts were made, and any reason for failed or unsuccessful contact; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H093982E3488C4579B14DC8C43023545F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any incidents of unclaimed or rejected claims for the body or property of the deceased, including a detailed description of where any unclaimed bodies and property have been disposed of.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H159BD07883E54E4B88C8E28B3D31D471"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Autopsy notifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual who dies while in the custody of a law enforcement agency, if an autopsy of that individual is required:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC3E63ECC71FF40579ED8283455D4C54D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The next-of-kin or designated contacts shall be informed immediately upon any determination that an autopsy shall be performed, and such notification shall include the reason that the autopsy is being performed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71940CAEDF5D4D80A177DD9C13896CE7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Results reported</header><text>A copy of the autopsy report and results shall be made available to the next-of-kin or designated contact immediately upon completion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4EE77248E3374065B1293DDF80D87314"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Independent autopsy</header><text>The State and the next of kin shall have the opportunity to perform a separate autopsy.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8DEC3C0409EC4F4C994F00E1C518D52F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Life-Threatening emergency notification minimum standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any life-threatening event occurring to an individual in the custody of a law enforcement agency:</text>
 <paragraph id="H01B7093CAF194B92B40F1A4C8A19CB75"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Written notification plan</header><text>A law enforcement agency shall have a written notification plan in place identifying all designated staff members who are authorized, trained and prepared to deliver notification of a life-threatening event to the next-of-kin or designated contact in a professional and compassionate manner.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3EAE4118909040A0B3887EC69D52414E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timeframe for notification</header><text>Notice to the designated emergency contact shall be made as soon as practicable after the life-threatening event occurs, and, where practicable without delaying treatment, prior to any required medical procedure, but in any event, not later than any medical discharge or clearance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB70CA835B094DE78AA2DA9FAF7B98D9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Manner of notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To minimize confusion and trauma suffered by the family or designated contact of the individual who has suffered a life-threatening event, reasonable efforts may be taken when practical to ensure that notification is made in-person and in a private setting.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DA2804C17C243BE8819A57AA395131A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Information required</header><text>Such notification shall include details of the life-threatening event, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H567E869D3EE444EEB0EE6C1DB842BFEA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether the individual is incapacitated, unconscious, or unable to speak;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81DDF7AC73E64BC48EFCBBD3E79BD4BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the cause and nature of the life-threatening event;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H939FAC75EAC0419CB1A8382F461EE5A4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether any medical procedures or life-saving measures were performed in response to the life-threatening event; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC156C626246B4459B665DCED33B25B31"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether any medical followup is recommended and the nature of the recommended followup.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EF64546EF71463A8DBF01C38706F740"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Documentation of attempts</header><text>All notification attempts shall be documented and maintained within the custodial record, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB9A7534843FD4FF59D4E6544299486C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the staff name and corresponding agency or department contact information for all those responsible for carrying out the notification;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19F10FB24BC64249A2E1791F68F78CFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date and time of successful and unsuccessful contacts; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B63620A0475400FAC4B0EA6842FE383"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the names and contacts to which attempts were made, and any reason for failed or unsuccessful contact.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H980E632F5FBB4758990308EA4AE4D4E1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report to attorney general</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2(b) of the Death in Custody Reporting Act of 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/13727">42 U.S.C. 13727(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8000570D425E446D9BC8B548774F541B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC92905A642E74BF5B090F5713DBB0271"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H73D95D070447493E80AA9E335EBFDD88"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA63A15393904CA8A8C0A3FC2C2448E1" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H77BA3ABC6E5F47FFABEB9529A406D6CE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the date and time notification of death was provided to the next of kin or designated contact;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BEDB1B54B364A52A4AECC8045A58735"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the date and time of each unsuccessful notification attempt was made; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H49618C328E2043639491FABE4EBAF37D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a detailed description of where any unclaimed bodies and property have been disposed of, including the amount of time lapsed prior to taking such action.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H51F1D937E21B41169B62C30FC5EB9B51"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HF4597E89496E49598475B0165225394D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In custody of a law enforcement agency</header><text>The term <term>in the custody of a law enforcement agency</term> means, with regard to an individual, that the individual is detained, under arrest, or is in the process of being arrested, is en route to be incarcerated, or is incarcerated at a municipal or county jail, State prison, State-run boot camp prison, boot camp prison that is contracted out by the State, any State or local contract facility, or other local, tribal or State correctional facility, including a juvenile facility or a medical or mental health facility.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F9C232CD28D480695518484321A9575"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Custodial record</header><text>The term <term>custodial record</term> means the central file of an individual in custody.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFB8DE8B9ADB47E2A1F390251CFB55F8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Juvenile facility</header><text>The term <term>juvenile facility</term> includes juvenile or youth detention center, placement facility, group home or other State, private or contracted unit maintaining the custody of a youth under court order or law enforcement action.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H09CAA4CFD6224BB5B60211F7F0B7ED00"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Life-threatening</header><text>The term <term>life-threatening event</term> means a medical event, episode, condition, or accident—</text> <subparagraph id="HBF6080251B2B4D8BB16F8DCED10F9DD7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>where, without immediate treatment for the condition, death is eminent;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A41A4D025ED43BAA9EE4F4D054FE9AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>where hospitalization is required because of a serious, life-threatening medical or surgical condition that requires immediate treatment; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A839B62DB604F8D8E36461E653B27BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>where an individual is unconscious or incapacitated such that they are incapable of providing consent for medical treatment.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


