<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9E1DD3B169D74E0580B1D0990AC73213" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2831 IH: Maritime Security Coordination Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2831</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170608">June 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000625">Mr. Donovan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve the port and maritime security functions of the Department of Homeland Security, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1DDEC067DBF44A69BA0DB640D24A44BA" style="OLC">
 <section id="H25038E8DD8BE4389851C2D1D6BF91AB9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Maritime Security Coordination Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8B53D97FF1184F01B2E7D38EAF43E0FB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strategic plan to enhance the security of the international supply chain</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of section 201(g) of the Security and Accountability for Every Port Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/941">6 U.S.C. 941(g)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H694CC17E58304FB1A3478F82EE4BCB16" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H5B29DEB606D94B0D8B8481AEA4DC01DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this paragraph and every three years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains an update of the strategic plan required by subsection (a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HC62BE91D8D774B21B53217B697C6019D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Container Security Initiative</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (l) of section 205 of the Security and Accountability for Every Port Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/945">6 U.S.C. 945</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H61D6245C51694B9F98E766A5A6E1A3C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC"><enum-in-header>(1) I</enum-in-header>n general.</header-in-text>—Not later than September 30, 2007,</quote> and inserting <quote>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of the Border and Maritime Security Coordination Improvement Act,</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56A8ECEC84AA4BEFBECF0D946C2975DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) through (H) as paragraphs (1) through (8), respectively, and by moving the margins of such paragraphs (as so redesignated) two ems to the left; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H51468FDC371744CD92FB216A604D3388"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2).</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HCF5778787E92417FA93ED7D909A1B34C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Cyber at ports</header> <subsection id="HC456983EC82A46DDB740CDE6322CC87F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cybersecurity enhancements to maritime security activities</header><text>Subparagraph (B) of section 70112(a)(2) of title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8C37F0DE5EA24959855585D1F58E6028"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (i) through (iii) as clauses (ii) and (iv), respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H717ACE49270A439EAC1D6E2E8EC41F7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting before clause (ii) the following new clause:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC709971D769C443D831146FC8E137901" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H4FC9BBC6782143E597D47866D363A36E" indent="up2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall facilitate the sharing of information relating to cybersecurity risks and incidents (as such terms are defined in section 227 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/148">6 U.S.C. 148</external-xref>)) to address port-specific cybersecurity risks and incidents, which may include the establishment of a working group of members of such committees to address such port-specific cybersecurity risks and incidents;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE7FE4A4F6A746938552DE41ECC22AC1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Vulnerability assessments and security plans</header><text>Title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD17C04579D5A41869904B2541552F2F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C) of section 70102(b)(1), by inserting <quote>cybersecurity,</quote> after <quote>physical security,</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0E30E11374A4B50AE0A29AF55DFF01E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C) of section 70103(c)(3)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC5B589E9E8C548679A6CE4ADD445AFBC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (i), by inserting <quote>cybersecurity,</quote> after <quote>physical security,</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68ED917C0E2248ACBAF45A1253F24374"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E02E037619C4922BDA046230CCFF7B4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (v) as clause (vi); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E629F5724404FF18A334E9D9965EDDB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (iv) the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block id="H7AAFE124BEB54219A8B33CE847ABC456" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H3912B03D32DC42C68785A18C0D5BF9FD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>prevention, management, and response to cybersecurity risks and incidents (as such terms are defined in section 227 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/148">6 U.S.C. 148</external-xref>)); and</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H74B70162E93F402EBFB541DCFF83E6CB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Facility inspection intervals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subparagraph (D) of section 70103(c)(4) of title 46, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H48430E11C9E448E894AE88F5E7C1233B" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H8A45F5FDC2C442D2A5B6CA6FF9A81424"><enum>(D)</enum><text>subject to the availability of appropriations, verify the effectiveness of each such facility security plan periodically, but not less than one time per year without notice, and more frequently as determined necessary, in a risk based manner, with or without notice to the facility.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HBE8B102F524842DDBB8725A175BE7151"><enum>6.</enum><header>Recognition of other countries’ trusted shipper programs</header>
 <subsection id="HB0F798E569224DCEBBF82BFB770E36BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 218 of the Security and Accountability for Every Port Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/968">6 U.S.C. 968</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H9F02C9DF8D1B40D19392F56209A9E6BA" style="OLC">
 <section id="H069B8C8D4CE94816B4E82D1783101921"><enum>218.</enum><header>Recognition of other countries’ trusted shipper programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days before signing an arrangement between the United States and a foreign government providing for mutual recognition of supply chain security practices which might result in the utilization of benefits described in section 214, 215, or 216, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE664F55F7D23488ABEB5F29EDB3DDE4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>notify the appropriate congressional committees of the proposed terms of such arrangement; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEAA8426D70274C6B9D598C48D98639D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determine, in consultation with the Commissioner, that such foreign government’s supply chain security program provides comparable security as that provided by C–TPAT.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H59F8E8D088974C34949136C7A6AF7D25"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Security and Accountability for Every Port Act of 2006 is amended by amending the item relating to section 218 to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H679121E983FA4D2796E1A487990669D6" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 218. Recognition of other countries' trusted shipper programs.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="HF31AC960A92C469C81A0E6A82FA489CE"><enum>7.</enum><header>Updates of maritime operations coordination plan</header>
 <subsection id="HCDDC55865746452E9CC2DF5979AAD77F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle C of title IV of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/231">6 U.S.C. 231</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HF786C47183034F7892921E750E4ED8F2" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD980B152103F47348CE19089981D0564"><enum>434.</enum><header>Updates of maritime operations coordination plan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section and biennially thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a maritime operations coordination plan for the coordination and cooperation of maritime operations undertaken by components and offices of the Department with responsibility for maritime security missions. Such plan shall update the maritime operations coordination plan released by the Department in July 2011, and shall address the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H247C166EF58C4EF393783D83E77F8B4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Coordination of planning, integration of maritime operations, and development of joint maritime domain awareness efforts of any component or office of the Department with responsibility for maritime homeland security missions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9296D8D5A76E4C8E83A09AA3C0F942CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Maintaining effective information sharing and, as appropriate, intelligence integration, with Federal, State, and local officials and the private sector, regarding threats to maritime security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H75E0294A5BFC4F248992FBF72D91CB1D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Cooperation and coordination with other departments and agencies of the Federal Government, and State and local agencies, in the maritime environment, in support of maritime homeland security missions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E34969D231A4643A25C9A1EC34D0196"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Work conducted within the context of other national and Department maritime security strategic guidance.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB6FEF74FB53049A69C3C86F331516B2E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by adding after the item relating to section 433 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H3D0054BDEAEC4C059CB57A8767CEA7E5" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 434. Updates of maritime operations coordination plan.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="HBA18C9CE82344656B70EA17FBB939E39"><enum>8.</enum><header>Evaluation of Coast Guard Deployable Specialized Forces</header>
 <subsection id="H20538221807D4BC6997BEA224419352E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report that describes and assesses the state of the Coast Guard’s Deployable Specialized Forces (in this section referred to as the <quote>DSF</quote>). Such report shall include, at a minimum, the following elements:</text>
 <paragraph id="H442AC5848C8E40859F8AEE4DE6E2BF53"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For each of the past three fiscal years, and for each type of DSF, the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HE21FB7B7A5AF4C4C8FBF6D48CDA9C6EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A cost analysis, including training, operating, and travel costs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H919885F0A2F54E09A94BB08213C96999"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of personnel assigned.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E5E7E57ECE2411AAF23106DEC3E1337"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The total number of units.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB79037AB6EA340E9B510CA8936F27559"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The total number of operations conducted.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA42D4FCC841453781EE190ECF638BCB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The number of operations requested by each of the following:</text>
 <clause id="H53FA0557C7F049E190C76A9EDEA83590"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Coast Guard.</text> </clause><clause id="H73632844C1F8432AA5CFF5D91B89C7A3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Other components or offices of the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6B1C30720AF44FADA556A2781D916B09"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Other Federal departments or agencies.</text> </clause><clause id="H79C36A158F704C468A412416186E29E6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>State agencies.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H224F8654FE9A40C88A5F0244C640AA05"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Local agencies.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE6505E7CAB14092A29B5C6269293ADA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The number of operations fulfilled by the entities specified in subparagraph (E).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H413122EE86EA4346968786E5C4109CBC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An examination of alternative distributions of DSFs, including the feasibility, cost (including cost savings), and impact on mission capability of such distributions, including at a minimum the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H69FB38F615714743AA3454BA7C54D56F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Combining DSFs, primarily focused on counterdrug operations, under one centralized command.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H404BC33D48654B9992570F0D935083B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Distributing counter-terrorism and anti-terrorism capabilities to DSFs in each major United States port.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCAF42CAEB4DB461CB00E09DDDA710F1C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deployable Specialized Force defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>Deployable Specialized Force</quote> means a unit of the Coast Guard that serves as a quick reaction force designed to be deployed to handle counter-drug, counter-terrorism, and anti-terrorism operations or other maritime threats to the United States.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H1DE7C70457FE440CAB64602F239ADCC8"><enum>9.</enum><header>Cost benefit analysis of co-locating DHS assets</header>
 <subsection id="H1B3D6678301145A7A2756ED52911305C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any location in which U.S. Customs and Border Protection’s Office of Air and Marine Operations is based within 45 miles of locations where any other Department of Homeland Security agency also operates air and marine assets, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall conduct a cost-benefit analysis to consider the potential cost of and savings derived from co-locating aviation and maritime operational assets of the Office of Air and Marine Operations at facilities where other agencies of the Department operate such assets. In analyzing such potential cost savings achieved by sharing aviation and maritime facilities, such analysis shall consider, at a minimum, the following factors:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB65FF229501141EEBAF182BD58957340"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Potential enhanced cooperation derived from Department personnel being co-located.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1449A4F9F8734438B1199C7CDA0063C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Potential costs of, and savings derived through, shared maintenance and logistics facilities and activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FEEF4C01D3449798A5B53568742A910"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Joint use of base and facility infrastructure, such as runways, hangars, control towers, operations centers, piers and docks, boathouses, and fuel depots.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01E3BD62082B49FAA72A46B16E1A1E99"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Potential operational costs of co-locating aviation and maritime assets and personnel.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D49C84EC2A24E5EBAB9951C781FDDEA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Short-term moving costs required in order to co-locate facilities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4CF19F1C49EB4209BDEAF009C44F4280"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Acquisition and infrastructure costs for enlarging current facilities, as needed.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC97A27C9D8A04A6E8006F8BBD3182254"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report summarizing the results of the cost-benefit analysis required under subsection (a) and any planned actions based upon such results.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HA55B91470FC14D69A0DD9B58EDEC6051"><enum>10.</enum><header>Repeal of interagency operational centers for port security and secure systems of transportation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Sections 70107A and 70116 of title 46, United States Code, are repealed.</text> </section><section id="H22CACC146D4843B390ECAC4721E22852"><enum>11.</enum><header>Conforming and clerical amendments</header> <subsection id="H226911CFEF514D979E5E96D881F9EB41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following provisions of the Security and Accountability for Every Port Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/347">Public Law 109–347</external-xref>) are amended as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H04C8C13AC2584BC5AD03F21769F91C30"><enum>(1)</enum><text>By striking section 105.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7B9816FF28854010B916BB3D83288DF5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>By redesignating sections 106 and 107 as sections 105 and 106, respectively.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB17F8713EAF4B6AA77344DF5690B0B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>By striking section 108.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H674B26F397444E98AC9125C7765E3BAA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>By redesignating sections 109 and 110 as sections 107 and 108, respectively.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D41E3CA6F884BCAA05E7D43AAF98A5E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In section 121 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/921">6 U.S.C. 921</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H5A9474C1DEA643A995F5DED569576DFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsections (c), (d), and (e); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H407E09BBFB034A3483EF3A96BC5D98C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (f), (g), (h), and (i) as subsections (c), (d), (e), and (f), respectively.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA501356CFD624214A9E45CFD53F10265"><enum>(6)</enum><text>By striking sections 122 and 127 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/922">6 U.S.C. 922</external-xref> and 927).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB71D0B7FFE174B659D7DCD2B20466767"><enum>(7)</enum><text>By redesignating sections 123, 124, 125, 126, and 128 as sections 122, 123, 124, 125, and 126, respectively.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C38E3F06E2B480B8733AD76E62F7573"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In section 233 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/983">6 U.S.C. 983</external-xref>), by striking subsection (c).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H98096AE7175F4DBDBA8FC12C1C6D017F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>By striking section 235 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/984">6 U.S.C. 984</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A11C114BFA94B849F0CE7F64CE8B6D0"><enum>(10)</enum><text>By redesignating section 236 as section 235.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H89EEFFAAA9AD4D67895ABCFD5BB9521F"><enum>(11)</enum><text>By striking sections 701 and 708 (and the item relating to such section in the table of contents of such Act).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H80E28EA12B3B4D74B542ADC0A51FDAEF"><enum>(12)</enum><text>By redesignating sections 702, 703, 704, 705, 706, 707, and 709 as sections 701, 702, 703, 704, 705, 706, and 707, respectively.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0D454504203E4A5BBD70DF51C26395B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header>
 <paragraph id="H24D94B7B78534E1683A6095551D70AB9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Security and Accountability for Every Port Act of 2006</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents of the Security and Accountability for Every Port Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/347">Public Law 109–347</external-xref>) is amended as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5A6F47AB060544A89B3F37F225F23CA4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In the list of items relating to subtitle A of title I, by striking the items relating to sections 105 through 110 and inserting the following new items:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F0E48A9C5CB4FC9976651CEA2BFEF3D" style="OLC">
							<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
								<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 105. Prohibition of issuance of transportation security cards to persons convicted of certain
			 felonies.</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 106. Long-range vessel tracking.</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 107. Notice of arrival for foreign vessels on the Outer Continental Shelf.</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 108. Enhanced crewmember identification.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDDD0F0BA63E46E095878EDC39727E9B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the list of items relating to subtitle C of title I, by striking the items relating to sections 122 through 128 and inserting the following new items:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33F2057C26E0408FBA29994880EC9517" style="OLC">
							<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
								<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 122. Random searches of containers.</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 123. Work stoppages and employee-employer disputes.</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 124. Threat assessment screening of port truck drivers.</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 125. Border Patrol unit for United States Virgin Islands.</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 126. Center of Excellence for Maritime Domain Awareness.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65A11AE95ECF4806ACBD48FB555C63FA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>In the list of items relating to subtitle C of title II, by striking the items relating to sections 235 and 236 and inserting the following new item:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB3917FBDA4174A3BAB1A8CC18D810836" style="OLC">
							<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
								<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 235. Information sharing relating to supply chain security cooperation.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3067961126C04A718414DB770A380525"><enum>(D)</enum><text>In the list of items relating to title VII, by striking the items relating to sections 701 through 709 and inserting the following new items:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H457E8B8E70AC4AA59E6A2EE4640EBC56" style="OLC">
							<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
								<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 701. Disclosures regarding homeland security grants.</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 702. Trucking security.</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 703. Air and Marine Operations of the Northern Border Air Wing.</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 704. Phaseout of vessels supporting oil and gas development.</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 705. Coast Guard property in Portland, Maine.</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 706. Methamphetamine and methamphetamine precursor chemicals.</toc-entry>
								<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 707. Protection of health and safety during disasters.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CE4997E4FEB4BF8BCF58DAAA757213B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Title 46</header><text>In the list of items relating to the analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/701">chapter 701</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, by striking the items relating to sections 70107A and 70116.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


