<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H589E6967E244482D873AE73132D222AF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2544 IH: Teacher Health and Wellness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2544</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170518">May 18, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Director of the National Institutes of Health to carry out a study to add to the
			 scientific knowledge on reducing teacher stress and increasing teacher
			 retention and well-being, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA0E6E10357F743BD9EB1FC750678A408" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9FFDDED8BB56493CB67C49989025F27E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Teacher Health and Wellness Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H38A411C3730848C8834D86D9CF06E4C5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD2504A7982DB4E9A9DADEB94B8BE0476"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">High levels of stress are adversely affecting teachers’ health. Teachers with high levels of stress are less effective in raising student achievement than their healthier peers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE434774E563149F38A5CEFFBB45EB4EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Elementary school teachers who have greater stress and show more symptoms of depression create classroom environments that are less conducive to learning.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H09120E6F9EB04807937E654410421505"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Stress is contributing to the high turnover rate among teachers, which causes instability for students and communities. This leads to higher costs for school districts to train new teachers and hinders students’ academic success.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A889DD2B3F6494E98480C21658BC450"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">School organization, low job autonomy, and a lack of ability to access teacher leadership opportunities are main sources of teacher stress. If teachers are unable to manage their stress levels, this leads to lower level teacher instruction, which then impacts student well-being.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE449E5B1F4343C4AC2280CF753388D3"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">High teacher turnover brings down students’ math and language arts scores.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0772E4A7B3D6467EBA16A2573FD75544"><enum>(6)</enum><text>According to a 2014 Gallup survey, 46 percent of teachers experience high daily stress during the school year. This percentage is tied for the highest rate of high daily stress among occupations and is a significant increase from teacher stress levels in 1985.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B1B6C5966524088818785BA9F19E404"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Stress affects the health and well-being of teachers. In a study of high school teachers, 46 percent of teachers were diagnosed with excessive daytime sleepiness and 51 percent with poor sleep quality, which compromises health quality of life and teaching performance.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HFE0C43FAE7F744DC80811E2754FA9AC7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on reducing teacher stress and increasing teacher retention and well-being</header>
 <subsection id="HDA8274130395403CA9D60C350AC43340"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institutes of Health shall carry out a five-year study on reducing teacher stress and increasing teacher retention and well-being by implementing and analyzing the results of any of the following programs:</text>
 <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H720693F591674342BDAF9F6AEAA6E8DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Workplace wellness programs that are designed to improve teacher health, attendance, and engagement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B6B2499507D4DE489877EACEE8210AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Social emotional learning programs that help teachers improve student engagement in the classroom.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H39AB04D01B9B49A1A8817CDB5B7C46DD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Teacher stress management programs that improve teacher performance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF98EE9B3195F4FA09F3BA094BDC501FF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mentoring and induction programs during the school year and teacher pre-service that improve teacher well-being.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9291C7A1B17B4A7A8D53FE70ADB8D648"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Organizational interventions such as principal training programs that reduce stress through supervisor/peer support and increasing opportunities for teachers to participate in professional learning communities, teacher leadership positions, and decision making regarding school interventions and management.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F6FFF040A8D4997871217FE86A8EBA5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Teacher residency programs that provide mental health and psychological support.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2D5903D2F3F498ABB89A9BF118FB6DE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Complementary health approaches, such as mindfulness meditation, that improve teacher performance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2CC43ED96CF642CD99F562176C7A63A9"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">School reorganization that creates the conditions to facilitate the transmission and sharing of knowledge among teachers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H459EA60437514FFAB3917F4F38C056CE"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other innovative evidence-based approaches that reduce stress and increase well-being in the teaching profession, which may include increased compensation.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC6930DE2FA643F2908FCEEE052C6572"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <paragraph id="H9A6739391FF5425197997D19D8A81004"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the end of the study carried out under subsection (a), the Director shall submit to the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9AA143B8C5624B7780429E80DE4E0A0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of the study carried out under subsection (a); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEACAC43CC6D84B8883E31BDB8FA90F56"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for—</text>
 <clause id="HE826F61769C34FFAAB2A2A6E05A5487E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>decreasing teacher stress and increasing teacher retention and well-being; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H18DC86D5CA5D4C9FAC45E86A41066B6B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>lowering stress-related health care costs for teachers.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H58925D9A77E144DB99C64C381B4D8AF2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The Director shall make publicly available the report submitted under paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6D21E0806BC64D10977BDF165ABC63D3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H3A0F2B02C042429FB686803C2E49345C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Complementary health approach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>complementary health approach</quote> includes integrative health care, adjunctive health care, and functional medicine.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBEA8A0B515BE40BE947F6E9678225FF2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the National Institutes of Health.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCCB8F25379F14B95A0897CD342207616"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BDF9985BD3B4F4F86F17C1ACD353F56"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State educational agency</header><text>The term <quote>State educational agency</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2FCAD30333C44C2584839EBCC677131D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No additional funds authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this Act. Such requirements shall be carried out using amounts otherwise authorized.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


