<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H59182C4E5E104BC8930B860F895D898A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3748 IH: Medicare Buy-In and Health Care Stabilization Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3748</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170912">September 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001200">Mr. McEachin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000523">Mr. Price of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000390">Mr. Kihuen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for an option for individuals who are
			 ages 50 to 64 to buy into Medicare, to provide for health insurance market
			 stabilization, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H02E16CC59056466FB802DFDA649059B1" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF6A06E34B08747C895E58DE58EF64DE1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicare Buy-In and Health Care Stabilization Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE04BEBAE44074A1E9A7643AEFCE84C8C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Medicare buy-in option</header> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB5482E333BA4889B98799F11D984380"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395c">42 U.S.C. 1395c</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD4C8CD8B3234957A20F9BC0DC9E81A0" style="traditional">
					<section id="H69C9BFB4452E41798CDF4A0EBE505F91"><enum>1899C.</enum><header>Medicare buy-in option </header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF4631593353C4AD6BB5A53EE2F557246"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Option</header>
 <paragraph id="H644D258A427B471EAE36AF1F4D130FFB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every individual who meets the requirements described in paragraph (3) shall be eligible to enroll under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E7D14B15B704FC8BBC9814530C111A0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An individual who meets the following requirements is eligible to enroll under this section:</text> <subparagraph id="H9F0CDA3AEEB14E5EA5BBF979550D6F9B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Age</header><text>The individual has attained 50 years of age, but has not attained 65 years of age.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8173A74832CF46D5835D1F178D41DAAF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Medicare eligibility (but for age)</header><text>The individual is not otherwise entitled to benefits under part A or eligible to enroll under part A or part B but would be eligible for benefits under part A or part B if the individual were 65 years of age.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H77DC6C288A064549ADC307AF582C0234"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual enrolled under this section is entitled to the same benefits under this title as an individual who is entitled to benefits under part A and enrolled under parts B and D.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H59972D561E4F450BAF1E27BC030356AA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enrollment and coverage periods</header><text>The Secretary shall establish enrollment and coverage periods for individuals who enroll under this section. Such periods shall be established in coordination with the enrollment and coverage periods for plans offered under an Exchange established under title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act. The Secretary shall establish such periods so that coverage under this section shall first begin on January 1 of the first year beginning at least one year after the date of the enactment of this section.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H5FB584BDDE8F4976BC3D9F66F84FFD1C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Buy-In premium</header>
 <paragraph id="H1AC5FC85B5A048DB8816746A7C9BDE84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amount of monthly premiums</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall (beginning for the first year that begins more than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section), during September of the preceding year, determine a monthly premium for individuals enrolled under this section. Such monthly premium shall be equal to <fraction>1/12</fraction> of the annual premium computed under paragraph (2)(B), which shall apply with respect to coverage provided under this section for any month in such year.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HE31516C9F31C4C01AD54BF469B81BE61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual premium</header>
 <subparagraph id="H4CC901E327174C1FB7A8883B17FF99A5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Combined National, per capita average for parts A, B, and D benefits</header><text>The Secretary shall estimate the average, annual per capita amount for benefits and administrative expenses that will be payable under parts A, B, and D in the year for all individuals enrolled under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1EE6D04E3174D9CBC1D4DAE226A46DF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Annual premium</header><text>The annual premium under this subsection for months in a year is equal to the average, annual per capita amount estimated under subparagraph (A) for the year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6ED7B7703F564BEEBFBC0E21E656EB38"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Adjustments</header><text>The Secretary shall adjust the annual premium under this subsection as necessary—</text> <clause id="H468B10CD73D4448BA98857386F37F04D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to ensure that expenditures under this title for any year are not increased by reason of this section; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA47760A93980404586F8340F31E31611"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by a geographic adjustment factor to address regional affordability concerns.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E3AEE1F89324A09BDCB1F77ABE0215A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional premium for certain D plans</header><text>Nothing in this section shall preclude an individual from choosing a prescription drug plan which requires the individual to pay an additional amount (because of the inclusion of supplemental prescription drug benefits or because the plan is a more expensive plan, pursuant to section 1860D–13(a)(1)). In such case, the monthly premium under paragraph (1) shall be increased with respect to such individual.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB6A95D92627A4CD6B7A5918F0B37054C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Payment of premiums</header>
							<paragraph id="H40F8BDCEE7FF4F32852A5C53B23C6509"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payment</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA2740B50E7DA4DA89BD75F78F729972E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Premiums for enrollment under this section shall be paid to the Secretary at such times, and in such manner, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7F4448C2CF954AEFB3E018BB8504A67A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Payment of premiums by employers on behalf of employees</header><text>An employer of an individual who enrolls under this section may make payments for the premiums for such enrollment on behalf of such individual pursuant to a process established by the Secretary. Such process shall ensure that enrollment under this section is the choice of the individual and not the employer.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC42904178DF54D0AA423E8E8EEF46431"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deposit</header><text>Amounts collected by the Secretary under this section shall be deposited in the Medicare Buy-In Trust Fund established under subsection (e).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H24031174044D4F9690F8069C901CA9E1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Medicare Buy-In Trust Fund</header>
							<paragraph commented="no" id="H430466281FC84F499E8D678F01359FF5">
								<enum>(1)</enum>
								<header>In general</header>
 <text>There is hereby created on the books of the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the <quote>Medicare Buy-In Trust Fund</quote> (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Trust Fund</quote>). The Trust Fund shall consist of such gifts and bequests as may be made as provided in section 201(i)(1) and such amounts as may be deposited in, or appropriated to, such fund as provided in this title.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H65BDF37C12C64FF093729F18DC2F74D3">
								<enum>(2)</enum>
								<header>Premiums</header>
 <text>Premiums collected under subsection (d) shall be transferred to the Trust Fund.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H13EEFD2B541544D7897F1978E019D2A2"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Incorporation of Provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (b) through (i) of section 1841 shall apply with respect to the Trust Fund and this title in the same manner as they apply with respect to the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund and part B, respectively, except that in applying such section 1841, any reference in such section to <quote>this part</quote> shall be construed to be a reference to this section and any reference in section 1841(h) to section 1840(d) and in section 1841(i) to sections 1840(b)(1) and 1842(g) are deemed to be references to comparable authority exercised under this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HEC30B1ED997F4E79928DBF7E13156DCF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall affect the benefits or eligibility under this title of individuals who would otherwise be entitled to or eligible for benefits under this title or title XIX, or both.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H05CF4EDB26C64A788C38F4F5F700585D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Treatment in relation to the Affordable Care Act</header>
 <paragraph id="HA876463781A943AC908CB42773822FDF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Satisfaction of individual mandate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of applying <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5000A">section 5000A</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, the coverage provided through enrollment under this section constitutes minimum essential coverage under subsection (f)(1)(A)(i) of such section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4171D04624FC436AAE70A46F2704045B"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligibility for premium assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coverage provided through enrollment under this section—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE439588FBB64DB8AEE17402D642ADB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be treated as coverage under a qualified health plan in the individual market enrolled in through the Exchange where the individual resides for all purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 other than subsection (c)(2)(B) thereof; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7DB9DA65ACA46E98779784A7D6BC24E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be treated as eligibility for other minimum essential coverage for purposes of subsection (c)(2)(B) of such section 36B.</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The Secretary shall determine the applicable second lowest cost silver plan which shall apply to
			 coverage provided through enrollment under this section for purposes of
 section 36B of such Code.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5DBFA0E4E0DC4825B2244F8D3405FAFD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligibility for cost-sharing subsidies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of applying section 1402 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC5310727014B4E5CAC50749B1F1A64E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coverage provided through enrollment under this part and parts B and D pursuant to this section shall be treated as coverage under a qualified health plan in the silver level of coverage in the individual market offered through an Exchange; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F10004D155142A0A8FEEF8BAA3BCB0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary shall be treated as the issuer of such plan.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9C1A8B664874AFCBBED0A65FA4B9C89"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of Exchanges</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coverage provided through enrollment under this section shall be deemed to be coverage under a qualified health plan for purposes of section 1311(d)(4)(C) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and shall be made available for enrollment, information comparison, and otherwise as such a plan through any Internet website maintained by an Exchange established under title I of such Act (as described in such section).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B6FC24216F14DADA3F9C046945B0785"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Access to Medigap</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coverage provided through medicare supplemental policies certified under section 1882 shall be made available to individuals eligible for enrollment pursuant to this section for enrollment, information, comparison, and otherwise as such a policy through any Internet website described in paragraph (4).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB45BF8DC940241EEA1A60BDD3D3EC22F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established an advisory committee to be known as the <quote>Medicare Buy In Oversight Board</quote> to monitor and oversee the implementation of this section, including the experience of the individuals enrolling under this section. The Medicare Buy In Oversight Board shall make periodic recommendations for the continual improvement of the implementation of this section as well as the relationship of enrollment under this section to other health care programs.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H99121C048E8D4F28A1088D21FD465A9D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Outreach and enrollment</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D6F7888619A4E7EBABB33F22BD3309F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period that begins on January 1, 2018, and ends on December 31, 2020, the Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities for the following purposes:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2A6117F79FFE4AF2AE2D68AAA3EF8E17"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Outreach and enrollment</header><text>To carry out outreach, public education activities, and enrollment activities to raise awareness of the availability of, and encourage, enrollment under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC5C2B821C7EF45EFB471209AD052821E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assisting individuals transition under this section</header><text>To provide assistance to individuals to enroll under this section.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4E57805D52044BF2B87A71A2A96A444F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Raising awareness of premium assistance and cost-sharing reductions</header><text>To distribute fair and impartial information concerning enrollment under this section and the availability of premium assistance tax credits under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and cost-sharing reductions under section 1402 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, and to assist eligible individuals in applying for such tax credits and cost-sharing reductions.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBAFEAEF05A6A411EBA92B7A0E33860D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H5B5DCEC38CEA43E68CB639D03F5C65C4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HC82C09562F8A4DDD99060EC2087AC43E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a State; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H323311CD877D47219653D18E86DCFE7E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a nonprofit community-based organization.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6BDDB3C77E574010A2726068EEB39C75"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Enrollment agents</header><text>Such term includes a licensed independent insurance agent or broker that has an arrangement with a State or nonprofit community-based organization to enroll eligible individuals under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H934967FA16934A679034E3A31746C279"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>Such term does not include an entity that—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H537650A2F40141338BE8313FE5D4E7E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a health insurance issuer; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H83E7E562FFB541E28C0FF806BF5307F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>receives any consideration, either directly or indirectly, from any health insurance issuer in connection with the enrollment of any individuals under this section.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H12F97C8BB721466793E07B5C720EC025"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this subsection, the Secretary shall give priority to awarding grants to States or eligible entities in States that have geographic rating areas at risk of having no qualified health plans in the individual market.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H94478B52599C4EB5830E118167F629A7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Out of any moneys in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $500,000,000 is appropriated to the Secretary for each of calendar years 2018 through 2020, to carry out this subsection.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB6249FC25D64448E97FB2E802FA9D561"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Implementation</header>
 <paragraph id="H76681D596F87431A8382A33DA803722C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H119194E93130473B98C8B916937D7078"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consult with other Federal agencies, including the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Labor, the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Department of Defense, and the Office of Personnel Management; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H496EB78CFB1B408D8F98536756C757FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incorporate significant public consultation and feedback, through public forums, notice and comment rulemaking, and any other appropriate mediums.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3C2D7170611450E86522CB5152D1E22"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>No later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report establishing the administrative parameters for the implementation of this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C687CB0C1674FD9A49D529B4C0EBFE0"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Feasibility study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct a study on the feasibility of applying this section with respect to individuals residing in States that are not within the 50 States or the District of Columbia.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0827914D089B43BC80C044FEFE9E46DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Medigap</header><text>Section 1882 of the Social Security Act is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H265CCCE1B9B84DC08847DC8C705987E7" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HBEEED7A327B74BA3975BD2BA9B21E8F7"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Development of New Standards for Certain Medicare Supplemental Policies relating to buy-In option</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall request the National Association of Insurance Commissioners to review and revise the standards for benefit packages described in subsection (p)(1), to otherwise update standards to include requirements for each medicare supplemental policy that offers such a policy in a State, with respect to each year, to accept every individual in the State who is eligible for enrollment pursuant to section 1899C and who applies for such coverage for such year if the individual applies for enrollment in such policy during the 30-day period following the date of enrollment pursuant to section 1899C and to accept every such individual during a period of transition from enrollment pursuant to such section to enrollment under this title pursuant to eligibility other than under such section. Such revisions shall be made consistent with the rules applicable under subsection (p)(1)(E) with the reference to the <quote>1991 NAIC Model Regulation</quote> deemed a reference to the NAIC Model Regulation as published in the Federal Register on December 4, 1998, and as subsequently updated by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners to reflect previous changes in law and the reference to <quote>date of enactment of this subsection</quote> deemed a reference to the date of enactment of this subsection (aa).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H81F906C033A94679970D9598D3D23C8F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Negotiation of lower covered part D drug prices on behalf of medicare beneficiaries</header>
 <subsection id="H40CA535B665F4F369D21CEFD67159E98"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Negotiation by secretary</header><text>Section 1860D–11 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-111">42 U.S.C. 1395w–111</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (i) (relating to noninterference) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H7B0894399A5D4BA5A0F9C1C2BACC556F" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HC38E7DF0834B449889A80CB7A755E394"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Negotiation of Lower Drug Prices</header>
 <paragraph id="H279A3CA35B4F4328947C851E651B8B22"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall negotiate with pharmaceutical manufacturers the prices (including discounts, rebates, and other price concessions) that may be charged to PDP sponsors and MA organizations for covered part D drugs for part D eligible individuals who are enrolled under a prescription drug plan or under an MA–PD plan.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="HB2A4415CED794D2C9925F0934143A6D2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No change in rules for formularies</header>
 <subparagraph id="H19092059515340CC98B9B893FF942005"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in paragraph (1) shall be construed to authorize the Secretary to establish or require a particular formulary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CA820934FB248B6AFBE597524774130"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not be construed as affecting the Secretary's authority to ensure appropriate and adequate access to covered part D drugs under prescription drug plans and under MA–PD plans, including compliance of such plans with formulary requirements under section 1860D–4(b)(3).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BA1244F91A9497B8FFB4597CB09BA9F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as preventing the sponsor of a prescription drug plan, or an organization offering an MA–PD plan, from obtaining a discount or reduction of the price for a covered part D drug below the price negotiated under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC21B9010990407C8CEB8FD74D4BF15F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Semi-annual reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than June 1, 2018, and every 6 months thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Ways and Means, Energy and Commerce, and Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on negotiations conducted by the Secretary to achieve lower prices for Medicare beneficiaries, and the prices and price discounts achieved by the Secretary as a result of such negotiations.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H60AA52BBFCA3425FBB5AD89368A83281"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall first apply to negotiations and prices for plan years beginning on January 1, 2018.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H5340C70B48B3474EB8EB1FDC7A4C1CA4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Individual Market Reinsurance Fund</header>
			<subsection commented="no" id="H37734556BBA446C581BAEB851235BC2C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of Fund</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H8E610DE983D64F238DBFAF05AF827C4F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established the <quote>Individual Market Reinsurance Fund</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Fund</quote>) to be administered by the Secretary to provide funding for an individual market stabilization reinsurance program in each State that complies with the requirements of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD7765A42D0934EDBB24226E2190B6D4A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Amounts made available to the Fund shall consist of the funds deposited into the Fund under paragraph (3) and shall be used to carry out this section (other than subsection (c)) for each calendar year beginning with 2018. Amounts made available to the Fund shall remain available without fiscal or calendar year limitation to carry out this section.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D6840A5839140A6ACCF31C8088A2AB6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cost-sharing in costs of Program</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H9A12D827BE8340778FD922FCCC92B8C6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A qualified health plan that participates in the reinsurance program established under subsection (b) shall pay the fee established under subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD26A603FEF9240508EE0561EADD7AE03"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary is authorized to charge a fee to each qualified health plan that participates in the reinsurance program established under subsection (b). Any amounts collected pursuant to this paragraph shall be deposited into the Fund for purposes of payments under subsection (b).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEBC2100B9F59456CA5CC6D637AD8EC92"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In establishing the fee under subparagraph (B)—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H2CBECE0DA5B841C19470176661CBB1A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary shall consult with interested parties; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HDC8B025C1AAA4516AC246D2A90C9F7CA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall ensure that the amount of such fee is not excessive so as to unduly discourage qualified health plans from participating in the reinsurance program.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H892B58548C994A339E93ECB33ACAA378"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Individual Market reinsurance program</header>
 <paragraph id="H5BF9EAEB74434DBB90DEFA3809948239"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall use amounts in the Fund to establish a reinsurance program under which the Secretary shall make reinsurance payments, subject to subsection (a)(3), to health insurance issuers with respect to high-cost individuals enrolled in qualified health plans offered by such issuers that are not grandfathered health plans or transitional health plans for any plan year beginning with the 2018 plan year. This subsection constitutes budget authority in advance of appropriations Acts and represents the obligation of the Secretary to provide payments from the Fund in accordance with this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C43773B71CE43A4A00B7179B5C37320"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of payment</header><text>The payment made to a health insurance issuer under paragraph (1) with respect to each high-cost individual enrolled in a qualified health plan issued by the issuer that is not a grandfathered health plan or a transitional health plan shall equal 80 percent of the lesser of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2040568F5ECB4FB2BF206FDD76DFB108"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount (if any) by which the individual’s claims incurred during the plan year exceeds—</text> <clause id="H7F7129B267994F969F7E3BAF3555D182"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of the 2018, 2019, or 2020 plan year, $50,000; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1113980C76D144F6A6C82DC9BC8C0556"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of any other plan year, $100,000; or</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75BD32EA4B5A42CEA8572C777EF8B67D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for plan years described in—</text>
 <clause id="H0A3F7EF4C1D44045BE4C4DB48F176A52"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subparagraph (A)(i), $450,000; and</text> </clause><clause id="HF27E2A2D66794AD793CD97A4C4180FEB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subparagraph (A)(ii), $400,000.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA528EF3B7ABC494D95DA28233FF6BEF5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Indexing</header><text>In the case of plan years beginning after 2018, the dollar amounts that appear in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (2) shall each be increased by an amount equal to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2E62E4AFBA84481E98F7467FF7CE6504"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such amount; multiplied by</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD4F19906816457CAF8C4C6C1E8CE28A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the premium adjustment percentage specified under section 1302(c)(4) of the Affordable Care Act, but determined by substituting <quote>2018</quote> for <quote>2013</quote>.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H526CC265651F4360B3317C66471A2901"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Payment methods</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7FA1C2724D3E4DB6BB4C048D8DBE9F03"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Payments under this subsection shall be based on such a method as the Secretary determines. The Secretary may establish a payment method by which interim payments of amounts under this subsection are made during a plan year based on the Secretary's best estimate of amounts that will be payable after obtaining all of the information.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A50E4AC89E34F07A069F1E77E15E013"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement for provision of information</header>
 <clause id="H0DAC27782B8E455080E83CE2213BDDC3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Payments under this subsection to a health insurance issuer are conditioned upon the furnishing to the Secretary, in a form and manner specified by the Secretary, of such information as may be required to carry out this subsection.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H130A87865239419FA629594FAAAE9606"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Restriction on use of information</header><text>Information disclosed or obtained pursuant to clause (i) is subject to the HIPAA privacy and security law, as defined in section 3009(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300jj-19">42 U.S.C. 300jj–19(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCD02E4EDB314803A66F77E784151347"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary flexibility for budget neutral revisions to reinsurance payment specifications</header><text>If the Secretary determines appropriate, the Secretary may substitute higher dollar amounts for the dollar amounts specified under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (2) (and adjusted under paragraph (3), if applicable) if the Secretary certifies that such substitutions, considered together, neither increase nor decease the total projected payments under this subsection.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD77C2E57A828448EA5DC6E4C4A29A745"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header>
 <paragraph id="H5E5FC6B54E524C04A53FE50EF7B26816"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit a report to Congress, not later than January 21, 2019, and each year thereafter, that contains the following information for the most recently ended year:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEF43CF4597C3455EB3A3876B6380EDF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number and types of plans in each State's individual market, specifying the number that are qualified health plans, grandfathered health plans, or health insurance coverage that is not a qualified health plan.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC01C7B7492B14818A5FD3154CFED50FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The impact of the reinsurance payments provided under this section on the availability of coverage, cost of coverage, and coverage options in each State.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2518F8144F0E4BFE9917C20404867E37"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The amount of premiums paid by individuals in each State by age, family size, geographic area in the State's individual market, and category of health plan (as described in subparagraph (A)).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6C17901218E443DACC212940D64B22C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The process used to award funds for outreach and enrollment activities awarded to eligible entities under subsection (c), the amount of such funds awarded, and the activities carried out with such funds.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H006C23950CCF4B349D5303A1C6436D29"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Such other information as the Secretary deems relevant.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF26DA00B823F4FF9B2AE43AE9E04F7F7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation report</header><text>Not later than January 31, 2022, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE4FB2C957A3D472D80CC8D8D48B385D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>analyzes the impact of the funds provided under this section on premiums and enrollment in the individual market in all States; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE8B9EAE3C6F4B32AC4F5681B794190A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contains a State-by-State comparison of the design of the programs carried out by States with funds provided under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5B36566F06C6451ABA415946386A0CC0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H3F673ECB306F449F97F50382D125BF83"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC8E90EEB19343AE92082430E5862483"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fund</header><text>The term <term>Fund</term> means the Individual Market Reinsurance Fund established under subsection (a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51182137464C4301A2909E476AAFA0EC"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grandfathered health plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>grandfathered health plan</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1251(e) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3BEEB6D9593402C94566145AE2F4C3A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>High-cost individual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>high-cost individual</term> means an individual enrolled in a qualified health plan (other than a grandfathered health plan or a transitional health plan) who incurs claims in excess of $50,000 during a plan year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A4D4CED3CD941EEBA99BF18D07E89F8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States and the District of Columbia.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE29F6280A7F24157AC1932FFA58B4F80"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Transitional health plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>transitional health plan</term> means a plan continued under the letter issued by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services on November 14, 2013, to the State Insurance Commissioners outlining a transitional policy for coverage in the individual and small group markets to which section 1251 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act does not apply, and under the extension of the transitional policy for such coverage set forth in the Insurance Standards Bulletin Series guidance issued by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services on March 5, 2014, February 29, 2016, and February 13, 2017.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8DE69316A8994B988280F0F287560FEE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reauthorization of risk corridors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1342(a) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18062">42 U.S.C. 18062(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>and calendar years 2018 through 2020</quote> after <quote>2016</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="HDB51B4AFE10E4A9782359DCF0CEFA07F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Enhancements for reduced cost sharing</header>
			<subsection id="H61C1B132193D45A9B09DED44F1CE1740"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Modification of amount</header>
 <paragraph id="HD6B2939BC08E4AB4B221B5FFD37BE132"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1402(c)(2) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18071">42 U.S.C. 18071(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H245F29591DA446F7ACC064B1BE0A4888" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H3409613CDAB24393AC753327E2ECECCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional reduction</header><text>The Secretary shall establish procedures under which the issuer of a qualified health plan to which this section applies shall further reduce cost-sharing under the plan in a manner sufficient to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD266532A74C44C36BBE7A01381AE6395"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible insured whose household income is not less than 100 percent but not more than 200 percent of the poverty line for a family of the size involved, increase the plan’s share of the total allowed costs of benefits provided under the plan to 95 percent of such costs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC956B784C70492DB32B2DEB022877AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible insured whose household income is more than 200 percent but not more than 300 percent of the poverty line for a family of the size involved, increase the plan’s share of the total allowed costs of benefits provided under the plan to 90 percent of such costs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H69771714611F44DF91149E241FBA8409"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible insured whose household income is more than 300 percent but not more than 400 percent of the poverty line for a family of the size involved, increase the plan’s share of the total allowed costs of benefits provided under the plan to 85 percent of such costs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9C1B6F5AE69F47379488FF9A26BFF927"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause (i) of section 1402(c)(1)(B) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18071">42 U.S.C. 18071(c)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7C454360DD04A31A1E05A189D8A7405" style="OLC">
 <clause commented="no" id="HB03383157A804FCD9305191CDF1770D1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure the reduction under this paragraph shall not result in an increase in the plan’s share of the total allowed costs of benefits provided under the plan above—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="HB91734EFE4E74624AD09863F9A48C3B5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>95 percent in the case of an eligible insured described in paragraph (2)(A);</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H557239FD7181452EA04A71F096B4E5E0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>90 percent in the case of an eligible insured described in paragraph (2)(B); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H89C985CD46294940A3D76A19F1E16724"><enum>(III)</enum><text>85 percent in the case of an eligible insured described in paragraph (2)(C).</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D2F093EFB144A9494A4E81B96FA17AE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header> <text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to plan years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H110F976895B949408586B281EAE7EE09"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1402 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18071">42 U.S.C. 18071</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9953D4838C24F7581686EA5BA588FAC" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HE6903C8526C4404293354DB8EDD5354B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated to the Secretary such sums as may be necessary for payments under this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H0267F3E3203140A580E7F89DC503BF0B"><enum>7.</enum><header>Technical Advisory Committee on Health Care Delivery System Reform and Program Integrity</header>
 <subsection id="H8011C19147BA44B49F3D8F31835E6D5C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established a committee to be known as the Committee on Delivery System Reform and Program Integrity.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE3800F0498E8465CB8818CE861243527"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall be composed of 11 members appointed by the Comptroller General of the United States. Such members shall include individuals with national recognition for their expertise in health care delivery system reform and the related delivery of health care. Health care providers and patient advocates shall have adequate representation on the Committee.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB0A5808A8392494E866077E21C59816C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall periodically submit to the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Congress written recommendations, provided in a comprehensive report format, to further the goals of health care delivery system reform that generally aim to improve the quality of patient care, improve the health of populations, and reduce the cost of care. The origin of these proposals can be derived from any initiative underway between the Department of Health and Human Services and any party, or other initiatives, national or regional in scope, that offer promise to accelerate the goals of delivery system reform or improve program integrity toward the goal of providing further stability to the appropriate Trust Funds under title XVIII of the Social Security Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


