<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HEFAEFEF0590446F087D63A0B0FC39D44" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4287 IH: Broadband Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4287</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171107">November 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a broadband infrastructure finance and innovation program to make available loans,
			 loan guarantees, and lines of credit for the construction and deployment
			 of broadband infrastructure, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE98517AD8F0049348D29D64E4D2C2E5F" style="OLC">
		<section id="H92EDD478E0EE42E9B5C575026BDFCD3B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="HD045FB4E98A44661875833A600457D84"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Broadband Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HE5A7F8E75043467EA783AC4D3FC6A432"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H92EDD478E0EE42E9B5C575026BDFCD3B" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5F2EF76F64D54E0AA40B6BCB1EEAD831" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H2AB148ADAC9C4E6888B28CB165B1DF13" level="section">Sec. 3. Determination of eligibility and project selection.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HCF18F107A4A741B28E1FC9AA68295F6B" level="section">Sec. 4. Secured loans.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H997AD3E627934509A775BDC48B13AD7C" level="section">Sec. 5. Lines of credit.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H339AEE5C9259452F92ED0F8BC83B02C8" level="section">Sec. 6. Alternative prudential lending standards for small projects.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H96DFF3CBFF5D40D59119CCCF7C4E8AC6" level="section">Sec. 7. Program administration.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H3F651380B07C42A5BC542BD0247D6B6F" level="section">Sec. 8. State and local permits.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4045139A61E942B2A3DFD91342F16D6C" level="section">Sec. 9. Regulations.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HC48C5A2389624C049D9126F34D5BA9C7" level="section">Sec. 10. Funding.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H99AD272F091D449FAAE018228DC3BF58" level="section">Sec. 11. Reports to Congress.</toc-entry></toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="H5F2EF76F64D54E0AA40B6BCB1EEAD831"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H9B649CC45D874AF08F1D04FE6433AEDE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Assistant Secretary</quote> means the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA6556C05966416189FC0991D505D255"><enum>(2)</enum><header>BIFIA program</header><text>The term <quote>BIFIA program</quote> means the broadband infrastructure finance and innovation program established under this Act.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4E79BB78ED7645B5A5595C6DA74E31E9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Broadband service</header><text>The term <quote>broadband service</quote> means broadband Internet access service (as defined in section 8.2 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H696615328B8A4633AB5704FCB4F7B089"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible project costs</header><text>The term <term>eligible project costs</term> means amounts substantially all of which are paid by, or for the account of, an obligor in connection with a project, including the cost of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD0C5799D18394A318E2CA3DA034C1FA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">development phase activities, including planning, feasibility analysis, revenue forecasting, environmental review, historic preservation review, permitting, preliminary engineering and design work, and other preconstruction activities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E653E1C4BA0491687188819A4BBD106"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">construction and deployment phase activities, including—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H17E4D3FB3BCA480AACFD4F41C17FC188"><enum>(i)</enum><text>construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation, replacement, and acquisition of real property (including land relating to the project and improvements to land), equipment, instrumentation, networking capability, hardware and software, and digital network technology;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H7B1966EEC51C441BA348A5FB9DFDFCE9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>environmental mitigation; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H68AD2B807CF14239B43C4B24F2D85DE9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>construction contingencies; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AF9FC80F125483685E9B3B5DFD938DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>capitalized interest necessary to meet market requirements, reasonably required reserve funds, capital issuance expenses, and other carrying costs during construction and deployment.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3865DFB4ECB44CEA974BA9BC0ED119D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal credit instrument</header><text>The term <term>Federal credit instrument</term> means a secured loan, loan guarantee, or line of credit authorized to be made available under the BIFIA program with respect to a project.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H55B7A3A28644498AB72DDB4A80B8F6BF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Investment-grade rating</header><text>The term <term>investment-grade rating</term> means a rating of BBB minus, Baa3, bbb minus, BBB (low), or higher assigned by a rating agency to project obligations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1FE5D97A45554638B7C2612C7062E0C7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Lender</header><text>The term <term>lender</term> means any non-Federal qualified institutional buyer (as defined in section 230.144A(a) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), known as Rule 144A(a) of the Securities and Exchange Commission and issued under the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77a">15 U.S.C. 77a</external-xref> et seq.)), including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5856C3E199D7484C97BDF90CAAC86D68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a qualified retirement plan (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4974">section 4974(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) that is a qualified institutional buyer; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D9521BF80964FBB9CE1E4CAEB14C67E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a governmental plan (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/414">section 414(d)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) that is a qualified institutional buyer.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D866E1FE95C48D1A05982E32614B392"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Letter of interest</header><text>The term <term>letter of interest</term> means a letter submitted by a potential applicant prior to an application for credit assistance in a format prescribed by the Assistant Secretary on the website of the BIFIA program that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFA624ABDA211414BA32C24A0E5F4E926"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describes the project and the location, purpose, and cost of the project;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE70D2D7F1F843838FA34E5CFD798EB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>outlines the proposed financial plan, including the requested credit assistance and the proposed obligor;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A5CF2148A4B417D947D986179452846"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides a status of environmental review; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52989B6969CB4C0A8B0F070ECBC17F7F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provides information regarding satisfaction of other eligibility requirements of the BIFIA program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H566B9E864EB4416DA4633B40DEF12D9B"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Line of credit</header><text>The term <term>line of credit</term> means an agreement entered into by the Assistant Secretary with an obligor under section 5 to provide a direct loan at a future date upon the occurrence of certain events.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7DFB51A06C540CDB4C7961E92138D37"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Loan guarantee</header><text>The term <term>loan guarantee</term> means any guarantee or other pledge by the Assistant Secretary to pay all or part of the principal of and interest on a loan or other debt obligation issued by an obligor and funded by a lender.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H60AB2C4AA17C4192AFCAF0EC9BBB96E9"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Obligor</header><text>The term <term>obligor</term> means a party that—</text> <subparagraph id="HEFFA3E1F63274A1C9FA209E51D8D363B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is primarily liable for payment of the principal of or interest on a Federal credit instrument; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB1A303D2768148B994E10C1CEA0DD1D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be a corporation, company, partnership, joint venture, trust, or governmental entity, agency, or instrumentality.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA865ED8B13B4F70868A8D583E46094B"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Project</header><text>The term <term>project</term> means a project—</text> <subparagraph id="H73A3DCF7AB0443BDB56EFEB4E31C01B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to construct and deploy infrastructure for the provision of broadband service; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E6E5D9D07E3477B9298DF79523B3D9D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that the Assistant Secretary determines will—</text> <clause id="HFF9ECED13E394583B1ABDDAD3A6EC15D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide access or improved access to broadband service to consumers residing in areas of the United States where such service is not available with a download speed of at least 100 megabits per second and an upload speed of at least 3 megabits per second; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE698930211054B15891C7304AC927998"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide access or improved access to broadband service to—</text> <subclause id="HD06D370C9E7940EDB142A6F6EBF08DE5"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">schools, libraries, medical and healthcare providers, community colleges and other institutions of higher education, and other community support organizations and entities to facilitate greater use of broadband service by or through such organizations;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD31CFC3E385B48A0882BD8A0F84A6A4A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>organizations and agencies that provide outreach, access, equipment, and support services to facilitate greater use of broadband service by low-income, unemployed, aged, and otherwise vulnerable populations;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7AA631A6B52D4A2BA7C6A1B094E02803"><enum>(III)</enum><text>job-creating strategic facilities located within a State-designated economic zone, Economic Development District designated by the Department of Commerce, Renewal Community or Empowerment Zone designated by the Department of Housing and Urban Development, or Enterprise Community designated by the Department of Agriculture; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6A41DAEBF1A64930B4C6DC22E3D5CD9A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>public safety agencies.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA20D5A97A1FB4F2BB55BCCB1693476A8"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Project obligation</header><text>The term <term>project obligation</term> means any note, bond, debenture, or other debt obligation issued by an obligor in connection with the financing of a project, other than a Federal credit instrument.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA92EF2015F0B48FF8B4F96B8CCAFA066"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Public authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>public authority</term> means a Federal, State, county, town, or township, Indian tribe, municipal or other local government or instrumentality with authority to finance, build, operate, or maintain infrastructure for the provision of broadband service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9B2AB77DF2F48AB95EBF57529089D29"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Rating agency</header><text>The term <term>rating agency</term> means a credit rating agency registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission as a nationally recognized statistical rating organization (as defined in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H75E90D8C3E1D4B6693B9BDB060AED76A"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Secured loan</header><text>The term <term>secured loan</term> means a direct loan or other debt obligation issued by an obligor and funded by the Assistant Secretary in connection with the financing of a project under section 4.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H099A07D085AC4578BCE2894CECBCF38E"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Small project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>small project</quote> means a project having eligible project costs that are reasonably anticipated not to equal or exceed $20,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7205AD3C6E9F4D01BF06D09451B9D690"><enum>(18)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/153">47 U.S.C. 153</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C284D2601B4479BB177756FEB1F9FE1"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Subsidy amount</header><text>The term <term>subsidy amount</term> means the amount of budget authority sufficient to cover the estimated long-term cost to the Federal Government of a Federal credit instrument—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H23F6CB672BC04FA9921C166159A4D16C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>calculated on a net present value basis; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1992ACE4113B44AE80489A8AD5DE7FB2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>excluding administrative costs and any incidental effects on governmental receipts or outlays in accordance with the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/661">2 U.S.C. 661</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC003968389CC47ACB6978A9B491B6A41"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Substantial completion</header><text>The term <term>substantial completion</term> means, with respect to a project receiving credit assistance under the BIFIA program—</text> <subparagraph id="H00D985732866411BA71D1C45C62E13CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the commencement of the provision of broadband service using the infrastructure being financed; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE77C7A0F353240F98B7703037A13B059"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a comparable event, as determined by the Assistant Secretary and specified in the credit agreement.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H2AB148ADAC9C4E6888B28CB165B1DF13"><enum>3.</enum><header>Determination of eligibility and project selection</header> <subsection id="H5AC4070942A545999890155ECECA90F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligibility</header> <paragraph id="H21261DC2496742EDBB3F96ACF398D56C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A project shall be eligible to receive credit assistance under the BIFIA program if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3AEAD0A406944B609B20ACC96DB80561"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the entity proposing to carry out the project submits a letter of interest prior to submission of a formal application for the project; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E8BBEBB0D74409F9A279173EF86DEB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the project meets the criteria described in this subsection.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H294ABDEA2BD04A3BA4121F2AE0F3A038"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Creditworthiness</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H3809C5D7FC7B457D971DC1B518DF0EBD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), to be eligible for assistance under the BIFIA program, a project shall satisfy applicable creditworthiness standards, which, at a minimum, shall include—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HA3755D0FD3814A76A9AF200D5207B9F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adequate coverage requirements to ensure repayment;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H892C2C21662C4845B018A7DAD74F2FDC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an investment-grade rating from at least 2 rating agencies on debt senior to the Federal credit instrument; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H3FE1FEEE804D4C15A8F9B7B034F4F24B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a rating from at least 2 rating agencies on the Federal credit instrument.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3918A91D9D4F4D69A9BFFC215B4C18A9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Small projects</header><text>In order for a small project to be eligible for assistance under the BIFIA program, such project shall satisfy alternative creditworthiness standards that shall be established by the Assistant Secretary under section 6 for purposes of this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD148A50547394D5992114546F6D5264F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A State, local government, agency or instrumentality of a State or local government, public authority, public-private partnership, or any other legal entity undertaking the project and authorized by the Assistant Secretary shall submit a project application that is acceptable to the Assistant Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H061E4642D9EF42AF9687D7B6191D8B52"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible project cost parameters for infrastructure projects</header><text>Eligible project costs shall be reasonably anticipated to equal or exceed $2,000,000 in the case of a project or program of projects—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4393181F96CD4BCCBA4E7ED3355CA630"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in which the applicant is a local government, instrumentality of local government, or public authority (other than a public authority that is a Federal or State government or instrumentality);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE12DF46E1D6A4AA483476244BB42CA1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>located on a facility owned by a local government; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64612139DC3446639F6CAAB729D9AFCB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for which the Assistant Secretary determines that a local government is substantially involved in the development of the project.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BC0DF4E921A4958A8A5856602BD92C2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Dedicated revenue sources</header><text>The applicable Federal credit instrument shall be repayable, in whole or in part, from—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H53D75ABDC8984B1B8114B6493285E7B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>amounts charged to—</text>
 <clause id="HB77841B04BFF4455B02A0A8CB2B21661"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subscribers of broadband service for such service; or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H6CCB650119F94A4BB0FEB8F0581A44A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subscribers of any related service provided over the same infrastructure for such related service;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H441C4F04776446F2AD128904817637FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>user fees;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A0F5AACA969404B9F2A8CB002874DB9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>payments owing to the obligor under a public-private partnership; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9382F4FF39C47738B976EBBFDA25930"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other dedicated revenue sources that also secure or fund the project obligations.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8517B3E491A4DEFB7DA8929CF7AAB3E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Applications where obligor will be identified later</header><text>A State, local government, agency or instrumentality of a State or local government, or public authority may submit to the Assistant Secretary an application under paragraph (3), under which a private party to a public-private partnership will be—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBB7967C92B6A4095B34D0E3CFAEB7121"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the obligor; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98B9181B0CC743F6A83B49D8A4454E9F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identified later through completion of a procurement and selection of the private party.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB09415906E8A48CAA9CB14CE914A79FF"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Beneficial effects</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall determine that financial assistance for the project under the BIFIA program will—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4B1BFF079D6D4736BBF35A2536079E30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>foster, if appropriate, partnerships that attract public and private investment for the project;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C6D8CEEF82C406F91464E8E7A7E109D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enable the project to proceed at an earlier date than the project would otherwise be able to proceed or reduce the lifecycle costs (including debt service costs) of the project; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3001578D6F2D47FF9B67AF72B10030FD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reduce the contribution of Federal grant assistance for the project.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CA73DD64473465D9A7D071B55F1BA0B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Project readiness</header><text>To be eligible for assistance under the BIFIA program, the applicant shall demonstrate a reasonable expectation that the contracting process for the construction and deployment of infrastructure for the provision of broadband service through the project can commence by no later than 90 days after the date on which a Federal credit instrument is obligated for the project under the BIFIA program.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H24D90ACFFB4F48F6B7CD1E218109BF39"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection Among Eligible Projects</header>
 <paragraph id="H1B1E359B6BE74758962C16258F94F60B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment of application process</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall establish a rolling application process under which projects that are eligible to receive credit assistance under subsection (a) shall receive credit assistance on terms acceptable to the Assistant Secretary, if adequate funds are available to cover the subsidy costs associated with the Federal credit instrument.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAC2E53C8189D4937B6E6E4FF2ABFC563"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preliminary rating opinion letter</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall require each project applicant to provide—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H992851F1440F4530BCF28EF9AAE8A48B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a preliminary rating opinion letter from at least 1 rating agency—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H3ED095D9410143AD8266D12B8E61108B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>indicating that the senior obligations of the project, which may be the Federal credit instrument, have the potential to achieve an investment-grade rating; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H169DFCAA56554949B3131508F57EFACE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>including a preliminary rating opinion on the Federal credit instrument; or</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF2F3431084CA4C3A84734DA6A052A714"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a small project, alternative documentation that the Assistant Secretary shall require in the standards established under section 6 for purposes of this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H527495A09CAE48CCA00601F7B8F1430D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technology neutrality required</header><text>In selecting projects to receive credit assistance under the BIFIA program, the Assistant Secretary may not favor a project using any particular technology.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB6A12177D4B04E2F9E5D860A726A8F15"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal Requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="HA4D78377EED04E45B17E6DAE5657A032"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The following provisions of law shall apply to funds made available under the BIFIA program and projects assisted with those funds:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8F658AD1B497400FBDACEDEDF4BA59BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref> et seq.).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6382D478EC1147FBAD1D3D766C7F8B8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4DD01BCB33B4D8FA994707E83AFFC43"><enum>(C)</enum><text>54 U.S.C. 300101 et seq. (commonly referred to as the <quote>National Historic Preservation Act</quote>).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A4991D3C3714A48A2A47CEAD7784318"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4601">42 U.S.C. 4601</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50485A543B7C42568E66933C87AAC23D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>NEPA</header><text>No funding shall be obligated for a project that has not received an environmental categorical exclusion, a finding of no significant impact, or a record of decision under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEB78494ACD254B48872A6AE8819164BB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref> et seq.), any project that receives credit assistance under the BIFIA program shall be considered a program or activity within the meaning of section 606 of such title (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d-4a">42 U.S.C. 2000d–4a</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79AAE90A611E4DF4AA0AED1F1DE538F7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application Processing Procedures</header>
 <paragraph id="HA18B770FE96F4D3A9D4254DFBC1F3C16"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of complete application</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of receipt of an application under this section, the Assistant Secretary shall provide to the applicant a written notice to inform the applicant whether—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA493421D0B574F3E8FBFC00701846595"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the application is complete; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87FC0BF76A174C4D858F9411066E78F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>additional information or materials are needed to complete the application.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8746C7B405E74AE09DFDFFBB69282A8D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approval or denial of application</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of issuance of the written notice under paragraph (1), the Assistant Secretary shall provide to the applicant a written notice informing the applicant whether the Assistant Secretary has approved or disapproved the application.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1A8BB8EF680E46C19744DCF634E47CE6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Approval before NEPA review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (c)(2), an application for a project may be approved before the project receives an environmental categorical exclusion, a finding of no significant impact, or a record of decision under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3071E38298224E7EAAF3A1E2F903A86D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Development Phase Activities</header><text>Any credit instrument secured under the BIFIA program may be used to finance up to 100 percent of the cost of development phase activities as described in section 2(4)(A).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HCF18F107A4A741B28E1FC9AA68295F6B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Secured loans</header>
			<subsection id="H86C4DCF1BFAD4AB38F4F12AED96742BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header>
 <paragraph id="H187A08151A8B4D77B1C056F03E7FE82D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), the Assistant Secretary may enter into agreements with one or more obligors to make secured loans, the proceeds of which shall be used—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD5BBF5DEA85C4A78AF041C2CF81EEA8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to finance eligible project costs of any project selected under section 3;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCF2BBB0182344E0BD4E9BF10858B6FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to refinance interim construction financing of eligible project costs of any project selected under section 3; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7C9712759874638907858E0EF5E698A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to refinance long-term project obligations or Federal credit instruments, if the refinancing provides additional funding capacity for the completion, enhancement, or expansion of any project that—</text>
 <clause id="HCD18741CCE954FD9BFF67D4B98245D3D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is selected under section 3; or</text> </clause><clause id="H8CC27FE4DB0C47FBA1C04FBF70C4EBFB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>otherwise meets the requirements of section 3.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H260CC3811627463496EB2E181AB8E957"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on refinancing of interim construction financing</header><text>A loan under paragraph (1) shall not refinance interim construction financing under paragraph (1)(B)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H739C45E4D23648A08512FA7A867C7ACD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the maturity of such interim construction financing is later than 1 year after the substantial completion of the project; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F04BA8E12D64A54AEFE8CD011858A96"><enum>(B)</enum><text>later than 1 year after the date of substantial completion of the project.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H92DCDE368C5D4CC696E84223F200A7F8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Risk assessment</header><text>Before entering into an agreement under this subsection, the Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall determine an appropriate capital reserve subsidy amount for each secured loan, taking into account each rating letter provided by a rating agency under section 3(b)(2)(A)(ii) or, in the case of a small project, the alternative documentation provided under section 3(b)(2)(B).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF8E4895AC67412594273E57F28C9813"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms and Limitations</header>
 <paragraph id="HF20CA6C4B43B4E0EAF91286F12787BAC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A secured loan under this section with respect to a project shall be on such terms and conditions and contain such covenants, representations, warranties, and requirements (including requirements for audits) as the Assistant Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB423543BE62A41E49A2DEE276621D672"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of a secured loan under this section shall not exceed the lesser of 49 percent of the reasonably anticipated eligible project costs or, if the secured loan is not for a small project and does not receive an investment-grade rating, the amount of the senior project obligations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9CAF1DE3097457880D7C6778ECAC102"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Payment</header><text>A secured loan under this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H1643B6B73C0C4CCC9B005F119C7780CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall—</text>
 <clause id="H3EEF205201C54B6B98D8D095611A2F96"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be payable, in whole or in part, from—</text> <subclause id="H62027E2094BB4CEDAB2998C43B097E6E"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">amounts charged to—</text>
 <item id="HE72764E67B32499DA9EE52A69AB86AEC"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>subscribers of broadband service for such service; or</text> </item><item id="HB33B4D3E163D44CA8F88BF3239160772"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subscribers of any related service provided over the same infrastructure for such related service;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="HD54AF67AC9AB490A973C31A8BE0C335D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>user fees;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H8FE2F0DD09A1402A9F0FA00A5A52846B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>payments owing to the obligor under a public-private partnership; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H449965103473455C87372ACBC19CF87E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>other dedicated revenue sources that also secure the senior project obligations; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H87930E40A60D4701B0F9AEAAE52D17AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include a coverage requirement or similar security feature supporting the project obligations; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB85AC93B16D249259A3211FA64F74AEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may have a lien on revenues described in subparagraph (A), subject to any lien securing project obligations.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AC4F4E15AAB421B93BC24F4E0E51EF9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Interest rate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The interest rate on a secured loan under this section shall be not less than the yield on United States Treasury securities of a similar maturity to the maturity of the secured loan on the date of execution of the loan agreement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DE2D5655EAC47B0B877AB4E9090A52D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Maturity date</header><text>The final maturity date of the secured loan shall be the lesser of—</text> <subparagraph id="H723A3A8570BF41EDA2CCD955842022A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>35 years after the date of substantial completion of the project; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01F708A8ABA945C9A943129CA06E7669"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the useful life of the infrastructure for the provision of broadband service being financed is of a lesser period, the useful life of the infrastructure.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5017DCC702014DD5B1658C4FD257E7A6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Nonsubordination</header>
 <subparagraph id="H833D0D12134B4C93940D4AD7739A356D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the secured loan shall not be subordinated to the claims of any holder of project obligations in the event of bankruptcy, insolvency, or liquidation of the obligor.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H155F92B7F4AD4893B03451B84125A4BB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Preexisting indenture</header>
 <clause id="H931FB8EBF34348FB83B4C915A45233B9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall waive the requirement under subparagraph (A) for a public agency borrower that is financing ongoing capital programs and has outstanding senior bonds under a preexisting indenture, if—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H4ADC80732DC94A048E047C6966B30677"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the secured loan—</text> <item commented="no" id="H831477019BDE4BCE8D8A38C25E0665FE"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is rated in the A category or higher; or</text>
 </item><item commented="no" id="H8AD2D86F4C15430892AF304F01D64A2D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in the case of a small project, meets an alternative standard that the Assistant Secretary shall establish under section 6 for purposes of this subclause;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H1144EED65F974B6BA03401C9AA6A9D41"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the secured loan is secured and payable from pledged revenues not affected by project performance, such as a tax-backed revenue pledge or a system-backed pledge of project revenues; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6C4A8EDCB93748D6824A5C5EE929FD46"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the BIFIA program share of eligible project costs is 33 percent or less.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H048B845758154C7B97DB19BE0DD24AF2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>If the Assistant Secretary waives the nonsubordination requirement under this subparagraph—</text>
 <subclause id="H3509BEC79B3E42AFA4EB6E0B77922C24"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the maximum credit subsidy to be paid by the Federal Government shall be not more than 10 percent of the principal amount of the secured loan; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7B24AB615B454E16AE93D10DAD89735E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the obligor shall be responsible for paying the remainder of the subsidy cost, if any.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H144D8F78F6164F528A8D6BC8F03707B9"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Fees</header><text>The Assistant Secretary may establish fees at a level sufficient to cover all or a portion of the costs to the Federal Government of making a secured loan under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBBD14E304AD84839A52CBB12A269E56B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Non-Federal share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The proceeds of a secured loan under the BIFIA program, if the loan is repayable from non-Federal funds—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5DA7E76D3832481E9637D88A2D8443C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may be used for any non-Federal share of project costs required under this Act; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2F4F54F30BB459EA8AEFE171DCD36B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not count toward the total Federal assistance provided for a project for purposes of paragraph (9).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F8B4820DC7E45E38C94025A5C8E3884"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Maximum Federal involvement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total Federal assistance provided for a project receiving a loan under the BIFIA program shall not exceed 80 percent of the total project cost.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31B95C9850CA4D22BE14CAE406AD7B07"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Repayment</header>
 <paragraph id="H27EA8F799C1740B0AA23008E0CCCACA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Schedule</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall establish a repayment schedule for each secured loan under this section based on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE1DDFD702AA94D8AA404BD393D768BCF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the projected cash flow from project revenues and other repayment sources; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6031BFCAA77F4CB08D539AC1E04C7157"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the useful life of the infrastructure for the provision of broadband service being financed.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H23BD865AA3A146DC9F44A32A4B697704"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commencement</header><text>Scheduled loan repayments of principal or interest on a secured loan under this section shall commence not later than 5 years after the date of substantial completion of the project.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HC17A06A40A07414F942DDF9BEA9EE353"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deferred payments</header>
 <subparagraph id="H07A072D1527A47E6862B0D17ECCE0F10"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If, at any time after the date of substantial completion of the project, the project is unable to generate sufficient revenues to pay the scheduled loan repayments of principal and interest on the secured loan, the Assistant Secretary may, subject to subparagraph (C), allow the obligor to add unpaid principal and interest to the outstanding balance of the secured loan.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H593DB51044F440089F87252B4CEB76FB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Interest</header><text>Any payment deferred under subparagraph (A) shall—</text> <clause id="H355F2AE700944C43A81427D06EEB8564"><enum>(i)</enum><text>continue to accrue interest in accordance with subsection (b)(4) until fully repaid; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HADEE19F77F2A4EE885506BA1037AC08B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be scheduled to be amortized over the remaining term of the loan.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB925099AECB45509A416FDBA6930D5E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Criteria</header> <clause id="HE28126F7251B4FE3860ECBA730D259D2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any payment deferral under subparagraph (A) shall be contingent on the project meeting criteria established by the Assistant Secretary.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6A1306B1E1A045828F8C44292D740373"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Repayment standards</header><text>The criteria established pursuant to clause (i) shall include standards for reasonable assurance of repayment.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H138759F33191444E836557FDA4C1396C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prepayment</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7D6AC3415EB6432E8D06C0FCC4BC5271"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Use of excess revenues</header><text>Any excess revenues that remain after satisfying scheduled debt service requirements on the project obligations and secured loan and all deposit requirements under the terms of any trust agreement, bond resolution, or similar agreement securing project obligations may be applied annually to prepay the secured loan without penalty.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC18D86FF9C5F4535AC46ADF847B87870"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of proceeds of refinancing</header><text>The secured loan may be prepaid at any time without penalty from the proceeds of refinancing from non-Federal funding sources.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H45025C9B5DAE43528CA38DFD4B3F10B8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sale of Secured Loans</header>
 <paragraph id="H630BA420135A40879C18F49F6FE8B370"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), as soon as practicable after substantial completion of a project and after notifying the obligor, the Assistant Secretary may sell to another entity or reoffer into the capital markets a secured loan for the project if the Assistant Secretary determines that the sale or reoffering can be made on favorable terms.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F0495A6BC9141FB99D145970648C4DE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consent of obligor</header><text>In making a sale or reoffering under paragraph (1), the Assistant Secretary may not change the original terms and conditions of the secured loan without the written consent of the obligor.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4D1E02EDAF7047D49180A806E065BF1A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Loan Guarantees</header>
 <paragraph id="H0AAD8E9D28FD4977861BD6747F668CAC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary may provide a loan guarantee to a lender in lieu of making a secured loan under this section if the Assistant Secretary determines that the budgetary cost of the loan guarantee is substantially the same as that of a secured loan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED587116476D4F61AB516B0202D9C118"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>The terms of a loan guarantee under paragraph (1) shall be consistent with the terms required under this section for a secured loan, except that the rate on the guaranteed loan and any prepayment features shall be negotiated between the obligor and the lender, with the consent of the Assistant Secretary.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H3CAC712DB75F42F5AB90BA458D5E9B32"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Streamlined Application Process</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H1C5F32207DC54838971F82203C60C0C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall develop one or more expedited application processes, available at the request of entities seeking secured loans under the BIFIA program, that use a set or sets of conventional terms established pursuant to this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC020AB494D8B45EB9B73F31712ACFD59"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>In establishing the streamlined application process required by this subsection, the Assistant Secretary may allow for an expedited application period and include terms such as those that require—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE4926AC58CBD4AB0A4F497AE5342C972"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that the project be a small project;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H369CEEA312BA41188331D5148BF8E4A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the secured loan to be secured and payable from pledged revenues not affected by project performance, such as a tax-backed revenue pledge, tax increment financing, or a system-backed pledge of project revenues; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4E3A1B257A7E49C6A73D37EEA490CA5E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>repayment of the loan to commence not later than 5 years after disbursement.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H997AD3E627934509A775BDC48B13AD7C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Lines of credit</header> <subsection id="H17F3663781B049C69A66B8A7386644B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header> <paragraph id="HC1FBFE190E804262BE5944C7BB76C21B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (2) through (4), the Assistant Secretary may enter into agreements to make available to one or more obligors lines of credit in the form of direct loans to be made by the Assistant Secretary at future dates on the occurrence of certain events for any project selected under section 3.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H896914B1C50442A198AFB8E80D1C0B17"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of proceeds</header><text>The proceeds of a line of credit made available under this section shall be available to pay debt service on project obligations issued to finance eligible project costs, extraordinary repair and replacement costs, operation and maintenance expenses, and costs associated with unexpected Federal or State environmental restrictions.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HABE5C2B2344B4A709BC37ED785F0C947"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Risk assessment</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H39284C77ADBB454AA6DFC12BFA9B6923"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), before entering into an agreement under this subsection, the Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget and each rating agency providing a preliminary rating opinion letter under section 3(b)(2)(A), shall determine an appropriate capital reserve subsidy amount for each line of credit, taking into account the rating opinion letter.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H68540C9987BC46A6A6DAED4838EAA3CC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Small projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before entering into an agreement under this subsection to make available a line of credit for a small project, the Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall determine an appropriate capital reserve subsidy amount for each such line of credit, taking into account the alternative documentation provided under section 3(b)(2)(B) instead of preliminary rating opinion letters provided under section 3(b)(2)(A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC5493E93D10B472383C908A9DCC38A11"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Investment-grade rating requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The funding of a line of credit under this section shall be contingent on—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4EF94A1363D048FCB0D851F78716B886"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the senior obligations of the project receiving an investment-grade rating from 2 rating agencies; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB8906C2AA9754B55B72DD439AF4E00FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a small project, the project meeting an alternative standard that the Assistant Secretary shall establish under section 6 for purposes of this paragraph.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB57494D26D6D44D98F7961BF51E431B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms and Limitations</header>
 <paragraph id="H9564F1C5A9234CC5B2BAC8DD2BF6466A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A line of credit under this section with respect to a project shall be on such terms and conditions and contain such covenants, representations, warranties, and requirements (including requirements for audits) as the Assistant Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H558FF089D7264599AF8DB6784FDD77C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum amounts</header><text>The total amount of a line of credit under this section shall not exceed 33 percent of the reasonably anticipated eligible project costs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB78756B9BB10455C882ADA99E5CA8AA0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Draws</header><text>Any draw on a line of credit under this section shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H7B7C826F57A24AD284B4209D5A72CB30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>represent a direct loan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92B2CBCBAAE54B4596B98B0CD4692420"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be made only if net revenues from the project (including capitalized interest, but not including reasonably required financing reserves) are insufficient to pay the costs specified in subsection (a)(2).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFBCCE70532F4E66B473E0C7B213F282"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Interest rate</header><text>The interest rate on a direct loan resulting from a draw on the line of credit shall be not less than the yield on 30-year United States Treasury securities, as of the date of execution of the line of credit agreement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAFA7A84B6865483AAE052780905BB757"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Security</header><text>A line of credit issued under this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H810FDD924D544897A5E83543F12BA5C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall—</text>
 <clause id="H97C2060859394B6F8450BBBEDB5838F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be payable, in whole or in part, from—</text> <subclause id="HEBBE80D9001A49A9B5A727A06D09435D"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">amounts charged to—</text>
 <item id="HC1A8A48227EA4B4699CFB857C487777D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>subscribers of broadband service for such service; or</text> </item><item id="H2D80CA26EE314FA4801D0B6CFFC006AA"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subscribers of any related service provided over the same infrastructure for such related service;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="HBBB7F2F4B85640FBBC30BD60712663CC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>user fees;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H858A3DCE48E0436DBB35A17B89BCEF0C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>payments owing to the obligor under a public-private partnership; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6EA727B5BC404883A267503F1AD03718"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>other dedicated revenue sources that also secure the senior project obligations; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H99E44F223B0F46C18A57D0853D7136A2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include a coverage requirement or similar security feature supporting the project obligations; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1740BD2271984CB4B11544F96A245686"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may have a lien on revenues described in subparagraph (A), subject to any lien securing project obligations.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2129D57769B9444BB5CF0C42B4CF09DA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Period of availability</header><text>The full amount of a line of credit under this section, to the extent not drawn upon, shall be available during the 10-year period beginning on the date of substantial completion of the project.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H2A9A43EF93A4444E8722379F4AD3DC55"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rights of third-party creditors</header>
 <subparagraph id="HFB7F6694141A44DEA8EEF27242B743D1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Against Federal Government</header><text>A third-party creditor of the obligor shall not have any right against the Federal Government with respect to any draw on a line of credit under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50A103B999634167B9BD0FC69F4199B0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assignment</header><text>An obligor may assign a line of credit under this section to—</text> <clause id="H65DEF54A7CDB44A7999EE2E41FAD9C58"><enum>(i)</enum><text>one or more lenders; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8DE0AC4587124D6EA977EE948FECA95A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a trustee on the behalf of such a lender.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H28DA95CF983F486AB0C4547B4CE5F85F"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Nonsubordination</header> <subparagraph id="H684C13E8A22E476F89D19963D3D4B462"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a direct loan under this section shall not be subordinated to the claims of any holder of project obligations in the event of bankruptcy, insolvency, or liquidation of the obligor.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H925522D47C7740E7A25C59CC353E4175"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Pre-existing indenture</header>
 <clause id="H39028B0D89BE4D0DB5855E374DD0AA9D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall waive the requirement of subparagraph (A) for a public agency borrower that is financing ongoing capital programs and has outstanding senior bonds under a preexisting indenture, if—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="HFD7BE2AE87684B47BF41FCFF239CA9A7"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the line of credit—</text> <item commented="no" id="H4B8C2082F1C64584885F29F34AC43F7A"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is rated in the A category or higher; or</text>
 </item><item commented="no" id="HB4C413A2C34343A18E81AEB73F8C4EFE"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in the case of a small project, meets an alternative standard that the Assistant Secretary shall establish under section 6 for purposes of this subclause;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="H1621A1AEA96C4C51910CD6E856C37431"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the BIFIA program loan resulting from a draw on the line of credit is payable from pledged revenues not affected by project performance, such as a tax-backed revenue pledge or a system-backed pledge of project revenues; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H753369CEB44B4A8EAB78BF34C5940E0D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the BIFIA program share of eligible project costs is 33 percent or less.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H57DA50439B6345B89F33E688CA49AEB0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>If the Assistant Secretary waives the nonsubordination requirement under this subparagraph—</text>
 <subclause id="H7A849852D8E5484AA6386C2CC93ED7DE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the maximum credit subsidy to be paid by the Federal Government shall be not more than 10 percent of the principal amount of the secured loan; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB23D4D60C7E94271843DEEDDA120862A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the obligor shall be responsible for paying the remainder of the subsidy cost.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2605031BB7C410E98DFF41D4B5FEB5D"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Fees</header><text>The Assistant Secretary may establish fees at a level sufficient to cover all or a portion of the costs to the Federal Government of providing a line of credit under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE80DF36ECC748A4919790014C02B93F"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Relationship to other credit instruments</header><text>A project that receives a line of credit under this section also shall not receive a secured loan or loan guarantee under section 4 in an amount that, combined with the amount of the line of credit, exceeds 49 percent of eligible project costs.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D1130EA46A147838BA3EC6BA6C6C558"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Repayment</header>
 <paragraph id="HA8458DEB0CF643B0A14910F15132C0C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall establish repayment terms and conditions for each direct loan under this section based on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA609ED3C8DAB400092FEDE08BD34FA04"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the projected cash flow from project revenues and other repayment sources; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H599AEBA16A1143489FA5AD788724E99F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the useful life of the infrastructure for the provision of broadband service being financed.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H59CF66D92E334E2CBB7F655E05551C21"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>All repayments of principal or interest on a direct loan under this section shall be scheduled—</text> <subparagraph id="H88779ECA51F248D7BF75F19E1DA40B79"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to commence not later than 5 years after the end of the period of availability specified in subsection (b)(6); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE18C6DF79444CAC9F4307B4A9D2112C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to conclude, with full repayment of principal and interest, by the date that is 25 years after the end of the period of availability specified in subsection (b)(6).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H339AEE5C9259452F92ED0F8BC83B02C8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Alternative prudential lending standards for small projects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary shall establish alternative, streamlined prudential lending standards for small projects receiving credit assistance under the BIFIA program to ensure that such projects pose no additional risk to the Federal Government, as compared with projects that are not small projects.</text>
		</section><section id="H96DFF3CBFF5D40D59119CCCF7C4E8AC6"><enum>7.</enum><header>Program administration</header>
 <subsection id="H73728731BDB5442CBD46FC1630865EA0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall establish a uniform system to service the Federal credit instruments made available under the BIFIA program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8642FB17E5B4499180D8C2B88D8E3E04"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fees</header><text>The Assistant Secretary may collect and spend fees, contingent on authority being provided in appropriations Acts, at a level that is sufficient to cover—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9D33640FD21B4F1FBEE60D4B9566F493"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the costs of services of expert firms retained pursuant to subsection (d); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC482EB35D4BD41A0B9DDA5F2C6F60ECF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>all or a portion of the costs to the Federal Government of servicing the Federal credit instruments.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C835760D7CD4620A8635B04664E59A5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Servicer</header>
 <paragraph id="H2606AF82E5D1416583ED8A0B815EF537"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary may appoint a financial entity to assist the Assistant Secretary in servicing the Federal credit instruments.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBDD0CE127F894A9FAC38938400234574"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>A servicer appointed under paragraph (1) shall act as the agent for the Assistant Secretary.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H08437D8DD1134246BA6E78A8CBEA23EE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fee</header><text>A servicer appointed under paragraph (1) shall receive a servicing fee, subject to approval by the Assistant Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBCEE173B4E1A47A0A29B4211773A78C2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Assistance From Expert Firms</header><text>The Assistant Secretary may retain the services of expert firms, including counsel, in the field of municipal and project finance to assist in the underwriting and servicing of Federal credit instruments.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2F0EC663B0B94360843DBE55412548F7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Expedited Processing</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall implement procedures and measures to economize the time and cost involved in obtaining approval and the issuance of credit assistance under the BIFIA program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H048CED35DB104EC08B8BBE9AB293A429"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Assistance to Small Projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amount appropriated under section 10(a), and after the set-aside for administrative expenses under section 10(b), not less than 20 percent shall be made available for the Assistant Secretary to use in lieu of fees collected under subsection (b) for small projects.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H3F651380B07C42A5BC542BD0247D6B6F"><enum>8.</enum><header>State and local permits</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The provision of credit assistance under the BIFIA program with respect to a project shall not—</text> <paragraph id="H8A152B0460F04FC1BB6117C0FD9A5044"><enum>(1)</enum><text>relieve any recipient of the assistance of any obligation to obtain any required State or local permit or approval with respect to the project;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D99DFAFA4D449A6ABD6A1645EE88FE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>limit the right of any unit of State or local government to approve or regulate any rate of return on private equity invested in the project; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H67AFF4E5A5B141E28C024DABF117DA24"><enum>(3)</enum><text>otherwise supersede any State or local law (including any regulation) applicable to the construction or operation of the project.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H4045139A61E942B2A3DFD91342F16D6C"><enum>9.</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary may promulgate such regulations as the Assistant Secretary determines to be appropriate to carry out the BIFIA program.</text>
		</section><section commented="no" id="HC48C5A2389624C049D9126F34D5BA9C7"><enum>10.</enum><header>Funding</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H442BB7472C024303A6BFB20FBDF0C0B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Assistant Secretary to carry out this Act $5,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2018, to remain available until expended.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8343225994714335B03D871BCEA052DF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amount appropriated under subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary may use not more than 5 percent for the administration of the BIFIA program.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H99AD272F091D449FAAE018228DC3BF58"><enum>11.</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header>
 <subsection id="H11E1104469E44CCE8A0383078F8EBD38"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Assistant Secretary shall submit to Congress a report summarizing the financial performance of the projects that are receiving, or have received, assistance under the BIFIA program, including a recommendation as to whether the objectives of the BIFIA program are best served by—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAA95B7BE0EFA40E88A03BCE41955A15E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>continuing the program under the authority of the Assistant Secretary; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF775E6AD3ED4914BEB6A2408F4ADCAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishing a Federal corporation or federally sponsored enterprise to administer the program.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H02DB3C584A8248478725CF972580B789"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application Process Report</header>
 <paragraph id="H15F48DD70B83422FB621C450B7E986C3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Assistant Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report that includes a list of all of the letters of interest and applications received for assistance under the BIFIA program during the preceding fiscal year.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H7FEE3A2DF6464D3195861E72BAAFF3F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H57DD6A5475444C09B857DEBDE725255D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each report under paragraph (1) shall include, at a minimum, a description of, with respect to each letter of interest and application included in the report—</text>
 <clause id="H0802E76069AB4C63A6A4C3DB52ECD255"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date on which the letter of interest or application was received;</text> </clause><clause id="H1B037A7532D74D41865D7AD3240F774A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which a notification was provided to the applicant regarding whether the application was complete or incomplete;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF8EEA222AAE441FAAED0E696954FC55F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the date on which a revised and completed application was submitted (if applicable);</text> </clause><clause id="H9D1B6023641C4D8AB1E71A5E3E2D798F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which a notification was provided to the applicant regarding whether the project was approved or disapproved; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC0AFC03975A4476B876D8E2E9EB77B28"><enum>(v)</enum><text>if the project was not approved, the reason for the disapproval.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02C4C3030D164623BE0E6B81C42A9D00"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Correspondence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report under paragraph (1) shall include copies of any correspondence provided to the applicant in accordance with section 3(d).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


