<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H60570746DE2F460FB2B9104FBFFFE176" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2233 IH: American Jobs First Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2233</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170428">April 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000607">Mr. Francis Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to improve the H–1B visa program, to repeal the
			 diversity visa lottery program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE8463CE4A84B408786497D3CC585304C" style="OLC">
		<section id="H4C7FCCBFB9934A7B817A7137E9CD9FF2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="HD88A6AE118484E1797EC43133A6D9627"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Jobs First Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H944D37BD132E4372A58C591CFCC21E08"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H4C7FCCBFB9934A7B817A7137E9CD9FF2" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H20BC0ECC0E224876AD3CAA925841E1ED" level="title">Title I—H–1B Visa Program</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H9475C441EB164613AFEE4D750F97DE5D" level="section">Sec. 101. Amendments to the Immigration and Nationality Act.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H36510A01045144129C2ABC65F74D674A" level="title">Title II—New H–1B Visa requirements</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE1831658454C4584B85DA59E7E52BFCB" level="section">Sec. 201. Bar on nondisparagement and nondisclosure agreements.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HDE9FF3F8241B446E9C787F92A0E30562" level="section">Sec. 202. United States Federal court jurisdiction over civil actions pertaining to misuse of the
			 H–1B visa program.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA626BF47624C4069BA9CB97A1EE7F6B9" level="title">Title III—Repeal of other provisions</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HC7813A435C85495EBE5CB76C72BD4632" level="section">Sec. 301. Repeal of the diversity visa lottery.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
			</subsection></section><title id="H20BC0ECC0E224876AD3CAA925841E1ED" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>H–1B Visa Program</header>
			<section id="H9475C441EB164613AFEE4D750F97DE5D"><enum>101.</enum><header>Amendments to the Immigration and Nationality Act</header>
 <subsection id="H6C67D6445D7B4C57A35064583CA68732"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Inadmissible aliens</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 212(n) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(n)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5548CDB8BB2B42258A363524CD104C2C" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="HC74B9DB6E2BF496098EADA6DB6DFC9BD"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Labor condition application</header>
 <paragraph id="H6A949A5CADB5474A8407F1875D7782EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien may not be admitted or provided status as an H–1B nonimmigrant in an occupational classification unless the petitioner employer has filed with the Secretary of Labor an application stating the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H00E609A3731D4BF1800C7AF79E6D183B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The petitioner employer—</text> <clause id="H497B543CD7964BF0BC1ADD8ED7DE9809"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is offering an annual wage to the H–1B nonimmigrant that is the greater of—</text>
 <subclause id="HA72EF739A1694960B7A728F45F63DD4A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the annual wage that was paid to the United States citizen or lawful permanent resident employee who did identical or similar work during the 2 years before the petitioner employer filed such application; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE76367CA379543D4A9B849975F89E10A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>$110,000, if offered not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>American Jobs First Act of 2017</short-title>, which amount shall be annually adjusted for inflation by July 1 of each year;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H93B68BF3DDEC45B998572014312E4319"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>will not require an H–1B nonimmigrant to pay a penalty for ceasing employment with the petitioner employer before the date agreed to by the H–1B nonimmigrant and the petitioner employer;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H73E55E4411B547B0951A5FD4E069F83F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>will not—</text> <subclause id="HB5605330D2D34C309307D0A48FA6408F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>require an alien who is the subject of a petition filed under paragraph (1) of section 214(c), for which a fee is imposed under paragraph (9) of such section, to reimburse, or otherwise to compensate, the petitioner employer for part or all of the cost of such fee;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H09FA846764D14CE9B439D4AC196BC2AD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>accept reimbursement or compensation for the fee described in subclause (I) from an H–1B nonimmigrant, even if such reimbursement or compensation is alleged to have been voluntarily given by the H–1B nonimmigrant;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFC8CF850EC7D4315A3C29F8D21049E76"><enum>(III)</enum><text>deduct such amounts from an H–1B nonimmigrant's pay before disbursal to such H–1B nonimmigrant for the purpose of covering the cost of such fee; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8E906E932CD748A2BDFB4ECF089CD4D3"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>require an H–1B nonimmigrant to pay any other amounts or fees for housing, vehicle use or rental, equipment use or rental, or other goods or services, unless the requirement of the payment of such amounts or fees is identical to the payments that are required by United States citizen or lawful permanent resident employees; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HC346ADF6FF1640C498F142389753FB1E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>will—</text> <subclause id="H04D83A6C50234EFBA07DE08C4B29C30F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>after the employer has filed an application under this subsection and placed an H–1B nonimmigrant designated as a full-time employee on the petition filed under section 214(c)(1) and the nonimmigrant has entered into employment with the petitioner employer (in nonproductive status due to a decision by the petitioner employer, based on factors such as lack of work or due to the nonimmigrant’s lack of a permit or license), pay the nonimmigrant full-time wages in accordance with paragraph (1)(A) for all such nonproductive time;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HADC47529D26444029CC179B265FF013D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>after the employer has filed an application under this subsection and placed an H–1B nonimmigrant designated as a part-time employee on the petition filed under section 214(c)(1) and the nonimmigrant has entered into employment with the petitioner employer (in nonproductive status under circumstances described in subclause (I)), pay the nonimmigrant for such hours as are designated on such petition in accordance with the rate of pay identified on such petition; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA3A29EE05F77410E8D4EB74E9FAE5646"><enum>(III)</enum><text>after the employer has filed an application under this subsection, offer to an H–1B nonimmigrant, during the nonimmigrant’s period of authorized employment, on the same basis, and in accordance with the same criteria, as the employer offers to United States citizens or lawful permanent residents, benefits and eligibility for benefits, including—</text>
 <item id="H66382C64BC834FE7BD96CF6C2BAE0E19"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the opportunity to participate in health, life, disability, and other insurance plans;</text> </item><item id="H60ECF682E3354E4F8AE03BF4DC4527A5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the opportunity to participate in retirement and savings plans; and</text>
 </item><item id="H542F3083801A4FEAA867D648269B2799"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>cash bonuses and noncash compensation, such as stock options (whether or not such compensation is based on performance).</text>
 </item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE47078E5C4524F43922D5B38585A8798"><enum>(B)</enum><text>With respect to workplace conditions—</text> <clause id="H11A8A565C4D641AEB8507D2FB40A87B9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>there has not been an employee-initiated strike at any point during the 2-year period ending on the date on which the petitioner employer files the visa application that sought redress for salary, wage, or benefit concerns;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H695A360A6A6A4EFFBC9CB5D28116ED91"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>there has not been a petitioner employer-initiated lockout at any point during the 2-year period ending on the date on which the petitioner employer filed such visa application; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF769157B23E24F3ABD207DC96F7FEA27"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>no employee in the same or substantially similar occupational classification for which the employer seeks H–1B nonimmigrants, has been displaced, furloughed, terminated without cause, or otherwise involuntarily separated without cause in any way at any point during the 2-year period ending on the date on which the petitioner employer filed such visa application.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E98B4634EDD4D28850F1864B2770ED1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The petitioner employer, at the time a visa application is filed—</text> <clause id="HAC9B464FC2204C81B5A95E1D0E67741D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has provided notice of the filing under this paragraph to the bargaining representative of its employees in the occupational classification and area for which aliens are sought; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H72D8AC71F59C4404B87A9B39AFC0E7E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if such employees do not have a bargaining representative, has provided notice of filing in the occupational classification through methods such as—</text>
 <subclause id="HCC2B3F7609764FBB8BBC461CA9885CB2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>physical posting in conspicuous locations at the place of employment; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H352F6B992BDA4EF99C5E04AA82B0B0BC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>electronic notification to employees in the occupational classification for which H–1B nonimmigrants are sought.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC1931B250304C74BD9D8B15AE114973"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The application contains—</text> <clause id="HC74965A124F84011AC15E9FBE7955FEA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the specific dollar value of the required wage, in accordance with subparagraph (A);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE4D169ECE50E46D788A789D127B755D8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the specific number of nonimmigrant employees sought; and</text> </clause><clause id="H1DD22596B90E48318BF8A5FA2F713715"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the occupational classification in which the nonimmigrant employees will be employed.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2769CD8E80124730AA59CFE379280000"><enum>(E)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9706DE47B0334B4DB1391FAEB829AD34"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The petitioner employer—</text> <subclause id="H10C7C81400A14D19A74D9BF8C0EDFAD0" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>will not replace a United States citizen or lawful permanent resident with one or more nonimmigrants;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H428E3F202B194D47A6FA7F4B88A9B823" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>will not contract with any third party to provide a nonimmigrant to replace any United States citizen or lawful permanent resident; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H19335082B94E4316AF1DA5A735D3CC63" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>has not displaced, furloughed, terminated without cause, or otherwise involuntarily separated, and will not displace, furlough, terminate without cause, or otherwise involuntarily separate a United States citizen or lawful permanent resident employed by the petitioner employer during the 4-year period beginning on the date that is 2 years before the date on which the petitioner employer filed any visa petition supported by the application.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H13B2397105154D869ED7C56883C85D71" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The 4-year period referred to in clause (i)(III) does not include any period of on-site, remote, teleconference-based, computer-based, or other virtual training of nonimmigrants by or with employees of the petitioner employer.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2719DB35773140159D7AFA52B0B287BE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The petitioner employer will not place an H–1B nonimmigrant employee with another employer (unless the petitioner employer, after diligent inquiry of the other employer, has no knowledge that, during the 4-year period beginning 2 years before the date on which the employee was placed with the other employer, the other employer has displaced or intends to displace a United States citizen or lawful permanent resident employed by the other employer) if—</text>
 <clause id="H52A1520F058E415297DC66B9925A8351"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the employee performs duties, in whole or in part, at one or more worksites owned, operated, or controlled by such other employer; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4E5D45E9D7334BD0A9F72E316ADD04C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>there are indicia of an employment relationship between the nonimmigrant and such other employer.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5FD796D904A43D4A5A6F2E55D92B19F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The petitioner employer, before filing an application under this paragraph—</text>
 <clause id="HF1592105DF2B4A53A43185613ADD0558"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has documented specific steps to recruit potential employees who are United States citizens or lawful permanent residents using mainstream and industry-focused media and online advertising campaigns, and offering wages that are at least as high as the wage requirements established for nonimmigrants in subparagraph (A), in order to recruit such citizens and residents for the job or jobs for which the nonimmigrant or nonimmigrants is or are sought;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAD8D66EE4FD34F708BE2DE9AA0557EA1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has offered the job to any United States citizen or lawful permanent resident who applies and possesses the same or better qualifications for such jobs;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFED2296218264B69B388034D465F4345"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>despite the efforts specified in clauses (i) and (ii), has been unable to hire United States citizens or lawful permanent residents for any of such available jobs;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H88A0F86C17C04557A586E1A79AB26341"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>has not intimidated, threatened, restrained, coerced, blacklisted, discharged, or in any other manner discriminated against an employee (including former employees and applicants for employment) because the employee—</text>
 <subclause id="H251F33EE27AD45429CEF32ED7D349F26"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has disclosed information to the petitioner employer, or to any other person or entity, that the employee reasonably believes evidences a violation of this subsection, or any rule or regulation pertaining to this subsection; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H454ED43DFC1B4E37AF97310246B90846"><enum>(II)</enum><text>cooperated, or sought to cooperate, in an investigation or other proceeding concerning the petitioner employer’s compliance or noncompliance with the requirements under this subsection or any rule or regulation pertaining to this subsection; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H3E7EE96578B940788FFC6A407600CDF6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>has executed a sworn affidavit or other court-recognized statement that—</text> <subclause id="HB30027BF375D450B8EA455E5E51E72BD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>swears or affirms the truth of the information regarding such recruiting efforts; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE4D7E2D0A62A4E078FAA9FE19289E570"><enum>(II)</enum><text>acknowledges that false statements made in such statement will subject the affiant to criminal prosecution under section 1621 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
										</subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA76CBACCBE2F43C3B299CDDDCFC74552"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification and transparency requirements</header>
 <subparagraph id="H19BFEF19DBCB4A9282015FB34CFA62E9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The petitioner employer shall make available for examination its materials relating to its application to the Secretary of Labor in accordance with paragraph (1).</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01B99E32E6B546D6A3A0093D71CECEFB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Internal and external publication of application materials</header>
 <clause id="HA6C4BD9EAFEC492388A22F5CE64FDB1B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Electronic publication</header><text>Not later than 1 business day after the date on which an application is filed in accordance with paragraph (1), the petitioner employer shall—</text>
 <subclause id="H58B56D8211C044C6904BA80F925B8E69"><enum>(I)</enum><text>electronically mail a copy of such application and necessary accompanying documentation to all employees at all business locations and worksites to ensure employer-wide employee awareness of the application; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA2E5E0ABB1BD45688F1AA34CDFA5F8D0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>post an electronic copy of the application and such accompanying documentation as are necessary on a publicly accessible website to ensure public awareness of the application.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HACFC821D53634F0BB8B04E12B6186224"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Physical posting</header><text>Not later than 5 business days after the date on which an application is filed in accordance with paragraph (1), the petitioner employer shall post copies of such application and necessary accompanying documentation in prominent places at all of its business locations and worksites to ensure that all of its employees are aware of the application.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CEB36F892AB4F57914B0F07C1AE3A45"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Failure to provide complete internal and external publication of application materials</header><text>If the Secretary of Labor receives proof that a petitioner employer has failed to meet the publication requirements under subparagraph (B) of any application that is filed in accordance with paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="HD0B8828BD6324FE69A333F91C21DA303"><enum>(i)</enum><text>deny such application; and</text> </clause><clause id="H33AD008CA5C84C01A06D36CE9D767195"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prevent such petitioner employer from filing another such application during the 2-year period beginning on such date of denial.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5B789ABED144D19B69EDA905932479A"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Secretary of labor application transparency obligations</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall—</text> <clause id="HDF23928910664416B9DDF39F71665F4C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>compile and publish on the Department of Labor website, on an ongoing basis—</text>
 <subclause id="H2D9D463589F84AF19F27EE90D7C17688"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the name of the petitioner employer that has filed an application under this subsection;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HE0443026D69D449D981AB25C206D5C58"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the date on which each such petitioner employer filed such application;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H88A7ECF8032145E88F35E7B4DA4C7758"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the number of H–1B visas that have been requested in such application;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HAFD8CB9EF4B54E5E8C0E3DF3517362A5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the sworn affidavit or other court-recognized statement required under paragraph (1)(G)(v); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFC04C0CFC8D343769B21EB36B8E281FD"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the name of the employee or employees who signed or executed the sworn affidavit or other court-recognized statement referred to in subclause (IV);</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H48967760A3F749649AAE6FB8B3726864"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than July 1 of each year, publish the information described in clause (i) for the preceding calendar year in the Federal Register; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFB04B10EFC384E48A30DF1F6E12ABA39"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>not later than July 1 of each year, submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that contains—</text> <subclause id="HC7DFCA254EDB4FDFB076AF53C962EDBF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the information described in clause (i);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7C74D3C1DF6E4008A22A718261C943D7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>information about any petitioner employers whose applications were denied under subparagraph (C);</text> </subclause><subclause id="H5B45CE77B2334364817D1B7473EDF5D1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>information about any ongoing investigations of petitioner employers for potential or determined violations of use of the H–1B visa program;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1480722C470E479D99C8C201B636FCD9"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>any referrals of potential violations of section 1621 of title 18, United States Code, to the Attorney General, as required under paragraph (3)(D)(i);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7EC43EB8DAA443728A0EFE6A5FC46D2E"><enum>(V)</enum><text>any assessments of civil penalties of petitioner employers, as required under clauses (ii) and (iii) of paragraph (3)(D); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEAACD20BC1094FF0BDED84833B634409"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>any additional information that the Secretary of Labor believes may be relevant to future congressional evaluation of the H–1B visa program.</text>
										</subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE68D79A9BB04DC585A1B6694D3F8553"><enum>(3)</enum><header>H–1B application investigations</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0EFCB48DFCFE42FC8B9B9EACE18A86F5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall establish a process for the receipt, investigation, and disposition of complaints respecting—</text>
 <clause id="HFE1ABC01AFF14293BC666C9CC61172B6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a petitioner employer’s failure to meet a condition specified in an application submitted under paragraph (1); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4FDE63A2984D45A788C979C3E5066142"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a petitioner employer’s misrepresentation of material facts in such an application.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8BAC072F1C34D1C8223EDA8D6C750F1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Investigation procedures</header> <clause id="H207270805DED400AB7C5D5F08DC69AC6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Labor may conduct an investigation of any complaint alleged against a petitioner employer—</text>
 <subclause id="H0BDC95078196441A841D9305A0D05B88"><enum>(I)</enum><text>based on the independent judgment of the Secretary;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HC1E088DE44D649D5BE11326B120BC56E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in response to a referral or complaint from the head of another Federal agency; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H159D5A0C4CFB452B8E516A6F0D60BBA4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>through any other method that, in the Secretary’s discretion, shows cause for such an investigation.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HCCB8C573281B4D72A64673694E2DAFB6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Complainants</header><text>A complaint may be filed by any aggrieved party, including—</text> <subclause id="H22BD2B3A89AB4ACEA31C986EFBE886E6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any United States citizen or lawful permanent resident who believes his or her job has been eliminated or could potentially be eliminated as the result of the petitioner employer hiring or seeking to hire a foreign national pursuant to a nonimmigrant visa;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H839E595CE0A24666B8C3B174C159B7E1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any trade association or union that represents any person described in subclause (I); and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H85280C03C86042C5B6646C29A9A49F76"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any foreign national hired for work in the United States pursuant to a nonimmigrant visa who believes he or she is subject to potentially unlawful workplace conditions or requirements.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H62250D3C462B42CAA579A3443F2AB610"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Process for foreign national complainants</header><text>The Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall devise a process under which an H–1B nonimmigrant who files a complaint regarding a violation under this subsection and is otherwise eligible to remain and work in the United States may be allowed to seek other appropriate employment in the United States for a period not to exceed the maximum period of stay authorized for such nonimmigrant classification.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBAC8B4B71C1B4FD28367C32179B7AC62"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Program pause for initiation of investigation</header><text>In any situation in which the Secretary of Labor commences an investigation of a petitioner employer under this paragraph, the Secretary of Labor may—</text>
 <subclause id="H52D4A2A121CE41B9B9E546B6BAB22253"><enum>(I)</enum><text>cease processing any application that is submitted under this subsection and filed by such petitioner employer until the conclusion of such investigation; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H33EE07D4EB1B402D83ABFDE9E0F8AE32"><enum>(II)</enum><text>suspend such petitioner employer’s usage of currently issued H–1B nonimmigrant visas, until the conclusion of such investigation.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88FEFB591CB94C09BE6000E62AF372F7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Initiation of investigation</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which a complaint is filed with the Department of Labor under this paragraph, the Secretary of Labor—</text>
 <clause id="HEF8EE8CEC15743FC9D830685589C8B44"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall determine whether a reasonable basis exists to make a finding under subparagraph (D);</text> </clause><clause id="HCC53E13D1A4D42CC9F2F4E686CD29033"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the date of such determination, shall provide for notice of such determination to the interested parties and an opportunity for a hearing on such determination, in accordance with section 556 of title 5, United States Code;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA5253A0C36804D3A920FFF1C1601D5DF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if such a hearing is requested and held, shall make a finding concerning the matter not later than 30 days after the date of such hearing; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6635F840F96C4AF5836751A3A64BD33A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the case of similar complaints respecting the same petitioner employer, may consolidate the hearings under this subparagraph on such complaints.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H256415CF76D04EC28BBCDA42D9A09FBA"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Penalties</header>
 <clause id="H7EF88F4589C74BF5BEB0C820EB60CBE2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Finding of possible criminal violation</header><text>If the Secretary of Labor, after notice and opportunity for a hearing under subparagraph (C), finds that a petitioner employer made one or more false statements in a sworn affidavit or similar court-recognized statement, the Secretary shall refer such petitioner employer to the Attorney General for criminal prosecution.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDF93FAA0BBD8455E8C930700D7627D70"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Finding of material failure without displacement</header><text>If the Secretary of Labor, after notice and opportunity for a hearing under subparagraph (C), finds that a petitioner employer materially failed to meet a condition required under paragraph (1), the Secretary may—</text>
 <subclause id="H396CFDFFC8C0489FAEFD0FEDF7B7492D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>impose a fine against the petitioner employer that is not less than $50,000 and not greater than $100,000 per violation, which shall be deposited into the general fund of the Treasury;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H37D10EA67A504686AF7650120F30FE0D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>immediately revoke all issued H–1B visas currently being used by the petitioner employer; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HEFE1ED30E4D143F7B484D1F1C6E2BA9B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>prohibit the petitioner employer from applying for additional H–1B visas for a period of not less than 5 years and not more than 10 years.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H6B708632D04F4F4B8352B4220D1A9F64"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Finding of material failure with displacement</header><text>If the Secretary of Labor, after notice and opportunity for a hearing under subparagraph (C), finds that a petitioner employer materially failed to meet a condition under paragraph (1), and, in the course of, or as a result of, such material failure, the petitioner employer displaced a United States citizen or lawful permanent resident employed by the petitioner employer during the period beginning 2 years before the date on which any visa petition supported by the application was filed and ending 2 years after such date, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subclause id="H011FA3CD97B34DB995DFAFA283502455"><enum>(I)</enum><text>impose a fine against the petitioner employer that is not less than $100,000 and not greater than $500,000 per violation, which shall be deposited into the general fund of the Treasury;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB8F242FB0E16449FAE901EE8CF5CA0FD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>immediately revoke all issued H–1B visas currently being used by the petitioner employer;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H762E28B0F6094145A7F0E84168B6F9B3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>permanently bar the petitioner employer from applying for additional H–1B visas; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0995D01ECAEE40A794D32EA7A3C0DD5F"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>require the petitioner employer to provide retroactive compensation for any displaced United States citizen or lawful permanent resident employee.</text>
										</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19FD00B277E14F509E1A413E86F756CE"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Scope of investigative authority</header>
 <clause id="H1C57272C7691471E83E177650A5237E0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Labor may initiate an investigation of any petitioner employer that employs nonimmigrants described in section 101(a)(15)(H)(i)(b) if the Secretary of Labor has reasonable cause to believe that the petitioner employer is not in compliance with this subsection.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4CA09587B4FC430CA2E05D1062010927"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>The Secretary of Labor (or the acting Secretary in case of the absence or disability) shall personally certify that reasonable cause exists to initiate an investigation under this subparagraph. The investigation may be initiated for reasons other than completeness and obvious inaccuracies by the petitioner employer in complying with this subsection.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF8EA5C1D23774C63A1559B66A17100F9"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Use of information</header><text>If the Secretary of Labor receives specific credible information from a source who is likely to have knowledge of a petitioner employer’s practices or employment conditions, or a petitioner employer’s compliance with the petitioner employer’s labor condition application under paragraph (1), and whose identity is known to the Secretary of Labor, and such information provides reasonable cause to believe that the petitioner employer has committed a willful failure to meet a condition under subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (E), (F), or (G)(i), has engaged in a pattern or practice of failures to meet such a condition, or has committed a substantial failure to meet such a condition that affects multiple employees, the Secretary of Labor may—</text>
 <subclause id="H8829458C2E204B78B4379C9ED299FBB4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>conduct an investigation into the alleged failure or failures; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H332CAF999E5143C0B71A77A4604BC049"><enum>(II)</enum><text>withhold the identity of the source from the petitioner employer, which shall not be subject to disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H11C61483362A4F6EA1FC04E218BC945D"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Procedure</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall establish a procedure for any person desiring to provide information described in clause (iii) that may be used, in whole or in part, as the basis for the commencement of an investigation described in such clause, to provide such information in writing on a form developed and provided by the Secretary and completed by or on behalf of the person. Such person may not be an officer or employee of the Department of Labor unless the information satisfies the requirement under clause (v)(II), although an officer or employee of the Department of Labor may complete the form on behalf of the person.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5165B33F6E35447389953DA3A40524D9"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Information sources</header><text>Any investigation initiated or approved by the Secretary of Labor under this subparagraph shall be based on information that—</text>
 <subclause id="H1D831CBF8C9E4DA49F384791BF21969E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>satisfies the requirements under clause (iii); and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HCC5665941885432AA5E3A611E4CF7127"><enum>(II)</enum> <item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H358C6B5092804ADEA30852F7C8A89888"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>originates from a source other than an officer or employee of the Department of Labor; or</text>
 </item><item id="HC38F66A0D9C44D008B0CD55524F6DFB1" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>was lawfully obtained by the Secretary of Labor in the course of lawfully conducting another Department of Labor investigation.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H7C3535E13CCF46EF8CF91E0DC9C9017A"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>The receipt of information by the Secretary of Labor that was submitted by a petitioner employer to the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Secretary of Labor for purposes of securing the employment of a nonimmigrant described in section 101(a)(15)(H)(i)(b) shall not be considered a receipt of information under clause (iii).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE28CFA607CF448FDAF98989573EDA4D2"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>An investigation described in clause (iii) (or a hearing described in clause (ix) based on such investigation) may not be conducted with respect to information about a failure to meet a condition described in clause (iii) unless the Secretary of Labor receives the information not later than 1 year after the date of the alleged failure.</text>
									</clause><clause id="HA32BDE0EAA6F44E6A4A61979A0CC3CDB"><enum>(viii)</enum><header>Notice</header>
 <subclause id="H2A511932F2BB4701B788775016DD7F69"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before initiating an investigation of a petitioner employer under this subparagraph, the Secretary of Labor shall provide notice of the intent to conduct such an investigation to such employer in such a manner, and containing sufficient information, to permit the petitioner employer to respond to the allegations before the investigation is commenced.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0A39FC8FEDBF4EE08F3EEEA703FA1827"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The Secretary of Labor is not required to comply with subclause (I) if the Secretary determines that such compliance would interfere with an effort by the Secretary to secure compliance by the petitioner employer with the requirements under this subsection. There shall be no judicial review of a determination by the Secretary of Labor under this clause.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HABB5BD6604B24EF8A1EDAA7BFDCA40A8"><enum>(ix)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>An investigation under this subparagraph may be conducted for a period of up to 60 days. Not later than 120 days after the Secretary of Labor determines, through an investigation under this subparagraph, that a reasonable basis exists to determine that the petitioner employer has committed a willful failure to meet a condition under subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (E), (F), or (G)(i) of paragraph (1), has engaged in a pattern or practice of failures to meet such a condition, or has committed a substantial failure to meet such a condition that affects multiple employees, the Secretary shall provide for notice of such determination to the interested parties and an opportunity for a hearing in accordance with section 556 of title 5, United States Code. If such a hearing is requested, the Secretary of Labor shall make a finding concerning the matter not later than 120 days after the date of the hearing.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFF70D4E4D2440239B6A248242DDA5E9"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Compliance</header>
 <clause id="H9BFBD0B2425C42E88648D18911838BBF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Good faith attempt</header><text>Except as provided in clauses (ii) and (iii), a person or entity is considered to have complied with the requirements under this subsection, notwithstanding a technical or procedural failure to meet such requirements, if there was a good faith attempt to comply with the requirements.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H79B979D792D945AFAE298F11B6D3DDCF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply if—</text> <subclause id="HD21AB3BBB55542218294B7D5E0EC5FC3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Department of Labor (or another enforcement agency) has explained to the person or entity the basis for the failure;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD1348ADC2F8A485D8C8C08E8ED26F0A9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the person or entity has been provided a period of not less than 10 business days after the date of the explanation to correct the failure; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HBFB8CF2CB0B8447E964E83F62363DE7C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the person or entity has not corrected the failure voluntarily within the period described in subclause (II).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H3592FB0E578C4545959356C08232B4A1"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Penalty avoidance</header><text>A person or entity shall not be assessed fines or other penalties for a violation of the prevailing wage requirements under paragraph (1)(A) if the person or entity establishes that the manner in which the prevailing wage was calculated was consistent with recognized industry standards and practices.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H565E5050976F4128A206A5F36DF1B0B0"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Clauses (i) and (iii) shall not apply to a person or entity that has engaged in, or is engaging in, a pattern or practice of willful violations of this subsection.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4AEFBED827D4157BD8A649F6C3C32B1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to supersede or preempt any other enforcement-related authority under this title, including section 274B, or under any other Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDB326476EA604A75B85A9717AAB21AC4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Admission of nonimmigrants</header><text>Section 214 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8362D25CB11243AE9FCC3FC3D56E98AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>Secretary of Homeland Security</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7CFE5B85DE7A40528CD01880536747BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subsection (b) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H774667B75D7543E084E941A135DB17FF" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HA0753DCDE7E34E10B4F7439F434BE498"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Presumption of status; written waiver</header> <paragraph id="HB6D39F724D05457AAA478F0EB02F18EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Every alien (other than a nonimmigrant described in subparagraph (L) or (V) of section 101(a)(15) and other than a nonimmigrant described in any provision of subparagraph (H) of such section except subclause (b1) of such subparagraph) shall be presumed to be an immigrant until the alien establishes to the satisfaction of the consular officer, at the time of application for a visa, and the immigration officers, at the time of application for admission, that he or she is entitled to a nonimmigrant status under section 101(a)(15).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE7859F5C7E144E0CAF4018DD8E354413"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Restrictions</header><text>An alien who is an officer or employee of any foreign government or of any international organization entitled to enjoy privileges, exemptions, and immunities under the International Organizations Immunities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/288">22 U.S.C. 288</external-xref> et seq.), and an alien who is the attendant, servant, employee, or member of the immediate family of any such alien shall not be entitled to apply for or receive an immigrant visa, or to enter the United States as an immigrant unless the alien executes a written waiver in the same form and substance as is prescribed under section 247(b).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD661A1726CB140578C517821E582F9DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="H2F27912D9B1645CDA010FE8B1DAFC488"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H408D6DE4BC9548CFA929B3238F7B0973"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (9)—</text> <clause id="H36EBED0BED8B401C95A67F837F2E163A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>(excluding</quote> and all that follows through <quote>organization) filing before</quote> and inserting <quote>filing</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEEA44C047FE3430AA42A60347C9EF0AA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>$1,500</quote> and inserting <quote>$10,000</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DE9E7FC523747709544346F983ECAAC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (10);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD11A98CA0174294B88B109108CA6CE9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (11)(A), by striking <quote>or the Secretary of State, as appropriate,</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C5940D4982041A8AEEFDB333366E33B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in paragraph (12)(C), by striking <quote>$500</quote> and inserting <quote>$2,000</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H90F85951E27A4A8E8AFE657F9D6F927C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Employment authorization</header><text>Section 274A(h) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H37B394C4F15E45B28A4E1FD4D79BCDE9" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF04EEFEB8F5D49C7B4BEC85D8D6BF99A"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Employment authorization for aliens no longer engaged in full-time study in the united states</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no alien present in the United States as a nonimmigrant under section 101(a)(15)(F)(i) may be provided employment authorization in the United States pursuant to the Optional Practical Training Program, or any such successor program, without an express Act of Congress authorizing such a program.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H59DD725F23CA406C80F0938175B01D31"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>Section 212 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</external-xref>) is amended by redesignating subsection (t), as added by section 1(b)(2)(B) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/449">Public Law 108–449</external-xref>, as subsection (u).</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="H36510A01045144129C2ABC65F74D674A" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>New H–1B Visa requirements</header>
			<section id="HE1831658454C4584B85DA59E7E52BFCB"><enum>201.</enum><header>Bar on nondisparagement and nondisclosure agreements</header>
 <subsection id="HE26FCDB4891F4D3BA35634A51ABFBB35"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A petitioner employer may not require a United States citizen or lawful permanent resident employee of such petitioner employer to sign any nondisparagement or nondisclosure agreement, regardless of its characterization or label, that conditions receipt of any financial or nonfinancial benefit from the petitioner employer upon the nondisclosure of such petitioner employer's potential misuse of the H–1B visa program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA7426EBA9B2A4D51B9A9A70E59383CA2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Patent or trademark affirmative defense in litigation</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), a petitioner employer, as a defense in litigation, may affirmatively assert that an agreement described in subsection (a) was necessary to prevent the disclosure of any highly technical information that might be related to a pending patent or trademark application.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HDE9FF3F8241B446E9C787F92A0E30562"><enum>202.</enum><header>United States Federal court jurisdiction over civil actions pertaining to misuse of the H–1B visa
			 program</header>
 <subsection id="HDD45CED04D9A4703A25B6B85D73501F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</text> <paragraph id="H201A6DA3D0924E5881F717CECD89AE21"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each United States district court shall have jurisdiction to address civil actions by any person claiming misuse of the H–1B visa program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2000C04B65024AA78107FB4C8B3DF213"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each United States court of appeals shall have jurisdiction to address appeals of civil actions by any person claiming misuse of the H–1B visa program for cases originating within a United States district court within that circuit; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7606BCBB9E1434B90947778A841E52A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Supreme Court of the United States shall have jurisdiction to address appeals of civil actions by any person claiming misuse of the H–1B visa program for cases originating from any United States court of appeals.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H10AE32D49B8F4DDFBBCDFBA7C95D6718"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No exhaustion requirement</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a person shall have standing to pursue a civil action claiming misuse of the H–1B visa program, in accordance with subsection (a), regardless of whether such person has exhausted all administrative remedies in connection with such claims.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H38250003748E4AAB97AF138811FF8712"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to affect or change any of the other jurisdictional, procedural, or administrative rules under title 28, United States Code, other than the specific establishment of jurisdiction of Federal courts, as provided in subsection (a).</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="HA626BF47624C4069BA9CB97A1EE7F6B9" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Repeal of other provisions</header>
 <section id="HC7813A435C85495EBE5CB76C72BD4632"><enum>301.</enum><header>Repeal of the diversity visa lottery</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title II of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HDE9216B4641E4D8EAA4CEFB23400CE18"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 201(a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA91082AE40E94050BCC9FBDFAEA838B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA824A16C50634F6CA6A4B7D346C22222"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a period; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAF529B1E38E403FB279248D468C4606"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3);</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H26C20A25CA614F96BA99369F91514DE1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 203—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA3176EE7F18146358A0E645C35323958"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subsection (c); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFA639DA43AC45A497D7BBA91CFD101C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text>
 <clause id="H56C2EDF3E6834DAD9DE9EEDC2426FE33"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2); and</text> </clause><clause id="HC107E611CC4546C9B2F687797D93B70B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (2); and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BF093B6463946F7843A907A70B8EA51"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 204(a)(1), by striking subparagraph (I).</text> </paragraph></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

