<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H7DD582E2EF204FE0B6B8655C695774EC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3122 EH: Veterans Care Financial Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3122</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to include on the internet website of the Department of Veterans Affairs a warning regarding dishonest, predatory, or otherwise unlawful practices targeting individuals who are eligible for increased pension on the basis of need for regular aid and attendance, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="HB1C3B520295840F69479CAE68CD72009">
<section id="H05B3805218024295BF53D850F164FEB5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Care Financial Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEFED402E3BB343A3AD601D8A2E9F240C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Secretary of Veterans Affairs notice of dishonest, predatory, or otherwise unlawful practices targeting individuals who are eligible for increased pension on basis of need for regular aid and attendance</header> <subsection id="HD89EE93FDFB34D17B6623DFBD3483FF9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notice required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall include on the internet website of the Department of Veterans Affairs a warning to veterans relating to dishonest, predatory, or otherwise unlawful practices targeting individuals who are eligible for increased pension under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/15">chapter 15</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, on the basis of need for regular aid and attendance.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H46AD84EEEB7F4095B22067333E4956B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO study</header>
<paragraph id="HC62343AF9016423D9A05E5271F066E2A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study required</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall complete a study on financial exploitation of veterans. Such study shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H474B74FDD7A04A3FA28E30A434C627D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the types of standards used by Federal and State agencies intended to protect vulnerable populations from financial exploitation; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6EF163DD39A2479F8AECB85945B5A5A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the types of financial exploitation facing veterans who are eligible for increased pension under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/15">chapter 15</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, on the basis of need for regular aid and attendance and any gaps in efforts to address these issues.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73F7D415B6AB4C6DB59512948C053243"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header> <subparagraph id="HD964E4381D3D4706A23F9AF83780736E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Preliminary report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a preliminary report on the study required under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC69F0B2FE7BE4106ADB20F0E3F1253D0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a final report on such study.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20171106" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives November 6, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

