<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCEA448B828154092A66D8CE72F96FC9D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3588 IH: Regionally Empowered Decision-making for Snapper, Noting the Angling Public and the Preservation of an Exceptional Resource Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3588</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000577">Mr. Graves of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001289">Mr. Byrne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to provide for management of
			 red snapper in the Gulf of Mexico, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9C906A9DF24645A4B7F5B2F616D2EF9E" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3F9C1674207D4A27AA059328BD65E1C9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Regionally Empowered Decision-making for Snapper, Noting the Angling Public and the Preservation of an Exceptional Resource Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RED SNAPPER Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="HED38BB34FA464373A51CC525A341FAA0"><enum>2.</enum><header>State exclusive fishery management authority over private recreational red snapper fishing seasons
			 in the Gulf of Mexico</header>
 <subsection id="H93FE147DDA7B45108275C11675BD367D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 407 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1883">16 U.S.C. 1883</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (d) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HF914B2B9C5304F4AA4C13C5CF1421380" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HCB0F7F2090E74877B89B3ED56A766571"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Catch limits</header><text>Any fishery management plan, plan amendment, or regulation for the red snapper fishery that is submitted by the Gulf of Mexico Fishery Management Council after the date of the enactment of the RED SNAPPER Act shall contain conservation and management measures that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9C8B4C05EF52462083D43C88EFDF89BC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish separate catch limits for each of—</text> <subparagraph id="HAA3DB8F3ABFD407F9741579C9C7B91AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>private recreational fishing;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6285F62A72C47E986E3A4C3963B75B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>federally permitted charter fishing; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AB31C0DA92046BD9BA0C76AB9B1B438"><enum>(C)</enum><text>commercial fishing; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H41CABD2124954493862396CF469394A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that such catch limits reflect allocations among such sectors and do not reflect any harvests in excess of such allocations.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H49B7AFC333424FF6A3308C12B91ADE88"><enum>(e)</enum><header>State exclusive authority over private recreational red snapper fishing seasons in the Gulf of
			 Mexico</header>
						<paragraph id="H97B6BBB47D874FC8BE52FCAAAF750DF1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exclusive authority</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2A2D8D2596A64B16B46C153B17D6D1F3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B) and paragraph (5), and subject to paragraph (4) and section 306(b), each of the Gulf States shall have exclusive authority to establish for each of fishing years 2018 through 2024 the timing and duration of the fishing season for private recreational fishing of red snapper in the Gulf of Mexico in the extended red snapper management zone of such Gulf State under paragraph (2).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36B2C17C213644A08DE2F3264479FE8C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule for Florida</header><text>With respect to the State of Florida, the exclusive authority provided under subparagraph (A) shall apply only to waters adjacent to the State of Florida in the Gulf of Mexico.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA12A812E09674F379688DD8A9D663B34"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extended red snapper management zone described</header>
 <subparagraph id="H208BDD5513E9475BA443A0C62B5B5022"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the extended red snapper management zone of a Gulf State consists of all waters that are—</text>
 <clause id="HA950A76A91C94A2682D7D4F7DA77C161"><enum>(i)</enum><text>seaward of the State seaward boundary of such Gulf State;</text> </clause><clause id="HF2E122FFDCBE487EB90818F8A35E1B4C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not further from shore than the 25-fathom line described under subparagraph (B); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0188947C4D5442B6B80D09AD347154C5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>between the projected lines determined for that State under section 4(a)(2)(A) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1333">43 U.S.C. 1333(a)(2)(A)</external-xref>).</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76E612E451104555ABBE5F5E059FC0F3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Description of line</header>
 <clause id="H722DAFCDC9F342D2A0FECA508EF6BAF7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>RED SNAPPER Act</short-title> and subject to clause (ii), the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register and make available on the website of the Department of Commerce a description of, and map showing, a continuous line in waters of the exclusive economic zone in the Gulf of Mexico along the coasts of the Gulf States, that is comprised of points that are, on average, 25 fathoms in depth.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H10B14CBCDC8D4459BD79D32033FD70F2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Minimum distance</header><text>No point on such continuous line shall be less than 25 nautical miles from the shore.</text> </clause><clause id="H50E1188F52D84F0DAB66C52B82F0FEF3"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Consultation with States</header><text>In determining the placement of such continuous line, the Secretary shall consult with appropriate agencies of each Gulf State.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA9CE0A7ABB34989BBB6D2FAED3474D0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>In determining a fishing season under this subsection, a Gulf State shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HE4FBBEF15A0147F3A1A3D7293EAF0720"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, ensure sustainable and responsible fishery management consistent with the national standards for fishery conservation and management in section 301; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA617A4E72E064FD0877E50294DF19D15"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include—</text> <clause id="HA6CB12390D164B0586565DDB03009881"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the most recent stock assessment for the red snapper in the Gulf of Mexico;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDEEFD02FB66C474EADD613B17047AEE9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>surveys of red snapper in the Gulf of Mexico certified under subsection (g);</text> </clause><clause id="H7632941301E74A11A2E48201C09B45D1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>data related to red snapper in the Gulf of Mexico collected by the Gulf States Marine Fisheries Commission, nongovernmental organizations, and nongovernmental sources, including fishermen, universities, and research institutions;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H38EC4E2D8F2C4660B7A1186094B3F10C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>consideration of the duration of the fishing seasons for red snapper within the State’s seaward boundary;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H53A53FCE132F4E7AA15D68347D50ABA0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>estimates of private recreational fishing effort and catch rates both within the State’s seaward boundary and within the State’s extended red snapper management zone under paragraph (2)(A); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2CCEC4F8C60A47DBBD455C26951256C2"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>relevant data from independent biological surveys, including State population estimates of the biomass of red snapper within the State’s seaward boundary and within the State’s extended red snapper management zone under paragraph (2).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F18D06EC62E44189FFA2E2435C228F3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation with respect to charter fishing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority of a State under paragraph (1) does not apply with respect to the timing or duration of the charter fishing season.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H361E8FCBA395407D9CBA7A40573DF78B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretarial action to address adverse effects of State actions</header><text>For purposes of section 306(b)(1), the extended red snapper management zone of a State under this subsection shall be treated as within the boundaries of such State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H50E65953E4F348D99C96BF893AC47AA2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 150 days before the end of the 2024 fishing year and biannually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives detailing the health of the red snapper fishery in the Gulf of Mexico. The report shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H614041B5F4804354A51A235BF027CCB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be based upon the boundaries prescribed in paragraph (2);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19F78316BA94412A871FABF3180C9ACC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describe the impact of the criteria listed under paragraph (3); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D980193B0C440E0A764CCDA20EB0ADD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include results of the NOAA Fisheries Southeast Region head boat surveys.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0888F18D67214BAFBB73730AAA194BB7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Relationship to other Federal authority and requirements</header><text>Nothing in this subsection affects the authority of the Secretary under any other provision of law—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE6FE4C52DB1347A799C8CDC08E470535"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to establish the acceptable biological catch and total allowable catch of red snapper in the Gulf of Mexico; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H762E67E2E07E48E9A4360ADBF0424988"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to establish any limited access privilege program for the commercial harvest of red snapper in the Gulf of Mexico.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C5A58BA26A849F4BAC583957CA5944E"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Relationship to State authority over State waters</header><text>Nothing in this subsection affects the authority of a Gulf State over the territorial waters of such State and fishing in such waters.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H68E4CED1AE7841AC92AB976061CB5893"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H5BFB3D8B749F40F5B17089277EA146E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>United States sovereign rights to fish and fishery management authority</header><text>Section 101(a) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1811">16 U.S.C. 1811</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>102,</quote> and inserting <quote>102 and section 407(e),</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2D4D08E215046E9A454A31C36750A8A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gulf Council</header><text>Section 302(a)(1)(E) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1852">16 U.S.C. 1852(a)(1)(E)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>paragraph (3)).</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (3) of this subsection and section 407(e)).</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H51AFA18FAAB04E21809DB600309AF1BE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Extension of State seaward boundary</header><text>Section 407 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1883">16 U.S.C. 1883</external-xref>) is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HA971D4363FF54573AC4474FC65217C95" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H6ADB5C1AA1E74534A2DB6571E08C386F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>State seaward boundary</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for the purpose of management of red snapper fisheries in the Gulf of Mexico, the seaward boundary of a Gulf State is a line 9 nautical miles seaward from the baseline from which the territorial sea of the United States is measured.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H858347C8623945ED8EC7920B977E42F4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal Gulf of Mexico red snapper management</header>
 <subsection id="H3E113D2FF2E9455DABD155696C375C19"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allocations of percentage of total allowable catch and seasons for other sectors</header><text>Section 407 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1883">16 U.S.C. 1883</external-xref>) is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H7784042E93A54583A0A3D894DE8975E4" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H7EAE67B06E954C7AA8FC755FAEA232BD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Acceptable biological catch, total allowable catch, and certified State surveys; allocation</header>
 <paragraph id="H29F23727F58D49F2B4CE104B5AA7A489"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inclusion of certified State surveys</header><text>In establishing the acceptable biological catch and total allowable catch for red snapper in the Gulf of Mexico, the Secretary shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA3909BD6780940DB9CBF289B5D9D955F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Gulf State recreational fisheries surveys that are certified under subsection (h); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8EE03D047074A22B316E1C2793FD482"><enum>(B)</enum><text>data related to red snapper in the Gulf of Mexico collected by the Gulf States Marine Fisheries Commission, nongovernmental organizations, and other nongovernmental sources, including universities and research institutions.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E3AC9278F2440DD845B5EFCCAE4D43F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocation and duration of commercial and federally permitted charter season</header><text>Beginning in fishing year 2018, the percentage of the total allowable catch of red snapper, and the duration of the red snapper fishing season in the Gulf of Mexico—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H29D2D47F78BA4026B16A203FC0085E27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the commercial fishing sector shall be the same as such percentage and duration, respectively, that applied for the most recent fishing year, unless amended by the Secretary; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07E423C9F5D046018264D370C47591B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for the federally permitted charter fishing sector may not be less than the allocation and duration that applied to such sector for the most recent fishing year, unless amended by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF34BFFF1E7514121B0B43A0C48C0D78E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fishing by federally permitted charter sector within Gulf State seaward boundaries</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to authorize limiting fishing for red snapper by the federally permitted charter sector within a Gulf State’s seaward boundary in any period in which such fishing in the exclusive economic zone is not prohibited.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4978D86D1A9E430DA265AE225949D3EC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State surveys</header><text>Section 407 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1883">16 U.S.C. 1883</external-xref>) is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HE8219C9022C44012B099C03AB74BE2BF" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H53F4ABAF8A40483B9EE34CFFBD1A8908"><enum>(h)</enum><header>State surveys</header>
 <paragraph id="H4E3AAE974A07440B9A9F87F523BA8122"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>A Gulf State that conducts a recreational fisheries survey in the Gulf of Mexico to make catch estimates for red snapper landed in such State may submit such survey to the Secretary for certification.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H9874BC7691684797A9047208AD024BC1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification</header>
 <subparagraph id="H5F7FDD1FA7C24BF0819F3C74A790DDEF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall make a certification or a denial of certification for any survey submitted under paragraph (1) not later than the end of the 6-month period beginning on the date the survey is submitted.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47ECBE2C8A744DC4B0E288FBB1228833"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deemed certified</header><text>A recreational fisheries survey is deemed to be certified effective upon the expiration of such period if the Secretary has not made a certification or denial of certification.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD156CD7454454CBE864137375BC1608D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Modification of surveys denied certification</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD04139E321354E87B44E6A22D323A771"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a survey of a Gulf State is denied certification under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall, not later than 60 days after the date of the denial, provide the Gulf State a proposal for modifications to the survey.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF201DC04AE0842C0A6236D00DE5CCEC3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Proposal</header><text>A proposal provided to a Gulf State for a survey under subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="HB72C210E8C9E44799119EEA41E67E671"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be specific to the survey submitted by such Gulf State and may not be construed to apply to any other Gulf State;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5E3A654DDD824E27BA914A22C9654FF7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall require revision to the fewest possible provisions of the survey; and</text> </clause><clause id="H5FB77BBFF86B48BB851C765A72AF2EF7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>may not unduly burden the ability of such Gulf State to revise the survey.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H258FCFEDE77E4528A64CFCB7F76E0CF7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Modified survey</header>
 <clause id="H37DCD39763514A47B326C20C58A9E15B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authority to submit</header><text>If a survey of a Gulf State was denied certification under paragraph (2), the Gulf State may modify the survey and submit the modified survey to the Secretary for certification or denial of certification.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD376BC8D0F664F0F90601D02F01BEFB5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Schedule</header><text>The Secretary shall make a certification or denial of certification for any modified survey not later than the end of the 30-day period beginning on the date the modified survey is submitted.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE8304328429940CD93684B8DA7929000"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Deemed certified</header><text>A modified survey is deemed to be certified effective upon the expiration of the period described in clause (ii) if the Secretary has not made a certification or denial of certification.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB2895A4BAB66420982BB3B1405E77DDC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reduction of barotrauma</header><text>Section 407 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1883">16 U.S.C. 1883</external-xref>) is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HD93DA643AA6B42FF90B29B3A21473BC0" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H516571EC430B45F69950889443003F2E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reduction of barotrauma</header><text>Each Gulf State shall develop and promote best practices for use in the red snapper fishery in the Gulf of Mexico to reduce barotrauma.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCC83194325B24B6CBE40EAE7593D3BEA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Section 407 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1883">16 U.S.C. 1883</external-xref>) is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H8A414230D1D8464CAB563A78BEE491B5" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H0F81B43965834874BBC4735D508B75D0"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to alter—</text> <paragraph id="HC7C5A5E7EB454F7BA219C2C93E50E294"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any commercial catch share program for Gulf of Mexico red snapper;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FE046EED9C1450A8ADE16673A3AC398"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any Federal program related to charter fishing; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H16FF9E5EAA184FEC953996A0DFD0DBF4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the fishing gear that may be used in the red snapper fishery in the Gulf of Mexico.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBCCBD490DAB8407880E76D77DC3C3A0E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 407 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1883">16 U.S.C. 1883</external-xref>), as amended by this section, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H7EDAFE342FD94C6A9F92A58EA288CDEE" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HCBE57E97EA4F47248E90C08AB8E4FC64"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H9FA78A9D1E8A4644B094219F0D4F27A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Gulf State</header><text>The term <quote>Gulf State</quote> means each of the States of Texas, Louisiana, Mississippi, Alabama, or Florida.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9E0A76117CA4BAABD203010D4FFF421"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Red snapper</header><text>The term <quote>red snapper</quote> means the species Lutjanus campechanus.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section><section id="H3FA5C43884464F9BBFB6390A7D9B8BDA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that in order to supplement State data collection efforts, Gulf States should continue modernizing fishery harvest data for red snapper through the development and implementation of voluntary electronic reporting applications for use by the private recreational fishing sector to determine red snapper catch rates and effort in the Gulf of Mexico.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


