<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H169474283A9949298F6E3D013383D805" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1513 IH: Social Security Must Avert Identity Loss (MAIL) Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1513</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170313">March 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000174">Mr. Sam Johnson of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000586">Mr. Renacci</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To restrict the inclusion of social security account numbers on documents sent by mail by the
			 Social Security Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3E1EA69BF2844F3E81FB1BE029D45C5D" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7800E3C6C43B4C53A7D2E96FFD23DA4A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Social Security Must Avert Identity Loss (MAIL) Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0D1474F5C89D4120B3BDE6D190B68911"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restriction on social security account numbers in documents sent by mail</header> <subsection id="HE587DB80FC3C4319A33EDE0BE2356847"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 205(c)(2)(C) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/405">42 U.S.C. 405(c)(2)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8A0E3F1521948818810AD5DF0F0F2A9" style="OLC">
					<clause id="H1DEA3F5AA15D43FCAD3AB8C091BAF021" indent="up3"><enum>(xiv)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H20680E8B994D405D8BD358EE2E3645F4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Commissioner of Social Security shall ensure that no document sent by mail by the Social Security Administration includes a complete social security account number unless the Commissioner determines that inclusion of such complete number is necessary.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA66E5D87BF5441F8B321E4381946B995" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this clause and not later than each of March 31 and September 30 of each of the first 6 years following the year in which such date of enactment occurs, the Commissioner of Social Security shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on the implementation of subclause (I). Such report shall include—</text>
 <item id="H62D9A855E476447AAA1340E66F88E7BC"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the title and identification number of each document used by the Social Security Administration during the previous year on which is printed an individual’s complete social security account number;</text>
 </item><item id="H04B44AABE9574BF5B80A03EC9F1334FD"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the most recent date on which each such document was updated; and</text> </item><item id="H6E24C6A0DAFB46EFAEE9E4143CF4D498"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the projected date on which complete social security account numbers will be removed from each such document, or if the Commissioner determines that inclusion of such complete number is necessary, the rationale for such determination.</text></item></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC077536A57024601B4DA87FD2DD8AC21"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of Social Security shall implement the amendments made under subsection (a) as soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


