<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAA33DF767B374B2882C827D68A1AB5B4" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3159 IH: Family Business Preservation Estate Tax Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3159</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170629">June 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reduce the taxable estate by the value of certain
			 family-owned business interests.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1D1A58464C434357A48FB17214BFA0B8" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF88CA6A841534712901A21AA7A7AACE7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Family Business Preservation Estate Tax Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H81EFD764232E4F05B7C2C440F375C28A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Taxable estate reduced by value of certain family-owned business interests</header> <subsection id="H7CC7C00494B744C3A75C04D60C8DA89B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 2056A the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAEB6C6EE46B04D7F8BE886FDBB403402" style="OLC">
					<section id="H7B94490C90A142C6993DA70CCC3884EB"><enum>2057.</enum><header>Family-owned business interests</header>
						<subsection id="H00AF71996F134507AE85426E51D269E0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header>
 <paragraph id="H9781D158E52E42E99797320A6DF7F264"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Allowance of deduction</header><text>For purposes of the tax imposed by section 2001, in the case of an estate of a decedent to which this section applies, the value of the taxable estate shall be determined by deducting from the value of the gross estate the adjusted value of the qualified family-owned business interests of the decedent which are described in subsection (b)(2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H414FC392B7AF4C509B6D741B0AB8AC50"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum deduction</header><text>The deduction allowed by this section shall not exceed the greater of—</text> <subparagraph id="HA5472D79EDE246E1B5F8030DE1A7B4EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the basic exclusion amount in effect under section 2010(c)(3) for the calendar year which includes the date of the death of the decedent, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H042AD2FCA0CF4A7B91A2A7BDF862DEDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the value of any qualified farmland which constitutes the qualified family-owned business interest (in the case of an entity described in subsection (e)(1)(B), qualified farmland held by such entity shall be treated as constituting a qualified family-owned business interest in the same proportion as the decedent’s ownership interest in such entity).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD77971E874894E319248C20A0D54AB6F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified farmland</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (2)(B), the term <quote>qualified farmland</quote> means qualified real property as defined in section 2032A(b) applied without regard to paragraph (2)(B) thereof.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H04793374E1CA435E8581915BC2A98E66"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Estates to which section applies</header>
 <paragraph id="H63B7D874DF7F45CA9D0FB92982D1E28E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This section shall apply to an estate if—</text> <subparagraph id="HAC22C97DB7D24401A9C9235069155704"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the decedent was (at the date of the decedent’s death) a citizen or resident of the United States,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFDAC788CE534401A1606992BA2C10A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the executor elects the application of this section and files the agreement referred to in subsection (h),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57277D73DF99469FB455D9C8D29CE748"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the sum of—</text> <clause id="H391C159249FF46C49A2A605D265C23E4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the adjusted value of the qualified family-owned business interests described in paragraph (2), plus</text>
 </clause><clause id="H781CA53253294C9388C25063D8AEC601"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of the gifts of such interests determined under paragraph (3),</text> </clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">exceeds 50 percent of the adjusted gross estate, and</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H637C9CA1F3A24AFFA3F85D8994902418"><enum>(D)</enum><text>during the 8-year period ending on the date of the decedent’s death there have been periods aggregating 5 years or more during which—</text>
 <clause id="H949161D7AD254F6692149F9E6FD87D57"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such interests were owned by the decedent or a member of the decedent’s family, and</text> </clause><clause id="H5AF5FD8413674E51A0D6C005D3AC6169"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>there was material participation (within the meaning of section 2032A(e)(6)) by the decedent or a member of the decedent’s family in the operation of the business to which such interests relate.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE71B9031FBF451E9DA1EE60AD3734FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Includible qualified family-owned business interests</header><text>The qualified family-owned business interests described in this paragraph are the interests which—</text> <subparagraph id="HC5D3B314E6714AA6B2F838597FCF9706"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are included in determining the value of the gross estate, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H364A3F660E5B43AB929EF86707F0B123"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are acquired by any qualified heir from, or passed to any qualified heir from, the decedent (within the meaning of section 2032A(e)(9)).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBD01D6686044BBC8FEFF4526BF32CE7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Includible gifts of interests</header><text>The amount of the gifts of qualified family-owned business interests determined under this paragraph is the sum of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD3B6BBD51A2D4480810BF5E61B24B148"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount of such gifts from the decedent to members of the decedent’s family taken into account under section 2001(b)(1)(B), plus</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5FC165D4D6E49CCB9D6F6515D9AD888"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount of such gifts otherwise excluded under section 2503(b),</text> </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">to the extent such interests are continuously held by members of such family (other than the decedent’s spouse) between the date of the gift and the date of the decedent’s death.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E920AA73EC245E88FBDCD7358842FEF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Adjusted gross estate</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>adjusted gross estate</quote> means the value of the gross estate—</text>
 <paragraph id="H280D5A366FE74A60A09D9B691175067E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reduced by any amount deductible under paragraph (3) or (4) of section 2053(a), and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7FE220362C1E48AA9ADA3FD1E259F37D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increased by the excess of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAF4691C2752B414CA1FF8C4A8A2802B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the sum of—</text> <clause id="H0AD88B7E56A34DB0AAEB59C5452E993F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of gifts determined under subsection (b)(3), plus</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1C76DD8AF11D45709A351E67574889EF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount (if more than de minimis) of other transfers from the decedent to the decedent’s spouse (at the time of the transfer) within 10 years of the date of the decedent’s death, plus</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD9E5C982EB5F4EAFB22CB7C432B91DEF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the amount of other gifts (not included under clause (i) or (ii)) from the decedent within 3 years of such date, other than gifts to members of the decedent’s family otherwise excluded under section 2503(b), over</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54F6EAB4E1E04C6DBB3368483A9C1C19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the sum of the amounts described in clauses (i), (ii), and (iii) of subparagraph (A) which are otherwise includible in the gross estate.</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">For purposes of the preceding sentence, the Secretary may provide that de minimis gifts to persons
			 other than members of the decedent’s family shall not be taken into
 account.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H890E5183000C47ABACA60AEE0345D82A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Adjusted value of the qualified family-Owned business interests</header><text>For purposes of this section, the adjusted value of any qualified family-owned business interest is the value of such interest for purposes of this chapter (determined without regard to this section), reduced by the excess of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H04217FF1BBB24676903E6A4AA59498A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any amount deductible under paragraph (3) or (4) of section 2053(a), over</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H260EB10B6AD849D4A1227CF457ADA9C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the sum of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB8E5DACAD7BA4792B9690AEAF3B82C35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any indebtedness on any qualified residence of the decedent the interest on which is deductible under section 163(h)(3), plus</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C67118C457D44A292EE0B4A63F4804B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any indebtedness to the extent the taxpayer establishes that the proceeds of such indebtedness were used for the payment of educational and medical expenses of the decedent, the decedent’s spouse, or the decedent’s dependents (within the meaning of section 152, determined without regard to subsections (b)(1), (b)(2), and (d)(1)(B) thereof), plus</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C3886A145444C3B899426421522AFB4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any indebtedness not described in subparagraph (A) or (B), to the extent such indebtedness does not exceed $10,000.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7B4EF2F215314C83A89DF27D97F7EE83"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Qualified family-Owned business interest</header>
 <paragraph id="HB3A68516920F4FBD9FF0E8FAF5714AE8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>qualified family-owned business interest</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H24C6C29C1E804070AF2E1F5DFEB7EFBD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an interest as a proprietor in a trade or business carried on as a proprietorship, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB77ECDF3F874ABCBC1FF4F4597F7DF3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an interest in an entity carrying on a trade or business, if—</text> <clause id="HC1013805BE414848927E7A149F9C997D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at least—</text>
 <subclause id="HAB3C8971E8F942638A8DEAADE4FDC3EF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>50 percent of such entity is owned (directly or indirectly) by the decedent and members of the decedent’s family,</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEA34194E6835464F9EBEC50C3C458CD9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>70 percent of such entity is so owned by members of 2 families, or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H86DB94772B004066BF1F79F495ED6282"><enum>(III)</enum><text>90 percent of such entity is so owned by members of 3 families, and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H3647B4CC0EB448D693D2BA9D64BB9C39"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for purposes of subclause (II) or (III) of clause (i), at least 30 percent of such entity is so owned by the decedent and members of the decedent’s family.</text>
									</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">For purposes of the preceding sentence, a decedent shall be treated as engaged in a trade or
			 business if any member of the decedent’s family is engaged in such trade
 or business.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8ACB0D18665E4C6BAC1D0F0E06763299"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Such term shall not include—</text> <subparagraph id="HFC6523A5D4BC4B1EBA23F7175BFE68D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any interest in a trade or business the principal place of business of which is not located in the United States,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5D3697555B847249F386DF54F024C6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any interest in an entity, if the stock or debt of such entity or a controlled group (as defined in section 267(f)(1)) of which such entity was a member was readily tradable on an established securities market or secondary market (as defined by the Secretary) at any time within 3 years of the date of the decedent’s death,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70E085DEA2C3433DAF9651A2B4B9B7D5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any interest in a trade or business not described in section 542(c)(2), if more than 35 percent of the adjusted ordinary gross income of such trade or business for the taxable year which includes the date of the decedent’s death would qualify as personal holding company income (as defined in section 543(a) without regard to paragraph (2)(B) thereof) if such trade or business were a corporation, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53EC38FB1B8648EF8901624E88282947"><enum>(D)</enum><text>that portion of an interest in a trade or business that is attributable to—</text> <clause id="H70A1F661DB054495B5EBE5402AD8469C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>cash or marketable securities, or both, in excess of the reasonably expected day-to-day working capital needs of such trade or business, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H682BB054FBDC45DF8CADBCEA7ECDF5BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other assets of the trade or business (other than assets used in the active conduct of a trade or business described in section 542(c)(2)), which produce, or are held for the production of, personal holding company income (as defined in subparagraph (C)) or income described in section 954(c)(1) (determined without regard to subparagraph (A) thereof and by substituting <quote>trade or business</quote> for <quote>controlled foreign corporation</quote>).</text>
									</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">In the case of a lease of property on a net cash basis by the decedent to a member of the
			 decedent’s family, income from such lease shall not be treated as personal
			 holding company income for purposes of subparagraph (C), and such property
			 shall not be treated as an asset described in subparagraph (D)(ii), if
			 such income and property would not be so treated if the lessor had engaged
			 directly in the activities engaged in by the lessee with respect to such
			 property.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A8D47929DCE407C887BC482CB88A658"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rules regarding ownership</header>
 <subparagraph id="HEDD7E0FCCBCA45D28E1B39AE8F37C53E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Ownership of entities</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)(B)—</text> <clause id="HEC33063ADE6B414EA93353B2339554F9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Corporations</header><text>Ownership of a corporation shall be determined by the holding of stock possessing the appropriate percentage of the total combined voting power of all classes of stock entitled to vote and the appropriate percentage of the total value of shares of all classes of stock.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H43966C27A20E43438791B4C3891AAF9F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text>Ownership of a partnership shall be determined by the owning of the appropriate percentage of the capital interest in such partnership.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B8A5C4CFAAF44E8A6A881511167F76C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ownership of tiered entities</header><text>For purposes of this section, if by reason of holding an interest in a trade or business, a decedent, any member of the decedent’s family, any qualified heir, or any member of any qualified heir’s family is treated as holding an interest in any other trade or business—</text>
 <clause id="H19E70D18652D4671942F00E4205D4A72"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such ownership interest in the other trade or business shall be disregarded in determining if the ownership interest in the first trade or business is a qualified family-owned business interest, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H21FA44F1712E4A1495CBD87A73B8FE94"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>this section shall be applied separately in determining if such interest in any other trade or business is a qualified family-owned business interest.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FFBE34A5CC34045A7537F08D1C68260"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Individual ownership rules</header><text>For purposes of this section, an interest owned, directly or indirectly, by or for an entity described in paragraph (1)(B) shall be considered as being owned proportionately by or for the entity’s shareholders, partners, or beneficiaries. A person shall be treated as a beneficiary of any trust only if such person has a present interest in such trust.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBCE4A17CBD9A4698B0355FB7AE153B12"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Tax treatment of failure To materially participate in business or dispositions of interests</header>
 <paragraph id="H3659AF8713994418B80FAEFBF0EE7873"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is imposed an additional estate tax if, within 10 years after the date of the decedent’s death and before the date of the qualified heir’s death—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBF5A352FA8F94889B208427234AA2DD2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the material participation requirements described in section 2032A(c)(6)(B) are not met with respect to the qualified family-owned business interest which was acquired (or passed) from the decedent,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC57F43B2BB2433282ED251D525A234A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the qualified heir disposes of any portion of a qualified family-owned business interest (other than by a disposition to a member of the qualified heir’s family or through a qualified conservation contribution under section 170(h)),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B769780AAE64DE9B7D49F3610AFE0B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the qualified heir loses United States citizenship (within the meaning of section 877) or with respect to whom an event described in section 877(e)(1) occurs, and such heir does not comply with the requirements of subsection (g), or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H173155F8AA34465C9DC8160248254772"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the principal place of business of a trade or business of the qualified family-owned business interest ceases to be located in the United States.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC596813D7544848B6CA252E59A7193E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional estate tax</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB42CCA9048254301BC0DCD2767C95140"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount of the additional estate tax imposed by paragraph (1) shall be equal to—</text> <clause id="HF29539DB3EEA445CBD723EC3FBF0B4B4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the applicable percentage of the adjusted tax difference attributable to the qualified family-owned business interest, plus</text>
 </clause><clause id="HABDAD2F59BBA4A09877275306D34459B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>interest on the amount determined under clause (i) at the underpayment rate established under section 6621 for the period beginning on the date the estate tax liability was due under this chapter and ending on the date such additional estate tax is due.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA6BF56527A14A0485643F8427B125A7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the applicable percentage shall be determined under the following table:</text>
									<table align-to-level="section" blank-lines-before="1" colsep="0" frame="none" line-rules="no-gen" rowsep="0" rule-weights="0.0.0.0.0.0" table-template-name="Flush/hang, 1 text, 1 num, bold hds" table-type="Leaderwork"><tgroup cols="2" rowsep="0"><colspec coldef="txt" colname="column1" colwidth="231pts" min-data-value="55"></colspec><colspec align="justify" coldef="fig" colname="column2" colwidth="190pts" min-data-value="5"></colspec><thead><row><entry align="left" colname="column1" morerows="0" namest="column1" rowsep="0"><bold>If the event described in <linebreak></linebreak> paragraph (1) occurs in the <linebreak></linebreak> following year of material <linebreak></linebreak> participation:</bold></entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" morerows="0" namest="column2" rowsep="0"><bold>The applicable <linebreak></linebreak>percentage is:</bold></entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">1 through 6</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">100</entry></row><row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">7</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">80</entry></row><row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">8</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">60</entry></row><row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">9</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">40</entry></row><row><entry align="left" colname="column1" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr">10</entry><entry align="right" colname="column2" rowsep="0">20.</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96A8BFD984BE4A0B84E4370166B4F72A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Adjusted tax difference</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="H4E31A5475B26469AA55F7A9FCF636F78"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The adjusted tax difference attributable to a qualified family-owned business interest is the amount which bears the same ratio to the adjusted tax difference with respect to the estate (determined under clause (ii)) as the value of such interest bears to the value of all qualified family-owned business interests described in subsection (b)(2).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H716C181AE40B49849088B46B2A7A2E9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Adjusted tax difference with respect to the estate</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the term <quote>adjusted tax difference with respect to the estate</quote> means the excess of what would have been the estate tax liability but for the election under this section over the estate tax liability. For purposes of this clause, the term <quote>estate tax liability</quote> means the tax imposed by section 2001 reduced by the credits allowable against such tax.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H23980A23835D4921A6A85D44135A2A85"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use in trade or business by family members</header><text>A qualified heir shall not be treated as disposing of an interest described in subsection (e)(1)(A) by reason of ceasing to be engaged in a trade or business so long as the property to which such interest relates is used in a trade or business by any member of such individual’s family.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9CBF629C000D4372B9BC71B08C5D5276"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Security requirements for noncitizen qualified heirs</header>
 <paragraph id="H258903BADA63447287B958BDE7A9D358"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except upon the application of subparagraph (F) of subsection (i)(3), if a qualified heir is not a citizen of the United States, any interest under this section passing to or acquired by such heir (including any interest held by such heir at a time described in subsection (f)(1)(C)) shall be treated as a qualified family-owned business interest only if the interest passes or is acquired (or is held) in a qualified trust.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3569A56CF1684C639707FA94EBA88EED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified trust</header><text>The term <quote>qualified trust</quote> means a trust—</text> <subparagraph id="H8FF312975A444E64BFCB926E5582D905"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which is organized under, and governed by, the laws of the United States or a State, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5672DBC32834988BF12110E72A43979"><enum>(B)</enum><text>except as otherwise provided in regulations, with respect to which the trust instrument requires that at least 1 trustee of the trust be an individual citizen of the United States or a domestic corporation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD01D5760D3B495899D970A8168DB9AC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Agreement</header><text>The agreement referred to in this subsection is a written agreement signed by each person in being who has an interest (whether or not in possession) in any property designated in such agreement consenting to the application of subsection (f) with respect to such property.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HACFAF00D615246B0BDCD59C153C379C6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Other definitions and applicable rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H141C6589D54340A8A6FBF33B3C478DF3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified heir</header><text>The term <quote>qualified heir</quote>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE3FBE801ED5948DE9A88FFECCC93964F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given to such term by section 2032A(e)(1), and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25273B0BE8A44C5F90D09380CB0A1F47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any active employee of the trade or business to which the qualified family-owned business interest relates if such employee has been employed by such trade or business for a period of at least 10 years before the date of the decedent’s death.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H536C22FA250A477D9B65E3839F0CCBC5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Member of the family</header><text>The term <quote>member of the family</quote> has the meaning given to such term by section 2032A(e)(2).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDF4EA770B8346A08ABF06E2D334106A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicable rules</header><text>Rules similar to the following rules shall apply:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5FD680ACA6FC4987AD2E15D029D32FCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 2032A(b)(4) (relating to decedents who are retired or disabled).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3972D9B3CD840B197E849A1159809C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 2032A(b)(5) (relating to special rules for surviving spouses).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18BD8C6658294A329CC5A7E54C851234"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 2032A(c)(2)(D) (relating to partial dispositions).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1C132D4663F4F898DB56D9561FFF6EE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Section 2032A(c)(3) (relating to only 1 additional tax imposed with respect to any 1 portion).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34C3E4FC0CF8495098841A492421864E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Section 2032A(c)(4) (relating to due date).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0039E424ED3B43229A5F3E84278B9552"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Section 2032A(c)(5) (relating to liability for tax; furnishing of bond).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33A7DF7BBA084CBBB6EE4B3BE532D5D9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Section 2032A(c)(7) (relating to no tax if use begins within 2 years; active management by eligible qualified heir treated as material participation).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82FC21B35DF846C482C4B7B1F32E8952"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Section 2032A(d) (relating to election; agreement).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94E923F6D3DF4300A85DFA4379489F78"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Section 2032A(e)(10) (relating to community property).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A289584D9ED4585A59097F3C0B936E2"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Section 2032A(e)(14) (relating to treatment of replacement property acquired in section 1031 or 1033 transactions).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55044CE52C9C4B1AA711A796E4FF21F2"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Section 2032A(f) (relating to statute of limitations).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2659084FE16403C9A2988AED67F61F6"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Section 2032A(g) (relating to application to interests in partnerships, corporations, and trusts).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA8EB19C3D4740969594F24A1888321B"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Subsections (h) and (i) of section 2032A.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98A6C6D254EB458DBF34A69860E18243"><enum>(N)</enum><text>Section 6166(b)(3) (relating to farmhouses and certain other structures taken into account).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11CFBFFB3B654493A92E86E0CA834F7B"><enum>(O)</enum><text>Subparagraphs (B), (C), and (D) of section 6166(g)(1) (relating to acceleration of payment).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9CECD9DB91849438A1EE44DC011A9C6"><enum>(P)</enum><text>Section 6324B (relating to special lien for additional estate tax).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H1E81548C0893497A8531A9949E20D6D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H7E5DEF19E7F341FA94A3AE68873ED941"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 2031(c)(10) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>(as in effect before its repeal)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF501DAE5147949A5B7FEBAD4AA0FE734"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for part IV of subchapter A of chapter 11 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 2056A the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7714FB6BF50B4158A2C5A86E409E0ADC" style="OLC">
						<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="HAEB6C6EE46B04D7F8BE886FDBB403402" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="H7B94490C90A142C6993DA70CCC3884EB" level="section">Sec. 2057. Family-owned business interests.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4B265ADA06144645BB90972DBC1CE02A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to the estates of decedents dying after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


