<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB864938253EB4EAFB705B727D224E9A0" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4173 RH: Veterans Crisis Line Study Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 295</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4173</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–400]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20171031">October 31, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks of Indiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001074">Mr. Hollingsworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HVR00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20171107">November 7, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="G000582">Miss González-Colón of Puerto Rico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001284">Mrs. Brooks of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000108">Mr. Visclosky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001077">Mr. Coffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000066">Mr. Young of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</cosponsor></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20171107">November 7, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on October 31, 2017</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to conduct a study on the Veterans Crisis Line.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HVR00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HCBAF16A5565F41FBB8CC47DC2BB5AEF0" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9299B076FEF848D792E218E76D7A6D41" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Crisis Line Study Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA96894EF68DB447C9914F4ED0E04774D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on efficacy of Veterans Crisis Line</header> <subsection id="H8C8D54BDC47048B9A27E90ED9C5C1FA7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall conduct a study on the outcomes and the efficacy of the Veterans Crisis Line during the five-year period beginning January 1, 2014, based on an analysis of national suicide data and data collected from the Veterans Crisis Line.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3A8E379D08874C6AA51E7E9487D99A52"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters included</header><text>The study under subsection (a) shall address the following:</text> <paragraph id="HAF245B6D1C60487A9B886F3A5D513EE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The efficacy of the Veterans Crisis Line in leading veterans to sustained mental health regimens, by determining—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0059F0C2B80A4399857198A2D0405B3F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of veterans who, after contacting the Veterans Crisis Line and being referred to a suicide prevention specialist, begin and continue mental health care furnished by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE0D4E705D254CE492CB8B0F311BB011"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of veterans who, after contacting the Veterans Crisis Line and being referred to a suicide prevention specialist, either—</text>
 <clause id="HD7A3DA9503E34281BA9D3C9E7DB47189"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">begin mental health care furnished by the Secretary but do not continue such care; or</text> </clause><clause id="HEBBB7A3B4B36475D9381E31A51730C9F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>do not begin such care.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2EAB1E5073C4979AF223D9B69465716"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The visibility of the Veterans Crisis Line, by determining—</text> <subparagraph id="H19CDAF083F4247A689ED12E7ACB288D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of veterans who contact the Veterans Crisis Line and have not previously received hospital care or medical services furnished by the Secretary; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32DD50FF18A14FFEB06AD8802B34EB46"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of veterans who contact the Veterans Crisis Line and have previously received hospital care or medical services furnished by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H984963B8C46F4506A0597AF5C9481306"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The role of the Veterans Crisis Line as part of the mental health care services of the Department, by determining, of the veterans who are enrolled in the health care system established under section 1705(a) of title 38, United States Code, who contact the Veterans Crisis Line, the number who are under the care of a mental health care provider of the Department at the time of such contact.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H52FE20725C744CA5ABFB545EEE54FA4E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether receiving sustained mental health care affects suicidality and whether veterans previously receiving mental health care furnished by the Secretary use the Veterans Crisis Line in times of crisis, with respect to the veterans described in paragraph (3), by determining the time frame between receiving such care and the time of such contact.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H768C765F5E77415297FAC6A89523C0DF"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The effectiveness of the Veterans Crisis Line in assisting veterans at risk for suicide when the Veterans Crisis Line is contacted by a non-veteran, by determining, of the number of non-veterans who contact the Veterans Crisis Line looking for support in assisting a veteran, how many of such individuals receive support in having a veteran begin to receive mental health care furnished by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H78B118BFA15F468C9CAD1BF39BC8EAB7"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The overall efficacy of the Veterans Crisis Line in preventing suicides and whether the number of contacts affects the efficacy, by determining—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H336A2786FA4E4A269CD05EB132426329"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of veterans who contact the Veterans Crisis Line who ultimately commit or attempt suicide; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09E8B927943546D29BDCCC93DCEE1BF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>of such veterans, how many times did a veteran contact the Veterans Crisis Line prior to committing or attempting suicide.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8AB70F59409492CB415C44231FAF54B"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The long-term efficacy of the Veterans Crisis Line in preventing repeated suicide attempts and whether the efficacy is temporary, by determining, of the number of veterans who contacted the Veterans Crisis Line and did not commit or attempt suicide during the following six-month period, the number who contacted the Veterans Crisis Line in crisis at a later time and thereafter did commit or attempt suicide.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC67F7664BBEB455FB88B100D69F239CA"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether referral to mental health care affects the risk of suicide, by determining—</text> <subparagraph id="H8E233DD3B14E4B29A2A20EDA86476575"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of veterans who contact the Veterans Crisis Line who are not referred to, or do not continue receiving, mental health care who commit suicide; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DCDCBB1CF7D4664A8ED5EDA9BAD23BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of veterans described in paragraph (1)(A) who commit or attempt suicide.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H173365227D6E44BAB4E680B26FCD5C16"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The efficacy of the Veterans Crisis Line to promote continued mental health care in those veterans who are at high risk for suicide whose suicide was prevented, by determining, of the number of veterans who contacted the Veterans Crisis Line and did not commit or attempt suicide soon thereafter, the number that begin and continue to receive mental health care furnished by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B7570D5CDC1450B8C9BF8A6AF0A5909"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such other matters as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBD1E98CC5F0A403EB1807EAC635714D6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction regarding data collection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to modify or affect the manner in which data is collected, or the kind or content of data collected, by the Secretary under the Veterans Crisis Line.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1E2ED0CEED554DAA95909EFA48DDFE62"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than March 1, 2020, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate the study under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB8AF80A45D81422294E88DC0273F723B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Veterans crisis line defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Veterans Crisis Line</term> means the toll-free hotline for veterans established under section 1720F(h) of title 38, United States Code.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date date="20171107">November 7, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


