<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF7A290AD031048E2B094B7FEA5193F8E" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2897 RH: To authorize the Mayor of the District of Columbia and the Director of the National Park Service to enter into cooperative management agreements for the operation, maintenance, and management of units of the National Park System in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 323</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2897</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–436, Parts I and II]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170613">June 13, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>December 4, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported from the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>December 5, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="B001250">Mr. Bishop of Utah</cosponsor></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>December 5, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union  and ordered to be
			 printed</action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To authorize the Mayor of the District of Columbia and the Director of the National Park Service to
			 enter into cooperative management agreements for the operation,
			 maintenance, and management of units of the National Park System in the
			 District of Columbia, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H841BADA795FD4376A2ABB558AA1EB48F" style="OLC">
		<section id="H82E8698A25F04C898CC826F518E8F0E8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Authorizing cooperative management agreements between District of Columbia and National Park
			 Service for operation, maintenance, and management of units of the
			 National Park System in the District of Columbia</header>
 <subsection id="H325D882B246145AA9D911CDA9A17EAAC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Mayor of the District of Columbia and the Director of the National Park Service may enter into cooperative management agreements under section 101703 of title 54, United States Code, for the operation, maintenance, and management of units of the National Park System located in the District of Columbia, including the design and construction of improvements to such units.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5F6BF31F3FD34109914BC0E1898D72D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>A cooperative management agreement entered into under this section may include such terms and conditions as may be agreed to by the Mayor and Director, including terms and conditions relating to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF78064A207CC4055896EFC66652F63FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the allocation of responsibility for the operation, maintenance, and management of a unit of the National Park System between the District of Columbia and the National Park Service; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E2DD851B63349A98B16FF3B4B8CE4CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the payment of funds by the National Park Service and the District of Columbia in support of the agreement.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1994630A21194B32979BFDCCEBD75796"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relation to other laws</header>
				<paragraph id="H04B4A700D529486BA6E0309D5FFCD1CF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Treatment of District of Columbia as a State for purposes of cooperative management agreements
 under title 54</header><text>Section 101703 of title 54, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7DA8A061D51545BC84285C9376DE7C70" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H2498E3CD3C8949CE89E3E462961B859E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition of State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this section, the term <term>State</term> means each of the several States and the District of Columbia.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A86CFCB439B41F1A95D6F50B8A4A1B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Anti-Deficiency Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in subchapter III of chapter 13 or subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/15">chapter 15</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Anti-Deficiency Act</quote>) may be construed to prohibit the payment or use of funds by the District of Columbia or the National Park Service to carry out a cooperative management agreement entered into under this Act, in accordance with the terms and conditions of the agreement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H23BF5191DF2C46208A28675FE0866873"><enum>(3)</enum><header>District of Columbia Home Rule Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in section 602(a)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act (sec. 1–206.03(a)(3), D.C. Official Code) may be construed to prohibit the District of Columbia from operating, maintaining, or managing a unit of the National Park System in accordance with the terms and conditions of a cooperative management agreement entered into under this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date date="20171205">December 5, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


