<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF764A33CEE6B438E849742A6FD051020" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4328 IH: Honoring World War I Memorials Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4328</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171109">November 9, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make grants for the rehabilitation of World War I
			 memorials.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H61F0B5D544F34853957B393B41779229" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4B1E69D496FB43AEB793F1BF38B018B3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may cited as the <quote><short-title>Honoring World War I Memorials Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4BC205CF534F4A17A76E9FE34B2206E5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purpose</header> <subsection id="H8D64DE90C21B4A038FD2C60B1FFF7432"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB412F821712C4E4B9BDCB0A9E5B2C139"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From 2014 through 2018, the United States and nations around the world mark the centennial of World War I, including the entry of the United States into the war in April 1917.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD804DE05EE494B44981AFDF641C8392B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The United States entry into the war marked the first time in the history of the United States that American soldiers went abroad in defense of liberty against foreign aggression and it marked the true beginning of the <quote>American Century</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1414F72C388848F3A0D73EA44FC4402E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>More than 4,000,000 men and women from the United States served in uniform during World War I and the United States suffered 375,000 casualties, including 116,516 deaths.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H719F3FEC5ABC42BC84EE1AA92B8452B5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In 2013, the World War I Centennial Commission Act was signed into law with a stated goal of ensuring <quote>a suitable observance of the centennial of World War I</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7CC62ACC193465F8E6A3ECC208E5954"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Part of the Centennial Commission’s stated mission is to <quote>bring attention to the thousands of World War I memorials in communities across the country that honor Americans who served in the war</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFCDDABDEFA174FB9A3441B7A7B039C97"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Centennial Commission has found that <quote>across the country there are local World War I memorials in thousands of cities and towns that are forgotten and in disrepair</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF20DF0B19F341B4989F97BC7B7E8645"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Centennial Commission has found sufficient cause to establish a matching grant program in recognition of the importance of rehabilitating World War I memorials. However, the grant amount of $2,000 is too low for the needs of many memorials.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2368486338624E9D8200073C8D9921D3"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Centennial Commission recognizes that restoring World War I memorials honors those who served and raises awareness of this momentous event in the Nation’s history.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD2FD5BAB5A434D3BA2804EAA4EF6B4CF"><enum>3.</enum><header>World War I memorial rehabilitation grant program</header>
 <subsection id="HDC15601DA342447F893D55723ED5849E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall make grants to eligible entities for the purpose of rehabilitating World War I memorials.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7BA9831038CC4C8F9D840B19E5AC87DF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, an entity shall—</text> <paragraph id="HC6B5422ADA27463FB1E019D9F2085FD7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be a nonprofit organization or a State or local government entity that owns or manages a World War I memorial; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A458D851CB8481180AD2F4FCA8A14A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary an application containing such information and assurances as the Secretary may require, including a description of the rehabilitation project for which the entity seeks a grant under this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA260B7B9614400B835212EA7D786806"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection of grant recipients</header><text>In selecting recipients of grants under this section, the Secretary shall prioritize, in descending order, the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HE6D33870D4CB41D9A58D050609E6D73D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Entities seeking grants to rehabilitate World War I memorials listed on the National Register of Historic Places.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4DE35E010D024A5F960DADDA313A9078"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Entities seeking grants to rehabilitate World War I memorials listed on a State register of historic places.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5385227F83A461198FAE35566CAF524"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>The recipient of a grant under this section shall use the grant to rehabilitate a World War I memorial.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H17935CC7D981464EBF9F842368B31088"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Amount of grant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each grant provided under this section shall be in an amount that does not exceed $15,000,000, and 50 percent of the cost of the rehabilitation project described in the application submitted by the eligible entity to which the grant is provided.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8DC47FF0B4E24957BBFFE91A0F7E81DD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs $50,000,000 for fiscal year 2018 to make grants under this section. Amounts appropriated pursuant to such authorization of appropriations shall remain available until expended.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD74B2FDCF30D4667A52A18D1D097B7E6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H0F479C86DE044AFFBA0A8718F3950F26"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rehabilitate</term> means, with respect to a memorial, to repair, reconstruct, restore, refurbish, or clean up the memorial consistent with the Secretary of the Interior’s Standards for the Treatment of Historic Properties (36 C.F.R. 68) and applicable guidelines.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HECAD010F36524A8F99C2EFE7101B457C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>World War I memorial</term> means a memorial that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs determines is dedicated to the memory of those who served in World War I, and does not include any memorial to members of the Armed Forces serving in multiple wars.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


