<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE654E7F3C64D421E9D1A306D6366CA6F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 530 IH: SECURE Our Democracy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 530</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170113">January 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000480">Mrs. Lowey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001111">Mr. Crist</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To expose and deter unlawful and subversive foreign interference in elections for Federal office,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HAE346E7FF26E4BF5A20DFFA7A7AC8039" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2EE3F30359234593AB51DB514F7338C0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safeguard our Elections and Combat Unlawful Interference in Our Democracy Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>SECURE Our Democracy Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H95CE1538B3434C86B72BE49F2F0D641E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H033DE3CC3191492AA51879AD57E63BFD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admitted; alien</header><text>The terms <term>admitted</term> and <term>alien</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H714304A74482485899C36254D134E4F9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H30856ADF4AC44BB1A15F3470000D5CD2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the House of Representatives—</text>
 <clause id="H921EBD7871FD4324BF787D9104BEF9E1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs;</text> </clause><clause id="HE2C7D059B0BD4BEB9C24F5AC5D0F7C85"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5FAD0F25B81942A680910145D200FFC4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Committee on Financial Services;</text> </clause><clause id="H421932C2EA4F469F88A6B32847FE1815"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1B52B10E2FB54B0BA832ADB051038550"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9B25548F3FC43199A6A0C7B486FFA55"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the Senate—</text>
 <clause id="HD819B834C7C14BCC9E41BAC280BD8334"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations;</text> </clause><clause id="H261E5BCA41134C7294890AC0C52AE4A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFB625786C3CA4B65BE4E1B256846585C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs;</text> </clause><clause id="H15B056F7633B435090CB4816D85216B2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H654BDF7A6C4546B88FF6D5700EE14C3F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the Select Committee on Intelligence.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E7630DEBE8A47F9A09DA08AE3CBA962"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Financial institution</header><text>The term <term>financial institution</term> has the meaning given such term in section 5312 of title 31, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1724273C85E44A11BBE5B18F19505E95"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <quote>foreign person</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HF1F25D49087E4E9EB74B91F59236065B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a natural person who is not a United States person under paragraph (5)(A); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECCBC4C96A42440B8FE408109E88786D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a foreign entity or foreign government.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4791FAEE5E5244A0868680FB27416681"><enum>(5)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1F60BB4A6B2B49FF934FBBA5C66CF65C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA572CFB40A134A5C999EBAB35E1A6E3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="H10325136CF1C413E9B590E6EFA797566"><enum>3.</enum><header>Identification of foreign persons responsible for actions to unlawfully access, disrupt, influence,
			 or in any way alter information or information systems related to United
			 States political parties or elections for Federal office</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H52072B3674F84D0787DF3B1B4B59070B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a list of each foreign person that the Secretary, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, determines—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HDCDCB72730AC4576A09A2D5383DE35D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was, at any time since January 1, 2015, involved in actions to unlawfully access, disrupt, misappropriate, influence, or in any way alter information or information systems related to United States political parties, candidates in elections for Federal office, or the administration of elections for Federal office; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H323FC3E3F07043EA92BC52646D2F6557"><enum>(2)</enum><text>worked or acted as an agent or instrumentality of or on behalf of or was otherwise associated with such a foreign person in a matter relating to an action described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HDD5A9085E4FE4D04AEADE779B3D03DB3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an update of the list required under subsection (a) as new information becomes available.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6F7A621EE7C345CE9A9505F2FBF72413"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H17671E449A9A445A91F77611CAB4E1D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the list required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3E7222322DF84236A5C2B0D1FA31EDD3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The name of a foreign person to be included in the list required under subsection (a) may be submitted in a classified annex only if the Secretary of State—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H12E7649BCAD842E3A8FDC5A9B4E0FFE8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determines that it is in the national security interests of the United States to do so; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE0E9264505254BD1899EAB565A5A88D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>15 days prior to submitting any such name in such a classified annex, provides to the appropriate congressional committees notice of, and a justification for, including or continuing to include any such foreign person in any such classified annex despite any publicly available information indicating that such foreign person is described in paragraph (1) or (2) of such subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA90B225E5A6042688A745F4FF48A7EC7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability; Nonapplicability of confidentiality requirement with respect to visa records</header><text>The unclassified portion of the list required under subsection (a) shall be made available to the public and published in the Federal Register, without regard to the requirements of section 222(f) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1202">8 U.S.C. 1202(f)</external-xref>) with respect to confidentiality of records pertaining to the issuance or refusal of visas or permits to enter the United States.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE9A68866F8024863A563050417AF9E52"><enum>4.</enum><header>Inadmissibility of certain aliens</header>
 <subsection id="HB27F282A61EF4B2E981057CB59B1837F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas</header><text>An alien is ineligible to receive a visa to enter the United States and ineligible to be admitted to the United States if such alien is a foreign person on the list required under section 3(a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDA6B54B98E0549E7AEC1FCC4D8BA6D68"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><text>The Secretary of State shall revoke, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), the visa or other documentation of any alien who is a foreign person on the list required under section 3(a) and who would therefore be ineligible to receive such a visa or documentation under subsection (a) of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H1734924FDBA24DCDB2D0D4CCE4B8D2C2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability to foreign entities and foreign governments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (a) and (b) of this section shall apply to aliens who are officials of, agents or instrumentalities of, working or acting on behalf of, or otherwise associated with a foreign entity or foreign government that is a foreign person included on the list required under section 3(a) if such aliens are determined by the Secretary of State to have knowingly authorized, conspired to commit, been responsible for, engaged in, or otherwise assisted or facilitated the actions described in such section 3(a).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H586837D23261415EA33A2E574B3D3158"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver for national security interests</header>
 <paragraph id="H82974286D47F4CADB5E770E0D41AC022"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State may waive the application of subsection (a) or (b) in the case of an alien if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H24FF8DD33B6844EA8768DF2F252C7D9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that such a waiver—</text> <clause id="HA133A14D2D58448AA4287708C903E45C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement between the United Nations and the United States of America regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, or other applicable international obligations of the United States; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H082242D737FC443EA5235817EC127A27"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is in the national security interests of the United States; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6462862BF0274AE091BC206FA770B11B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prior to granting such a waiver, the Secretary provides to the appropriate congressional committees notice of, and a justification for, such waiver.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EDC7801F2AD400597EC253776754265"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing for certain waivers</header><text>Notification under subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1) shall be made not later than 15 days prior to granting a waiver under such paragraph if the Secretary of State grants such waiver in the national security interests of the United States in accordance with subparagraph (A)(ii) of such paragraph.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA9A6911971454AE99441FCB5EDD0C600"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text>The Secretary of State shall prescribe such regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H9B9B7831301C43CEAA0A94D208C8B525"><enum>5.</enum><header>Financial measures</header> <subsection id="HBE27EC09F3DD4A9BA9B3A850C24D916C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Freezing of assets</header> <paragraph id="HAD8169465FF34AC7A79072EEE02A85E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President, acting through the Secretary of the Treasury, shall exercise all powers granted by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) (except that the requirements of section 202 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>) shall not apply) to the extent necessary to freeze and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of a foreign person that is on the list required under section 3(a) of this Act if such property or interests in property are in the United States, are or come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2A62D75030764DC3AE04D91842B25867"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability to foreign entities and foreign governments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall apply to aliens who are officials of, agents or instrumentalities of, working or acting on behalf of, or otherwise associated with a foreign entity or foreign government that is a foreign person included on the list required under section 3(a) if such aliens are determined by the President, acting through the Secretary of the Treasury, to have knowingly authorized, conspired to commit, been responsible for, engaged in, or otherwise assisted or facilitated the actions described in such section 3(a).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D5EAE811741432B9E8DC8366B9EA232"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver for national security interests</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury may waive the application of subsection (a) if the Secretary determines that such a waiver is in the national security interests of the United States. Not less than 15 days prior to granting such a waiver, the Secretary shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees notice of, and a justification for, such waiver.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H00EB9FA3CFC747748872FACBE89E8738"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header>
 <paragraph id="H5D7B6BF730A141F7A45E7167F392CD39"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A foreign person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this section or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out this section shall be subject to the penalties specified in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of such section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE2A1538C75FC465887FF8E88FACE6DCE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability to foreign entities and foreign governments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall apply to aliens who are officials of, agents or instrumentalities of, working or acting on behalf of, or otherwise associated with a foreign entity or foreign government that is a foreign person included on the list required under section 3(a) if such aliens are determined by the President, acting through the Secretary of the Treasury, to have knowingly authorized, conspired to commit, been responsible for, engaged in, or otherwise assisted or facilitated the actions described in such section 3(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD43EB376387349DFB32E7C038ECAD907"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements for financial institutions</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President, acting through the Secretary of the Treasury, shall prescribe or amend regulations as needed to require each financial institution that is a United States person and has within its possession or control assets that are property or interests in property of a foreign person that is on the list required under section 3(a) if such property or interests in property are in the United States, are or come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person to certify to the Secretary that, to the best of the knowledge of such financial institution, such financial institution has frozen all assets within the possession or control of such financial institution that are required to be frozen pursuant to subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H0843278A163B40AC8D36A2790B12D5C8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text>The President, acting through the Secretary of the Treasury, shall issue such regulations, licenses, and orders as are necessary to carry out this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H59B81415BF3C4602AD6CFEC2BB500AEE"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header>
 <subsection id="H6ADB255BE7AA405F969917C50209FC22"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the actions taken to carry out this Act, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4E95425BD34543D8B2F3FB16D20BCBAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of each foreign person on the list required under section 3(a);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H51408871C30A4858B47B5D9A8C38BB1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the dates on which such foreign persons were added to such list; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAAF839821A04DF6B9A7643F8CEA67FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of the actions described in such section that were undertaken by each such foreign person.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC9C56492C03B485EAEEAD491995AD764"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The Secretary of State shall submit the first report required under this section not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act. The Secretary shall submit subsequent reports under this section not later than 60 days after the date of each regularly scheduled general election for Federal office, beginning with the election held in 2018.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H13D5658AA05C44E3A005B0563B48D34B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex if such is in the national security interests of the United States. If a classified annex is included in any such report, the Secretary of State shall include in such report a specific national security justification for such classified annex.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


