<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0B0A163088FE4B138DA5B4E909F52DAD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2676 IH: Police Reporting Information, Data, and Evidence Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2676</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To require States to report to the Attorney General certain information regarding use of force incidents involving law enforcement officers and civilians, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HF693258556BC44A3BA2421756B190E1E" style="OLC"> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF777F1FAA70C469E87E549352D7B701C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Police Reporting Information, Data, and Evidence Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PRIDE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9118703BC88F4300AA8FC425A3116BD5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF05F1AD0519A4EFA86BD9C222DD0978B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Byrne grant program</header><text>The term <term>Byrne grant program</term> means any grant program under subpart 1 of part E of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3750">42 U.S.C. 3750</external-xref> et seq.), without regard to whether the funds are characterized as being made available under the Edward Byrne Memorial State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance Programs, the Local Government Law Enforcement Block Grants Program, the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program, or otherwise.</text></paragraph> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE715D537E0AE40ADA32064CA6E387CFF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 901 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3791">42 U.S.C. 3791</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95C8A20752D44CE68B43A60CBA02D2EE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Law enforcement officer</header><text>The term <term>law enforcement officer</term> means any officer, agent, or employee of a State, unit of local government, or Indian tribe authorized by law or by a government agency to engage in or supervise the prevention, detection, or investigation of any violation of criminal law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H46D9FF63D6AD40C7AC5E5CC177D4FF95"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given the term in section 901 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3791">42 U.S.C. 3791</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF58BCE40D6B43718231EAB1E3F7380A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Use of force</header><text>The term <term>use of force</term> includes the use of a firearm, Taser, explosive device, chemical agent (such as pepper spray), baton, impact projectile, blunt instrument, hand, fist, foot, canine, or vehicle against an individual.</text></paragraph></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H66EE40009E2942BA95CE8D5AAD80FB62"><enum>3.</enum><header>Use of force reporting</header> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEE3D876D522447A8E04DE1AA8CF7840"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62FB70E3CB1E496B8744C3210D0F32BD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning in the first fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of this Act and each fiscal year thereafter in which a State or Indian tribe receives funds under a Byrne grant program, the State or Indian tribe shall—</text> 
<subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C65DA32B14E49608770F1F2D9A8F11B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>report to the Attorney General, on a quarterly basis and pursuant to guidelines established by the Attorney General, information regarding—</text> <clause id="H5A2A387038E9434381D05407CF4D3BB5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any incident involving the shooting of a civilian by a law enforcement officer who is employed—</text> 
<subclause id="HD3C0233F31034C1F9BB5B5D3D2EA5B34"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of an Indian tribe, by the Indian tribe; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H5C8AE9F6FEDA4E18946D103F501C36FC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of a State, by the State or by a unit of local government in the State;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HDDB046F10672442595E98BAD439304A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any incident involving the shooting of a law enforcement officer described in clause (i) by a civilian; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF9FADB6812B04BEB9B3EB7AA4116326D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any incident in which use of force by or against a law enforcement officer described in clause (i) occurs, which is not reported under clause (i) or (ii);</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6CFEEEBE20A74D43ABC47CF3C486DC57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish a system and a set of policies to ensure that all use of force incidents are reported by law enforcement officers; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H187622D861894051A921965B78C5B94C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>submit to the Attorney General a plan for the collection of data required to be reported under this section, including any modifications to a previously submitted data collection plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6CE6C2FE9C284050BEAF9F5A07355070"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report information required</header> 
<subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD4460448E444E2F9A3689C9171AB663"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1)(A) shall contain information that includes, at a minimum—</text> <clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C227C98B0AA4734AAC43998F799212B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the national origin, sex, race, ethnicity, age, physical disability, mental disability, English language proficiency, housing status, and school status of each civilian against whom a law enforcement officer used force;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1D1F6BDE121C4B839D00053BE28ED7ED"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date, time, and location, including zip code, of the incident and whether the jurisdiction in which the incident occurred allows for the open-carry or concealed-carry of a firearm;</text></clause> <clause id="HEAC35E0E3D3A40BC950ED1EC02C97A72"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whether the civilian was armed, and, if so, the type of weapon the civilian had;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCF33347C08B449EEADA02B4B8B08034E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the type of force used against the officer, the civilian, or both, including the types of weapons used;</text></clause> <clause id="H8C6C4DEDF78B4F2081C00C573B4B33CB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the reason force was used;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFD3070628C7D44118791D504B04FB8F8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a description of any injuries sustained as a result of the incident;</text></clause> <clause id="H247E79091A074A249CACF215305A8099"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the number of officers involved in the incident;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H407801548BCE4CEC8573EFDAA30DAC65"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the number of civilians involved in the incident; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94E4E5DC7D90488E9944054896C3FA74"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>a brief description regarding the circumstances surrounding the incident, which shall include information on—</text> 
<subclause id="H17816116C875470AB11C50A0C99C1CCA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the type of force used by all involved persons;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HAD050DD111544C2BB8F672044AC01379"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the legitimate police objective necessitating the use of force;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H518E1328D90D4ECB85348DB22B5C51C8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the resistance encountered by each law enforcement officer involved in the incident;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE9E3DDA54A174674B46F073064D36D49"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the efforts by law enforcement officers to—</text> 
<item id="H6B860A906C1A43539286791CA176AB76"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>de-escalate the situation in order to avoid the use of force; or</text></item> <item id="H961036F145A24F65B45C5437B5E325D4"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>minimize the level of force used; and</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H90949B7CDC044E339731D290EBD9CCF7"><enum>(V)</enum><text>if applicable, the reason why efforts described in subclause (IV) were not attempted.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6985F8804A3F4425A485C2B51F041355"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Incidents reported under Death in Custody Reporting Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State is not required to include in a report under subsection (a)(1) an incident reported by the State in accordance with section 20104(a)(2) of the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/13704">42 U.S.C. 13704(a)(2)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0AF7F863AFEB468AB006F80E19B85221"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Audit of use-of-force reporting</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and each year thereafter, each State and Indian tribe described in paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8BA68A1507864316B918F9A71DA6EB77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct an audit of the use of force incident reporting system required to be established under paragraph (1)(B); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5A18FB4A8874F5695119305D021109F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit a report to the Attorney General on the audit conducted under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16BDDC067395465D8E4D86FC8A247A26"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compliance procedure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to submitting a report under paragraph (1)(A), the State or Indian tribe submitting such report shall compare the information compiled to be reported pursuant to clause (i) of paragraph (1)(A) to open-source data records, and shall revise such report to include any incident determined to be missing from the report based on such comparison. Failure to comply with the procedures described in the previous sentence shall be considered a failure to comply with the requirements of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H08787D5975114511AD02ED13415B4946"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ineligibility for funds</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8FC8BCEBAAB2426996DB5F44EF7ECA1E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For any fiscal year in which a State or Indian tribe fails to comply with this section, the State or Indian tribe, at the discretion of the Attorney General, shall be subject to not more than a 10-percent reduction of the funds that would otherwise be allocated for that fiscal year to the State or Indian tribe under a Byrne grant program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93D6B6EEE4884199B73573B0CBFD6018"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reallocation</header><text>Amounts not allocated under a Byrne grant program in accordance with paragraph (1) to a State for failure to comply with this section shall be reallocated under the Byrne grant program to States that have not failed to comply with this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07853067E6CB41BAB192092737A2466F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public availability of data</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H871B9EFD56654C539778E95F8592DC63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and each year thereafter, the Attorney General shall publish, and make available to the public, a report containing the data reported to the Attorney General under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A72E722018041E99C64157739F068CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Privacy protections</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to supersede the requirements or limitations under section 552a of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Privacy Act of 1974</quote>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAEF0AF09ECDC49409B198BC56BB455C2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, in coordination with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, shall issue guidance on best practices relating to establishing standard data collection systems that capture the information required to be reported under subsection (a)(2), which shall include standard and consistent definitions for terms, including the term <term>use of force</term> which is consistent with the definition of such term in section 2.</text></subsection></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0582C15418C42158A059ABBD609690A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Community and law enforcement partnership grant program</header> <subsection id="H8C48DC920DAD4115927B732C2BEDCED2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text>The Attorney General may make grants to eligible law enforcement agencies to be used for the activities described in subsection (c).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9BD8AA8001E84CAC8FF93487933B82B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>In order to be eligible to receive a grant under this section a law enforcement agency shall—</text> <paragraph id="H0E83A09F180E42C782FE22F14B550733"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be located in a State or Indian tribe that receives funds under a Byrne grant program;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H868A9648124049C8A915FCD6EFBE1031"><enum>(2)</enum><text>employ not more than 100 law enforcement officers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F1B044B58764D5D8EFD7854F9177EDF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>demonstrate that the use of force policy for law enforcement officers employed by the law enforcement agency is publicly available; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H07CC826A2E194CF38FBA644CA1C1010D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish and maintain a reporting system that may be used by members of the public to report incidents of use of force to the law enforcement agency.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC280C9F6ED9A492BB1873DF61EF330F6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Activities described</header><text>A grant made under this section may be used by a law enforcement agency for—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0DD31F864CF64281B17B9790F3EC2175"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the cost of assisting the State or Indian tribe in which the law enforcement agency is located in complying with the reporting requirements described in section 3;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6150E092042146F58DE4C23728F59C1E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the cost of establishing necessary systems required to investigate and report incidents as required under subsection (b)(4);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E590BD89C374E058C1E20C7AF52002D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>public awareness campaigns designed to gain information from the public on use of force by or against law enforcement officers, including shootings, which may include tip lines, hotlines, and public service announcements; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H97D4EF53421046DD8C48894C17B5D17D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use of force training for law enforcement agencies and personnel, including training on de-escalation, implicit bias, crisis intervention techniques, and adolescent development.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H611826C1A4854A4D9A4A1872C956C2BE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Compliance with reporting requirements</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6584555337ED4F3E919E5A695A7DFC63"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and each year thereafter, the Attorney General shall conduct an audit and review of the information provided under this Act to determine whether each State or Indian tribe described in section 3(a)(1) is in compliance with the requirements of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H40E2905B0429463D9CCF135B460FC926"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consistency in data reporting</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8513FFB9975D4E5EA5EA7A10F5DABC41"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any data reported under this Act shall be collected and reported in a manner consistent with existing programs of the Department of Justice that collect data on law enforcement officer encounters with civilians.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33A995084519413D8E5B651D05D46BA5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>The Attorney General shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12ED14B4F2F547AA95147784C02D4447"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issue guidelines on the reporting requirement under section 3; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD837D29BD4AD4B53937472E14D1504D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seek public comment before finalizing the guidelines required under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D798E3C95D94821BA14A19263DFC665"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Attorney General such sums as are necessary to carry out this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


