<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5FEAAC80B3114992BB463A5B35C75334" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2212 IH: Creating and Restoring Equal Access To Equivalent Samples Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2212</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170427">April 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote competition in the market for drugs and biological products by facilitating the timely
			 entry of lower-cost generic and biosimilar versions of those drugs and
			 biological products.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H27006D31BDED4ACB80A4A5944F3EF46F" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCFDF39D1340648AF816D6B96E27FF8B3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Creating and Restoring Equal Access To Equivalent Samples Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CREATES Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBFEB3E300895427C8957C0874BB3C9D8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H22FDC835BB9443739EA5950F682E8013"><enum>(1)</enum><text>It is the policy of the United States to promote competition in the market for drugs and biological products by facilitating the timely entry of low-cost generic and biosimilar versions of those drugs and biological products.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H142AB6177A354B2B9EA0E1311EB6B044"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Since their enactment in 1984 and 2010, respectively, the Drug Price Competition and Patent Term Restoration Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/417">Public Law 98–417</external-xref>; 98 Stat. 1585) and the Biologics Price Competition and Innovation Act of 2009 (Subtitle A of title VII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>; 124 Stat. 804), have provided pathways for making lower-cost versions of previously approved drugs and previously licensed biological products available to the people of the United States in a timely manner, thereby lowering overall prescription drug costs for patients and taxpayers by billions of dollars each year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H012C936500424C18AD3E76D44B612251"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In order for these pathways to function as intended, developers of generic drugs and biosimilar biological products (referred to in this section as <quote>generic product developers</quote>) must be able to obtain quantities of the reference listed drug or biological product with which the generic drug or biosimilar biological product is intended to compete (referred to in this section as a <quote>covered product</quote>) for purposes of supporting an application for approval by the Food and Drug Administration, including for testing to show that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5D3C0AC9F549494EB191D0F7204F517F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a prospective generic drug is bioequivalent to the covered product in accordance with subsection (j) of section 505 of the Federal, Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>), or meets the requirements for approval of an application submitted under subsection (b)(2) of that section; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DF910C97B4342108D492811A2F659DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a prospective biosimilar biological product is biosimilar to or interchangeable with its reference biological product under section 351(k) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262(k)</external-xref>), as applicable.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1FDA9D277F549B993CC4EE8E7E019B8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For drugs and biological products that are subject to a risk evaluation and mitigation strategy, another essential component in the creation of low-cost generic and biosimilar versions of covered products is the ability of generic product developers to join the manufacturer of the covered product (referred to in this section as the <quote>license holder</quote>) in a single, shared system of elements to assure safe use and supporting agreements, or secure a variance therefrom, as required by section 505–1 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355-1">21 U.S.C. 355–1</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB57518FD88847EAB36A1A9150448622"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Contrary to the policy of the United States to promote competition in the market for drugs and biological products by facilitating the timely entry of lower-cost generic and biosimilar versions of those drugs and biological products, certain license holders are preventing generic product developers from obtaining quantities of the covered product necessary for the generic product developer to support an application for approval by the Food and Drug Administration, including testing to show bioequivalence, biosimilarity, or interchangeability to the covered product, in some instances based on the justification that the covered product is subject to a risk evaluation and mitigation strategy with elements to assure safe use under section 505–1 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355-1">21 U.S.C. 355–1</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5EFA245C20C0495BA94C3CD19002B7B8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Director of the Center for Drug Evaluation and Research at the Food and Drug Administration has testified that some manufacturers of covered products have used REMS and distribution restrictions adopted by the manufacturer on their own behalf as reasons to not sell quantities of a covered product to generic product developers, causing barriers and delays in getting generic products on the market. The Food and Drug Administration has reported receiving significant numbers of inquiries from generic product developers who were unable to obtain samples of covered products to conduct necessary testing and otherwise meet requirements for approval of generic drugs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CFA72B93FAB4465A2F2CE799FBA2F77"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Chairwoman of the Federal Trade Commission has testified that the Federal Trade Commission continues to be very concerned about potential abuses by manufacturers of brand drugs of REMS or other closed distribution systems to impede generic competition.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED8A6DE4228D43AE98D2C1CE48DBF180"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Also contrary to the policy of the United States to promote competition in the market for drugs and biological products by facilitating the timely entry of lower-cost generic and biosimilar versions of those drugs and biological products, certain license holders are impeding the prompt negotiation and development on commercially reasonable terms of a single, shared system of elements to assure safe use, which may be necessary for the generic product developer to gain approval for its drug or licensing for its biological product.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC3EBAED75BD41F6BCD4AD1029252FFA"><enum>(9)</enum><text>While the antitrust laws may address the refusal by some license holders to provide quantities of a covered product to a generic product developer, a more tailored legal pathway would help ensure that generic product developers can obtain necessary quantities of a covered product in a timely way for purposes of developing a generic drug or biosimilar biological product, facilitating competition in the marketplace for drugs and biological products.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45C2B4259C8749349C3C09C188111B2C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The antitrust laws may address actions by license holders who impede the prompt negotiation and development of a single, shared system of elements to assure safe use, and the Food and Drug Administration has some authority to waive the requirement of a single, shared system. Clearer regulatory authority to approve different systems that meet the statutory requirements to ensure patient safety, however, would limit the effectiveness of bad faith negotiations over single, shared systems to delay generic approval. At the same time, clearer regulatory authority would ensure all systems protect patient safety.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H7EDF01BE7F0840C78CD73FB6F2A88671"><enum>3.</enum><header>Actions for delays of generic drugs and biosimilar biological products</header>
 <subsection id="H3201A03379A74A31848CCBF612DDDEB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H14EA895A14A44C10AB8309D9F536C1FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered product</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA117F6631754437A8BC88DC8BA2FD0FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text> <clause id="HAFDA164A421D4BC19EB517997F8F7F0D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any drug approved under subsection (b) or (j) of section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>) or biological product licensed under subsection (a) or (k) of section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>);</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE48DE34475874798A011091E5DDC4196"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any combination of a drug or biological product described in clause (i); or</text> </clause><clause id="H2FDB9B5786DB4CBE950316A1CD34805D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>when reasonably necessary to demonstrate sameness, biosimilarity, or interchangeability for purposes of section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>), or section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>), as applicable, any product, including any device, that is marketed or intended for use with such drug or biological product; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A139359676C4D01BB34063DE4C50B4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any drug or biological product that the Secretary has determined to be currently in shortage and that appears on the drug shortage list in effect under section 506E of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/356e">21 U.S.C. 356e</external-xref>), unless the shortage will not be promptly resolved—</text>
 <clause id="H902E1743491144F9941979DCBDD5B871"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as demonstrated by the fact that the drug or biological product has been in shortage for more than 6 months; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H598A86D67C334BB992A61985884FE58A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as otherwise determined by the Secretary;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E25D57E588A4126B276EF4009ADAACB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>device</term> has the meaning given the term in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC41F2E5DBE804EA18F28DF6458096DEC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>eligible product developer</term> means a person that seeks to develop a product for approval pursuant to an application for approval under subsection (b)(2) or (j) of section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>) or for licensing pursuant to an application under section 351(k) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262(k)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4424E84F53DD48D1AADDA3EC2BF668D2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>license holder</term> means the holder of an application approved under subsection (c) or (j) of section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>) or the holder of a license under subsection (a) or (k) of section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>) for a covered product;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA52E18D06D04C2B9C0E3CD98BAF9078"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>REMS</term> means a risk evaluation and mitigation strategy under section 505–1 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355-1">21 U.S.C. 355–1</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7D2B8DC537B4942AF67102E32EF0168"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>REMS with ETASU</term> means a REMS that contains elements to assure safe use under section 505–1 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355-1">21 U.S.C. 355–1</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56887157952E4BFCA24EFF61C5D7610B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA37015652D004B3B86E6F456484F770D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the term <term>single, shared system of elements to assure safe use</term> means a single, shared system of elements to assure safe use under section 505–1 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355-1">21 U.S.C. 355–1</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9B4B47B29434FAF9578ED5868EB0280"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the term <term>sufficient quantities</term> means an amount of a covered product that allows the eligible product developer to—</text> <subparagraph id="H5630B77BD3F54CDF8903EEE0B9CDACFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct testing to support an application—</text>
 <clause id="H2215E513A0B64955890B9BCA3C2B4C5F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for approval under subsection (b)(2) or (j) of section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7B6673B230BC4C13B2842A9DBD875FE3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for licensing under section 351(k) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262(k)</external-xref>); and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD4F3E3A9B5543048B75F0B563FBE6AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>fulfill any regulatory requirements relating to such an application for approval or licensing.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4988FB60968545F29A1939B7E7BEE96A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil action for failure To provide sufficient quantities of a covered product</header>
 <paragraph id="HDFDC5AA8369242CDA780CFE789AC500A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible product developer may bring a civil action against the license holder for a covered product seeking relief under this subsection in an appropriate district court of the United States alleging that the license holder has declined to provide sufficient quantities of the covered product to the eligible product developer on commercially reasonable, market-based terms.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H646E3420D17949209B045D4A71C0409A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header>
 <subparagraph id="H8BF27813CB354FD0BF2BA64EF45D8AD1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To prevail in a civil action brought under paragraph (1), an eligible product developer shall prove, by a preponderance of the evidence—</text>
 <clause id="H13E72B5498354F89A1BA3E0B6018B1FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that—</text> <subclause id="HA04BFD2BAD0E40938D147D46B11CC10C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the covered product is not subject to a REMS with ETASU; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1A187DB07DDD4D4FA3F8ADE9DF3B53E2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the covered product is subject to a REMS with ETASU—</text> <item id="HB70A69E60A0D45D9A640F09FCC9AE6B3"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the eligible product developer has obtained a covered product authorization from the Secretary in accordance with subparagraph (B); and</text>
 </item><item id="H6D754F6A4A5D4A98B843F114F02C89EF"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the eligible product developer has provided a copy of the covered product authorization to the license holder;</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="HB0A649AEA118490C8B73C2EB01937A03"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that, as of the date on which the civil action is filed, the product developer has not obtained sufficient quantities of the covered product on commercially reasonable, market-based terms;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6FAF2699D5494451BEA346E271A94626"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that the eligible product developer has requested to purchase sufficient quantities of the covered product from the license holder; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD2AE0CF0CFFD4B3E800C7F316FCFD7BC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>that the license holder has not delivered to the eligible product developer sufficient quantities of the covered product on commercially reasonable, market-based terms—</text>
 <subclause id="HDC6BA6EC3C774B3DA83888E39652EF45"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for a covered product that is not subject to a REMS with ETASU, by the date that is 31 days after the date on which the license holder received the request for the covered product; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC261BDC120BA469AA9C603A787100621"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for a covered product that is subject to a REMS with ETASU, by 31 days after the later of—</text> <item id="H16456B5B55C1462786EAEFECB7C0B5DC"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the date on which the license holder received the request for the covered product; or</text>
 </item><item id="HC60B7DD8EAEE47039940C86A62921876"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the date on which the license holder received a copy of the covered product authorization issued by the Secretary in accordance with subparagraph (B).</text>
								</item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE1DD8F3739C4273BEE1B51F7B5EBB0A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorization for covered product subject to a REMS with ETASU</header>
 <clause id="H0216084F0C2540AA93E21058ECD649E8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Request</header><text>An eligible product developer may submit to the Secretary a written request for the eligible product developer to be authorized to obtain sufficient quantities of an individual covered product subject to a REMS with ETASU.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H757193EDA7BB46EC9F6F06DD3ABF02CA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which a request under clause (i) is received, the Secretary shall, by written notice, authorize the eligible product developer to obtain sufficient quantities of an individual covered product subject to a REMS with ETASU for purposes of—</text>
 <subclause id="HE78CEF96015E4D04BAF5AB7E799675A3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>development and testing that does not involve human clinical trials, if the eligible product developer has agreed to comply with any conditions the Secretary determines necessary; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC250421F41CA49278CF7BC9FCC229018"><enum>(II)</enum><text>development and testing that involves human clinical trials, if the eligible product developer has—</text> <item id="HBA5710AA224C4F319CDC168590D175E8"><enum>(aa)</enum> <subitem commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE890F45D1E684111B94DA4A2A6C44C62"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>submitted protocols, informed consent documents, and informational materials for testing that include protections that provide safety protections comparable to those provided by the REMS for the covered product; or</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="H7626AB2E6EC54D4693B2FEB15898DC3B" indent="up1"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>otherwise satisfied the Secretary that such protections will be provided; and</text> </subitem></item><item id="HF797E30CD839401698F6D0A1A56DAECB"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>met any other requirements the Secretary may establish.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H5B41976043684A5E89AB3CCBB87AFFA8"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>A covered product authorization issued under this subparagraph shall state that the provision of the covered product by the license holder under the terms of the authorization will not be a violation of the REMS for the covered product.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H042E6AFE0D054476B6E45A93ABF4C238"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Affirmative defense</header><text>In a civil action brought under paragraph (1), it shall be an affirmative defense, on which the defendant has the burden of persuasion by a preponderance of the evidence—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H30B02BAC752D42B388F04FF59041839B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that, on the date on which the eligible product developer requested to purchase sufficient quantities of the covered product from the license holder—</text>
 <clause id="H7F1C9FC4108042B7A831BD500DFF49E7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>neither the license holder nor any of its agents, wholesalers, or distributors was engaged in the manufacturing or commercial marketing of the covered product; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD2197B5FDFB44965AF4244DEFAD91DE3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>neither the license holder nor any of its agents, wholesalers, or distributors otherwise had access to inventory of the covered product to supply to the eligible product developer on commercially reasonable, market-based terms; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC0778205E954875AFBEA075D61FA0A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that—</text> <clause id="H1AA08AB10B484057A90B5C4C003CF5D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the license holder sells the covered product through agents, distributors, or wholesalers;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA0CC8F7811734C6AA83540CC75DACFAC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the license holder has placed no restrictions, explicit or implicit, on its agents, distributors, or wholesalers to sell covered products to eligible product developers; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCCA94EABAABA4FEB94422FCB30356DC8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the covered product can be purchased by the eligible product developer in sufficient quantities on commercially reasonable, market-based terms from the agents, distributors, or wholesalers of the license holder.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H549D3B98E4C048A781CD6A13753952FC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Remedies</header>
 <subparagraph id="H4B3C695E615E45D2BA0000EECE0C72A9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If an eligible product developer prevails in a civil action brought under paragraph (1), the court shall—</text>
 <clause id="H7F44A2F43D2D4649975B7E0575909D13"><enum>(i)</enum><text>order the license holder to provide to the eligible product developer without delay sufficient quantities of the covered product on commercially reasonable, market-based terms;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA331C3C90ECF48AD8E639E2475195144"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>award to the eligible product developer reasonable attorney fees and costs of the civil action; and</text> </clause><clause id="HCECE550BF53E468AA202B34ADE341E31"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>award to the eligible product developer a monetary amount sufficient to deter the license holder from failing to provide other eligible product developers with sufficient quantities of a covered product on commercially reasonable, market-based terms, if the court finds, by a preponderance of the evidence—</text>
 <subclause id="H3EABD37792BB4998A24CF4004F013F27"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that the license holder delayed providing sufficient quantities of the covered product to the eligible product developer without a legitimate business justification; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H843DB37F258544F2924122B3A5CA48FD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that the license holder failed to comply with an order issued under clause (i).</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97AA40A647F749A4B1FDDBB4DBF31C3E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Maximum monetary amount</header><text>A monetary amount awarded under subparagraph (A)(iii) shall not be greater than the revenue that the license holder earned on the covered product during the period—</text>
 <clause id="H8A3F8B4C08D14607A964AC25DBE268E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>beginning on—</text> <subclause id="H9F3914165ED241B3BB501CE6029F8FA3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for a covered product that is not subject to a REMS with ETASU, the date that is 31 days after the date on which the license holder received the request; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3B05E9895E044AD08DBCF87F2C845BE9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for a covered product that is subject to a REMS with ETASU, the date that is 31 days after the later of—</text>
 <item id="H4498DDF4A8644E45B8734C43FB255E81"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the date on which the license holder received the request; or</text> </item><item id="H63452A12CD1F441F9BD0924A1581547F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the date on which the license holder received a copy of the covered product authorization issued by the Secretary in accordance with paragraph (2)(B); and</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H35FB8DD7402349A084548EA97E89DF21"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ending on the date on which the eligible product developer received sufficient quantities of the covered product.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B4A66E19021469C994A3E9B325FD0E1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Avoidance of delay</header><text>The court may issue an order under subparagraph (A)(i) before conducting further proceedings that may be necessary to determine whether the eligible product developer is entitled to an award under clause (ii) or (iii) of subparagraph (A), or the amount of any such award.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9FC629701FBA4FE2A5B19D04152B41A0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation of liability</header><text>A license holder for a covered product shall not be liable for any claim arising out of the failure of an eligible product developer to follow adequate safeguards to assure safe use of the covered product during development or testing activities described in this section, including transportation, handling, use, or disposal of the covered product by the eligible product developer.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HF1714E9D78F342CC8A253E38779333F3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header>
 <paragraph id="H6E2459AD5F094CE38DBA9D2D3B374764"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>antitrust laws</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H658F4A91216D461FA59F76658B09BF9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H284CF01B0D6946B79924B1D8F113AA61"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>) to the extent that such section applies to unfair methods of competition.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA90D2AECE57946EF925067EFA4F2DEA6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Antitrust laws</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the operation of any provision of the antitrust laws.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9B1BAF04BCEA4A3FB002AE0F4262DA0B"><enum>4.</enum><header>REMS approval process for subsequent filers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 505–1 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355-1">21 U.S.C. 355–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA0117A7859184BBD91D8952491654F8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (g)(4)(B)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8191ACF7D1194F96A8837A1FC5D27C40"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (i) by striking <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF16FE1B88CC42E2ABE27BEA3F04DF0B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii) by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2263DD7780C7476081B946830844DA61"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H807FDA63345B43209DABA81F525D35DF" style="OLC"> <clause id="H5628EBC2816E471EB5F07E019D259D87"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>accommodate different approved risk evaluation and mitigation strategies for a reference drug product and a drug that is the subject of an abbreviated new drug application.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC52FDFC640D34DE69012E19FD4B81BF3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (i)(1), by striking subparagraph (B) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38BF665A56C14AADA77E0A4A03667CED" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H2D32177517484BE19AA795C678498990"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Elements to assure safe use, if required under subsection (f) for the listed drug.</text>
 <clause id="H7311CA5378054B61A5F6FC180171116C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Subject to clause (ii), a drug that is the subject of an abbreviated new drug application may use—</text> <subclause id="HDA5E2A73C10446B0A113E6DD66433FB3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a single, shared system with the listed drug under subsection (f); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC86D2CED1A13411C8B2646E77AC5BEF8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a different, comparable aspect of the elements to assure safe use under subsection (f).</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H02AACACC5C9B45918DD971E4D25024AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Secretary may require a drug that is the subject of an abbreviated new drug application and the listed drug to use a single, shared system under subsection (f), if the Secretary determines that no different, comparable aspect of the elements to assure safe use could satisfy the requirements of subsection (f).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


