<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA103B4FC976342BB9C2EDA1EF5D0BB53" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 611 IH: VA Accountability First and Appeals Modernization Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 611</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170123">January 23, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for the removal or demotion of employees of the
			 Department of Veterans Affairs based on performance or misconduct, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4527AD91EF334E89A2BAAE81F568D64D" style="OLC">
		<section id="HD4282C2C4A0D4FD5AA126F4920377EC9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="HD1463D6264544773877E022D03C4115F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>VA Accountability First and Appeals Modernization Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H9AD16B9FE13042A5B60E837916CEA4CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc>
					<toc-entry idref="HD4282C2C4A0D4FD5AA126F4920377EC9" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H91B1318C6FB04B0D8C9031C04E8FACBE" level="section">Sec. 2. References to title 38, United States Code.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBD88CFDF6A0642088B01F595C30AFE31" level="section">Sec. 3. Removal or demotion of employees based on performance or misconduct.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE8ED3553F35C437FB309BCBB2C962AB7" level="section">Sec. 4. Reduction of benefits for members of the Senior Executive Service within the Department of
			 Veterans Affairs convicted of certain crimes.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H2861F312D96D483AAC961B989450E8FD" level="section">Sec. 5. Authority to recoup bonuses or awards paid to employees of Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H11E3C4EEA7FA488EBB12CF5E586258FE" level="section">Sec. 6. Authority to recoup relocation expenses paid to or on behalf of employees of Department of
			 Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF94DFA4E9C334F82910C10A769FA4C03" level="section">Sec. 7. Expansion of personnel actions for senior executives based on performance or misconduct and
			 establishment of Senior Executive Disciplinary Appeals Board.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H1A898D08D83D487290B55A08F94DE53B" level="section">Sec. 8. Reform of rights and processes relating to appeals of decisions regarding claims for
			 benefits under laws administered by Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H3C7D234C170647D395C9A38C81BFDA81" level="section">Sec. 9. Limitation on awards and bonuses paid to senior executive employees of Department of
			 Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry></toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="H91B1318C6FB04B0D8C9031C04E8FACBE"><enum>2.</enum><header>References to title 38, United States Code</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided, whenever in this Act an amendment or repeal is expressed in terms of an amendment to, or repeal of, a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision of title 38, United States Code.</text>
		</section><section commented="no" id="HBD88CFDF6A0642088B01F595C30AFE31"><enum>3.</enum><header>Removal or demotion of employees based on performance or misconduct</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H8C3ADD4A378B45DC9C2CE88D78B410FB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/7">Chapter 7</external-xref> is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HCC35B45AD2F949AF9E7D57917DB8D136"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating section 715 as section 725; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8B0798536403469B8706C764B8D9F050"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after section 713 the following new section 715:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAFAD91F30C934A8ABB4AF71DEA6C474D" style="USC"> <section commented="no" id="H2501B82E98A64A05BC10C4A86FA76CC4"><enum>715.</enum><header>Employees: removal or demotion based on performance or misconduct</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB9B1B34B1554991BEE5503587BD1C40"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may remove or demote an individual who is an employee of the Department if the Secretary determines the performance or misconduct of the individual warrants such removal or demotion. If the Secretary so removes or demotes such an individual, the Secretary may—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC59CD1670BF94F9883D8D38EC12E0040"><enum>(1)</enum><text>remove the individual from the civil service (as defined in section 2101 of title 5); or</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F22E3DB2244423EA7718E4577BB76C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demote the individual by means of—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC1A2081A241448E7A6A58E8E51E1DCBC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a reduction in grade for which the individual is qualified and that the Secretary determines is appropriate; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBB6194B14BEE4C0D8E21F74CDACA181C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a reduction in annual rate of pay that the Secretary determines is appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9DA4B1E3A0634EE1A9FDF1FCBCE974AB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pay of certain demoted individuals</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H17370FE31BC6428E9796D175D54A108B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any individual subject to a demotion by a reduction in grade under subsection (a)(2)(A) shall, beginning on the date of such demotion, receive the annual rate of pay applicable to such grade.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCF4EFE8ED1EE41679E60D84FEC137FFF" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An individual demoted as described in paragraph (1) may not be placed on administrative leave or any other category of paid leave during the period during which an appeal (if any) under this section is ongoing, and may only receive pay if the individual reports for duty. If an individual so demoted does not report for duty, such individual shall not receive any pay, awards, bonuses, incentives, allowances, differentials, student loan repayments, special payments, or benefits from the Department.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H648CF4D967D74C00A32ACAAFC66D5230"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice to Congress</header><text>Not later than 30 days after removing or demoting an individual under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives notice in writing of such removal or demotion and the reason for such removal or demotion.</text>
							</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H22CB62CB728A4AFBBFF2CE8CC731C636"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Procedure</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA6DA4BE34E9D46D9AD880E593692D85F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subsection (b) of section 7513 of title 5 shall apply with respect to a removal or demotion under this section, except that the period for notice and response, which includes the advance notice period required by paragraph (1) of such subsection and the response period required by paragraph (2) of such subsection, shall not exceed a total of ten calendar days.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC5BB5FA26814030A9AABC8D1C1ED829" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The procedures under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/43">chapter 43</external-xref> of title 5 shall not apply to a removal or demotion under this section.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4F95BCDF889A4ADDA57EE77AA18EC51C" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H152EB341E18E427CAF41A467FC08AB9B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Subject to subparagraph (B) and subsection (e), any removal or demotion under subsection (a) may be appealed to the Merit Systems Protection Board under section 7701 of title 5.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFFC8A3230C1B4521BB0136500E4E078D" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An appeal under subparagraph (A) of a removal or demotion may only be made if such appeal is made not later than seven days after the date of such removal or demotion.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H268F311ABC354747A744477EF0389797"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Expedited Review by Merit Systems Protection Board</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA17712CD27EE4190ABF168EBCE2699A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Upon receipt of an appeal under subsection (d)(3)(A), the Merit Systems Protection Board shall expedite any such appeal under such section and, in any such case, shall issue a decision not later than 60 days after the date of the appeal.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEEDF326357584CDF8BFC4771F5EB8F1E" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 7701(c)(1)(B) of title 5, the Merit Systems Protection Board shall uphold the decision of the Secretary to remove or demote an employee under subsection (a) if the decision is supported by substantial evidence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAC56617C3E5A49EDBCD96FE83546EA31" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The decision of the Merit Systems Protection Board under paragraph (1), and any final removal or demotion described in paragraph (4), may be appealed to the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit pursuant to section 7703 of title 5. Any decision by such Court shall be in compliance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7462">section 7462(f)(2)</external-xref> of this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDB0E64DF4DFA4FFBAC5FA918E5101A2F" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In any case in which the Merit Systems Protection Board cannot issue a decision in accordance with the 60-day requirement under paragraph (1), the removal or demotion is final. In such a case, the Merit Systems Protection Board shall, within 14 days after the date that such removal or demotion is final, submit to Congress and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that explains the reasons why a decision was not issued in accordance with such requirement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2780E1BEA5C6425992A67215FF57E52E" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Merit Systems Protection Board may not stay any removal or demotion under this section.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H85D2B2B2545947D6B1EC7853E37D251A" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>During the period beginning on the date on which an individual appeals a removal from the civil service under subsection (d) and ending on the date that the Merit Systems Protection Board issues a final decision on such appeal, such individual may not receive any pay, awards, bonuses, incentives, allowances, differentials, student loan repayments, special payments, or benefits from the Department.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0AAFF6BA3E334E9387D0EAC2445F98AE" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall provide to the Merit Systems Protection Board such information and assistance as may be necessary to ensure an appeal under this subsection is expedited.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H100B37C6C4034B26B9210EAF59EBBEBB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Whistleblower protection</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFF59891090364B1893280DF41706F4A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the case of an individual seeking corrective action (or on behalf of whom corrective action is sought) from the Office of Special Counsel based on an alleged prohibited personnel practice described in section 2302(b) of title 5, the Secretary may not remove or demote such individual under subsection (a) without the approval of the Special Counsel under section 1214(f) of title 5.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4404935443814D2ABFB098AA604C99F1" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In the case of an individual who has filed a whistleblower complaint, as such term is defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/731">section 731</external-xref> of this title, the Secretary may not remove or demote such individual under subsection (a) until a final decision with respect to the whistleblower complaint has been made.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H013D98D6E8BB41B6A6521AACA4848C8C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination of investigations by Office of Special Counsel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Special Counsel (established by section 1211 of title 5) may terminate an investigation of a prohibited personnel practice alleged by an employee or former employee of the Department after the Special Counsel provides to the employee or former employee a written statement of the reasons for the termination of the investigation. Such statement may not be admissible as evidence in any judicial or administrative proceeding without the consent of such employee or former employee.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HDB6DA7813B9A41ACAD4D61D89E486649"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Relation to other authorities</header><text>The authority provided by this section is in addition to the authority provided by subchapter V of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/74">chapter 74</external-xref> of this title, subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 5, <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/43">chapter 43</external-xref> of such title, and any other authority with respect to disciplining an individual.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4B9F5EA343C549A3BE54136113A115A4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HCB7D41E45CCA46E5BD4290C57BB6CF7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>individual</term> means an individual occupying a position at the Department but does not include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5E76FFF7FBCE4101BEB18282E841BA64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual, as that term is defined in section 713(g); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD25E7B56C1B4B3E9BC499DBD1589F96"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a political appointee.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCFBAC8CF59C4BF1841FD4E5E6A3D95D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>grade</term> has the meaning given that term in section 7511(a) of title 5.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H85304F1EDFD34E50A0A3046C533E967E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>misconduct</term> includes neglect of duty, malfeasance, or failure to accept a directed reassignment or to accompany a position in a transfer of function.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5E8D97C43A174E8CB997962AB0B994D6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>political appointee</term> means an individual who is—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H187F286D3E514BF19F25C5E485C7CB0A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employed in a position described under sections 5312 through 5316 of title 5 (relating to the Executive Schedule);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE7D978E2CCD34402A7F0D77E5552B931"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a limited term appointee, limited emergency appointee, or noncareer appointee in the Senior Executive Service, as defined under paragraphs (5), (6), and (7), respectively, of section 3132(a) of title 5; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1E468C42D12A4F9CB259099E9D6443F9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>employed in a position of a confidential or policy-determining character under schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5 of the Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H5B2B4399F5954257B75E9F9B76567DCA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical and conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="HED6F81C8C1D4440088F6409C72E3046C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Clerical</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/7">chapter 7</external-xref> is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HD18DAEFF5092478BB559837729EA1005"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to section 715 and inserting the following new item:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65664D1724DA485096114E8374085D13" style="USC">
							<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
								<toc-entry level="section">715. Employees: removal or demotion based on performance or misconduct.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">and</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H724B85886CEE4CB89304EDF63E2CB96B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after the item relating to section 715 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13B148DD8D594EA2B6A005CE1D7CC96B" style="OLC"> <toc> <toc-entry level="section">725. Congressional testimony by employees: treatment as official duty.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB973AE705C16456F9D39D998D8EAE764"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming</header><text>Section 4303(f) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H585614A4E22E4AA4817CE027AE07CFD6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of paragraph (2);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B3B5924AD1C46D8883B45713BBFAACD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (3) and inserting <quote>, or</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71E73E5843324B42BB1845DB615B4DFE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0230884E6BB44C07BD015C043FE4B6AA" style="USC"> <paragraph id="HD3C3B67320064826BEA9634F5D01B14B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any removal or demotion under section 715 of title 38.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE8ED3553F35C437FB309BCBB2C962AB7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reduction of benefits for members of the Senior Executive Service within the Department of Veterans
			 Affairs convicted of certain crimes</header>
			<subsection id="H6870A48F5E8A418183F8899050B14D30"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reduction of benefits</header>
 <paragraph id="H4788090F648940F9B85D031E913222DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter 7 is further amended by inserting after section 715, as added by section 3, the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F49C6F3D6384A43A0560A0C8A09D6C3" style="USC">
						<section id="H7F05FA72BDA648358F3FFBA24052248F"><enum>717.</enum><header>Senior executives: reduction of benefits of individuals convicted of certain crimes</header>
							<subsection id="H24E8E643AF074AA494847DCA35F1325A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reduction of annuity for removed employee</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC18658E34FEE4DFBA69B06AD55C80217"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall order that the covered service of an individual removed from a senior executive position for performance or misconduct under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/713">section 713</external-xref> of this title, chapter 43 or subchapter V of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 5, or any other provision of law shall not be taken into account for purposes of calculating an annuity with respect to such individual under chapter 83 or <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/84">chapter 84</external-xref> of title 5, if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD16D3653769C45988038019077571569" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the individual is convicted of a felony that influenced the individual’s performance while employed in the senior executive position; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DBB46302AD740829C76051FD53EE867" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>before such order is made, the individual is afforded—</text> <clause id="H99500E9580754AC5A579B082BEF9AFC4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>notice of the order and an opportunity to respond to the order; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD6B7D26AE50F4D5294CDCDC61F435FB2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consistent with paragraph (2), an opportunity to appeal the order to another department or agency of the Federal Government.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF373AEF55CB40A3A9AE116DF086DD31" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If a final decision on an appeal made under paragraph (1)(B)(ii) is not made by the applicable department or agency of the Federal Government within 30 days after receiving such appeal, the order of the Secretary under paragraph (1) shall be final and not subject to further appeal.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H032D5E2A888141DDA10643C6B1ADDE3B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reduction of annuity for retired employee</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4C1F896A95C742CF89DCCAB9013E386A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may order that the covered service of an individual who is subject to a removal or transfer action for performance or misconduct under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/713">section 713</external-xref> of this title, chapter 43 or subchapter V of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 5, or any other provision of law but who leaves employment at the Department prior to the issuance of a final decision with respect to such action shall not be taken into account for purposes of calculating an annuity with respect to such individual under chapter 83 or <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/84">chapter 84</external-xref> of title 5, if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3C312F5A62F843F6B42024B1953B3B60" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the individual is convicted of a felony that influenced the individual’s performance while employed in the senior executive position; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF777426E92994983A8D1E48FC7720EB9" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">before such order is made, the individual is afforded—</text> <clause id="H10BA214874F4439ABF66D216B8F90F4A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notice of the order and an opportunity to respond to the order; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H554928AF01CC4A40B8D86A7A56EF2A05"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an opportunity for a hearing conducted by another department or agency of the Federal Government.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB580716DED074B82B820A318C3A76012" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall make such an order not later than seven days after the date of the conclusion of a hearing described in paragraph (1)(B) that determines that such order is lawful.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDB999AB339294F079A5F3A207984E57D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administrative requirements</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H86902400E4CD45739A47EE82AFA9BCE7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than 30 days after the Secretary issues an order under subsection (a) or (b), the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall recalculate the annuity of the individual.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE7FF93DCC9A40EBA89D39835E79497D" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A decision regarding whether the covered service of an individual shall be taken into account for purposes of calculating an annuity under subsection (a) or (b) is final and may not be reviewed by any department or agency or any court.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H30BF1D30E7F04DCAB1142328671F9EDE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Lump-Sum Annuity Credit</header><text>Any individual with respect to whom an annuity is reduced under subsection (a) or (b) shall be entitled to be paid so much of such individual’s lump-sum credit as is attributable to the period of covered service.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7193BB490AB745BE84419C8DF4A72054"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Spouse or children exception</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, shall prescribe regulations that may provide for the payment to the spouse or children of any individual referred to in subsection (a) or (b) of any amounts that (but for this subsection) would otherwise have been nonpayable by reason of subsection (a) or (b). Any such regulations shall be consistent with the requirements of sections 8332(o)(5) and 8411(l)(5) of title 5, as the case may be.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1D92AF425D134D718FD8D30BAF08D706"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H8F408F40AB5E4006B9EB0CDAB3786FD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered service</term> means, with respect to an individual subject to a removal or transfer for performance or misconduct under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/713">section 713</external-xref> of this title, chapter 43 or subchapter V of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 5, or any other provision of law, the period of service beginning on the date that the Secretary determines under such applicable provision that the individual engaged in activity that gave rise to such action and ending on the date that the individual is removed or transferred from the senior executive position or leaves employment at the Department prior to the issuance of a final decision with respect to such action, as the case may be.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H962AE136F59C4797B0872743C66C245F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>lump-sum credit</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8331(8) or section 8401(19) of title 5, as the case may be.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63C8570FD93F4D7CABE53B73A12BF9A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>senior executive position</term> has the meaning given such term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/713">section 713(g)(3)</external-xref> of this title.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD10F74211D014C1091709D83B1D5D92D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>service</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8331(12) or section 8401(26) of title 5, as the case may be.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD033B9D7DA1E4637A7D74090929DCFDB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 7 is further amended by inserting after the item relating to section 715, as added by section 3, the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAC365FEF33654D30A8D249F4FEB2E332" style="USC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">717. Senior executives: reduction of benefits of individuals convicted of certain crimes.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H95805BB468F74A2795C6218857B6CD5B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Section 717 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(1), shall apply to any action of removal or transfer under section 713 of title 38, United States Code, commencing on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H2861F312D96D483AAC961B989450E8FD" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authority to recoup bonuses or awards paid to employees of Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
 <subsection id="H7920ABC922B249F7A7053F7F1DA6F366"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 7 is further amended by inserting after section 717, as added by section 4, the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H82416B0EB76048A0AAC7D6739BCEEEAC" style="USC">
					<section id="H6D2B98F0D4DA4B8F8E49A689D6715212"><enum>719.</enum><header>Recoupment of bonuses or awards paid to employees of Department</header>
 <subsection id="H968E4B652B6146A38A5F036BD07D5D80"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Recoupment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may issue an order directing an employee of the Department to repay the amount, or a portion of the amount, of any award or bonus paid to the employee under title 5, including under chapter 45 or 53 of such title, or this title if—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA8D09C6824E5477F8AA505258C12E26C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary determines such repayment appropriate pursuant to regulations prescribed under subsection (c); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E218A703FA84ED7ACF413FC9AC8FE3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>before such repayment, the employee is afforded notice and an opportunity for a hearing conducted by another department or agency of the Federal Government.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3377F46D998546179DADD2289690083C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4A65DDDE08874AD5AC49D5D3BABE90DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Upon the issuance of an order by the Secretary under subsection (a), the employee shall be afforded—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5D51745634CA478AA32FC6518EE75316" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notice of the order and an opportunity to respond to the order; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA0B135FE6104CAB85A8902C9CB0E2B2" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consistent with paragraph (2), an opportunity to appeal the order to another department or agency of the Federal Government.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86F303BA3B3C424288EEB206958EE5EC" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If a final decision on an appeal made under paragraph (1)(B) is not made by the applicable department or agency of the Federal Government within 30 days after receiving such appeal, the order of the Secretary under subsection (a) shall be final and not subject to further appeal.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA4ECEDE1464A4E40ADD606EFC5818BD5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HDCF434DC365D4D82AC2B4C4DAF61FFB7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 7 is further amended by inserting after the item relating to section 717, as added by section 4, the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F449F5921604A4FB524541B073FB09B" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">719. Recoupment of bonuses or awards paid to employees of Department.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1E24B87061834A4AB08004E81439A3A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Section 719 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall apply with respect to an award or bonus paid by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8FBDFFA4DDB7421E882A561A1B266495"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this section or the amendments made by this section may be construed to modify the certification issued by the Office of Personnel Management and the Office of Management and Budget regarding the performance appraisal system of the Senior Executive Service of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
			</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11E3C4EEA7FA488EBB12CF5E586258FE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to recoup relocation expenses paid to or on behalf of employees of Department of Veterans
			 Affairs</header>
 <subsection id="H20E4185C19394B178F3552986D2A68DC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 7 is further amended by inserting after section 719, as added by section 5, the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB1B080FAD6F044D8B897F22B4FE749C1" style="USC">
					<section id="H03C775B9264841519BBF27762DA299AA"><enum>721.</enum><header>Recoupment of relocation expenses paid on behalf of employees of Department</header>
						<subsection id="H3547E9FDC1D3445CB8D2A839D5BB6BF3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Recoupment</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB47837C0D17A46729556CD1E66C69327"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may direct an employee of the Department to repay the amount, or a portion of the amount, paid to or on behalf of the employee for relocation expenses under title 5, including any expenses under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5724">section 5724</external-xref> or <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5724a">5724a</external-xref> of such title, or this title if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5EA7F6845125444EA6596E26D317B55B" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that—</text> <clause id="HB57719A000AC4447867A2CBCF9554EE7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the employee has committed an act of fraud, waste, or malfeasance; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB3028B7E94364A2490D19DA94FAC3957"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such repayment is appropriate pursuant to regulations prescribed under subsection (c); and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H392687223B6B4FC98FCA90AE75017425" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>before such repayment is ordered, the individual is afforded—</text>
 <clause id="H96DE526BB2A4468A91F0A33C3076EF26"><enum>(i)</enum><text>notice of the determination of the Secretary and an opportunity to respond to the determination; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB8C96D00D9E84F61BB57891F16F66056"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consistent with paragraph (2), an opportunity to appeal the determination to another department or agency of the Federal Government.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD42C667A562643A1AD384D34DD648610" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If a final decision on an appeal made under paragraph (1)(B)(ii) is not made by the applicable department or agency of the Federal Government within 30 days after receiving such appeal, the order of the Secretary under paragraph (1) shall be final and not subject to further appeal.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2916B902B860454ABB1372085D223476"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A decision by the applicable department or agency of the Federal Government regarding a repayment by an employee pursuant to subsection (a)(1)(B)(ii) is final and may not be reviewed by any department, agency, or court.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H553C35AAE18E45CE90DE5114C4B017D0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H96B006E68A6C48688ED124814024CAD4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 7 is further amended by inserting after the item relating to section 719, as added by section 5, the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED95452083484638836BC509F755ABAD" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">721. Recoupment of relocation expenses paid to or on behalf of employees of Department.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFA01CFF329CE412C992B9E72E7DFB1FF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Section 721 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall apply with respect to an amount paid by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to or on behalf of an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs for relocation expenses on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0687820B333F4DBB8A5FB24491B4F3CF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this section or the amendments made by this section may be construed to modify the certification issued by the Office of Personnel Management and the Office of Management and Budget regarding the performance appraisal system of the Senior Executive Service of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
			</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF94DFA4E9C334F82910C10A769FA4C03" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Expansion of personnel actions for senior executives based on performance or misconduct and
			 establishment of Senior Executive Disciplinary Appeals Board</header>
 <subsection id="H22BD1A05AF734A8A8BE6872F88FE41D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expansion of covered personnel actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a)(1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/713">section 713</external-xref> is amended, in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting after <quote>such removal.</quote> the following: <quote>If the Secretary determines that the performance or misconduct of such an individual does not warrant removal from the senior executive service position, the Secretary may suspend, reprimand, or admonish the individual.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCC1EAB907D64467984E53FB0C6AB62AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Removal of appeal to Merit Systems Protection Board</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 713 is further amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB3FEBB6FC8034BDBBED3014EB8EC7DCE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBAF60E91804F4DA3BFAA3A46FC17AAB3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>so removes</quote> and inserting <quote>removes</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE176614BBB8D4382B43170803D92D66B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7434F49E26F740B99DA5DC70FE0CC6E8" style="USC">
 <paragraph id="H29B476E7F8B24AC3ABD53B1F47C5CC79" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the date that is five days before taking any personnel action against a senior executive under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall provide the individual with—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1F02F783984F4F468CDCFABC27BAFE30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notice in writing of the proposed personnel action, including the reasons for such action; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B19BD752225431681220884A94F9520"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an opportunity to respond to the proposed personnel action within the five-day period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6784E22E9C8E4B26A5BB4F6C6611C235"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)—</text> <subparagraph id="H94A416AF62814AC0B3D73EF449468303"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>under this section</quote> and inserting <quote>under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/723">section 723</external-xref> of this title</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBEF175028A249EBA82DDC39B3F09C4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the second sentence;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDC0A46EFBDE4B688F0C2FE5A561ED07"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H48F6CE2D8D8546068249DF65E106CF95"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>30</quote> and inserting <quote>five</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A8A60CF738E40369375860CF7C0CAED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and the reason for such removal or transfer</quote> and inserting <quote>, the reason for such removal or transfer, the name and position of the individual, and all charging documents and evidence pertaining to such removal or transfer</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H21ECC7FB37E040998663463628A383A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking subsections (d) and (e) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F9E812C2C5148AAA4C0AFB274775FE8" style="USC"> <subsection id="H293FEBE6ADF9408F92C56945E7BFB980"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Procedure</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9BBE2E9BE32E4F44BC621053BDE5DDA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The procedures under title 5 shall not apply to any personnel action under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8CA0E63BF8DE488FA6C345F10FE0BD7E" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (3), a personnel action under this section—</text> <subparagraph id="HD24B8922A88D47A6A43D70D61EDD2A0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may be appealed to the Senior Executive Disciplinary Appeals Board under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/723">section 723</external-xref> of this title; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7A363C31CA84FCBADFB5F5C36C708A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not be appealed to the Merit Systems Protection Board under section 7701 of title 5.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EAA1185B1DE4A79B2221DF95511D7C4" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An appeal under paragraph (2)(A) of a personnel action under this section may only be made if such appeal is made not later than seven days after the date of such action. If no such appeal is made, the decision of the Secretary under this section shall be final.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB852C863158148ECB80FAEC9957910C5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (f) and (g) as subsections (e) and (f), respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC820429C770349E5857E8765EA16C911"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (f), as redesignated by paragraph (5), by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0139B46F36304B40A0FB01FF4D723653" style="USC">
 <paragraph id="H6BEC904FB8724D7D9C49018314A5FA2C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>suspend</term> means the placing of an individual in a temporary status without duties and pay for a period greater than 14 days.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9776CFAAB8B74504AC965477F9B5CB23"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Removal of expedited procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 707 of the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/146">Public Law 113–146</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/713">38 U.S.C. 713</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA236F75C08A34764901D43464272D453"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDF97F0C0A0C401DAD1325AF92DEA4D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (b) and (c), respectively.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H965F66F82A97425A9B61783E36C5B70A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Senior Executive Disciplinary Appeals Board</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 7 is further amended by inserting after section 721, as added by section 6, the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D83E2CAE8C344B49E1199A13A109F08" style="USC">
					<section id="HD5EEE4C0E48A4FABA8B5CCB59F035B3B"><enum>723.</enum><header>Senior Executive Disciplinary Appeals Board</header>
 <subsection id="HDB67D48268894BE6A83188175A530FE8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall from time to time appoint a board to hear appeals of any personnel action taken under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/713">section 713</external-xref> of this title. Such board shall be known as the Senior Executive Disciplinary Appeals Board (in this section referred to as the <quote>Board</quote>). Each Board shall consist of three employees of the Department. The Board shall have exclusive jurisdiction to review any personnel action under section 713.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5189BF2C83B547DF8B0E8B8AF92311CC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review and decision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon an appeal of such a personnel action, the Board shall—</text> <paragraph id="H4BCA058738864DCDAAB379E297F72E44"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review all evidence provided by the Secretary and the appellant; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A8BBE3B490640B49DE7699CF6B327BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>issue a decision not later than 21 days after the date of the appeal.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H68109E1DC1DF4BFAB5210BCD4EEE01E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Hearing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall afford an employee appealing a personnel action an opportunity for an oral hearing. If such a hearing is held, the appellant may be represented by counsel.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7845C62084E84767B9045DF0E1EF1949"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Standard of review</header><text>The Board shall uphold the decision of the Secretary if—</text> <paragraph id="H7BB016856C9443E8A36A76C026767E0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>there is substantial evidence supporting the decision; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8850BA22B712410495B9036DE6F904B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the applicable personnel action is within the tolerable bounds of reasonableness.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58288C0512414709ADDF6E2579B8B9AC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reversal by Secretary</header><text>If the Board issues a decision under this section that reverses or otherwise mitigates the applicable personnel action, the Secretary may reverse the decision of the Board. Consistent with the requirements of subsection (g), the decision of the Secretary under this subsection shall be final.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAAF9A787F685495081D38609C52B85A8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No decision by Board</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the Board cannot issue a decision in accordance with the 21-day requirement under subsection (b)(2), the personnel action is final.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4DF49BDB92D64AF5A896AE1B8D2B1D4D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Appeal of decision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A petition to review a final order or final decision of the Secretary or the Board under this section shall be filed in the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit. Any decision by such Court shall be in compliance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7462">section 7462(f)(2)</external-xref> of this title.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDD12C76678874C298FF9B465B120C0AD"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Prohibition on receipt of benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period beginning on the date on which an individual appeals a removal from the civil service under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/713">section 713(d)</external-xref> of this title and ending on the date that the Board or Secretary issues a final decision on such appeal, such individual may not receive any pay, awards, bonuses, incentives, allowances, differentials, student loan repayments, special payments, or benefits from the Department.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H9F39F437B3C443189E9119971393E68D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical and clerical amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="HB1F666F20CB34F0D80CBB313D108B3D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The section heading of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/713">section 713</external-xref> is amended to read as follows: <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Senior executives: personnel actions based on performance or misconduct</header-in-text></quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H037A124BE8F24DF99B37C5F9104A97EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 7 is further amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H994058114AB14E6AB4CC736C2D405E0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to section 713 and inserting the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1832267494CE4A158013BDED8931652C" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">713. Senior executives: personnel actions based on performance or misconduct.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">and</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67485F25547948DFB3CCBD9F787DE3CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after the item relating to section 721 the following new item:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB09FFC000F664604A3BA052A2B80CFAE" style="USC">
							<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
								<toc-entry level="section">723. Senior Executive Disciplinary Appeals Board.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9E48B925F99940D0B7BA75BD924E15F4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section or section 723 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (d), shall be construed to apply to an appeal of a removal, transfer, or other personnel action that was pending before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H1A898D08D83D487290B55A08F94DE53B"><enum>8.</enum><header>Reform of rights and processes relating to appeals of decisions regarding claims for benefits under
			 laws administered by Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header>
 <subsection id="HDF08D2C1C408483CB76A314B8C97A7A9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/101">Section 101</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H40F7CCC4E1B047ED808EBE354C7A33C0" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H87B55C23C5B4443A9F9DF125F00680A2"><enum>(34)</enum><text>The term <term>agency of original jurisdiction</term> means the activity which entered the original determination with regard to a claim for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB518BB3EAD9E485AB5A23301736BADAA"><enum>(35)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>relevant evidence</term> means evidence that tends to prove or disprove a matter in issue.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H7F70A3945A3143DD9DA49B2B770E11AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice regarding claims</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5103">Section 5103(a)</external-xref> is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD1EC5AFFE00543058ABEB88F5320F94A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>The</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD66B39BEA6194127A0D1E4A3BE193E68"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(B)(i) by striking <quote>, a claim for reopening a prior decision on a claim, or a claim for an increase in benefits;</quote> and inserting <quote>or a supplemental claim;</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H996EDEF8D2504F89B190557BEA220E32"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21A289A4C3A04E91A4B08BF5E803A6F9" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H1BDD94692B2246878884310250FA20DF" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The requirement to provide notice under paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to a supplemental claim that is filed within the time frame set forth in subparagraphs (B) and (D) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5110">section 5110(a)(2)</external-xref> of this title.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A9C5FF0C0134FFBA75D937E9D38AAA2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Modification of rule regarding disallowed claims</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5103A">Section 5103A(f)</external-xref> is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H041D427F840347AFB1DD1584214ABBDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>reopen</quote> and inserting <quote>readjudicate</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H04251168445144F28DD658BFEC362D4B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>material</quote> and inserting <quote>relevant</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1DD0AC7E9D7340B883EEC91D3C4918EB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Modification of duty To assist claimants</header> <paragraph id="H4C047CA91D2C4224B02BA1F0AE2B9258"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitations on duty</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5103A">Section 5103A(a)</external-xref> is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE0515403F40F4C36829A38DF0B046952"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>The</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H868B422B23684A9AA967914F71335060"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD06429DF8FF9433286AE60620F78FABF" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HFBE4F73CC0904614808023F744364C5C" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary’s duty to assist under paragraph (1) shall apply only to a claim, or supplemental claim, for a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary until the time that a claimant is provided notice of the decision of the agency of original jurisdiction with respect to such claim, or supplemental claim, under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5104">section 5104</external-xref> of this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DDA7D9214E94F8F9A589DBC12E043CB" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Secretary’s duty to assist under paragraph (1) shall not apply to—</text> <subparagraph id="H0793D55B7AC740FABB4178521587B18D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>higher-level review by the agency of original jurisdiction, pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5104B">section 5104B</external-xref> of this title; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D9EECF7F2DB45ED8A72645354D69485"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to review on appeal by the Board of Veterans’ Appeals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H55E60AA2BA3548069196B8C7E9BF37FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Correction of errors from duty to assist</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5103A">Section 5103A</external-xref> is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3895D503536946DBA65C6BACBDB1C324"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (e) through (g) as subsections (f) through (h), respectively; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H113D299D3A524C44900ECC77778C09B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) the following new subsection:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F5FD53B2C54431388891879E78F8A71" style="OLC">
							<subsection id="H93C2CC6589DB4FFCA107D3BB5E082EC2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Correction of duty To assist errors</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H35AA7CF4AE1E45B3B1C4F2AE6F703985"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If, during review of the agency of original jurisdiction decision under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5104B">section 5104B</external-xref> of this title, the higher-level reviewer identifies an error on the part of the agency of original jurisdiction to satisfy its duties under this section, and that error occurred prior to the agency of original jurisdiction decision being reviewed, unless the claim can be granted in full, the higher-level reviewer shall return the claim for correction of such error and readjudication.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="HD976F7A4EBC34B2C8827E323B9BFC076" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H250F5ED410C544C29305AD06328EABAF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>If the Board, during review on appeal of a decision of the agency of original jurisdiction, identifies an error on the part of the agency of original jurisdiction to satisfy its duties under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5103A">section 5103A</external-xref> of this title, and that error occurred prior to the decision of the agency of original jurisdiction on appeal, unless the claim can be granted in full, the Board shall remand the claim to the agency of original jurisdiction for correction of such error and readjudication.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6208982D507496AA47DCEFC1DD55D48" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Remand for correction of an error under subparagraph (A) may include directing the agency of original jurisdiction to obtain an advisory medical opinion under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5109">section 5109</external-xref> of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9D44717497A74C79862ED1B7456B86B2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Decisions and notices of decisions</header><text>Subsection (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5104">section 5104</external-xref> is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC871842F7152429385DFD68CF983ADDA" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HB832E82828BA41F2BDA45D41E0A16D4C"><enum>(b)</enum><text>In any case where the Secretary denies a benefit sought, the notice required by subsection (a) shall also include all of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2876DDE7DD484859B565A5B44182773C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Identification of the issues adjudicated.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B485849E27F448CB22BF16157A76A27"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A summary of the evidence considered by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H13A12CAECDCC48B896CD4922C40C7532"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A summary of the applicable laws and regulations.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9FDD98DC725747AA9E66378A552C52BB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Identification of findings favorable to the claimant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B8C1505E8154ADABAD9D4F5AC589E40"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Identification of elements not satisfied leading to the denial.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA44EE2DEB0F4F758449B518AE7DAC80"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An explanation of how to obtain or access evidence used in making the decision.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C13085621C34E62931EF4F4C570483E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>If applicable, identification of the criteria that must be satisfied to grant service connection or the next higher level of compensation.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HF0D2155AC20D485BBEE23EE5F64B5FDE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Binding nature of favorable findings</header>
 <paragraph id="H73DDB704E2A642E7A47E6FE62CB2E6BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/51">Chapter 51</external-xref> is amended by inserting after section 5104 the following new section:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF066D0F53F4148C38F2887960617E5E5" style="USC"> <section id="H5C951F119CB1446AA3BAF88E716A0418"><enum>5104A.</enum><header>Binding nature of favorable findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any finding favorable to the claimant as described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5104">section 5104(b)(4)</external-xref> of this title shall be binding on all subsequent adjudicators within the Department, unless clear and convincing evidence is shown to the contrary to rebut such favorable finding.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2B3C2001F1F4023B6595D0DBEA0235D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/51">chapter 51</external-xref> is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 5104 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A471D1236514C5FAC165791AAE350ED" style="OLC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5104A. Binding nature of favorable findings.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H30FDF4F021FD4B9E8FAAE25AFB572DF5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Higher-Level review by agency of original jurisdiction</header>
 <paragraph id="H6949535CEE1D4BED87AE7DE39D4CCFE8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter 51, as amended by subsection (f), is further amended by inserting after section 5104A, as added by such subsection, the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BACD673394B47C2A6DA875E2246DCC0" style="USC">
						<section id="H195E6BD43EA84F929EC8105A11EB6976"><enum>5104B.</enum><header>Higher-level review by the agency of original jurisdiction</header>
 <subsection id="H7A450DD2BA4441F7AE5D09B25E5371A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A claimant may request a de novo review of the decision of the agency of original jurisdiction by a higher-level adjudicator within the agency of original jurisdiction.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HEC90FC635865466D9B4B78F0B5E6B83F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Time and manner of request</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6C20848ADC1440BC9365E7FFCE04D136"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A request for higher-level review by the agency of original jurisdiction shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="HAD24081BF24049CA8E4D1437EECD804D" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in writing in such form as the Secretary may prescribe; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9AF6D78C6644BD89F046BC58CA935BE" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>made within one year of the notice of the agency of original jurisdiction’s decision.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB45BD4119CB247E5856D0E525FCBD59C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Such request may specifically indicate whether such review is requested by a higher-level adjudicator at the same office within the agency of original jurisdiction or by an adjudicator at a different office of the agency of original jurisdiction.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7958308ED75841C3B4FF1CDAFA883170"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Decision</header><text>Notice of a higher-level review decision under this section shall be provided in writing.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HE1475939984443948D9A6CFC20F56B55"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evidentiary record for review</header><text>The evidentiary record before the higher-level reviewer shall be limited to the evidence of record in the agency of original jurisdiction decision being reviewed.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6231071B61E45D7874879CD962CAB37"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 51, as amended by subsection (f), is further amended by inserting after the item relating to section 5104A, as added by such subsection, the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H41B1EE4CFCE648F29E3AB987533AD3AB" style="OLC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5104B. Higher-level review by the agency of original jurisdiction.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D53D899C7F3430EAE09C8CC2ED5A2BD"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Supplemental claims</header>
 <paragraph id="H6EE47B6149F24EA989A939DA6ADB4C0B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5108">Section 5108</external-xref> is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD2E828B2C354376A39993362C66A94E" style="USC"> <section id="HE4BAAC1BCC01461DAA1A11143C0AECC6"><enum>5108.</enum><header>Supplemental claims</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If new and relevant evidence is presented or secured with respect to a supplemental claim, the Secretary shall readjudicate the claim taking into consideration any evidence added to the record prior to the former disposition of the claim.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H352C34A87D2541069B2806AE2057B549"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/51">chapter 51</external-xref> is amended by striking the item relating to section 5108 and inserting the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H96E548E6E98B4D9FB430CFC759FBF13F" style="OLC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5108. Supplemental claims.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B60AB8C31474543A9C6D8044F5F9B9B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Remand of claim for advisory medical opinion</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5109">Section 5109</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCA0A2A40F4D44680BF4CB4225BB7BAD8" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HA24467C90DAB4D09893B8AEAA82FA3A2"><enum>(d)</enum><text>The Board of Veterans’ Appeals may remand a claim to direct the agency of original jurisdiction to obtain an advisory medical opinion under this section to correct an error on the part of the agency of original jurisdiction to satisfy its duties under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5103A">section 5103A</external-xref> of this title when such error occurred prior to the decision of the agency of original jurisdiction on appeal. The remand instructions set forth by the Board shall include the questions to be posed to the independent medical expert providing the advisory medical opinion.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8F11EE1A8C7E42F88A5D1E68AD39938A"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Effective dates of awards</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5110">Section 5110</external-xref> is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HDB195BEDEC7D45D6845C98849BCD94F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subsection (a) to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE9F879164C1B42D198F1FF98B36EC1F4" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="H7245DA18386A4058AF8A579D902B7BAA"><enum>(a)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB5DBB0FB9F5F4B7FAB08DC7C2BE1B981"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Unless specifically provided otherwise in this chapter, the effective date of an award based on an initial claim, or a supplemental claim, of compensation, dependency and indemnity compensation, or pension, shall be fixed in accordance with the facts found, but shall not be earlier than the date of receipt of application therefor.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3775EDFBE63A4D9FA10EB6AA9F6A675C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For purposes of determining the effective date of an award under this section, the date of application shall be considered the date of the filing of the initial application for a benefit if the claim is continuously pursued by filing any of the following, either alone or in succession:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCCCD045DC1884C86AD22B5C8A93B7D7D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A request for higher-level review under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5104B">section 5104B</external-xref> of this title on or before the date that is one year after the date on which the agency of original jurisdiction issues a decision.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33215AF03F794017933D7AAA9575E4CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A supplemental claim under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5108">section 5108</external-xref> of this title on or before the date that is one year after the date on which the agency of original jurisdiction issues a decision.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46D49C83E80547DAAE0E91E5042FEC30"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A notice of disagreement on or before the date that is one year after the date on which the agency of original jurisdiction issues a decision.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB576F907085D40D799F85BD2864BD76E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A supplemental claim under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5108">section 5108</external-xref> of this title on or before the date that is one year after the date on which the Board of Veterans’ Appeals issues a decision.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3407A4B398440CB96CBD0DF8AEB1EDC" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, for supplemental claims received more than one year after the date on which the agency of original jurisdiction issued a decision or the Board of Veterans’ Appeals issued a decision, the effective date shall be fixed in accordance with the facts found, but shall not be earlier than the date of receipt of the supplemental claim.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7AA6092CD78842B0857202A078A6D5E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (i), in the first sentence—</text> <subparagraph id="H66C846A272F24FDC93960E47FFAC39C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>reopened</quote> and inserting <quote>readjudicated</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H486FE19138F24431B86EC231BFF8D65B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>material</quote> and inserting <quote>relevant</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2253521C01724A2EA7A78939E7B1E2C2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>reopening</quote> and inserting <quote>readjudication</quote>.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE2D27542B61E410796E5419D3A0DA902"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definition of award or increased award for purposes of provisions relating to commencement of
 period of payment</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5111">Section 5111(d)(1)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>or reopened award</quote> and inserting <quote>award or award based on a supplemental claim</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HBEB83679E0F64060AFB5A8EBB0CFA51F"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Modification on limitation on fees allowable for representation</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5904">Section 5904(c)</external-xref> is amended, in paragraphs (1) and (2), by striking <quote>notice of disagreement is filed</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>claimant is provided notice of the agency of original jurisdiction’s initial decision under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5104">section 5104</external-xref> of this title</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H3FE5DAA1ABC14BA7A70BB4FB327A683E"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Modification of Board of Veterans' Appeals referral requirements after order for reconsideration of
 decisions</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7103">Section 7103(b)(1)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>heard</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>decided</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H4B02014B07A14B31A2D019A0E8C70393"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Conforming amendment relating to readjudication by Board of Veterans' Appeals</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7104">Section 7104(b)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>reopened</quote> and inserting <quote>readjudicated</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HDF0BF82367974A6DBECA7CCF114D389D"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Modification of rights and procedures for appeals to Board of Veterans' Appeals</header>
 <paragraph id="H4156AA95FF014F16B36D9CC1C255B690"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7105">Section 7105</external-xref> is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H217FAC2F23974D68BE8C74ACBAB9D244"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <clause id="H395AE415761D46D5894669B35EA7EBB6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking the first sentence and inserting <quote>Appellate review shall be initiated by the filing of a notice of disagreement in the form prescribed by the Secretary.</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H28B407F36C0A4F5B9AE7262E541A281E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>hearing and</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C5BF537447345DE9AE6873CE27BC9E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending subsection (b) to read as follows:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF120F1A4EDC48D7AAE1188D0E6AC0FA" style="OLC">
							<subsection id="HA2063AC1BD994005A58EFB0A8EF782BE"><enum>(b)</enum>
								<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1B8F5E10ECD141FFB25860944CCE21F1"><enum>(1)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0AC109EEE4DE4510BD79AB37E519DE96"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except in the case of simultaneously contested claims, notice of disagreement shall be filed within one year from the date of the mailing of notice of the decision of the agency of original jurisdiction pursuant to section 5104, 5104B, or 5108 of this title.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H755AE67F78D647A5A550FC43FB80B316" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A notice of disagreement postmarked before the expiration of the one-year period shall be accepted as timely filed.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE90E67866FE4E55A7E1CF26210AE269" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A question as to timeliness or adequacy of the notice of disagreement shall be decided by the Board.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0735A40E0D2E428DBFF94E7370321B2D" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB4E95D0785FC4E4090B980BF08FFC2E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Notices of disagreement shall be in writing, shall set out specific allegations of error of fact or law, and may be filed by the claimant, the claimant's legal guardian, or such accredited representative, attorney, or authorized agent as may be selected by the claimant or legal guardian.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H062E7030EC6C47F0B3C774977596BC57" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not more than one recognized organization, attorney, or agent may be recognized at any one time in the prosecution of a claim.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC984C447847942C6B02F7555706177E7" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Notices of disagreement shall be filed with the Board.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DF57470A6654BBCBD7A2DBDADFB54C7" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H615F1652934D4347BC0129ABDC364ED0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The notice of disagreement shall indicate whether the claimant requests—</text>
 <clause id="H8BEB1012D90648FD9ACBDCB7FA09EA9A" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a hearing before the Board;</text> </clause><clause id="HD1F5B705C70F4BA1ABCA0049F0C8C955" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an opportunity to submit additional evidence without a hearing before the Board; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9C49DBB8253A40FF826FF4008D9C4C29" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a review by the Board without a hearing or submission of additional evidence.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDE9998995154547AB88A9B0E84B2CCB" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If the claimant does not expressly request a hearing before the Board in the notice of disagreement, no hearing before the Board may be held.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0003C9E5BAE42FA88EBEC8A3B691958"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by amending subsection (c) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95A72597F7BF4966AD16CC5201C2DD8F" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H468BE9F7C5EC4CF385C09AEF64A8BC1A"><enum>(c)</enum><text>If no notice of disagreement is filed in accordance with this chapter within the prescribed period, the action or decision of the agency of original jurisdiction shall become final and the claim may not thereafter be readjudicated or allowed, except as may otherwise be provided by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5104B">section 5104B</external-xref> or <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5108">5108</external-xref> of this title or such regulations as the Secretary may promulgate that are consistent with this title.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF62556CAD1B40B080814B1CEE81127A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d) and inserting the following new subsection (d):</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBAE19A67978843ECA4F50379D61F2049" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H0A5ECB79264C43B7B4B2C059742D14D5"><enum>(d)</enum><text>The Board of Veterans’ Appeals may dismiss any appeal which fails to allege specific error of fact or law in the decision being appealed.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DB2AB8A2E4A46908F169D2C90170AA4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by striking subsection (e); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54CA7E6CB077442A8E91C9A42BCB7346"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">notice of disagreement and</header-in-text></quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87294CC281E64454881685884066CA55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/71">chapter 71</external-xref> is amended by striking the item relating to section 7105 and inserting the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H557E20C8AF4F47EFB94F3E71FFF31A3B" style="OLC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">7105. Filing of appeal.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA28B5838F90546F2B35CAC9C790B4D7E"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Modification of procedures and requirements for simultaneously contested claims</header><text>Subsection (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7105A">section 7105A</external-xref> is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDEE69E925A614B9BB4A83A3A3576EC56" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H9D20E2EE53F0442C87532FEDE8F38C6A"><enum>(b)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDCB66E760A3144A583BC47C01280AB19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The substance of the notice of disagreement shall be communicated to the other party or parties in interest and a period of thirty days shall be allowed for filing a brief or argument in response thereto.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4520091D53764EBC85FF451FCE1E0B24" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Such notice shall be forwarded to the last known address of record of the parties concerned, and such action shall constitute sufficient evidence of notice.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HDA5174EB05F9440699332BC4E65F8837"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Repeal of procedures for administrative appeals</header>
 <paragraph id="H2B53141E41084949B45B0E69416A9BA6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/71">Chapter 71</external-xref> is amended by striking section 7106.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFED9931DBC144480BD75ED2B2C0E2815"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/71">chapter 71</external-xref> is amended by striking the item relating to section 7106.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3238F5FD25DD43DBAE8B27C7F4D0DBF1"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Modifications relating to appeals: dockets; hearings</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7107">Section 7107</external-xref> is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H72CD4E2AB90F4D88A58CD6405009BA9A" style="USC"> <section id="H4B97DA15C10D4E72B06DE00A9E9FBA2C"><enum>7107.</enum><header>Appeals: dockets; hearings</header> <subsection id="H50E62A0CAD7143BD936EFF18C1A92E69"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Dockets</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBC7AAAD2A33248E2BC76E0D280B0873C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Board shall maintain two separate dockets as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H82F6ABAF37904BA0B6D01A38BF480206" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A non-hearing option docket shall be maintained for cases in which no Board hearing is requested and no additional evidence will be submitted.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6892D6830A474AA3964D414DE3EF5F07" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A separate and distinct hearing option docket shall be maintained for cases in which a Board hearing is requested in the notice of disagreement or in which no Board hearing is requested, but the appellant requests, in the notice of disagreement, an opportunity to submit additional evidence.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC64415B87710445AB4C351B99E05DC70" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), each case before the Board will be decided in regular order according to its respective place on the Board’s non-hearing option docket or the hearing option docket.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB31D4E01AD17412CAF6C3B615D389F88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advancement on the docket</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE1E93017328C47A79B1A9B864BA0BDE9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A case on either the Board’s non-hearing option docket or hearing option docket may, for cause shown, be advanced on motion for earlier consideration and determination.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6AFFDBDCFADD4EA686AB2DB92FB735E4" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any such motion shall set forth succinctly the grounds upon which the motion is based.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BFB2E2BDA3A4D6F928A559E766AB535" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Such a motion may be granted only—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2EDD828F61CF442CBB6968785DD9A76C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the case involves interpretation of law of general application affecting other claims;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35A559EADFBD444FBB92257A26421DEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the appellant is seriously ill or is under severe financial hardship; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA70171C5A984628A2B4A5BF98A96A53"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for other sufficient cause shown.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36178E2A202C407EBC3A61C552E2951A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Manner and scheduling of hearings for cases on board hearing option docket</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF8C6F7BE0EDF4C1090CA947C22044768"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For cases on the Board hearing option docket in which a hearing is requested in the notice of disagreement, the Board shall notify the appellant whether a Board hearing will be held—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDE0AB7351BC64D4AB96F8AECAE9D841E" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at its principal location, or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3E98CECAC2543B4A4507CD3E331578E" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by picture and voice transmission at a facility of the Department where the Secretary has provided suitable facilities and equipment to conduct such hearings.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H67401835E2A149B8B4FA68DF9D24FBC4" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H375F49F9EDEA48609B2CB06CF02D935F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Upon notification of a Board hearing at the Board’s principal location as described in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1), the appellant may alternatively request a hearing as described in subparagraph (B) of such paragraph. If so requested, the Board shall grant such request.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2078322F31F64EA89CDE5CA6930CF888" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Upon notification of a Board hearing by picture and voice transmission as described in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1), the appellant may alternatively request a hearing as described in subparagraph (A) of such paragraph. If so requested, the Board shall grant such request.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1712AA68E3EA4BAAA1B147B47664A63A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Screening of cases</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to preclude the screening of cases for purposes of—</text> <paragraph id="H47327F4433CF444B9970D8A84871B570"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determining the adequacy of the record for decisional purposes; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56854BF6E8E542FC93891C08787D22AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the development, or attempted development, of a record found to be inadequate for decisional purposes.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HC3E1250B52D84F85B0C932CFC71F040C"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Repeal of authority for independent medical opinions</header>
 <paragraph id="H0D34E0D6A3DD4D918FAB13EDD1D11457"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/71">Chapter 71</external-xref> is amended by striking section 7109.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H88681C07B7334504A979F058F6AF9CE8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/71">chapter 71</external-xref> is amended by striking the item relating to section 7109.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H22445F9BF18B4140B6088EA725EECBD0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5701">Section 5701(b)(1)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>or 7109</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E371CC37444419AA8980B71BB8FD910"><enum>(t)</enum><header>Modification of standard for review of decisions on grounds of clear and unmistakable error</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7111">Section 7111(e)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>, without referral to any adjudicative or hearing official acting on behalf of the Secretary</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HAFE73235BCBA409EAA637835C8E485B4"><enum>(u)</enum><header>Evidentiary record before Board of Veterans' Appeals</header>
 <paragraph id="H0C5A6361A3A241728CF0330669D0F71E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/71">Chapter 71</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H82ABDC88832A4E79B26A2AF50DFA49BF" style="USC"> <section id="H3EB72EE009B149A9B833C1E4C4224DF3"><enum>7113.</enum><header>Evidentiary record before the Board of Veterans' Appeals</header> <subsection id="H19B6D04F13064311A4125169F475C873"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Non-Hearing option docket</header><text>For cases in which a hearing before the Board of Veterans' Appeals is not requested in the notice of disagreement, the evidentiary record before the Board shall be limited to the evidence of record at the time of the decision of the agency of original jurisdiction on appeal.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H636374F23E0247C09C9ACBAC0B7C7434"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hearing option docket</header>
								<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4004FE60002047F7B0ECBA6E453645F1"><enum>(1)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9176C9B2EFF14D66813983814D005C39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), for cases on the hearing option docket in which a hearing is requested in the notice of disagreement, the evidentiary record before the Board shall be limited to the evidence of record at the time of the decision of the agency of original jurisdiction on appeal.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29CDC163792949D2B60F2D96E1B6286B" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The evidentiary record before the Board for cases on the hearing option docket in which a hearing is requested, shall include each of the following, which the Board shall consider in the first instance:</text>
 <clause id="H4389A91CBA98485587177BD5649F9E05"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Evidence submitted by the appellant and his or her representative, if any, at the Board hearing.</text> </clause><clause id="H82F5C7CC8E004EDFA0B87BC97A754C05"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Evidence submitted by the appellant and his or her representative, if any, within 90 days following the Board hearing.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3E54B401AB54D6690A5154B376A20C2" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBF0CE3CE04DB461DBD745ABB8C21C6D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), for cases on the hearing option docket in which a hearing is not requested in the notice of disagreement, the evidentiary record before the Board shall be limited to the evidence considered by the agency of original jurisdiction in the decision on appeal.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AD7DC9DED534352B91692D2D76CF9D9" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The evidentiary record before the Board for cases on the hearing option docket in which a hearing is not requested, shall include each of the following, which the Board shall consider in the first instance:</text>
 <clause id="H9C04593446AF413F89E8D366FAA6582C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Evidence submitted by the appellant and his or her representative, if any, with the notice of disagreement.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H77B4C3AE55114B1E9AB7F986B27B81B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Evidence submitted by the appellant and his or her representative, if any, within 90 days following receipt of the notice of disagreement.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H12E4332580BD4D9DB4C2D8E9ACFD8B86"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/71">chapter 71</external-xref> is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7112 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEEC6B37DF58A4A0CB6B6D6AE5B83DB27" style="OLC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">7113. Evidentiary record before the Board of Veterans' Appeals.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3C7D234C170647D395C9A38C81BFDA81"><enum>9.</enum><header>Limitation on awards and bonuses paid to senior executive employees of Department of Veterans
 Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 705 of the Veterans Access, Choice, and Accountability Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/146">Public Law 113–146</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/703">38 U.S.C. 703</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4F7F414121C54AE0BA88336E62849E34"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a), by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subsection (b), the Secretary</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H33F777D1E50D4C05871CACAAAE53D23B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsection (b) as subsection (c); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD08AF721C6A5457BA88272C187B733DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsection (b):</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF87C26BFFFE94EADB16030163E942C99" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H1F414069123A4A2AA62DE44C61D68AF8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on awards and bonuses for senior executive employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021, no award or bonus may be paid to any employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs who is employed in a Senior Executive Service position, as that term is defined in section 3132(a)(2) of title 5.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


