<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H519612969F0B474D9D6AD84A798EB0C8" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1387 RH: To reauthorize the Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Act, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 34</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1387</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–62]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170307">March 7, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001076">Mr. Chaffetz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000372">Mr. Frelinghuysen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000621">Mr. DeSantis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action><action-date>March 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor> and <cosponsor name-id="R000604">Mr. Russell</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action>
			<action-date>March 27, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed<pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To reauthorize the Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Act, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HA725A4573F19493F88197C2417866CBC" style="OLC">
		<section id="H1D99B463657543B3888B67BBFB60E53F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; references in act</header>
 <subsection id="H646ADE504AC44DDE9789CDDBCECF97EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the “Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Reauthorization Act” or the “SOAR Reauthorization Act”.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HED4CEBB49B37423BA453A3BA191D7263"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References in Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided, whenever in this Act an amendment is expressed in terms of an amendment to or repeal of a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to that section or other provision of the Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Act (division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/10">Public Law 112–10</external-xref>; sec. 38–1853.01 et seq., D.C. Official Code).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H958B20A0BBB742F1A5A613E3E1DC91A3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Repeal</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 817 of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref>) is repealed, and any provision of law amended or repealed by such section is restored or revived as if such section had not been enacted into law.</text>
 </section><section id="H9EC76EFD9B004E8BBFE372CCBD3D7955"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3003 (sec. 38–1853.03, D.C. Official Code) is amended by striking “particularly parents” and all that follows through “, with” and inserting “particularly parents of students who attend an elementary school or secondary school identified as one of the lowest-performing schools under the District of Columbia’s accountability system, with”.</text>
 </section><section id="H9D85CBFAFA4F4FF0A97509DC88191C6F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibiting imposition of limits on types of eligible students participating in the program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3004(a) (sec. 38–1853.04(a), D.C. Official Code) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9833FB5D822D4E6297B4F90A6B463079" style="OLC">
				<paragraph id="H0A7B2B3336204BD494B1C3A25A67445E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibiting imposition of limits on eligible students participating in the program</header>
 <subparagraph id="H8AEE51E855B6426981A0A42E02C73029"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program under this division, the Secretary may not limit the number of eligible students receiving scholarships under section 3007(a), and may not prevent otherwise eligible students from participating in the program under this division, based on any of the following:</text>
 <clause id="H4FF82A4689274673A725895EC376B783"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The type of school the student previously attended.</text> </clause><clause id="H6077633A77CD492C8FCDD7029ACA896A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether or not the student previously received a scholarship or participated in the program, including whether an eligible student was awarded a scholarship in any previous year but has not used the scholarship, regardless of the number of years of nonuse.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFB9C25E47EE94285931F67170AF61C2B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Whether or not the student was a member of the control group used by the Institute of Education Sciences to carry out previous evaluations of the program under section 3009.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD7F634345094ED98BED1F5C6FA1A7A7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in subparagraph (A) may be construed to waive the requirement under section 3005(b)(1)(B) that the eligible entity carrying out the program under this Act must carry out a random selection process, which gives weight to the priorities described in section 3006, if more eligible students seek admission in the program than the program can accommodate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H1367A675B9B94846827CEFDFFC290D78"><enum>5.</enum><header>Requiring eligible entities to utilize internal fiscal and quality controls</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3005(b)(1) (sec. 38–1853.05(b)(1), D.C. Official Code) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE888169CC32B4F5691C8B39EF73CA93B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I), by striking “, except that a participating school may not be required to submit to more than 1 site visit per school year”;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H19101092C0D247CC8D4B3A9DE3160E84"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (K) and (L) as subparagraphs (L) and (M), respectively;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H42D4AFF231CB407389CF1852CCF8CD0B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (J) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC816C8C8CBC4416EB25BBCC4976F25D0" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H223A2A3EF26B42F19301253C25191B5E"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the entity will ensure the financial viability of participating schools in which 85 percent or more of the total number of students enrolled at the school are participating eligible students that receive and use an opportunity scholarship;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8BCBA8768624EAEB030D770545F544B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (L), as redesignated by paragraph (2), by striking “and” at the end; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB12D936F67CC4B7AA771A56CBC775200"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E7306F58965472BBA8E98FC5CEB30EF" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HAD6C93232D9A4D2181CC7845014573F9"><enum>(N)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the eligible entity will ensure that it—</text> <clause id="HF388D184BEE44EA091FA677033CABBE6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">utilizes internal fiscal and quality controls; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H894750DF32404DE3A55E944BDE63DD53"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">complies with applicable financial reporting requirements and the requirements of this division; and</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H6F5F401BCD63416DB0153FFF5AB1B821"><enum>6.</enum><header>Clarification of priorities for awarding scholarships to eligible students</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3006(1) (sec. 38–1853.06(1), D.C. Official Code) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HDBBD09890E564DF38B67BDC265E5D32E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking “attended” and all that follows through the semicolon and inserting “attended an elementary school or secondary school identified as one of the lowest-performing schools under the District of Columbia’s accountability system; and”;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4EBF9555C8904BA4AE53EF8308FD3CD4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F875ACE66CC472BBB4E27B303932A57"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (B); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6865FBCE95634DE2A0A20732ECBF11B4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), as redesignated by paragraph (3), by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting “or whether such students have, in the past, attended a private school;”.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H55D5F2078A234297827F16523BA9659C"><enum>7.</enum><header>Modification of requirements for participating schools and eligible entities</header>
 <subsection id="HB2B90C1D939645A5AB827DE1DFC8E5AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Criminal Background Checks; Compliance With Reporting Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3007(a)(4) (sec. 38–1853.07(a)(4), D.C. Official Code) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H9180E0C049214D94848DCDB96D33E557"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking “and” at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF1FC4ED0D8C4700A0C53194B9715C4C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (F) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H262AB489C9F64340A4661E671BAB7B4A" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H2F26C4676E1548408A4C84DC94E328AC"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensures that, with respect to core subject matter, participating students are taught by a teacher who has a baccalaureate degree or equivalent degree, whether such degree was awarded in or outside of the United States;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F0793A052064AF1AB0AFE84D2F1B20C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H467FE9C89E3B4E08A6320A27A46B062B" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HCBED7CA5079E470BAA439D124ACC9AA3"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conducts criminal background checks on school employees who have direct and unsupervised interaction with students; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H272348D2FBA440C2BE2E05AAB32CE858"><enum>(H)</enum><text>complies with all requests for data and information regarding the reporting requirements described in section 3010.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5CB9D4196C774E348CD175A3C236BE20"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Accreditation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3007(a) (sec. 38–1853.07(a), D.C. Official Code), as amended by subsection (a), is further amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC1A30D308D0B4749BB8467FC6434013F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking “paragraphs (2) and (3)” and inserting “paragraphs (2), (3), and (5)”; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H620B60972EDB4993BCAB64193122F46A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5283C05F15C04859872D387D5F2EFBF9" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H57C75F1BDEF843209E258CB3EAC7B06B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Accreditation requirements</header> <subparagraph id="HD359AD53BFAE49CE801BD2982F2435C5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds provided under this division for opportunity scholarships may be used by a participating eligible student to enroll in a participating private school unless the school—</text>
 <clause id="HD6EDDBCB16D9404C89BFD050856D025C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a school that is a participating school as of the date of enactment of the SOAR Reauthorization Act—</text>
 <subclause id="H6874A9D76D30476588C23179A6EEB798"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is fully accredited by an accrediting body described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (G) of section 2202(16) of the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/134">Public Law 104–134</external-xref>; sec. 38–1802.02(16)(A)–(G), D.C. Official Code); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H74A5AEE0DBF24BF1AA69353699032EA5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if such participating school does not meet the requirements of subclause (I)—</text> <item id="H97AA6213E19F4114B9A2092855AD18E8"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref>), the school is pursuing full accreditation by an accrediting body described in subclause (I); and</text>
 </item><item id="H1E88A3622A2143C7AE5849E1C034E28F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is fully accredited by such an accrediting body not later than 5 years after the date on which that school began the process of pursuing full accreditation in accordance with item (aa); and</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H6C08AB2F2728409B933830B82DCD740C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a school that is not a participating school as of the date of enactment of the SOAR Reauthorization Act, is fully accredited by an accrediting body described in clause (i)(I) before becoming a participating school under this division.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66D5E90B49DF4B829AD54D8913B42687"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reports to eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of the SOAR Reauthorization Act, each participating school shall submit to the eligible entity a certification that the school has been fully accredited in accordance with subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1DC414CAFFA4E57AC861B346AF6A8B1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Assisting students in enrolling in other schools</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a participating school fails to meet the requirements of this paragraph, the eligible entity shall assist the parents of the participating eligible students who attend the school in identifying, applying to, and enrolling in another participating school under this division.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1795A8B312A48CFB71BF565FC389808"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Treatment of students awarded a scholarship in a previous year</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity shall treat a participating eligible student who was awarded an opportunity scholarship in any previous year and who has not used the scholarship as a renewal student and not as a new applicant, without regard as to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HED6C0FE1F2CA4060B35DDDCEC29C4464"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether the eligible student has used the scholarship; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF769DB57BC064BF3B39ED3FF2E4A8510"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the year in which the scholarship was previously awarded.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0573154CB1794FC7AB94AF3A0A3A6489"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds for administrative expenses and parental assistance</header>
 <paragraph id="HAEEE3F8EAF4D463F8FD7627B987F389E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3007 (sec. 38–1853.07, D.C. Official Code) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H32613FFF581740C19612469D9630C2D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsections (b) and (c) and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB8C69FE8E21A4B799EF257050AC0EC4D" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HBC25C0BEC9264EFFA120BECA414A8DD4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrative expenses and parental assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make $2,000,000 of the amount made available under section 3014(a)(1) for each fiscal year available to eligible entities receiving a grant under section 3004(a) to cover the following expenses:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC7756466A3AB40F2A24B70257268C742"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The administrative expenses of carrying out its program under this division during the year, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H682079A42AC6414E859F58A8E65781C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determining the eligibility of students to participate;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54BD44639EE5406AB8E69ABD017CA90B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>selecting the eligible students to receive scholarships;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55E8BCE302D645FDB5BDDADAA55E1F2D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>determining the amount of the scholarships and issuing the scholarships to eligible students;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07F58546A3E64680A565788CDEF92E11"><enum>(D)</enum><text>compiling and maintaining financial and programmatic records;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1E28B1FC33E41DEBCF3318542888443"><enum>(E)</enum><text>conducting site visits as described in section 3005(b)(1)(I); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H327EB17FE87348C594960F435B1F5BCC"><enum>(F)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD733538DA34B4436A226C7948C5847D4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conducting a study, including a survey of participating parents, on any barriers for participating eligible students in gaining admission to, or attending, the participating school that is their first choice; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7C8F9256843A43AE9BF62D8120B51E66" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not later than the end of the first full fiscal year after the date of enactment of the SOAR Reauthorization Act, submitting a report to Congress that contains the results of such study.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H12E34CF69A954972A980FD006CE37615"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The expenses of educating parents about the eligible entity’s program under this division, and assisting parents through the application process under this division, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6D6C66C304154494AC5330CF235DC641"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing information about the program and the participating schools to parents of eligible students, including information on supplemental financial aid that may be available at participating schools;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5802ED57E60243D7AC3871FC3DE63F76"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing funds to assist parents of students in meeting expenses that might otherwise preclude the participation of eligible students in the program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04171CA7BA33428098AAAE2F056DAC8E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>streamlining the application process for parents.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H564F76FDF9884AB8A859ABF4E5ED14DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (c); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF065A2A8D03431A98305C8D088F35D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (e), as added by section 162(b) of the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2017 (division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/223">Public Law 114–223</external-xref>, as amended by section 101(3) of the Further Continuing and Security Assistance Appropriations Act, 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/254">Public Law 114–254</external-xref>)), as subsection (d).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF878AB6DCB94AF283F79E8C2EDE9FAA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3007(d) (sec. 38–1853.07(d), D.C. Official Code), as redesignated by paragraph (1)(C), is amended by striking <quote>subsections (b), (c), and (d)</quote> each place it appears in paragraphs (2)(B) and (3) and inserting <quote>subsections (b) and (c)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H03A103A642A1412C9A254FB8BEB0D129"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clarification of use of funds for student academic assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3007(c) (sec. 38–1853.07(c), D.C. Official Code), as redesignated by subsection (c)(1)(B), is amended by striking “previously attended” and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting “previously attended an elementary school or secondary school identified as one of the lowest-performing schools under the District of Columbia’s accountability system.”.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H39A75DFDD17D486E851251537A9BCBB1"><enum>8.</enum><header>Program evaluation</header>
			<subsection id="HB3CB57A569154C0D94787123F7FD8B4D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Revision of evaluation procedures and requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="H14A93D6FABC54314BEF7CA38550D5691"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3009(a) (sec. 38–1853.09(a), D.C. Official Code) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E8B4CEA362A4FA8A3A17669FCF93634" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HF8FC6556AE7348088C3545EB5F4F676A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="HD1C57B9403654827973249F0ACB605D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Duties of the Secretary and the Mayor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE8DA351BA1D540E5BEB5BD4E9D70CFAB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>jointly enter into an agreement with the Institute of Education Sciences of the Department of Education to evaluate annually the opportunity scholarship program under this division;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38D127836F4F4A5C9A097E9C652C0500"><enum>(B)</enum><text>jointly enter into an agreement to monitor and evaluate the use of funds authorized and appropriated for the District of Columbia public schools and the District of Columbia public charter schools under this division; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF1B042DCE6640F19FD7D7C721C1CB65"><enum>(C)</enum><text>make the evaluations described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) public in accordance with subsection (c).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H36E7933A04514234BEB591682D064D2F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties of the Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, through a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HF4E0CBBA76CB489B8419C7F6A7900F71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that the evaluation under paragraph (1)(A)—</text>
 <clause id="H0B439DF72E1C49EB91BAA8C1D4E751DA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is conducted using an acceptable quasi-experimental research design for determining the effectiveness of the opportunity scholarship program under this division that does not use a control study group consisting of students who applied for but did not receive opportunity scholarships; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7DA615351A794D4B83663314E7ACB36F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>addresses the issues described in paragraph (4); and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4887FDD6294A4F3E94CDBF6B1F1DEE4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disseminate information on the impact of the program—</text>
 <clause id="HFF79C21EEF7741BA8E7780F7163FD10F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>on academic achievement and educational attainment of participating eligible students who use an opportunity scholarship; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7559A68793E548EAA5C9EDE9B17C5E58"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on students and schools in the District of Columbia.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D485C1780844F5EB376C01703F1174E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties of the Institute on Education Sciences</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Institute of Education Sciences of the Department of Education shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF87D2BADCC5749A5B5566663EC439373"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assess participating eligible students who use an opportunity scholarship in each of grades 3 through 8, as well as one of the grades at the high school level, by supervising the administration of the same reading and mathematics assessment used by the District of Columbia public schools to comply with section 1111(b) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABDBA865E2854296BC68F9F97249B615"><enum>(B)</enum><text>measure the academic achievement of all participating eligible students who use an opportunity scholarship in the grades described in subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA624D227F3694D99AF8D358E742538E2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>work with eligible entities receiving a grant under this division to ensure that the parents of each student who is a participating eligible student that uses an opportunity scholarship agrees to permit their child to participate in the evaluations and assessments carried out by the Institute of Education Sciences under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AE710C4C9F64E5084681EF252D37F1D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Issues to be evaluated</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The issues to be evaluated under paragraph (1)(A) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H1B7585F8881E4DF487E6723DCFCCA132"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A comparison of the academic achievement of participating eligible students who use an opportunity scholarship on the measurements described in paragraph (3)(B) to the academic achievement of a comparison group of students with similar backgrounds in the District of Columbia public schools and the District of Columbia public charter schools.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06BCD29AC6594E51959E2B26680A6DC5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The success of the program under this division in expanding choice options for parents of participating eligible students and increasing the satisfaction of such parents and students with their choice.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3304FAF946CB43718B3BFC2C41B38816"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The reasons parents of participating eligible students choose for their children to participate in the program, including important characteristics for selecting schools.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H018BFE3F6FBF4AC3B61F3252905D05A2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A comparison of the retention rates, high school graduation rates, college enrollment rates, college persistence rates, and college graduation rates of participating eligible students who use an opportunity scholarship with the rates of students in the comparison group described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37484A644E6C48529B7BCEF9B4D4C6D5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A comparison of the college enrollment rates, college persistence rates, and college graduation rates of students who participated in the program in 2004, 2005, 2011, 2012, 2013, 2014, and 2015 as the result of winning the Opportunity Scholarship Program lottery with such enrollment, persistence, and graduation rates for students who entered but did not win such lottery in those years and who, as a result, served as the control group for previous evaluations of the program under this division. Nothing in this subparagraph may be construed to waive section 3004(a)(3)(A)(iii) with respect to any such student.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC42DCC375E7B436E90759B12F9B32D7A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A comparison of the safety of the schools attended by participating eligible students who use an opportunity scholarship and the schools in the District of Columbia attended by students in the comparison group described in subparagraph (A), based on the perceptions of the students and parents.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9573B22EE9D24DB7A9FD46212507F8C1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>An assessment of student academic achievement at participating schools in which 85 percent of the total number of students enrolled at the school are participating eligible students who receive and use an opportunity scholarship.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1E813D988D647BF816ABA228FB43462"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Such other issues with respect to participating eligible students who use an opportunity scholarship as the Secretary considers appropriate for inclusion in the evaluation, such as the impact of the program on public elementary schools and secondary schools in the District of Columbia.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB23667F3A74148C9A4C76E0784FAB516"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Prohibiting disclosure of personal information</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1028A8DF03644CC68AE6B79AAD76B3F9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any disclosure of personally identifiable information obtained under this division shall be in compliance with section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (commonly known as the ‘Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974’) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF18F0D2A55E46ECA8C2C58AC3B8F408"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Students not attending public school</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any student who is not attending a public elementary school or secondary school, personally identifiable information obtained under this division shall only be disclosed to—</text>
 <clause id="H53EA28CD563A4576B80ACC58AA45A7F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>individuals carrying out the evaluation described in paragraph (1)(A) for such student;</text> </clause><clause id="HA549D59A2D4E4C2CBEDD113AB7FC3D22"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the group of individuals providing information for carrying out the evaluation of such student; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9900B61585064663A2052D6530C32CA0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the parents of such student.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H62E3CAAB63FD48839213702BA3836A36"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transition of evaluation</header> <subparagraph id="HEDC012906FCD40F0A79C26EA212363F2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Termination of previous evaluations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education shall—</text>
 <clause id="H38CCD4FE36204C589A63F18A275CA477"><enum>(i)</enum><text>terminate the evaluations conducted under section 3009(a) of the Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Act (sec. 38–1853.09(a), D.C. Official Code), as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act, after obtaining data for the 2017–2018 school year; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9F4D859CF52E458AAD6548F8C5E893D6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit any reports required for the 2017–2018 school year or preceding years with respect to the evaluations in accordance with section 3009(b) of such Act.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92091CE8407D4E6A89DF92693665493C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>New evaluations</header>
 <clause id="H1B4E0C4299A447C689D8F327E9CB3BE1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective beginning with respect to the 2018–2019 school year, the Secretary shall conduct new evaluations in accordance with the provisions of section 3009(a) of the Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Act (sec. 38–1853.09(a), D.C. Official Code), as amended by this Act.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB349727DECFC4D7587D96A2854776540"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Most recent evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a component of the new evaluations described in clause (i), the Secretary shall continue to monitor and evaluate the students who were evaluated in the most recent evaluation under such section prior to the date of enactment of this Act, including by monitoring and evaluating the test scores and other information of such students.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0DD7523A38F7457998372DBFAF8C0F2E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duty of Mayor To ensure Institute has all information necessary To carry out evaluations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3011(a)(1) (sec. 38–1853.11(a)(1), D.C. Official Code) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8AB95334FEE34612B81C2C5F34DAF432" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HE3B3C6CF2FE047F3BF9CAC186959CFAD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information necessary to carry out evaluations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensure that all District of Columbia public schools and District of Columbia public charter schools make available to the Institute of Education Sciences of the Department of Education all of the information the Institute requires to carry out the assessments and perform the evaluations required under section 3009(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H8EFFA4021F0B48638CDB4D78FB312A49"><enum>9.</enum><header>Funding for District of Columbia public schools and public charter schools</header>
 <subsection id="H2AF9E8C85DA543589927971C326DE0BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mandatory withholding of funds for failure To comply with conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3011(b) (sec. 38–1853.11(b), D.C. Official Code) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H909279B283FD48F0A156A6E62D8BBDAF" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HEDC40669A98142DAA73D6E17EE139409"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, after reasonable notice and an opportunity for a hearing, the Secretary determines that the Mayor has failed to comply with any of the requirements of subsection (a), the Secretary may withhold from the Mayor, in whole or in part—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0772705AD5144EAE813EF7B96EDAD8B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the funds otherwise authorized to be appropriated under section 3014(a)(2), if the failure to comply relates to the District of Columbia public schools;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C41F8BEB5254FC487A51A014664CC4D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the funds otherwise authorized to be appropriated under section 3014(a)(3), if the failure to comply relates to the District of Columbia public charter schools; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H588C95E6D0B54AF79C3A04929DAD5ADC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the funds otherwise authorized to be appropriated under both paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 3014(a), if the failure relates to both the District of Columbia public schools and the District of Columbia public charter schools.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAD8CD7AC31AB4FBDB8DA95C7D9EBFF86"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules for use of funds provided for support of public charter schools</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3011 (sec. 38–1853.11, D.C. Official Code) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE4271C23FF3642A9B344E66560EE1929"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) and (c) as subsections (c) and (d), respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E04065BBA024999B23790B569D882A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C099FB607404F6E89178EE97B4091B5" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H12E7E3B0AD5F491FB8714BDD9B0009BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Specific rules regarding funds provided for support of public charter schools</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following rules shall apply with respect to the funds provided under this division for the support of District of Columbia public charter schools:</text>
 <paragraph id="H6C65474FF79F4EF7A91F9479D1BB0E5B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary may direct the funds provided for any fiscal year, or any portion thereof, to the Office of the State Superintendent of Education of the District of Columbia.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF98717F10FE7473DAD9D0AA7984DF80E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Office of the State Superintendent of Education of the District of Columbia may transfer the funds to subgrantees that are—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC277B69BD8AA4CF29F9DE708CB9815BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specific District of Columbia public charter schools or networks of such schools; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90E8AA8A014948BCB6B94894F231A4AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>District of Columbia-based nonprofit organizations with experience in successfully providing support or assistance to District of Columbia public charter schools or networks of such schools.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DED3AE4EDDF42C99ABA64CB007E5F8A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The funds provided under this division for the support of District of Columbia public charter schools shall be available to any District of Columbia public charter school in good standing with the District of Columbia Charter School Board, and the Office of the State Superintendent of Education of the District of Columbia and the District of Columbia Charter School Board may not restrict the availability of such funds to certain types of schools on the basis of the school’s location, governing body, or the school’s facilities.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H917B557010A0445AB3B1CDD9CCD53C33"><enum>10.</enum><header>Revision of current memorandum of understanding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than the beginning of the 2018–2019 school year, the Secretary of Education and the Mayor of the District of Columbia shall revise the memorandum of understanding which is in effect under section 3012(d) of the Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Act as of the day before the date of the enactment of this Act to address the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H029B41CEB5F04EEC8CED8F9CBD2D8E3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The amendments made by this Act.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4ADBCE759389480CB1B5B9A901CD53A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The need to ensure that participating schools under the Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Act meet fire code standards and maintain certificates of occupancy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FA4F71077F941CF8D5FBA5449CE054A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The need to ensure that District of Columbia public schools and District of Columbia public charter schools meet the requirements under such Act to comply with all reasonable requests for information necessary to carry out the evaluations required under section 3009(a) of such Act.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H15CF526BDCB8402282C2FEB2BF31026F"><enum>11.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3013 (sec. 38–1853.13, D.C. Official Code) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD9935973F04B4656A64742E4FF9F01AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (10) as paragraphs (2) through (11), respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H280E3413A8BC455098DD1CB9A93832C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (2), as redesignated by paragraph (1), the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H72038B21C62B4D3F90B5216AA8B34DB2" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HBD89488C660B4B15A976FCC19D73C6A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Core subject matter</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>core subject matter</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5148426E74104CF6961844BCD97DECAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>mathematics;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72ADB1A561774B2AB218BDA1FD86BFA7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>science; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C2B38D6A3D44646870B4F45FEA9177F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>English, reading, or language arts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCFD51A7EC498422E872E6CE8BFCCD909"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(B), as redesignated by paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>household with a</quote> before <quote>student</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HB6201E1979A745D09F0D50A4DB490635"><enum>12.</enum><header>Extension of authorization of appropriations</header>
 <subsection id="HB686A59B8E1C4FE89F7C3C218B464722"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3014(a) (sec. 38–1853.14, D.C. Official Code) is amended by striking “and for each of the 4 succeeding fiscal years” and inserting “and for each fiscal year through fiscal year 2022”.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6C1A8659FA2B482AA1B055CAC21FD31A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on September 30, 2016.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H9E09650A014844FB9CD1CE27964E0084"><enum>13.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided, the amendments made by this Act shall apply with respect to school year 2018–2019 and each succeeding school year.</text>
		</section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>March 27, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


