<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5A217B8799CB4602AB39EC36F62F84A1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2706 IH: Financial Institution Customer Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2706</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000569">Mr. Luetkemeyer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000598">Mr. Rothfus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000491">Mr. Lucas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001074">Mr. Hollingsworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001059">Mr. Hultgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001193">Mr. MacArthur</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide requirements for the appropriate Federal banking agencies when requesting or ordering a
			 depository institution to terminate a specific customer account, to
			 provide for additional requirements related to subpoenas issued under the
			 Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H93A39B815276419EBB537F1A391D99C3" style="OLC">
 <section id="H805A11D49E46410D800095DD8996AE48" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Financial Institution Customer Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF78168FF5EA94D328F60A7D2BAEFAE12"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirements for deposit account termination requests and orders</header> <subsection id="H32AEEA55E2CA4DF9A02B9088506865EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Termination requests or orders must be material</header> <paragraph id="H765F32C3296E4D82A3F65F831D9CE2F3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An appropriate Federal banking agency may not formally or informally request or order a depository institution to terminate a specific customer account or group of customer accounts or to otherwise restrict or discourage a depository institution from entering into or maintaining a banking relationship with a specific customer or group of customers unless—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7DF16C09E157455086D7FED63E048151"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the agency has a material reason for such request or order; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60707B691DF94F7DB1CFCB1C9E55A7CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such reason is not based solely on reputation risk.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE965BF566C75447B8D23BF6FE1CEC01A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of national security threats</header><text>If an appropriate Federal banking agency believes a specific customer or group of customers is, or is acting as a conduit for, an entity which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H59A53B8D02594A108FAF3E407B3EBA1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>poses a threat to national security;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H719026B813F940CB9BA663FB9F656D24"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is involved in terrorist financing;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC02841157B5F4245902744AFD8F635EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is an agency of the Government of Iran, North Korea, Syria, or any country listed from time to time on the State Sponsors of Terrorism list;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6B6D26735434C709555DEAF48B78BD3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is located in, or is subject to the jurisdiction of, any country specified in subparagraph (C); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85EACAAAE0F240F8B49C5C3724C29092"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does business with any entity described in subparagraph (C) or (D), unless the appropriate Federal banking agency determines that the customer or group of customers has used due diligence to avoid doing business with any entity described in subparagraph (C) or (D),</text>
					</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">such belief shall satisfy the requirement under paragraph (1).</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H44FECCE1CAA840B69EB4ED1A4A1AF4E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice requirement</header>
 <paragraph id="HA0864B2EA0354734A8434B9DB3B30AD6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an appropriate Federal banking agency formally or informally requests or orders a depository institution to terminate a specific customer account or a group of customer accounts, the agency shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H41656F80F1994A0AA190809FD7801D07"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide such request or order to the institution in writing; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC741CBF134244A69F4F28AEC465D048"><enum>(B)</enum><text>accompany such request or order with a written justification for why such termination is needed, including any specific laws or regulations the agency believes are being violated by the customer or group of customers, if any.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H535A2A24BED14A5EA7DA840BD5A74314"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Justification requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A justification described under paragraph (1)(B) may not be based solely on the reputation risk to the depository institution.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCEBF7ACE32D14E21A8BD2D8BBD5933E4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Customer notice</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HFF6533080750467485727ACC51507AFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided under paragraph (2), if an appropriate Federal banking agency orders a depository institution to terminate a specific customer account or a group of customer accounts, the depository institution shall inform the customer or customers of the justification for the customer’s account termination described under subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E5A71F011D24C429783DA8475DEFB32"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice prohibited in cases of national security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an appropriate Federal banking agency requests or orders a depository institution to terminate a specific customer account or a group of customer accounts based on a belief that the customer or customers pose a threat to national security, or are otherwise described under subsection (a)(2), neither the depository institution nor the appropriate Federal banking agency may inform the customer or customers of the justification for the customer’s account termination.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8BF318B1265548A2BDCC0C150EEA5DB5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each appropriate Federal banking agency shall issue an annual report to the Congress stating—</text> <paragraph id="H98A727670DEB4B6EBE9B95BB8D7E0228"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the aggregate number of specific customer accounts that the agency requested or ordered a depository institution to terminate during the previous year; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HECC1A0CA103F4C46A1CF08C6E71919DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the legal authority on which the agency relied in making such requests and orders and the frequency on which the agency relied on each such authority.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6F7FE3D966A4F6DA32BA0D180029024"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H79D8B0A32C974F43B94E7861B9AF56FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate Federal banking agency</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate Federal banking agency</quote> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3D481261DC69491DBC1B76F30B8E580A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the appropriate Federal banking agency, as defined under section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H797851D39038489EA8AE6E1A6BE9BBB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the National Credit Union Administration, in the case of an insured credit union.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EB9176BF498468E97A522F84FAFDDF6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Depository institution</header><text>The term <quote>depository institution</quote> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCF3BEE03856440E9AC37A8DA7EEE992B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a depository institution, as defined under section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7464D6BA2464578A5C2864BC22059E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an insured credit union.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF2A29BD7F3D945D6878DD2499CD0D961"><enum>3.</enum><header>Amendments to the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 951 of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1833a">12 U.S.C. 1833a</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H10C7300493984EBE96F891D7F5B37832"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(2), by striking <quote>affecting a federally insured financial institution</quote> and inserting <quote>against a federally insured financial institution or by a federally insured financial institution against an unaffiliated third person</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H67B0243B922046F891D20E442F4170E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (g)—</text> <subparagraph id="HD9D6C026329745FD937F713136F18523"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the header, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">subpoenas</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">investigations</header-in-text></quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D50333F71464722B32BD06595E7E6C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (1)(C) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB4180332BF32470487778257886B51DF" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HD37C9790ACFD49468C265D794AE3E68F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">summon witnesses and require the production of any books, papers, correspondence, memoranda, or other records which the Attorney General deems relevant or material to the inquiry, if the Attorney General—</text>
 <clause id="HE14EEFE86C8C44CDB3679EDCE16DD568"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requests a court order from a court of competent jurisdiction for such actions and offers specific and articulable facts showing that there are reasonable grounds to believe that the information or testimony sought is relevant and material for conducting an investigation under this section; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H559A0185BC5B4F4BADD68D4A3F71901C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">either personally or through delegation no lower than the Deputy Attorney General, issues and signs a subpoena for such actions and such subpoena is supported by specific and articulable facts showing that there are reasonable grounds to believe that the information or testimony sought is relevant for conducting an investigation under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


