<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF21DD9E41B7A4D1B9BCD65788C177C9F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4479 IH: Student Right to Know Before You Go Act of 2017 </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4479</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171129">November 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a new higher education data system to allow for more accurate, complete, and secure
			 data on student retention, graduation, and earnings outcomes, at all
			 levels of postsecondary enrollment, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H76F30A3811944767862CE4BC29512E67" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA99E3647302F4EDEACAB5F563399788A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Student Right to Know Before You Go Act of 2017 </short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H054CBF9086444B1981B3C0AE294F107F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99EFEE89C5274408B052E11079868ABE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Aided student</header><text>The term <term>aided student</term> means a student enrolled in an institution of higher education who has received assistance under a Federal student financial aid program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE642D12BCEC342A49059654CC86A9181"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Commissioner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Commissioner</term> means the Commissioner for Education Statistics.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF33F6F5E5518417895595D6B97CE4C9B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Department</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8FC9AD0D0E2247AABA1DB528C944F919"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal student financial aid program</header><text>The term <term>Federal student financial aid program</term> means any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H89917CEB06E049F99AD15D16AC08BEBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Federal Pell Grant program under subpart 1 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H000675FE068D429F8DD9F92D511CDB57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Federal Family Education Loan program under part B of such title (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1071">20 U.S.C. 1071</external-xref> et seq.).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5199AE2932A340A096F3588D14DF5F08"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Federal Direct Loan program under part D of such title (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087a">20 U.S.C. 1087a</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H491EF2381B3045799571934F5BDE9526"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Federal Perkins Loan program under part E of such title (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087aa">20 U.S.C. 1087aa</external-xref> et seq.).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02B7BD3B5FF14F02B1A954F57D77443C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Higher education data system</header><text>The term <term>higher education data system</term> means the data system established under section 3(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D77D6178252441BB582B492B86C6AFD"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7564185C8ED1496584777AED4ED9D7C8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>IPEDS</header><text>The term <term>IPEDS</term> means the Integrated Postsecondary Education Data System administered by the Commissioner of Education Statistics.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H19E197FAF6614E8FBE0602A22934A341"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Machine-readable format</header><text>The term <term>machine-readable format</term> means a format in which information or data can be easily processed by a computer without human intervention while ensuring no semantic meaning is lost.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD06C4001C0A34B089AE906F09C527E28"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Personally identifiable information</header><text>The term <term>personally identifiable information</term> includes—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HAD239087526D479BA0580B184CEF493D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a student's name;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2ACE1D36C5F74269A65F44E5A8516F54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the name of a student's parent or other family members;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H24CD94856BC2491A878ECBDBD510E278"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the address of a student or student's family;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD1133154A077453A896D598057A8E821"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a personal identifier, such as a student's social security number, student number, or biometric record;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDCB74D9B826249C3BB2BBE135B39DCA3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>other indirect identifiers, such as a student's date of birth, place of birth, and mother's maiden name;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEB157FDEEC01431196766B3030A52A2B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other information that, alone or in combination, is linked or linkable to a specific student that would allow a reasonable person in the school community, who does not have personal knowledge of the relevant circumstances, to identify the student with reasonable certainty; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H70470E08AD5A43F68D0C10E4F5BAC1DF"><enum>(G)</enum><text>information requested by a person who the educational agency or institution reasonably believes knows the identity of the student to whom the education record relates.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H13DAE4CE22AE43A9A04A309B566063FD"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Reporting entity</header><text>The term <term>reporting entity</term> means an institution of higher education, Federal agency, or other entity that submits data components for the higher education data system.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE91A7167A86E4CF0AD3BACB4FB6DD259"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB2EEB83D48245D29C92BAB5DABCAEC3"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Secure multi-party computation</header><text>The term <term>secure multi-party computation</term> means a computerized system that enables different participating entities in possession of private sets of data to link and aggregate their data sets for the exclusive purpose of performing a finite number of pre-approved computations without transferring or otherwise revealing any private data to each other or anyone else.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H073DC9D7BF644E70B6499DDCEE22F9C4"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Student-focused IPEDS metrics</header><text>The term <term>student-focused IPEDS metrics</term> means the aggregate metrics required under IPEDS, as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act, that are student-related and calculated using student-related data components (such as student enrollment rates and graduation rates).</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H14B66C6B14BB49468FF98AE120DBD2F7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Higher education data system</header>
 <subsection id="H54D60736F3EA4ECFBA71CF38D1D639C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of new data system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">By not later than October 1, 2020, the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner, shall establish and maintain a new higher education data system that meets the requirements of subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF7DFC34B27294A92A5E2AE9CC78357FE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements of data system</header><text>The higher education data system shall—</text> <paragraph id="HEACD9A95661C48BD90F27BB7EF676062"><enum>(1)</enum><text>facilitate the compilation of statistical data necessary to create a robust and useful higher education data system while minimizing the privacy and security risks by using commercially available technology that, at a minimum, uses technical protection measures that reasonably ensure that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H561AE1FBDDEB48889943119C97A82A3E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a reporting entity’s raw data, including personally identifiable information, shall not be accessible through the system to the Department or any party other than the reporting entity;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52223ACC9BA540388C118DAE1DEFACD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no information about the data components used in the system is revealed by the system to the Department or any other party, except as incorporated into the outcome metrics described in section 5; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H161012CEAC214E2AA5FFA0A1228DF9EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>no data or information that can identify an individual is revealed by the system to the Department or any other party;</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2F0275A9EDD470381108888C19DC392"><enum>(2)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD52AA92C5D634210954DB3C83E4A43A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>permit only the Office of the Commissioner, directly and not by grant or contract, to perform statistical queries necessary to determine the outcome metrics described in section 5 using the data components submitted by the reporting entities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1989DCB69B254C6FA27BE868F49FF12D" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prohibit, using commercially available technology, any other queries by the Department or any other party through the system;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F64643D20E6493F918E69438AB7FFD1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be resistant, to the extent possible using commercially available technology, to attempts by any party to individually identify individuals in the data components submitted by reporting entities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA316851DFAF40F8A78842659BD65164"><enum>(4)</enum><text>minimize, to the extent possible using commercially available technology, the privacy risks to individuals whose data has been submitted by a reporting entity that could result from data breaches of any system operated by the reporting entity.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3731176DB05B4F2BAF57ECFEAC49EF87"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In designing, establishing, and maintaining the higher education data system, the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner, shall use the best available cybersecurity and privacy-enhancing technologies to protect the data collected under such system and the privacy of the underlying individuals. In designing the data system, the Commissioner—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H54FFC79A6E64487893866E962B956E77"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall use secure multiparty computation technologies; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10A498CB1F984425808D2DD05B77B8A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may utilize technology other than secure multiparty computation technologies if the other technology—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H43EF732E5B1041848B8A682D335F0933"><enum>(A)</enum><text>fully complies with subparagraphs (A) through (C) of subsection (b)(1); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H18040A67B9F84A9D91E96CF3A1F58CFF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>delivers greater student privacy and security than secure multiparty computation.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE673534D8C1E44CABB06AA8797506FB3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rules and guidance</header>
 <paragraph id="H835B687CF2DC44DC801D75A2F89209C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">By not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner, shall issue rules regarding how reporting entities, and other entities performing the reporting duties in accordance with section 4(a)(2)(B), shall comply with the requirements established under this Act and the amendments made to the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref> et seq.) by this Act. Such rules shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6720ABF86E4F43F086112FD356880060"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish common definitions for reporting entities to follow in submitting the data components required under section 4; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H77508DCFB7B94F128FD1DEE991396A7D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish the collection and submission requirements for the higher education data system.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H477CC16D22964E57AAE0B64EE4850485"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Protection of data</header><text>The Secretary shall promulgate and periodically review rules or guidance relating to security under this Act, which shall govern the access, use, and disclosure of data collected in connection with the activities authorized in this Act. The rules or guidance described in this paragraph shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HED9488A4ACD1405AB3973BEB6B76468F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be consistent with the need to protect data from unauthorized access, use, and disclosure; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3998332DF7E4FB9BA9C2299AB56068E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include—</text>
 <clause id="HC5074B545BFF424E9E83CFD3893512BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an audit capability and requirements for routine audits;</text> </clause><clause id="H0EAA76380E784B6B81EFEEB5EA9AB296"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>access controls; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E4C2A296FB44D5A97CD2FAAE15CAF32"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>requirements to ensure sufficient data security, quality, validity, and reliability.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1560865F25D545D6B5561E3CDDAC9F57"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every 5 years, the Secretary shall review, and update as appropriate, the rules and guidance issued under paragraphs (1) and (2).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEF6166E27FBE47B9AC37306E1A7F6671"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The Secretary shall provide a clear, prominent, comprehensible, and non-misleading notice of the requirements of this section that shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCE7C219AB6A042A48D7244D748C76064"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describe how the requirements of this section are to be implemented, and how personal information is to be collected, used, analyzed, or retained pursuant to this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3F1EB1DE7C9042FFA98CC74EFE9BCCA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be posted on the website of the Department and made available to all reporting entities.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC291750483C1423F8C74C611247FAC10"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to place requirements or restrictions on activity not specifically related to establishing and maintaining the higher education data system.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H3681DC3AA7CA4A63A6760AB6FC3C727C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reporting of data components</header>
			<subsection id="HBA04391CCE6E4CA5B17AEDEB579FD283"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Data components reported by institutions of higher education</header>
 <paragraph id="HA78734ABBE7F4EC58807E62AB946F7C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>By not later than October 1, 2020, each institution of higher education participating in any Federal student financial assistance program shall report to the higher education data system—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H93270E93ACD7417E989A3E9594628BD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not more than the minimum student-level data necessary to enable the Commissioner to calculate the metrics described in section 5 for each year; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAF5608588D044828937F3C11631AAFA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not more than the minimum student-level data necessary for the Commissioner to calculate the student-focused IPEDS metrics for each year.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H56BE179CD14F47D994760049A6290373"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of technology</header><text>In reporting the data described in paragraph (1) to the higher education data system, the institution may—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE4E0AA30C4314C0291E358BE37B990A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>directly report the data using the technology described in section 3(b)(1) and authorized in a rule or guidance issued under section 3(d); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85365B885A944D39B0388313F05042E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit such data to a third-party ser­vi­cer that has demonstrated the capacity to utilize such technology and agreed to conduct the reporting for the institution.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7E291CA652B043A1AA5D9F89B1D164ED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Data components reported from the Social Security Administration and the Secretary of the Treasury</header><text>Beginning October 1, 2020, the Commissioner of Social Security and the Secretary of the Treasury shall report to the higher education data system the earnings data components for individuals employed in the United States, including the self-employed, independent contractors, and members of the military, that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H072F6653562E4B199CDD9F3D5EAC90E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are available to the Commissioner of Social Security or the Secretary, respectively; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA401BC8E3D0B426BAA0620A167482447"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are necessary, as determined by the Commissioner for Education Statistics, for the calculation of the outcome metrics described in section 5 for each year.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3216030B81EE4CB7A7E3DD303007C5B5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Military-Related data components reported from the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of
 Veterans Affairs</header><text>Beginning October 1, 2020, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall report to the higher education data system the data components relating to the recipients of educational assistance benefits provided directly to ser­vice­mem­bers and veterans under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and Secretary of Defense, that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4EF4D7E16B324E30904F75829F70F5DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are available to each such Secretary; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H32EC8BBD3A1F464BA8087A574057F237"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are necessary, as determined by the Commissioner, for the calculation of the outcome metrics described in section 5 for each year.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H364ED02F077D45079FD1BEEA604BFAC1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Financial assistance eligibility data from the Secretary of Education</header><text>Beginning October 1, 2020, the Secretary shall provide to the higher education data system the data components relating to individual eligibility for, and receipt of aid from, all Federal student financial aid programs that are necessary for the calculation of the outcome metrics described in section 5 for each year.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H74A5ECCBAC7A442F871C26475C4C1E5F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Establishment of new metrics</header>
			<subsection id="H49F303DA6E3144AD833737FFF61886D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Metrics</header>
 <paragraph id="H26FD4327BB1B477DB7426F8D3FA7CD3A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner, shall use the higher education data system to calculate only the metrics described in subsections (b) and (c) for each institution participating in the system and, wherever applicable and feasible, for each program of study at the institution.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3F1E5CD020B9445C815D7EAF76E5E483"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period of data</header><text>The Secretary shall calculate the metrics described in subsections (b) and (c) for the previous year.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA3D61692917D4FF1AF2529D16F75602E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Education and debt-Related metrics</header>
 <paragraph id="HEF5161CCD0554F6DBECE9A5CCB93449E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The education and debt-related metrics to be calculated under the higher education data system are the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF21BAC32298C42ECB3677FCDCFDED135"><enum>(A)</enum><text>All student-focused IPEDS metrics.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF77DFB0B175647FE9097ABF122CEDC83"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The percentage of students who receive each of the following:</text>
 <clause id="H67B43B38335A49938C2CEBEF48202FB0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Federal grants.</text> </clause><clause id="H5FC5973765954DA5B8AB2F66E2EBD962"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Federal loans.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0A226A0000E04211ABB8291F1F43E4D7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>State grants.</text> </clause><clause id="HD3FFF0B8545F4BD092C34605CF3203A7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>State loans.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H700964B8213A4B1484FDD2D45F570D16"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Private loans.</text> </clause><clause id="HEBB0458854584C12A5E50BDBD2A74A1D"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Private scholarships.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDF4ACC40F4224AFD9470A84F2938EE26"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Institutional grants.</text> </clause><clause id="H5227DBEBFD0145ADB4FE534DD52DDB3A"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Institutional loans.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EA22ABD7D834D159D1B9249727A109D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Student completion rates, calculated based on the percentage of students who complete the program within 100 percent, 150 percent, and 200 percent of normal program completion time.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB48E02689DD549E698C97FD004547D5D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The mean and median amount of Federal loan debt, including accrued interest, incurred by aided students while enrolled in the institution for the most recent award year for which data are available.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF98ACFE38ECC4290B042C627C4EDEEDE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The mean and median amount of total Federal loan debt, including accrued interest, incurred by aided students of the institution, as of the date of the student's graduation or completion of the student's program of study.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15D692E795FA4B9B9C1226A067A49157"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The mean and median amount of total Federal loan debt, including accrued interest, of aided students who do not complete a program, measured as of the day before the student's repayment period for any such loans begin.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCF05C5FDD9D45B3B9A72067CD645DD7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The loan repayment rates of students who enrolled in the institution, as of 2, 6, and 15 years after the date of program completion or exit.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H503B136F89AD41F3B039524612147C15"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Student transfer rates, which shall be defined as the percentage of students who leave an institution and successfully enroll in a program of study at another institution, by sector of transfer, including whether the receiving program of study is offered by a public 4-year institution, public 2-year institution, public less-than-2-year institution, private nonprofit 4-year institution, private nonprofit 2-year institution, private nonprofit less-than-2-year institution, private for-profit 4-year institution, private for-profit 2-year institution, or private for-profit less-than-2-year institution.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91304E9964A1480AA53FB33EB5EB0B28"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Transfer student completion rates, which shall be defined as the percentage of students who leave an institution, successfully enroll in a program of study at another institution, and complete such program of study, by sector of transfer (as described in subparagraph (H)).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FB1A6A3EB8E4C70B0F8888C1C8A949F"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Rates of continuation to subsequent levels of education, including lateral, higher, and lower levels of degree or credential progression, disaggregated by credential sought (including master's degree, law degree, medical degree, veterinary degree, and postbaccalaureate certificate).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA3A7488689F4B1A92082FDDA2100961"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The percentage of students who receive the degree level they initially sought and the percentage of students who receive a higher degree level.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECCEA6A2BB4245B58D93833824CD2777"><enum>(L)</enum><text>The percentage of students who drop out of the institution without receiving a degree or credential.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE3D7F4D1C124186B372FF0D5D541C87"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disaggregation</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB8C5E67D02DF415FB4731ACE45D0F01F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The education and debt-related metrics described in paragraph (1) shall be disaggregated and separately provided, except as allowed under subparagraph (B), on the basis of the following uncombined categories of data:</text>
 <clause id="HA01021C0DBF247E084963067AB2BB72C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Students who received a Federal Pell Grant under subpart 1 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0AE82FEEFBFD42588BCE61998B01E059"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Students who received a loan under part B or D of such title (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1071">20 U.S.C. 1071</external-xref> et seq.; 1087 et seq.) but not a Federal Pell Grant.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0C46BA0B623747C8BFC954C614E245AF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Students who received neither a Federal Pell Grant, nor a loan under such part B or D.</text> </clause><clause id="HEAA5412C8EB74619B996A2205F358024"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Students who are recipients of educational assistance benefits provided directly to veterans under the law. The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall coordinate with the Secretary to make available data sufficient to enable such reporting under this subparagraph.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H22FDE517C9EB46A89BDE543D4616094A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Students who are servicemembers or veterans.</text> </clause><clause id="H4E5F531C73CF492AB032B14FB76D2F85"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Enrollment status, including the following:</text>
 <subclause id="HF5EE49092B364698B0FEC6EDDFA079E9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>First-time, full-time students.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H9869199D132249039007CCFB5D2651C1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>First-time, part-time students.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9728A11EC6684E708E9DA78DC8EBF601"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Non-first-time, full-time students.</text> </subclause><subclause id="HC6FBC81860DA4AF2811BB87846B7EDC0"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Non-first-time, part-time students.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HC999FF574EAA452E829887AF3D19269A"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Race or ethnicity.</text> </clause><clause id="HC8EBC36B3C2B4D1F993BBCE493A78498"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Age or age intervals.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBAE3402DE45249CD84902EEB4CAD14FB"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Gender.</text> </clause><clause id="H2B6E923D11874A39AEF5CBC128C3A6A9"><enum>(x)</enum><text>First-generation postsecondary education student status.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6EA4D850831D4CBE8E439A35636BF6AF"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>The type of credential (including a baccalaureate degree, associate's degree, and a certificate) sought by the student through the program of study.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H6310218378D348518E5D270A81DC6553"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>Whether the student is college-ready or non-college-ready in mathematics and science, as determined by the institution of higher education.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H0BAA5C61003C4D8185C79D31B37B6D52"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>Completion status.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC8A025675A6C4733A8828B328D67F44A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The education and debt-related metrics described in a category under any of clauses (i) through (iv), (xi), or (xiii) of subparagraph (A) may be derived for purposes of the requirements of such subparagraph by combining data for such category with another single category of data described in any of clauses (i) through (xiii) of such subparagraph.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5F62622D364749019CDD2CAD765CB93D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Earning metrics</header><text>The earning metrics shall be calculated in the following manner:</text> <paragraph id="HDABEA7569DBC4E92B21702F905E5FD26"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The earnings metrics shall consist of the debt-to-earnings ratio, and the annual earnings from employment, of students who enrolled in the institution of higher education—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0F779C63A4274CE18C5670D23449C825"><enum>(A)</enum><text>calculated at the mean, median, and 10th, 25th, 75th, and 90th percentiles of such students; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D70D4943AB04960BEF74F9B131F73A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>further disaggregated by—</text>
 <clause id="HF0967D5DB60C4ED6A25A3A17E75C7DBF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>program of study and credential received;</text> </clause><clause id="H722AFAA6812647589D616FC457C821C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the State in which the student is employed; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8177539E3A824BA59F375A821EBE5084"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>completion status.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H568C0C09BE93491C9AD9B3F12FE4C8F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The debt-to-earnings ratios and the annual earnings from employment calculated and dis­ag­gre­ga­ted under paragraph (1) shall be calculated and reported for students for each of the following time periods:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H868AF59A97D447479BB6BAE582535A84"><enum>(A)</enum><text>2 years after the student's educational program completion or exit.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41D1E36D92DF4636BDFAE8442A31234C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>6 years after the student's educational program completion or exit.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC34C20816C064A329E295F0DF8781794"><enum>(C)</enum><text>15 years after the student's ed­u­ca­tion­al program completion or exit.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCAE943A18EDA4892A6393E4D4B23E550"><enum>6.</enum><header>Transition</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H82A7EF274BEB4E29BBB85D397A26F627"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensuring comparability of data metrics</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For a period of 5 years beginning on the date on which the new outcome metrics under this Act are first reported to the public under section 7(a), the Secretary shall be responsible for publishing all student-focused IPEDS metrics as required under IPEDS as of the day before the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3700652CE0BE48C1BC6F96127526F873"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Transition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning 5 years after the date on which the new outcome metrics under this Act are first reported to the public under section 7(a), the higher education data system shall replace any separate reporting or data collection requirements under IPEDS involving the student-focused IPEDS metrics.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HCAE212CF986C4669BA91ECA19059C7E2"><enum>7.</enum><header>Disclosure and use of data</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H7CB6BCE6EAD94AA7983F648B72C4A7B8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H5119EE52DCE84C4FB2EB50188EF96CFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make the outcome metrics described in section 5 for each year available on the website of the Department and through any other appropriate method, in a timely and user-friendly manner; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H78285A6FF681464E9614C677CA78EA82"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish such outcome metrics in a machine-readable format—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H33180B7AFF4F44A784D8BB6DD1D9E5DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on the website of the Department and through any other appropriate method; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H73D09BC5AEA94194987A3348CC55BD6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a timely manner.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E7E845E81434932B9C596348123B034"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sale of data components prohibited</header><text>The Secretary shall not sell any data components collected for the higher education data system to any third party.</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC779DD1C585346808D61EDA8EB70531C"><enum>8.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect any other activity related to data collection undertaken by the Department of Education or any other Federal agency that is authorized under any other Federal law, except as provided under section 6 with respect to the collection of the IPEDS student-focused metrics.</text>
		</section><section id="HE43E0C443A4C475EAA417DD3E190720D"><enum>9.</enum><header>Amendments to the Higher Education Act of 1965</header>
 <subsection id="H15B007F41E0544C8820977011EFEAE54"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Removing duplicative requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD68EF30F836140478F40E15B8E7478F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 132(i)(4), by inserting at the end the following: <quote>, subject to the requirements of the <short-title>Student Right to Know Before You Go Act of 2017</short-title> and until the Secretary determines that the transition to the higher education data system established under such Act has occurred.</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H156E18D81D7D42BA8DC4A7B887FF1C48"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 485, by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6DC3E13FB0844717A682D2A895C83086" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H984D0763101A4FD9BB6BA9AA18B831D3"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Alignment with institutional reporting requirements</header> <paragraph id="HFF04608B03B64165A2036B664C3807F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Student Right to Know Before You Go Act of 2017</short-title>, the Secretary shall issue guidance outlining which data metrics required to be submitted by institutions of higher education under such Act are duplicative of institutional reporting requirements under this section or other requirements under such Act.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HE2B724AE42304514920EC0B8276B491D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Link to institutional reporting website</header>
 <subparagraph id="H61166EDA5F9E4D739DB4B02F4CF59850"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Student Right to Know Before You Go Act of 2017</short-title>, an institution of higher education participating in any program under this title shall—</text> <clause id="H88328E9BC1C24AF7A9BC08E6823B7157"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding any other provision of law, not be required to meet any duplicative requirements identified under paragraph (1); and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2483081A62B94E78B485981693391E48"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide a prominently displayed link on the institution's website to the website of the Department that provides the outcome metrics of the higher education data system established under the <short-title>Student Right to Know Before You Go Act of 2017</short-title>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C87981ED0EE4EA0AC6DC542C8B1189C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements of link</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The link described in subparagraph (A)(ii) shall—</text> <clause id="H44192E9AD10F442AACF65612061BA2D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at a minimum, be included on any webpage for the institution with cost, financial aid, admissions, or other consumer information; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0112C76B71C14808BBEA1EAF2B5FE8E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be clear, conspicuous, and readily accessible, as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H807F632E30BA49889485186CB1E6236A"><enum>10.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2026.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


