<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB3D631E69F944B3E956C59DFE565F08B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1558 IH: Repeatedly Flooded Communities Preparation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1558</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170316">March 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to ensure community accountability for areas
			 repetitively damaged by floods, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H75140846EB284BE788430F602B008AD9" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1BBFE7B4D2DA4886A0E2F5C17C59569E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Repeatedly Flooded Communities Preparation Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H90731721386A4B378488FA0EEA555AD6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Community accountability for repetitively flooded areas</header> <subsection id="H832B78BF282C432599B812AFC8672169"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1361 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4102">42 U.S.C. 4102</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HE104A4A58FF84C1E9F5A00154B9B7855" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HCC5725D8FF1A41D3AD28EA49B39EBCF2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Community accountability for repetitively damaged areas</header>
 <paragraph id="H06FFFE51825C474A814B5F7C8ECE221B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall, by regulation, require any covered community (as such term is defined in paragraph (3))—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1F85011F2CA944908CE22EE575B291DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to identify the areas within the community where properties described in paragraph (5)(B) or flood-damaged facilities are located to determine areas repeatedly damaged by floods and to assess, with assistance from the Administrator, the continuing risks to such areas;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA92A22D1D1164BB7A209B90361518B34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to develop a community-specific plan for mitigating continuing flood risks to such repetitively flooded areas and to submit such plan and plan updates to the Administrator at appropriate intervals;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A5D4AE4647D495BAE0DDEB6035C2B2C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to implement such plans;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3232AE83D9EB428B93DE94289E930BAE"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to make such plan, plan updates, and reports on progress in reducing flood risk available to the public, subject to section 552a of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9978E14A0F154648AD0923B97C4C9E69"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Incorporation into existing plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Plans developed pursuant to paragraph (1) may be incorporated into mitigation plans developed under section 1366 of this Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4104c">42 U.S.C. 4104c</external-xref>) and hazard mitigation plans developed under section 322 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5165">42 U.S.C. 5165</external-xref>).</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H0EBC670D060944B8A6286B10755397F3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assistance to communities</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA784566267544D61A4C723F37B374E54"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To assist communities in preparation of plans required under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall, upon request, provide covered communities with appropriate data regarding the property addresses and dates of claims associated with insured properties within the community.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF45DC645FD88474790F56BDBB86C190E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mitigation grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making determinations regarding financial assistance under the authorities of this Act, the Administrator may consider the extent to which a community has complied with this subsection and is working to remedy problems with addressing repeatedly flooded areas.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D933EDE50A94A7D94E405E5EA8200EC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sanctions</header><text>The Administrator shall, by regulations issued in accordance with the procedures established under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, regarding substantive rules, provide appropriate sanctions for covered communities that fail to comply with the requirements under this subsection or to make sufficient progress in reducing the flood risks to areas in the community that are repeatedly damaged by floods. Such sanctions shall include suspension from the national flood insurance program and probation under such program, in the manner provided under section 59.24 of the Administrator’s regulations (44 C.F.R. 59.24).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H40172AE9E14C4D38B9881F186A9EC1D6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered community</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>covered community</quote> means a community—</text> <subparagraph id="H02CC9D98B3454823B440412AF3A0EB57"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is participating, pursuant to section 1315, in the national flood insurance program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE41F881BCCF4F05B5F8CE161CA8187C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>within which are located—</text> <clause id="H2D0810A015C2421BA3908FCABD2799C3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>50 or more repetitive loss structures (as such term is defined in paragraph (4));</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE1B43CED550D481CBA87A08103D9A51F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>5 or more severe repetitive loss structures (as such term is defined in section 1366(h)) for which mitigation activities meeting the standards for approval under section 1366(c)(2)(A) have not been conducted; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDEE98C3A890E41E48A0B192E1986A2B9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a public facility or a private nonprofit facility (as such terms are as defined in section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122</external-xref>)), that has received assistance for repair, restoration, reconstruction, or replacement under section 406 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172</external-xref>) in connection with more than one flooding event in the most recent 10-year period.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H33FEBFB4DD014979BB3A1E78559FA832"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Repetitive-loss structure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>repetitive loss structure</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1370 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4121">42 U.S.C. 4121</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A048C18D2714FE1889470386D161090"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Reports to congress</header><text>Not later than the expiration of the 6-year period beginning upon the date of the enactment of this subsection, and not less than every 2 years thereafter, the Administrator shall submit a report to the Congress regarding the progress in implementing plans developed pursuant to paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF003029DFE394E0B8EAEC1FEBE5F8149"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall issue regulations necessary to carry out subsection (e) of section 1361 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, as added by the amendment made by subsection (a) of this section, not later than the expiration of the 12-month period that begins on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


