<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB6041C82D69B435DAEDAB67435D27EC7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1442 IH: Public Service Federal Eligibility Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1442</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20170309">March 9, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To extend the period of eligibility for non-competitive appointment of Peace Corps and VISTA volunteers and certain overseas employees, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H98C0C4FFDE3743BEA1F4E93EF5E249B0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9D0A62A25AF34CB3A1E78FCB85D56EBB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Service Federal Eligibility Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H69E889E7356A41DA8A891C95D2931908"><enum>2.</enum><header> Extension of eligibility for non-competitive appointment of Peace Corps and VISTA volunteers and certain overseas employees</header> <subsection id="H96E5A38972494C79BCF4E80A3489BDEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other law, rule, or regulation, the eligibility for non-competitive appointment of any individual provided under Executive Order 11103 (relating to non-competitive appointment of eligible Peace Corps volunteers) or Executive Order 12721 (relating to non-competitive appointment of certain overseas employees) or a VISTA volunteer under title I of the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4951">42 U.S.C. 4951</external-xref> et seq.) shall be extended by an amount of days (if any) equal to the number of days that such eligibility coincides with any Federal hiring freeze. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H47947FE98AFF468994BA85B5244C2729"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of Federal hiring freeze</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>Federal hiring freeze</quote> means the memorandum titled <quote>Presidential Memorandum Regarding the Hiring Freeze</quote> published on January 23, 2017, or any other substantially similar memorandum, Executive order, or other action by the President to prevent a department or agency of the Federal Government from filling vacant Federal civilian employee positions or creating new such positions.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

