<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6F3B0CE2024C4FA4A5B938FA5B9FD068" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1710 IH: Making Education Affordable and Accessible Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1710</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170323">March 23, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to make education affordable and accessible.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5F1DC0CC1DB94D4BBF234296B3AB6BD7" style="OLC">
 <section id="H80D76EAF24914F918C9A68227D5D6794" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Making Education Affordable and Accessible Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7926E8F4FA3145B0981DC60DF5931287"><enum>2.</enum><header>Credit-based academic transition programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title VII of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1138">20 U.S.C. 1138</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF47406DCDB6941C9A73393BE80EFBB36"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating section 745 as section 746;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC88D13E59A946449BAD6DFDC859ACA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 746, as redesignated by paragraph (1), by striking <quote>fiscal year 2009</quote> and inserting <quote>fiscal year 2018</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F7A0E7DCDBA4703925561254E04B71D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after section 744 the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7A1D4D045284C0AB0161F1FE8968479" style="OLC"> <section id="H1FF3E097C46E4BB9B5E3A764D17264C4"><enum>745.</enum><header>Credit-based academic transition programs</header> <subsection id="H3594E15B74D049ED8E9EE992BD92F533"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to expand access for high school students to the opportunities offered in credit-based academic transition programs established through partnerships between high schools and institutions of higher education utilizing dual or concurrent enrollment programs or early college high school programs that enable such students to earn college credits while in high school.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H51311AE8FC344BAEB7D1FC40D476E846"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible institution</header><text>In this section, the term <term>eligible institution</term> means an institution of higher education that carries out a dual or concurrent enrollment program or an early college high school program that enables high school students to earn college credits while in high school.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HACD6A3A12CD14A6BA08B1AB02B40C2FB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text>The Secretary may award grants to eligible institutions to carry out credit-based academic transition programs described in subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA04A1D2CB4CA4004BBE216EC7D8534F5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible institution that desires to receive a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H061BD3B5AF1D45D39330D65D7EEFACF8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible institutions that serve students from low-income families, students from rural communities, or students who are the first in their family to receive postsecondary education.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H01037946F78048768CD8E99616C568D4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible institution that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds—</text> <paragraph id="HB79E2CE1490C4A6E84D5C34B1DAF7039"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to carry out a dual or concurrent enrollment program or an early college high school program for high school students, through which such students while enrolled in high school are enrolled in postsecondary courses at the eligible institution, through which such students can earn college credits that can be transferred to 2-year and 4-year institutions of higher education in the State;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69587A5599344325A91D2EB703B1DAFB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide teachers, principals, and other school leaders with professional development activities that enhance or enable the provision of postsecondary coursework through a dual or concurrent enrollment program or an early college high school program; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H50078E7400E84AC38B3A7339DEBBD96F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to support activities such as—</text> <subparagraph id="H7A67985EA71046748EDD27753DF1247D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designing the curriculum and sequence of courses in collaboration with teachers from the local educational agency and faculty from the eligible institution;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EAA4F098E9E4DAAB7FB30B55AE6D59B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing a course articulation process for defining and approving courses for high school and postsecondary credit or credentials for both 2-year and 4-year institutions of higher education in the State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC314450B6A594C3E9722CC0099789998"><enum>(C)</enum><text>outreach programs to provide elementary school and secondary school students, especially those in middle grades, and their parents, teachers, school counselors, and principals information about and academic preparation for the credit-based academic transition programs described in subsection (a);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDC902705FEB4D3F99D6BC143F0B38FA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>helping students meet eligibility criteria for postsecondary courses and ensuring that students understand how credits earned will transfer to institutions of higher education in the State; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70E7CAB847304E158B0C75379BF7F70E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>coordinating secondary and postsecondary support services and academic calendars.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4BA7A8E21544EB9A4E3817A497DA566"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Flexibility of funds</header><text>An eligible institution that receives a grant under this section may use grant funds for any of the costs associated with carrying out credit-based academic transition programs described in subsection (a), including the costs of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H922E5FA61C8D4109B543913246A4FF67"><enum>(1)</enum><text>tuition and fees, books, and required instructional materials for such program so that students will not be required to pay tuition or fees for postsecondary courses; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF8D820D9CB54C16B0068A3B412A0F6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transportation to and from such program.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36BAD474E0E04EB5AB6AD384F8462B4F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Evaluation and report</header><text>Each eligible institution receiving a grant under this section shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2867DB7FC5D44EEFA6CAC336E309A6B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct an independent evaluation of the effectiveness of the activities carried out by such eligible institution under this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA62AD49DC2424B638EBF75E8309ADEA8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prepare and submit to the Secretary a report containing the results of the evaluation described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0DD2A23689AB4BF4BA7748034C8A8967"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to impose on any State or public institution of higher education any requirement or rule regarding credit-based academic transition programs described in subsection (a) that is inconsistent with State law.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


