<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE59B2F44150C4D418491676597A2AFEB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3115 IH: Superior National Forest Land Exchange Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3115</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170629">June 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000587">Mr. Lewis of Minnesota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a land exchange involving Federal land in the Superior National Forest in Minnesota acquired by the Secretary of Agriculture through the Weeks Law, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDDBC6161E63447DA8C28D8F8E02B7228" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCEE5162E2AEF4EE8AF74D623344A5048" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="H141E217BEE6F42F9861861F055F7748E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Superior National Forest Land Exchange Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCF3D9F3504C4424BA469292029FA5717"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="HCEE5162E2AEF4EE8AF74D623344A5048" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H6655E7FFFC3C43E7B8B9112D9AB39020" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF635D3DA14EC4E2ABA9F73A0394E1E13" level="section">Sec. 3. Purpose and need for NorthMet Land Exchange.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H8F5CF1B8F02244B19E1972EEF961C184" level="section">Sec. 4. Definitions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE938E27A771346D993A129C44053EBA0" level="section">Sec. 5. NorthMet Land Exchange.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HCB635764AD214D29A14E3495F9E3764C" level="section">Sec. 6. Valuation of NorthMet Land Exchange.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB193447AD4354B0492997205C622C017" level="section">Sec. 7. Maps and legal descriptions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB77828058031422496576C10103714A4" level="section">Sec. 8. Post-exchange land management.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF31F97CDFA1E4411B764901A1416FC15" level="section">Sec. 9. Miscellaneous provisions.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6655E7FFFC3C43E7B8B9112D9AB39020"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="H759AB3952EF34C9F92ED08E9B42477BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On January 9, 2017, the Forest Service issued a Final Record of Decision approving the NorthMet Land Exchange between the United States and Poly Met Mining, Inc., a Minnesota Corporation, involving National Forest System land in the Superior National Forest in Minnesota.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC1281A2F5F7C458DBA6AAB2709728210"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Final Record of Decision is based on the Final Environmental Impact Statement for the NorthMet Mining Project and Land Exchange.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF23AC17956AF4603A554086D64600065"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Final Record of Decision was issued as the result of a complex, multi-year review under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.) and other laws and a public-input process that included—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD2207B76714E4504A56D4A9E4349BC6B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the October 2009 publication of a Draft Environmental Impact Statement on the mining operation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC71A2F8E802A4C9889D3BEB22FE7805E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a 2009 Forest Service Feasibility Analysis of the Land Exchange and Forest Service inclusion as a co-lead agency on the land exchange and proposed mining operation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAD538D9030C74A978F338DC62769C57E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a September 2010 Agreement to Initiate a land exchange between Poly Met and the Forest Service;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDF6278A88FAC4941B44EEE29147C0013"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the December 2013 completion of a Supplemental Draft Environmental Impact Statement analyzing the mining operation and the land exchange;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H55DA555427464E35920D54533EB4C547"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the November 2015 completion of a Final Environmental Impact Statement on the mining operation and the land exchange;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3D62CCE432346A5A277DA46A4618CB2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the November 2015 issuance of a Forest Service draft Record of Decision approving the NorthMet Land Exchange; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H83591F5F29B04BB292C37E2000D2C7C7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the December 2016 execution of a Memorandum of Agreement under section 306108 of title 54, United States Code (former section 106 of the National Historic Preservation Act).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1CF8900195DC423F9199B66179E3401D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 6,650 acres of Federal land proposed for conveyance to Poly Met in the NorthMet Land Exchange is National Forest System land, the surface estate of which is administered as part of the Superior National Forest, but which is underlain by the privately owned NorthMet ore body.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3C0B9B233847497E9EB2D208AB14EEC7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Poly Met owns and controls the mineral rights to the NorthMet ore body through long-term mineral leases and proposes to build an open pit mine to recover the minerals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59BD478997D842D3B4B899FCD00D7E9B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The United States owns the remainder of the property rights, including the surface that would be removed to access the minerals as proposed by Poly Met, and this separate ownership of the surface and subsurface, known as a split estate, raises fundamental legal and land management conflicts.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1B41C8A115284B84A3A1BE8F361FC3A0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Federal land was purchased by the Forest Service, for National Forest System purposes, under the authority of section 6 of the Act of March 1, 1911 (commonly known as the Weeks Law; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/515">16 U.S.C. 515</external-xref>), and the Forest Service has taken the position that the mineral rights that were reserved when the lands were acquired by the United States in 1935 do not include the right to surface mine as proposed by Poly Met.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB3BF5E158C8B4C3AA653C5224399E457"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Due to the incompatibility between National Forest management objectives and Poly Met’s intended mining operations, in the absence of a land exchange, the Forest Service is not willing or able to authorize such private, surface mining operations on lands of the Superior National Forest.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9818BF507229479C81D36051A8E28FD8"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Poly Met disagrees with the Forest Service position and argues that the mineral rights it seeks to utilize provide for access to the minerals by any mining method, including open pit or surface mining.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF93833420C94C96839BC2B0CD60D4D8"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This fundamental conflict raises the possibility of litigation between Poly Met and the Forest Service that has no certain outcome and could set an adverse judicial precedent, not only for the 6,650 acres of Federal land, but also for other lands owned by the United States that were acquired under the authority of section 6 of the Act of March 1, 1911 (commonly known as the Weeks Law; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/515">16 U.S.C. 515</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9446FF68437A45A0B4A13097FD6126C2"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The NorthMet Land Exchange would permanently resolve this fundamental conflict and risk to the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB6923E997664A6897582D4CDE0F7A2F"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consummation of the NorthMet Land Exchange will not authorize Poly Met’s mining proposal to occur because other governmental entities, primarily the State of Minnesota and the United States Army Corps of Engineers, will still have the responsibility and authority to make decisions related to approval of the mining proposal.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC76A51835A1E4779B94907CC6D92C7FA"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the NorthMet Land Exchange, the United States will acquire 6,690 acres of non-Federal private land that will be open to public use and enjoyment and managed as a part of the Superior National Forest.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF635D3DA14EC4E2ABA9F73A0394E1E13"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purpose and need for NorthMet Land Exchange</header> <subsection id="H5E44C97EE00E4D3FA16D0C3029237908"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the purpose of this Act to further the public interest by consummating the NorthMet Land Exchange as specifically set forth in this Act. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7874D181D81B4D8E96AF17FD1C095B41"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Need</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the findings under section 2 of this Act supporting the advisability and need for the NorthMet Land Exchange, according to the Final Record of Decision, the NorthMet Land Exchange is advisable and needed because the NorthMet Land Exchange will—</text> <paragraph id="H3FC2043D680D48199F6AA673ECCEBF32"><enum>(1)</enum><text>result in a 40-acre net gain in National Forest System lands;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA01F7EE159D44D99088CDDD7DC6ED1A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improve the spatial arrangement of National Forest System lands by reducing the amount of ownership boundaries to be managed by 33 miles;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A67481A7FDA4E6385EA1F09ADFD59E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improve management effectiveness by exchanging isolated Federal lands with no public overland access for non-Federal lands that will have public overland access and be accessible and open to public use and enjoyment;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9C885E316D644CBEA0B6A7A95A4A88B4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>result in Federal cost savings by eliminating certain easements and their associated administration costs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H947D8C98EE284C2FA1E625F5F3BEBDEA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>meet several of the priorities identified in the land and resource management plan for Superior National Forest to protect and manage administratively or congressionally designated, unique, proposed, or recommended areas, including acquisition of 307 acres of land to the administratively proposed candidate Research Natural Areas, which are managed by preserving and maintaining areas for ecological research, observation, genetic conservation, monitoring, and educational activities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE1C1F2A3209C496D9C6B9ACFD5C25774"><enum>(6)</enum><text>promote more effective land management that would meet specific National Forest needs for management, including acquisition of over 6,500 acres of land for new public access, watershed protection, ecologically rare habitats, wetlands, water frontage, and improved ownership patterns;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5654075F8FB848DC9AC841972939FCE0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>convey Federal land generally not needed for other Forest resource management objectives, because such land is adjacent to intensively developed private land including ferrous mining areas, where abundant mining infrastructure and transportation are already in place, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H98D38BB5FE0B4F24BDE1EF213EAE6A95"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a large, intensively developed open pit mine lying directly to the north of the Federal land;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB690919177AB470BA750757300974BB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a private mine railroad, powerlines, and roads lying directly to the south of the Federal land; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2AC4B40363C94F77A21AC0EAC1E733C1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>already existing ore processing, milling, and tailings facilities located approximately 5 miles to the west of the Federal land; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0E2C5A87C0849A28718B3B5545730B2"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide a practical resolution to complex issues pertaining to the development of private mineral rights underlying the Federal land surface, and thereby avoid potential litigation which could adversely impact the status and management of the Federal land and other National Forest System land acquired under the authority of section 6 of the Act of March 1, 1911 (commonly known as the Weeks Law; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/515">16 U.S.C. 515</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
<section id="H8F5CF1B8F02244B19E1972EEF961C184"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H34A46B952D004F0C9D500126A9AA17EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Collection Agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Collection Agreements</term> means the following agreements between the Secretary and Poly Met pertaining to the NorthMet Land Exchange:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD965699B237F45F3855F9031C5CBFB27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The agreement dated August 25, 2015.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB71E88686FF142A19022811B6D94626C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The agreement dated January 15, 2016.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4408A528CDC459F8716D1488495C4AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal land parcel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal land parcel</term> means all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to approximately 6,650 acres of National Forest System land, as identified in the Final Record of Decision, within the Superior National Forest in St. Louis County, Minnesota, as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Federal Land Parcel–NorthMet Land Exchange</quote>, and dated June, 2017.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A40940F0D1A40FDBDBA7761164A374F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Non-Federal land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>non-Federal land</term> means all right, title, and interest of Poly Met in and to approximately 6,690 acres of land in four separate tracts (comprising 10 separate land parcels in total) within the Superior National Forest to be conveyed to the United States by Poly Met in the land exchange as generally depicted on an overview map entitled <quote>Non-Federal Land Parcels–NorthMet Land Exchange</quote> and dated June 2017, and further depicted on separate tract maps as follows:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H42F8AFFEACC149A6A2831BFE49609F6E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Tract 1</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Approximately 4,650 acres of land in St. Louis County, Minnesota, generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Non-Federal Land Parcel–NorthMet Land Exchange–Hay Lake Tract</quote>, and dated June, 2017.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAAB3D89F8BDF4DE5B8D084A39135E5E4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Tract 2</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Approximately 320 acres of land in 4 separate parcels in Lake County, Minnesota, generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Non-Federal Land Parcels–NorthMet Land Exchange–Lake County Lands</quote>, and dated June, 2017.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBC2E41690BD544A5B704397E07D50EBC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Tract 3</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Approximately 1,560 acres of land in 4 separate parcels in Lake County, Minnesota, generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Non-Federal Land Parcels–NorthMet Land Exchange–Wolf Lands</quote>, and dated June, 2017.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H62AD55059F2C4B3FA7C86C7593DD362C" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Tract 4</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Approximately 160 acres of land in St. Louis County, Minnesota, generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Non-Federal Land Parcel–NorthMet Land Exchange–Hunting Club Lands</quote>, dated June, 2017.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6DDF4CDAE4041D5B3B60F16117F744F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>NorthMet Land Exchange</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>NorthMet Land Exchange</term> means the land exchange specifically authorized and directed by section 5 of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H864731FE6D21419F98D54201AAEEBB6B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Poly Met</header><text>The term <term>Poly Met</term> means Poly Met Mining Corporation, Inc., a Minnesota Corporation with executive offices in St. Paul, Minnesota, and headquarters in Hoyt Lakes, Minnesota.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F2ABCB94E684DD88EFE6884B7198816"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Record of Decision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Record of Decision</term> means the Final Record of Decision of the Forest Service issued on January 9, 2017, approving the NorthMet Land exchange between the United States and PolyMet Mining, Inc., a Minnesota Corporation, involving National Forest System land in the Superior National Forest in Minnesota.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2558F5FBF4984C58BF914C268F25D368"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H73A95DD1804545F4927CCB1EC74515EF"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Minnesota.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HE938E27A771346D993A129C44053EBA0"><enum>5.</enum><header>NorthMet Land Exchange</header> <subsection id="HCAC8CD4E7262431297F52F53D068937A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exchange authorized and directed</header> <paragraph id="H39E883BF4D2F463682CE7924206B26C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to section 6(c)(1) and other conditions imposed by this Act, if Poly Met offers to convey to the United States all right, title, and interest of Poly Met in and to the non-Federal land, the Secretary shall accept the offer and convey to Poly Met all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Federal land parcel.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A99772669A443FE8EBD1B24692007F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Land exchange expedited</header><text>Subject to the conditions imposed by this Act, the NorthMet Land Exchange directed by this Act shall be consummated not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC68F3DE8A3C7419880EE6D929C332BA8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form of conveyance</header> <paragraph id="HB41FCDEABA354DB4B9AF07ABABEF83A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Non-Federal land</header><text>Title to the non-Federal land conveyed by Poly Met to the United States shall be by general warranty deed subject to existing rights of record, and otherwise conform to the title approval regulations of the Attorney General of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAFE82F28C2024028B539074BFE2181C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal land parcel</header><text>The Federal land parcel shall be quitclaimed by the Secretary to Poly Met by an exchange deed.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4F3305B841204FA3A5E3C44CEDC5C676"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exchange costs</header> <paragraph id="H5ED7288CDD4A4015BD9182DAF9B02AAF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reimbursement required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Poly Met shall pay or reimburse the Secretary, either directly or through the Collection Agreements, for all land survey, appraisal, land title, deed preparation, and other costs incurred by the Secretary in processing and consummating the NorthMet Land Exchange. The Collection Agreements, as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act, may be modified through the mutual consent of the parties.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37F0F763F6974CB4BBBB1CF6EB4C14F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deposit of funds</header><text>All funds paid or reimbursed to the Secretary under paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H3B8864952974420A9D0DCBB689963609"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be deposited and credited to the accounts in accordance with the Collection Agreements;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H33B470F70C28445E8D4BEAB3A8628A94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be used for the purposes specified for the accounts; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H565310446FF94E5B8CCFD5C182BB67E6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall remain available to the Secretary until expended without further appropriation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H37416FD8167F40709F86B9BD42372428"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conditions on land exchange</header> 
<paragraph id="HA84D0B420A9D4596809AAEA9060DDB4A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reservation of certain mineral rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (a), the United States shall reserve the mineral rights on approximately 181 acres of the Federal land parcel as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Federal Land Parcel–NorthMet Land Exchange</quote>, and dated June, 2017.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H835DF169DBE74CDC830EBCBDBC662CD9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Third-party authorizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As set forth in the Final Record of Decision, Poly Met shall honor existing road and transmission line authorizations on the Federal land parcel. Upon relinquishment of the authorizations by the holders or upon revocation of the authorizations by the Forest Service, Poly Met shall offer replacement authorizations to the holders on at least equivalent terms.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HCB635764AD214D29A14E3495F9E3764C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Valuation of NorthMet Land Exchange</header> 
<subsection id="HCCA1D37243D2422588AA6D1B545581B9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appraisals</header><text>The Congress makes the following new findings:</text> <paragraph id="HD42A8B480786436BBF1A23267CD7FC4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appraisals of the Federal and non-Federal lands to be exchanged in the NorthMet Land Exchange were formally prepared in accordance with the Uniform Appraisal Standards for Federal Land Acquisitions, and were approved by the Secretary in conjunction with preparation of the November 2015 Draft Record of Decision on the NorthMet Land Exchange.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68CB06DDD440479F97C5BE8A17481F0A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The appraisals referred to in paragraph (1) determined that the value of the non-Federal lands exceeded the value of the Federal land parcel by approximately $425,000.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C8C198393F74689A3199507508D3DD9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Based on the appraisals referred to in paragraph (1), the United States would ordinarily be required to make a $425,000 cash equalization payment to Poly Met to equalize exchange values under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.), unless such an equalization payment is waived by Poly Met.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2AAF16BE5EBB42E196BE3E8C0D2725E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Values for consummation of land exchange</header><text>The appraised values of the Federal and non-Federal land determined and approved by the Secretary in November 2015, and referenced in subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="HDD788CB2EC1F4035A70068840D96F609"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be the values utilized to consummate the NorthMet Land Exchange; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H85C4437B5609413BA65B78F2D93CE0C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not be subject to reappraisal.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDC6BD24782E048629E39C281331406D6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver of equalization payment</header> <paragraph id="H51D0CC8BBA6E48D99F6A31C4BD0A61B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Condition on land exchange</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 206(b) of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1716">43 U.S.C. 1716(b)</external-xref>), and as part of its offer to exchange the non-Federal lands as provided in section 5(a)(1) of this Act, Poly Met shall waive any payment to it of any monies owed by the United States to equalize land values. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A326CE686CE487CAD5E7038C2BCE46D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A waiver of the equalization payment under paragraph (1) shall be considered as a voluntary donation to the United States by Poly Met for all purposes of law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HB193447AD4354B0492997205C622C017"><enum>7.</enum><header>Maps and legal descriptions</header> <subsection id="H981A7EA6DA6E4ABAB4BD62E8CEFD1A44"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Minor adjustments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">By mutual agreement, the Secretary and Poly Met may correct minor or typographical errors in any map, acreage estimate, or description of the Federal land parcel or non-Federal land to be exchanged in the NorthMet Land Exchange.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCC47FBA6C33B422B8B8CB4871C9EDACF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conflict</header><text>If there is a conflict between a map, an acreage estimate, or a description of land under this Act, the map shall control unless the Secretary and Poly Met mutually agree otherwise.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H14B1AB6AFCC34ED8B124E3CCCC177189"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exchange maps</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The maps referred to in section 4 depicting the Federal and non-Federal lands to be exchanged in the NorthMet Land Exchange, and dated June, 2017, depict the identical lands identified in the Final Record of Decision, which are on file in the Office of the Supervisor, Superior National Forest.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB77828058031422496576C10103714A4"><enum>8.</enum><header>Post-exchange land management</header> 
<subsection id="H7F96663A62814EBEB1D6F46AD504DAE4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Non-federal land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon conveyance of the non-Federal land to the United States in the NorthMet Land Exchange, the non-Federal land shall become part of the Superior National Forest and be managed in accordance with—</text> <paragraph id="H422F955A54BB487CA7ACE392DD4B79C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Act of March 1, 1911 (commonly known as the Weeks Law; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/500">16 U.S.C. 500</external-xref> et seq.); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7853C5E1F42465E880253093266D337"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the laws and regulations applicable to the Superior National Forest and the National Forest System.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3D8A85DF24E440E28ED12650553708E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Planning</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon acquisition by the United States in the NorthMet Land Exchange, the non-Federal lands shall be managed in a manner consistent with the land and resource management plan applicable to adjacent federally owned lands in the Superior National Forest. An amendment or supplement to the land and resource management plan shall not be required solely because of the acquisition of the non-Federal lands.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0CE37EFFD6A14E8F972E2AEDAAEF2027"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon conveyance of the Federal land parcel to Poly Met in the NorthMet Land Exchange, the Federal land parcel shall become private land and available for any lawful use in accordance with applicable Federal, State, and local laws and regulations pertaining to mining and other uses of land in private ownership.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HF31F97CDFA1E4411B764901A1416FC15"><enum>9.</enum><header>Miscellaneous provisions</header> <subsection id="HB8580799809C491B9FE8D3E607B8B7D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Withdrawal of acquired Non-Federal land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The non-Federal lands acquired by the United States in the NorthMet Land Exchange shall be withdrawn, without further action by the Secretary, from appropriation and disposal under public land laws and under laws relating to mineral and geothermal leasing.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H19FF78E15F45411BBD66BB3BD8B7726C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Withdrawal revocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any public land order that withdraws the Federal land parcel from appropriation or disposal under a public land law shall be revoked without further action by the Secretary to the extent necessary to permit conveyance of the Federal land parcel to Poly Met.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H24F0D463D018482FA7BDCB0FC52921CF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Withdrawal of federal land pending conveyance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal land parcel to be conveyed to Poly Met in the NorthMet Land Exchange, if not already withdrawn or segregated from appropriation or disposal under the mineral leasing and geothermal or other public land laws upon enactment of this Act, is hereby so withdrawn, subject to valid existing rights, until the date of conveyance of the Federal land parcel to Poly Met.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H925CC49B23C7413DABB8FACEEB9F432C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Act controls</header><text>In the event any provision of the Record of Decision conflicts with a provision of this Act, the provision of this Act shall control.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

