<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD3ED045025C346D2816FADB6EC7CA5AD" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 965 IH: Saint-Gaudens National Historical Park Redesignation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 965</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170207">February 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster of New Hampshire</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To redesignate the Saint-Gaudens National Historic Site as the <quote>Saint-Gaudens National Historical Park</quote>, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9E43C67387E84D56A39FF66A977A506A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0F8D88FBA79C43F9AD659279D1B5DC85" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Saint-Gaudens National Historical Park Redesignation Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF9EECA5A5BF7427C96DC86A4779B8D82"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2ABE4CC9AD0348119FDF5E6035B21368"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Augustus Saint-Gaudens was one of the greatest sculptors in the United States, creating well-known public monuments to Civil War heroes, peerless bas-reliefs, and the 1907 United States gold coinage, which are considered to be the most beautiful coins ever minted;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A9AB95052EC42739D9750A21D144175"><enum>(2)</enum><text>from 1885 until the death of Augustus Saint-Gaudens in 1907, Augustus Saint-Gaudens maintained a residence and studios in Cornish, New Hampshire, where many of the most famous works of Augustus Saint-Gaudens were created and perfected;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H014C1D03D2CC4C79981934A50CD9A68D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the presence of Saint-Gaudens in Cornish, New Hampshire, attracted leaders and practitioners in painting, sculpture, etching, writing, poetry, drama, dance, musical composition, musical performance, architecture, landscape architecture, jurisprudence, politics, and other artistic disciplines to relocate to Cornish, forming the Cornish Art Colony, which was—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H53319AC88DEF4922A347F1B8DADFEDD2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>one of the earliest art colonies; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29E4B3202BEE49EF8580F7BC9A41EB77"><enum>(B)</enum><text>one of the richest and most diverse concentrations of practicing artists in the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H74F92732F4BD4D93B68312DA5BA7841C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the core of the Cornish Art Colony is currently preserved at Aspet, the estate of Augustus Saint-Gaudens, and at the Blow-Me-Down Farm, which served as a social hub for the Colony, both of which are part of the Saint-Gaudens National Historic Site; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45B4D33E4FDA4212BC5283D60EE55BEF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>throughout the long history of the Saint-Gaudens National Historic Site, the Historic Site and the partner organization of the Historic Site, the Saint-Gaudens Memorial, have promoted the arts through the regular presentation of musical concerts, historical dramas, visual arts exhibitions, artistic workshops, and the oldest artist-in-residence program in the National Park Service, creating a vibrant artistic community that promotes the creation, performance, and interpretation of the artistic heritage of the United States.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H95A5199C09E246858116AE7257C6DF40"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation of Saint-Gaudens National Historical Park</header>
 <subsection id="HE83DFEF9E57A4D02A66620AE80C0AED0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Saint-Gaudens National Historic Site shall be known and designated as the <quote>Saint-Gaudens National Historical Park</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H7F59D44C4543460E9F7D5A3237712AE4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendments to <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/88/543">Public Law 88–543</external-xref></header><text>Public Law 88–543 (78 Stat.749) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFAD384012CF84C2D8906D08A48125991"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>National Historic Site</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>National Historical Park</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H44AEBB05C3C640CAA281E106F5E698A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 2(a), by striking <quote>historic site</quote> and inserting <quote>Saint-Gaudens National Historical Park</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBAF033FADFE749C7AC1A8FDEE4D047DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any reference in any law, regulation, document, record, map, or other paper of the United States to the Saint-Gaudens National Historic Site shall be considered to be a reference to the <quote>Saint-Gaudens National Historical Park</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


