<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCD55BA9A749A40C292BA26643B062D05" key="H" public-private="public">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2961 IH: Remedial Education Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2961</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20170620">June 20, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve remedial education programs that train students in the competencies needed to succeed in higher education.</official-title>
</form> 
<legis-body id="H46A1BBEE927A44F58EFF0E035BC563FC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H88E153F4E32C401CB736B45886023B60" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Remedial Education Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H310E028A7DA74F09ABFAC3B6FD375055"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6195D07B2CC648108FA8CA2651802225"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve remedial education and support students as they move throughout credit and non-credit bearing course work and complete postsecondary education;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A3DE7ED17DD4F3F87CB3ED201F9AE04"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide funding to improve remedial education based on 5 models found to have success on a small scale;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5C0439CF00EB4F6781CB484913195153"><enum>(3)</enum><text>through thorough collection of data, reports, and evaluations, compare within and between models of remedial education and their impact on postsecondary education completion; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE66C2321774A4552B182EF834195BB9E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop strategies for replication of successful models and improve sustainability of remedial education programs.</text> </paragraph></section>
<section id="H76C33B3830BC4104AB6F0A58392324CF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Remedial education grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part G of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1088">20 U.S.C. 1088</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 486A the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H322412C6643F465093A8334EDFE39305" style="OLC"> <section id="H58429206A71B4CBA84FE0A936D59A76D"><enum>486B.</enum><header>Remedial education grants</header> <subsection id="H89E15474C29F46E38FB7469D6C924D79"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header> <paragraph id="H8239C18E21844BC4B4579E466087C818"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From the funds appropriated under subsection (i), the Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to improve remedial education in higher education.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7286C4445441430B80283F74913C5116"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant under this section shall be awarded for a period of 5 years.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H895B7111613C45EFB7555A56361A6CA2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minimum awards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total amount of funds provided under a grant awarded under this section shall not be less than $500,000.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H70E71AF3E137444DADCC20EED4890608"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that desires to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require, which shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HA5397DD14FC04BB6A48C0B9B84F854B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how the eligible entity will use the grant funds to develop or improve a remedial education program that includes evidence-based, effective strategies for providing instruction to ensure that students are prepared for courses at the postsecondary level.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5B9913AF5DC247B6958AF0841B0631D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assurance that the eligible entity will use more than 2 measures (such as a student’s college entrance examination score, grade point average, high school course list, or a placement examination) to identify students in need of remedial education who may be eligible to participate in the remedial education program developed or improved under the grant.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D00E3A3B76043B081AC724A81FEC006"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how the eligible entity, in developing or improving such a program, will consult with stakeholders, including individuals with expertise in remedial education, students enrolled in remedial education, and faculty instructors for remedial education.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H25FEFA9DFF14426489CD2AED9C9D0117"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The eligible entity’s plan for sustaining the program after the grant period has ended.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6B5F58AEEC84D47A7E1A895D6B1F9F3"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The eligible entity’s plan for monitoring and evaluating the program, including how the eligible entity will use the data collected under subsection (g) to continually update and improve the program.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA4FB79D33F8844B3979027B3D758CA38"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant to develop or improve a remedial education program through one or more of the following models:</text> <paragraph id="HD5F7D569E97F412184D002D297C51AED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Aligning course work</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Working with a local educational agency or State educational agency that is part of the eligible entity to develop or improve programs that provide alignment between high school coursework and postsecondary education, and that may include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7BFC3AF574CB4697909D1291D604800C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assessments in high school to measure student readiness for courses at the postsecondary level; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9A1C9AFAE4BA4CA3BF5714939CAB6220"><enum>(B)</enum><text>interventions in high school that improve student competencies for courses at the postsecondary level.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6F589F31CF784E38B33A7A30F1CD4E4B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Accelerated course work</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Redesigning or improving remedial education that—</text> <subparagraph id="HFF0D571EDEF24343BB0AA1048C13678C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>allows students to enroll in more than one sequential remedial education course or training in a semester, or the equivalent;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD4C6FF1BBD984C2C878B65FC00C1753C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>condenses the time of the remedial education; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H105287DC29124729B8A72AF9B4E9F1C0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides shortened, intensive courses or training to improve competencies of students for courses at the postsecondary level.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9CFA8DEBE232481EA5217EF0D0EBB2A7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Modular instructional methods</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing or improving remedial education that—</text> <subparagraph id="HD8CAE908AEC549C29156BAD95244F464"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specifically targets the skills that students need to move forward in courses at the postsecondary level; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H68FC4F7F09F942E393C6BFC6C66C3883"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be used to develop new assessments, redesign courses to provide targeted skill instruction, or provide faculty professional development.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB19FFDEF8FA34ED9917E19C2621B4F95"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Co-requisite model</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing or improving remedial education programs that allow a student to enroll in remedial education (which may be provided through a modular instructional method) while also enrolled in a course at the postsecondary level.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBC737BDCD04540318F20C0B497F43549"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Systemic reform to implement comprehensive, integrated support programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Implementing and improving comprehensive, integrated, evidence-based support programs that—</text> <subparagraph id="H96DC4ED557CB4A429C62B559D487E845"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enable students enrolled in remedial education to reach completion and graduation at an institution of higher education within 150 percent of the normal time for completion of, or graduation from, the program of study for which the students are enrolled; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1836C110DC7048D9B75D82A74008AABA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may include financial supports, academic tutoring or support, and advising that enable students to find success in remedial education and courses at the postsecondary level.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9D286038BB7C41ADB19E09040B5DBB6A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H412419EE23C444E4ABCC8B8806592642"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure—</text> <subparagraph id="H1AE6EFFD21724F48AE87BEB8EF90C697"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a minimum of 30 eligible entities are awarded grants for each 5-year grant period;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H480597166E734007A84D6A87676D5677"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an equitable geographic distribution of such grants, including an equitable distribution between urban and rural areas; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC047FF426C1D41849105332343EB3FDD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that grants are used to develop or improve remedial education programs—</text> 
<clause id="H43BB6C64E4774DBFBCF4A5D1DECF7170"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for a range of types and sizes of institutions of higher education; and</text> </clause> <clause id="HDAA71FD3E0694DAEB44779F587ECDFF8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for each of the models described in subsection (c) to ensure statistical comparisons are possible within and among such models; and</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8563F2DE5E0147989F64852520A8BA67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>give preference to eligible entities that primarily serve low-income students.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H28BD867AF3A84B4394321F68072FCFCC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Fiscal Requirements</header> <paragraph id="H2DD0F8A52B6F44F1A03182F48AF82963"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text>A grant awarded under this section shall be used to supplement, not supplant, funds that would otherwise be used to carry out the activities described in this section.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC7979457579B4ED88BD99D9FB5AB9D59"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matching funds</header> 
<subparagraph id="HA6AC94903B1A456289D2BC309C54494F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), an eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall provide, from non-Federal sources, an amount equal to 10 percent of the amount of the grant for the cost of activities assisted under the grant.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA9AB714DCA394B6AB9234A3BA47AF6CE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The requirements of subparagraph (A) shall not apply to—</text> 
<clause id="HBF108245E6454CAEA6DBB57111F31E4A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Tribal Colleges or Universities; or</text> </clause> <clause id="HC3EED8256CE94B159A8D2B5852AEB5FB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>institutions of higher education located in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, or the Republic of Palau.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC8272ECFEC804AC6A1692ABBA3A7424B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Experimental authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, a student may be eligible to receive loans or grants under this title for up to 2 academic years for enrollment in a remedial education program under this section.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H4BAB0114F4EA4F4DA3CEB4A0C391907A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Data Collection, Reports, Evaluations, and Dissemination</header> <paragraph id="H15FB46CE1AFA4C58B29526F8290026BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information</header> <subparagraph id="H1BE32D422055457D926E222803D5D66D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Student-level data</header><text>Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall provide, on an annual basis for each year of the grant period and for 5 years after such grant period, to the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences and the Secretary, the student-level data with respect to the students who are or were enrolled in a remedial education program funded under the grant to enable the Director, for each such year, to—</text> 
<clause id="H5E0A3E38DC534D2A9F1F743517FFC74C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determine the information described in subparagraph (B) with respect to each such remedial education program; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H4C373AD6EA13484AB7D3BBE53A73FA9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit to the authorizing committees, and make publicly available in an accessible format, such information.</text> </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H035AA7BEB1214F34B26EEF04C91FE2DD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Aggregate student data</header><text>The Director shall determine, with respect to each remedial education program for which an eligible entity provides student-level data under subparagraph (A), the following information:</text> <clause id="H27204A6399BC467AA40BAD81EC06740C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The number of students who are or were enrolled in such a remedial education program.</text> </clause>
<clause id="HE1AF2472CD224687AEF171AE623CC817"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The type of remedial education offered under the program.</text> </clause> <clause id="HA75865E6D7B545B095210F6CD10AA057"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The cost of such remedial education program.</text> </clause>
<clause id="H1CBF9DAF5945477986440C9F97FE76E4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The number of students who complete such remedial education program.</text> </clause> <clause id="H256531ECEC33436E8936274228663CCA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The length of time students spend in such remedial education program, as measured by semester, trimester, or clock hours.</text> </clause>
<clause id="H6C546EFEE9894524BC470DE5D9D0C7DB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The length of time students who complete such remedial education program take to graduate with a recognized educational credential from an institution of higher education.</text> </clause> <clause id="HA8A833D4AD5E4674804C9E1A4678B7F6"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The number of students who enroll in postsecondary-level courses upon completing the remedial education program.</text> </clause>
<clause commented="no" id="HB1153357ED8942DEAE69BA25BFA1C7A3"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The number and percentage of such students who graduate, or are on track to graduate, from an institution of higher education within 150 percent of the normal time for completion of, or graduation from, the program of study for which the students are enrolled.</text> </clause> <clause id="H6B1065ECC8204B57B1A81E9DC564886B"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>The amount of grant or loan funds under this title awarded to students for enrollment in such remedial education program.</text> </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB83D7F4F28B84DAAB5FDB16CF240EBB3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Disaggregation</header><text>The information determined under subparagraph (B) shall be disaggregated by race, gender, socioeconomic status, Federal Pell Grant eligibility status, status as a first-generation college student, Veteran or active duty status, and disability status.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C4A8A2FC71647B0AF5A5D205D5EA6DA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Not later than 6 years after the first grant is awarded under this section, the Director, in consultation with the Secretary and using the information determined under paragraph (1), shall submit to the authorizing committees and make publicly available in an accessible format, the results of a multi-year, rigorous evaluation on the impact of remedial education programs funded under this section that shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDFF47D7B09E84936851AC81185A7109F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effectiveness of the remedial education programs in providing the skills necessary for students to advance through remedial education and complete courses at the postsecondary level;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC2BC1C6DDFAB43D3B85DF2525A164A98"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the quality of outcomes of the remedial education programs within and among models of remedial education described in subsection (c);</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4826A9D7FDDD44BBACDE3E5FA89A5B3E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the sustainability and replicability of the remedial education programs that demonstrate success, as determined by the number and percentage of students who graduate from an institution of higher education within 150 percent of the normal time for completion of, or graduation from, the program of study for which the students are enrolled; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H69014DC63F0746C7850152F6364BAD86"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of the authority under subsection (f) in assisting students who complete a remedial education program funded under this section in graduating from an institution of higher education within 150 percent of the normal time for completion of, or graduation from, the program of study for which the students are enrolled.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA6F30881C58148069FB2871B89A6DB96"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports and Dissemination</header> 
<subparagraph id="H96DD0E8801CE41CFBF6FFA1F8B52939E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the first grant is awarded under this section, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the authorizing committees, and make available to the public in an accessible format, a report on each remedial education program funded under this section.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8168B7D64F0545039CCE921334430E7B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subsequent report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the last grant is awarded under this section, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the authorizing committees, and make available to the public in an accessible format, a report that—</text> 
<clause id="HB1E5C5DB58B84436937530EB24EC19A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reviews the activities and program performance of each remedial education program funded under this section; and</text> </clause> <clause id="HBDEDA521BEAF4E239F8E15ECB1DB4014"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides guidance and recommendations on how successful remedial education programs (as determined by the number and percentage of students who graduate from an institution of higher education within 150 percent of the normal time for completion of, or graduation from, the program of study for which the students are enrolled) can be replicated.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF389FFCDC3054C77A8C19C8579491153"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Data privacy</header> 
<paragraph id="HCC1A9AE3E7A8427A9823FEF21CD56A75"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any person who obtains or has access to personally identifiable information in connection with this section to willfully disclose to any person (except as authorized in this Act or any Federal law) such personally identifiable information.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF970F63E390E4BBE8A6333502FA71F91"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who violates paragraph (1) shall be fined not more than $5,000, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both, together with the costs of prosecution.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H278A118CFD0940C3BA36713B0CA29395"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Employee or officer of the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a violation of paragraph (1) is committed by any officer or employee of the United States, the officer or employee shall be dismissed from office or discharged from employment upon conviction for the violation.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E683B24374B4FB2B775259AB209A0F6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sale of data prohibited</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data collected under this section shall not be sold to any third party by the Director, any postsecondary institution, or any other entity.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H349C45F3225D4A72B0C7810592017CD0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitation on use by other Federal agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall not allow any other Federal agency to use data collected under this section for any purpose except as explicitly authorized by this Act.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HB323BA84D4EE4B5CA972D6DD02D1B63E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Law enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Personally identifiable information collected under this section shall not be used for any law enforcement activity or any other activity that would result in adverse action against any student, including debt collection activity or enforcement of the immigration laws.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H26ACB74DC1CA477D8CDEE320F19BC4A1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $162,500,000 for fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HD8B2F259B53A44F68020CC0F31460C4A"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBFC8A8805EB04880802A7F179A3BE8B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H61B4115244234235AAD4998491D7FD2E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible Entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAA34665432494A56AFB96161B7E74409"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an institution of higher education; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7326C9D5521448B798A492BD6241793F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a partnership between an institution of higher education and at least one of the following:</text> 
<clause id="H8329B13048ED425FBD71ACF737DED0A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A local educational agency.</text> </clause> <clause id="H8A7CF96806F3463C83B846E56AC5A6F3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A State educational agency.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H49C065CE4D9A495D91153BBC31673C17"><enum>(3)</enum><header>First-generation college student</header><text>The term <quote>first-generation college student</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 402A(h).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H20CB530A48964F53BBFA2FF78A9504BB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6E64CF32F54A4FEB9D17A3B4F220D1D5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Remedial education</header><text>The term <quote>remedial education</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="HBFE8FB6661C5441786010238327E75A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means education (such as courses or training) offered at an institution of higher education that—</text> 
<clause id="H67390D4DD32B4E73877556CFB6F4E34D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is below the postsecondary level; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H2D545EECD337491AA55D7C0FB64C20D5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is determined by the institution to be necessary to help students be prepared for the pursuit of a first undergraduate baccalaureate degree or certificate or, in the case of courses in English language instruction, to be necessary to enable the student to utilize already existing knowledge, training, or skills; and</text> </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD00A41F80159474BAF29508349ECB6B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes developmental education that meets the requirements of subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F72555FBBCC47F28D90F2C44BD6A481"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Tribal College or University</header><text>The term <quote>Tribal College or University</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 316.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section>
<section id="HEBF01A7D9A794A5C8A1CA4D013EF1893"><enum>4.</enum><header>Exception to student unit record ban</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 134(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1015c">20 U.S.C. 1015c(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4AAF6EE716074182B640E63ED025D379"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0488936F0B4C4FD8A54890A21BACDDB6" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HFBDCCA1C7C434D9AB0F1B23B2201C5F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is necessary</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and inserting the following:</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C108FE06E6E47689CAAFAA2000D26D6" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H0995D8FB1DD640EE81B305F89A3493E7"><enum>(1)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCB8536ABAFA141A1A13E04D0804B3A93"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is necessary</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC85D1FB732FC47C3A5172FEB91314C08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E73CE896D7F447BBCA111BD0E31A0DB" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H39DF05362D27463E8738AEB5945AE241"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was in</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and inserting the following:</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD74BFA6D7C8411A8CCB384100A4C21C" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H89988DE3E4494300804F8F81602132B5" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was in</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H32346BB06CF942B6BE56CAA7F5B35000"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H59F08F951320459DAF05FD8F783220D8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F47829992A7495AB9AC68352D110C1E" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H3C759BDA6CC24F6E985FD7E0317501E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is necessary for the operation of section 486B.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


