<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFC58EF5D0B68477AB2C527AB40806767" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1260 IH: Generational Residences and Nurturing Dwellings Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1260</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170228">February 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to provide assistance to eligible nonprofit organizations to provide specialized housing and supportive services for elderly persons who are the primary caregivers of children that are related to such persons.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD224C8CD32B94CD4B2ABD47972111F03" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC5D7ED32D8544746BBDEB91B8215758D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Generational Residences and Nurturing Dwellings Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GRAND Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HADED974B04044D928DE7F433357ACBAD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Assistance for specialized housing for elderly caregivers</header> <subsection id="HA5E6A33DB2A342E699398BF2DE310333"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Department of Housing and Urban Development a program to provide assistance to eligible nonprofit organizations to expand the supply of specialized housing for qualified relatives raising a child.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB6E9EFB6FE6D40B098CEB3B075C5BF9B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall preclude a recipient of assistance under a program established under subsection (a) from applying for or receiving financial assistance under any other program established in the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2E934A5DE2ED45828646EECB6CA4E9C1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header> <paragraph id="HAF54C9A6D8064503980124B2A23D3528"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive assistance under the program established under subsection (a), an eligible nonprofit organization shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, which shall include a description of how the eligible nonprofit organization will serve the housing needs of low-income families in a particular geographic area.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H811DF23754614C94875BDE085CD50F65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tenant-based rental assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive assistance to provide tenant-based rental assistance as described in subsection (d)(2), an application submitted under paragraph (1) shall include assurances that the eligible nonprofit organization will coordinate with a public housing agency in administering any such assistance received under this Act, as required by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1A8CCB5DC667491288B804F4B2A4F264"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In providing assistance under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible nonprofit organizations that plan to use such assistance as described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (f).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H97FD3BBA11C44529AE9D4A75E381D251"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limit on organizations selected</header><text>For each fiscal year, the Secretary may select not more than 5 eligible nonprofit organizations to receive assistance under the program under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1B7DFA2920BE49D5A180DE380663A277"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recipient of assistance under this program shall use such assistance for the following purposes:</text> 
<paragraph id="HDA294FC31CE54D06994AFDD42CFEA4BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>New housing</header><text>To finance the construction, reconstruction, moderate or substantial rehabilitation, or acquisition of a structure or a portion of a structure to be used as specialized housing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3696732AD6394BC598A5D71AFA3F909A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Operational expenses and supportive services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To provide assistance for ongoing operational expenses of any specialized housing, including costs of supportive services required for such housing.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB82E406EB8044B8D9AF02F5BA0EA53FB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rental voucher assistance</header><text>To provide tenant-based rental assistance under section 8(o) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)</external-xref>) for entities that meet the requirements under such section for use only by qualified relatives who are raising a child and are eligible for such assistance for rental of a dwelling unit that qualifies as specialized housing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H079971FA9FBA4252AE6720D29DC28F00"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Elderly housing project rental assistance</header><text>To provide project rental assistance under section 202(c)(2) of the Housing Act of 1959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1701q">12 U.S.C. 1701q(b)(2)</external-xref>) for entities that meet the requirements under such section in connection with dwelling units that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H73E00E905D144F9289E1AEEEEA50E1E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>qualify as specialized housing; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H52FBE4F209C64F74883AEBFAC5996BC7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are made available for occupancy only by qualified relatives who are raising a child and are eligible for occupancy in such housing, except that notwithstanding section 202(k)(1) of the Housing Act of 1959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1701q">12 U.S.C. 1701q(k)(1)</external-xref>), such qualified relatives may include elderly persons (as such term is defined in section 3 of this Act).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD1756C5130854C80BD978B8FF372BD96" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H343E7E4B019344D2B7542AB7095D94DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Child</header><text>The term <term>child</term> means an individual who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD794E9EF3A2347F2B913A2484AA20852"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not attending school and is not more than 18 years of age; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H533D2ED4EBEA4951BE381EE45D413B8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is attending school and is not more than 19 years of age.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF75B03BFADF54A89879BF6983487739F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elderly person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>elderly person</term> means a person who is 60 years of age or more.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H23AEAA65300241818DCB06B6F19E1D77"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible nonprofit organization</header> <subparagraph id="HB1EED65FB48847E490C7DFFBCC8A7E68"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>eligible nonprofit organization</term> means an organization that—</text> 
<clause id="HAD50CC9BB26D42558BEDEEBD2642DEC9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides specialized housing and supportive services for qualified relatives who are raising a child; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC033B1001DBF45EB912D516EF52FB969"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and is exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3ECFEFFBF37848F6BB06346C0F52565E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Political divisions included</header><text>Such term includes organizations that provide such services in each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H80CFEFC6F40C4151AB090DBDC2EE9B34"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Low-income families</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>low-income families</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3(b) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6A4069BAEE44BE89660C834CE30F9EC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Qualified Relative</header> 
<subparagraph id="H39D8FCFCB22448E397E29726302CD6A9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified relative</term> means an individual who is an elderly person and, with respect to a child, who—</text> <clause id="HA1EEBAAF360E43A9985BA28EDFD43D9A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not a parent of the child by blood or marriage; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7656460A830E4E65B4AEC1E49AFE655B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is—</text> <subclause id="HB0B9C3C422CD4ADCACADB76CF96FD506"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a relative of the child by blood or marriage; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3EECE955A6594422B198576CFDE44AC2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a legal guardian of the child.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H53D572A475A142A9A8689DE2A1B6F243"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Adopted children</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a child who was adopted, the term includes an individual who, by blood or marriage, is a relative of the family who adopted the child.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB2E17574DD2D4C898D8ACA79BDC554AC"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Raising a child</header><text>The term <term>raising a child</term> means, with respect to an individual, that the individual—</text> <subparagraph id="HD5B5E1D779A44497B661D129D300BFF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>resides with the child; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H130E8C198DB549F8817D29EB71BE20DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is the primary caregiver (or is, together with a spouse or other household member, a primary caregiver) for the child—</text> <clause id="HC5427E01574D4EB0AF58CC7B3E48D265"><enum>(i)</enum><text>because the biological or adoptive parents of the child do not reside with the child or are unable or unwilling to serve as the primary caregiver for the child; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8DFBAF973FAF48CBB6EB75AF2A84F7E3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>regardless of whether the individual has a legal relationship to the child (such as guardianship or legal custody).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A0816FB5FDA4433A74607EC84C68F5B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5012537708C147C287C79C0B7B86A9FB"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Specialized housing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>specialized housing</term> means housing that—</text> <subparagraph id="HD187E6ADAFFE499BBF5FFF0881460240"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is affordable (as the Secretary shall define for purposes of this Act) for low-income families;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCAA439F02B3249D5AAECC5A6A4C92FB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is restricted to occupancy only by low-income families;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA15794753727417A9837F461CC0E874E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is designed to meet the special physical needs of elderly persons;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFE41F60FA4914FA69C4E99803F037EE7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>accommodates the provision of supportive services that are expected to be needed, either initially or over the useful life of the housing, by elderly persons and children that the housing is intended to serve; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEA6DDD1B624E406D943C07C636D468B4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provides a range of such services that are tailored to the needs of elderly persons and children occupying such housing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23FD4171EDA44956BEDA1D5926524FD3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

