<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0F123BBF4E5B4A1096BF87693DD5D4B1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 302 IH: Sports Medicine Licensure Clarity Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 302</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170105">January 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000374">Mr. Abraham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000533">Mr. Duncan of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000461">Mr. Flores</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001036">Mr. Hensarling</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Thomas J. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001092">Mr. Collins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000184">Mrs. Noem</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide protections for certain sports medicine professionals who provide certain medical
			 services in a secondary State.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4E119FA8B4D2407B91127D560FE603D2" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3D0D098D9DDB49E6B5E152121CF5254A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sports Medicine Licensure Clarity Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H17F52FC3A7784AE88971CB0C45D005B1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Protections for covered sports medicine professionals</header> <subsection id="H8E7F14C030E04639827EAE627DAF37CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a covered sports medicine professional who has in effect medical professional liability insurance coverage and provides in a secondary State covered medical services that are within the scope of practice of such professional in the primary State to an athlete or an athletic team (or a staff member of such an athlete or athletic team) pursuant to an agreement described in subsection (b)(4) with respect to such athlete or athletic team—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF07C23F744284B2DBC4E2B3BD7110DDA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such medical professional liability insurance coverage shall cover (subject to any related premium adjustments) such professional with respect to such covered medical services provided by the professional in the secondary State to such an individual or team as if such services were provided by such professional in the primary State to such an individual or team; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H376FD9E9620C4C39B79AC25439996A1E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the extent such professional is licensed under the requirements of the primary State to provide such services to such an individual or team, the professional shall be treated as satisfying any licensure requirements of the secondary State to provide such services to such an individual or team.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H99D46750A62F4B1695329243E07E7152"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="HAEA763E666314619A9C7DECD688D0E9E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Athlete</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>athlete</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1B94260E570C48B182E114267A9414D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual participating in a sporting event or activity for which the individual may be paid;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA03205A82D9943F98A0E1CA11D7BBCB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an individual participating in a sporting event or activity sponsored or sanctioned by a national governing body; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCBA3DA0856B4FA499B8430ED416D633"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an individual for whom a high school or institution of higher education provides a covered sports medicine professional.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H89E68D5CEF0F40A6BA454D8302163D7C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Athletic team</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>athletic team</quote> means a sports team—</text> <subparagraph id="H029F503A98C44B7681F8E9A0711246AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>composed of individuals who are paid to participate on the team;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3609CE631684469B8EDA10012A564A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>composed of individuals who are participating in a sporting event or activity sponsored or sanctioned by a national governing body; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF821EFC180104F368549FBBCA89EAF9D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for which a high school or an institution of higher education provides a covered sports medicine professional.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEAFC37FCF6B4B0A978F282BAC489851"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered medical services</header><text>The term <term>covered medical services</term> means general medical care, emergency medical care, athletic training, or physical therapy services. Such term does not include care provided by a covered sports medicine professional—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE88ED4F8D7A94D7D9140EAB53F29DB9A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at a health care facility; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDB525B75C0D4C26A382E603353FC47B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>while a health care provider licensed to practice in the secondary State is transporting the injured individual to a health care facility.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6C24BB3D3C24F4681255079CF0C6B31"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered sports medicine professional</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered sports medicine professional</term> means a physician, athletic trainer, or other health care professional who—</text> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H889E5B48596A4B29A7BD797DD9BF68A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is licensed to practice in the primary State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA6F74025077449FB128164FE632C47C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides covered medical services, pursuant to a written agreement with an athlete, an athletic team, a national governing body, a high school, or an institution of higher education; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC4FB8E778654D8BB0D772884E008479"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prior to providing the covered medical services described in subparagraph (B), has disclosed the nature and extent of such services to the entity that provides the professional with liability insurance in the primary State.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E36B68BC53B422EBD4F158F44C4B77E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Health care facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>health care facility</term> means a facility in which medical care, diagnosis, or treatment is provided on an inpatient or outpatient basis. Such term does not include facilities at an arena, stadium, or practice facility, or temporary facilities existing for events where athletes or athletic teams may compete.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD2C72272EB344371A55072868BAF3688"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A12F2135D59431892BF3D26BEE99262"><enum>(7)</enum><header>National governing body</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>national governing body</term> has the meaning given such term in section 220501 of title 36, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H14EDA4F846B04809A684FBBA0CC58904"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Primary State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>primary State</term> means, with respect to a covered sports medicine professional, the State in which—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC8E003A5B09D42F7A322FBEE4F192245"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the covered sports medicine professional is licensed to practice; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3685A79CC89F420C92ED0EA9059AA3D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the majority of the covered sports medicine professional’s practice is underwritten for medical professional liability insurance coverage.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B251885C06943629D428987F0C737D3"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secondary State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>secondary State</term> means, with respect to a covered sports medicine professional, any State that is not the primary State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C240E9C7C034E35982C0B9D2F9D5119"><enum>(10)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


