<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2C205614C8B548AFA38E0D83C445041B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3149 IH: Renewable Chemicals Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3149</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170629">June 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide credits for the production of renewable
			 chemicals and investments in renewable chemical production facilities, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8355ECB720DA445BB171752B221DF5D8" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7CA8303838EB4416B336FC559BF7652E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Renewable Chemicals Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4508722D3C3243D0A4EEB1F6AEC2068B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Credits for production of renewable chemicals and investments in renewable chemical production facilities</header> <subsection id="HE1EB0B59D78148A282775C06BAF221AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Production of renewable chemicals</header> <paragraph id="H30A0E91B79344E94A15C7C80DBFBB0A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H36CEC405BAAA46D9AE89BA239A4C44D4" style="OLC">
						<section id="H4C5BFAD1322D4880902697A50E104364"><enum>45S.</enum><header>Credit for production of renewable chemicals</header>
 <subsection id="HE5497A6E500046728AD0AB9C2AAD590A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of section 38, the production credit for renewable chemicals for any taxable year is an amount (determined separately for each renewable chemical) equal to $0.15 per pound of biobased content of each renewable chemical produced during the taxable year—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBE31D2E22C6D4B9A8C4DD7B08643430F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by the taxpayer, or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H49DB0C6F6F59448AA32BF886BFAC37AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for the taxpayer by a contract manufacturer under a binding written agreement.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H303C39C3185F4A6FAAD5704BD81129C9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The amount of the credit determined under subsection (a) with respect to a renewable chemical produced during any taxable year shall not exceed the credit amount allocated for purposes of this section by the Secretary to the taxpayer with respect to such chemical for such taxable year under section 48E(e).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H31C6A9AD7CC240A2B14E1D85D2DF08BD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H46AF47D90E0342578FF1C73857AE053F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Renewable chemical</header> <subparagraph id="HC19CC9076F4E4C6D9547BD47002F14AF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>renewable chemical</term> means any chemical which—</text>
 <clause id="H0C95D726F5AB4CD7AB5E6EC04FD7AD91"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is produced in the United States (or in a territory or possession of the United States) from renewable biomass,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1B151EC479274BA5BA3F909CD1A43319"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is sold or used by the taxpayer—</text> <subclause id="HC1F1BA56712F470B913B98F608F1A809"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for the production of chemical products, polymers, plastics, or formulated products, or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H488B1D2F5212480D8C3141701D2E39BB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>as chemicals, polymers, plastics, or formulated products,</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HB5EAB2E3D75C4C329962CB5799EB569C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is not less than 95 percent biobased content,</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF94973B2DE0A4B7CA25AC1C185970811"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is the product of, or is reliant upon, biological conversion, thermal conversion, or a combination of biological and thermal conversion of renewable biomass,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3B9199EEEA0A4D8C95FE9C63F135BBCD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>is not sold or used for the production of any food, feed, or fuel,</text> </clause><clause id="H2C9A02F26FF74877B4331EF6A7C721F1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not a combination of renewable chemicals on the list under clause (vii) (or added to such list under subparagraph (B)) for which a credit has been claimed by the taxpayer in any taxable year under this section or section 48E, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE8951FC1879E427E9380A9D84F7EE2FC"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>is acetic acid, acrylic acid, acyl glutamate, adipic acid, algae oils, algae sugars, 1,4-butanediol (BDO), iso-butanol, n-butanol, C10 and higher hydrocarbons produced from olefin metathesis, carboxylic acids produced from olefin metathesis, cellulosic sugar, diethyl methylene malonate, dodecanedioic acid (DDDA), esters produced from olefin metathesis, ethyl acetate, ethylene glycol, farnesene, 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid, gamma-butyrolactone, glucaric acid, hexamethylenediamine (HMD), 3-hydroxy propionic acid, iso-butene, isoprene, itaconic acid, lactide, levulinic acid, polyhydroxyalkonate (PHA), polylactic acid (PLA), polyethylene furanoate (PEF), polyethylene terephthalate (PET), polyitaconic acid, polyols from vegetable oils, poly(xylitan levulinate ketal), 1,3-propanediol, 1,2-propanediol, rhamnolipids, short and medium chain carboxylic acids produced from anaerobic digestion, succinic acid, terephthalic acid, vegetable fatty acid-derived ethyl esters containing vegetable oil, or p-xylene.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AACA325270E49AEAFC4D2621C28C81E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional renewable chemicals</header><text>The Secretary may add chemicals to the list of renewable chemicals in subparagraph (A)(vii). Not later than 180 days after the enactment of this section, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall establish a program to consider applications from taxpayers to add renewable chemicals to such list. Any chemical added to such list must meet the requirements set forth in clauses (i) through (v) of subparagraph (A) (without regard to the phrase <quote>by the taxpayer</quote> in clause (ii) thereof).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H43D74F22DCE142688F81318F38BAB1C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Biobased content</header><text>The term <term>biobased content</term> means, with respect to any renewable chemical, the biobased content of the total mass of organic carbon in such chemical (expressed as a percentage), determined by testing representative samples using the American Society for Testing and Materials (ASTM) D6866.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA056EBE3BABA46C28EEAD72E26A264D3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Renewable biomass</header><text>The term <term>renewable biomass</term> has the meaning given such term in section 9001(13) of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/8101">7 U.S.C. 8101(13)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCEF4057A50864E82B38449B96B159CE3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National limitation on credits for renewable chemicals</header><text>See section 48E(e) for rules relating to national limitation on credits under this section.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H73B21EF07FE34D359C6EDA89FE552328"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination with investment credit for renewable chemical production facilities</header><text>See section 48E(f) for rules coordinating section 48E with this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDA9E7DD402E04F44A7F8305F59CA9DBF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section or section 48E, the Secretary may not allocate any credit amount under this section to any taxable year which begins more than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0746DAFC4DBE472E850B5BCFB357F4B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Credit to be part of general business credit</header><text>Subsection (b) of section 38 of such Code is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (35), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (36) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="HDB193019497447EE8CD53E1D3AF27486" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H4F4D28D5CEAE492E88E7098147553414"><enum>(37)</enum><text>the renewable chemicals production credit determined under section 45S(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31D33C7A47844EFC8D88686B0BE8CA8A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Investment credit in lieu of production credit</header>
 <paragraph id="HC23022F8FCD445E79E3C43594E27E782"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/46">Section 46</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (5), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (6) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98E260A7FA7D4B1CA2DCC577A0D367DF" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H55C67A273C22409B8972C55BE7E71AAC"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the renewable chemical production facilities credit.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC863A7749226472CA0CDE0DBEA592EBE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Renewable chemical production facilities credit</header><text>Subpart E of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after section 48D the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA038BAB37E644969A11E02A4619D9B03" style="OLC">
						<section id="HB3559FD5CC374B9CA3D05962957B957C"><enum>48E.</enum><header>Investment credit for renewable chemical production facilities</header>
 <subsection id="HD815F37F7AEE4612BCCCCC2CD657DCAC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 46, the renewable chemical production facilities credit for any taxable year is an amount equal to 30 percent of the basis of any eligible property which is a part of a renewable chemical production facility placed in service by the taxpayer during such taxable year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD502618B50F4D8D864FB8919387171F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of the credit determined under subsection (a) with respect to a renewable chemical production facility of the taxpayer during any taxable year shall not exceed the credit amount allocated for purposes of this section by the Secretary to the taxpayer for such taxable year under subsection (e).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7E8BC29FEF504B9782B38073FC50176E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Renewable Chemical Production Facility</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="HABFCA7D4E44D44CE913A131B027B6EBD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>renewable chemical production facility</term> means a facility—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H70992AEFA3E042DFBF61CA78F9CD2581"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which is owned by the taxpayer,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6FA262513A842B0B34D7EBF9114AAD2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which is originally placed in service after the date of the enactment of this section and before the first day of the taxable year which begins 6 years after the date of the enactment of this section,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA5FC6C888E446B5924D39E18BED06F4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to which—</text> <clause id="HE0544C1E7E6B4F58A468A9835ADB5F58"><enum>(i)</enum><text>no credit has been allowed under section 45S for chemicals produced at such facility in any previous taxable year, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF9ADC931EC794384BE52D31FC503005F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the taxpayer makes an irrevocable election to have this section apply, and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A3A5FAB2FD64A2EB1BD145477192FAE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>which is used to produce renewable chemicals.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H036321EE2C414800A15966501FC43E32"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible property</header><text>The term <term>eligible property</term> means any property—</text> <subparagraph id="H507831A1B75C470C8A3DBB289666D8A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which is—</text>
 <clause id="H22DB50319E6040939CC66A8A9243AD52"><enum>(i)</enum><text>tangible personal property, or</text> </clause><clause id="H709ED2FFCBB041CCB7AF4B9E30CE2639"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other tangible property (not including a building or its structural components),</text>
										</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">but only if such property is used as an integral part of the renewable chemical production
 facility, and</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB33A4A05556048F99FFEA3CEC41D875B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to which depreciation (or amortization in lieu of depreciation) is allowable.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5A92DFDAF7440408C53B06431D6F168"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Renewable chemical</header><text>The term <term>renewable chemical</term> has the meaning given such term by section 45S(c)(1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H497F60EE007F45A9B434F12919412A0F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Certain qualified progress expenditures rules made applicable</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rules similar to the rules of subsections (c)(4) and (d) of section 46 (as in effect on the day before the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990) shall apply for purposes of this section.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H658135EC285647E3AAE49E66EA0E7057"><enum>(e)</enum><header>National limitation on credits for renewable chemicals</header>
 <paragraph id="HB15CE7B0F5EC40359C61470034A30647"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall establish a program to allocate credit amounts under this section and section 45S to taxpayers who produce renewable chemicals for taxable years ending after the date of the enactment of this section.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H83D8E46A9BB54101A9C2967B65671F53"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD7CDE43447D34AF2B5C2C1B50068E307"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Aggregate limitation</header><text>The total amount of credits that may be allocated under such program shall not exceed $500,000,000.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H534FAA75D663407FB5E1BDA0C4D2044F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Taxpayer limitation</header><text>The amount of credits that may be allocated to any taxpayer for any taxable year under such program shall not exceed $25,000,000. For purposes of the preceding sentence, all persons treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of section 52, or subsection (m) or (o) of section 414, shall be treated as one taxpayer.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A24FC7CDE7746189BE3C4694861E1C6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>In determining to which taxpayers to make allocations of the credit amount under such program, the Secretary shall take into consideration—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H60F2E29B585949C19E8CF9FA9FE2B370"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of jobs created and maintained (directly and indirectly) in the United States (including territories and possessions of the United States) as a result of such allocation during the credit period and thereafter,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F2F8D303BAA45CB8BF91DCE6F12F240"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the degree to which the production of the renewable chemical demonstrates reduced dependence on imported feedstocks, petroleum, non-renewable resources, or other fossil fuels,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BFFCD6902E848E995BD4A2BC0E3160E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the technological innovation involved in the production method of the renewable chemical,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E23699B208E4593ABD32D884BCC02DA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the energy efficiency and reduction in lifecycle greenhouse gases of the renewable chemical or of the production method of the renewable chemical, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EE17338BA3E4178B69173A4E3CF9CA4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>whether there is a reasonable expectation of commercial viability.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEBDEA10E39F4500AAA864AB84C7FD9B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Redistribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a credit amount allocated to a taxpayer for a taxable year with respect to any renewable chemical or renewable chemical production facility (determined without regard to this paragraph) exceeds the amount of the credit with respect to such chemical determined under this section on the taxpayer’s return for such taxable year—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8DA900758C384CB0B87AC55AB964DF4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the credit amount allocated to such taxpayer for such taxable year with respect to such renewable chemical shall be treated as being the amount so determined on the taxpayer’s return, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H740B684D8A164478B9CF41A034373233"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such excess may be reallocated by the Secretary consistent with the requirements of this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A7E7AEC5A26402EADFF2FCD81DF776E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Disclosure of allocations</header><text>The Secretary shall, upon making an allocation of credit amount under this section, publicly disclose the identity of the taxpayer and the amount of the credit with respect to such taxpayer.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B89B9277D814A909F7A41F80A4E6EA2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Coordination with production credit for renewable chemicals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a taxpayer makes an election under subsection (c)(1)(C)(ii) with respect to a renewable chemical production facility, a credit shall not be allowed under section 45S for any renewable chemical produced by such facility.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF8508C2114024B1AAD0103208714C386"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary to carry out this section and section 45S.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2C93D51EA273454FB45C8725B911CA8F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Secretary may not allocate any credit amount under this section to any taxable year which begins more than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C664500C7014A209E599FBFCED4982D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Credits allowable against alternative minimum tax</header><text>Subparagraph (B) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/38">section 38(c)(4)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating clauses (vii) through (ix) as clauses (ix) through (xi), respectively, and by inserting after clause (vi) the following new clauses:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H1662E674CC564A4A83699B67F73DC500" style="OLC">
 <clause id="HC28BCF97490145BDAC7AF8852589B33A"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the credit determined under section 45S,</text> </clause><clause id="H8601113D218A4FAB849F900E580FE8C3"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the credit determined under section 46 to the extent that such credit is attributable to the renewable chemical production facilities credit under section 48E,</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HE9DBE3B18E504405A10DC6AB3F9D63A7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H011ABA2D59BD486D81863565F0ECCDA4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3823BC2301B14710BAA5E376E502BD22" style="OLC">
						<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H36CEC405BAAA46D9AE89BA239A4C44D4" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="H4C5BFAD1322D4880902697A50E104364" level="section">Sec. 45S. Credit for production of renewable chemicals.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D8FCECC086F4EBC866DD6E79DD8F9F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The table of sections for subpart E of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA03644D6E56B405787A45410BBA6EC3C" style="OLC">
						<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="HA038BAB37E644969A11E02A4619D9B03" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="HB3559FD5CC374B9CA3D05962957B957C" level="section">Sec. 48E. Investment credit for renewable chemical production facilities.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H877ECC504A244037A2F0327298FD5E4A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective dates</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to renewable chemicals produced and renewable chemical production facilities placed in service after the date of the enactment of this Act, in taxable years ending after such date.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


