<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC85B715254FB41EFA084FE16820B5EA3" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 211 IH: Chugach Region Lands Study Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 211</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170103">January 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to complete a land exchange with the Chugach Regional
			 Alaska Native Corporation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8DFABC9073464EF7A0B9BF77AE45F237" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD3C3F3F6BB1248FB88284333750454D4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Chugach Region Lands Study Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H18F1F108B3EC48A1A3FDD40538AC6499" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Chugach Alaska Corporation Land Exchange Pool Act</header> <subsection id="HB599CCCD2D7F416DBE674B5FBAF8108E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1B4064B81F374500A7961547C1BDC50C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>CAC</header><text>The term <term>CAC</term> means Chugach Alaska Corporation.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H89495BBB0BE0457CACC7C0384AA39D2A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Alaska.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9869B7A5FC3D4763B2A743F9DCF41854"><enum>(3)</enum><header>CAC lands</header><text>The term <term>CAC Lands</term> means lands conveyed to CAC pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>) in which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB7003E9F21964DD0B2F0E5ED009E7A12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>both the surface estate and the subsurface estate were conveyed to CAC; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF9B0D1ED73C473FB4F1448C6E4958E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the subsurface estate was conveyed to CAC and the surface estate or a conservation easement in the surface estate was acquired by the State or by the United States as part of the Exxon Valdez Oil Spill Trustee Council Habitat Protection and Acquisition Program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA43FFFBB09749DDABC028EE7B6CF2F1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification of Federal lands</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior, in coordination with the Secretary of Agriculture and in consultation with Chugach Alaska Corporation (CAC), shall identify not less than 500,000 acres of economically viable Federal land in or outside the State of Alaska that can be made available to CAC in exchange for any CAC Lands identified by CAC as available to the United States for exchange. Any such exchange shall be pursuant to mutual agreement of CAC and the United States and consummated in accordance with all applicable legal authorizations, except that any acre-for-acre exchange of such Federal lands for such CAC Lands shall be conclusively deemed to be in the public interest.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


