<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H37C807BDE381411DA3486A246340B60E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1745 IH: Relief From Sequestration Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1745</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170327">March 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">Committee on the Budget</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 to eliminate the section
			 251A sequestrations.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HADCF36A2AF8140F789D4DD012FE6E3A9" style="OLC">
 <section id="H369774F9FD13406FA7508A490166ABE5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Relief From Sequestration Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section commented="no" id="HA4F651205280468790AB62E499342853"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purposes</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H51B502C63370488386F318D560FE0D19"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H275B953D07F44AE09CBBE33CE757073C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Sequestration was designed as a forcing mechanism for an agreement on a comprehensive, deficit reduction plan. It has failed to produce the intended results.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE70557A295984BFA8DBA009D0483A3D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Budget Control Act of 2011 was enacted to avert a default on Federal debt obligations.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE95DD71CEC2F49A2BBD9C925E3D87471"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Because the Joint Select Committee on Deficit Reduction failed to recommend legislation providing an additional $1.2 trillion in deficit reduction, Federal law mandates that the additional savings be sequestered.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF6594055483B4CEE9F717DCB6F40C5A5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Congress must enact a comprehensive, deficit reduction plan to solve the country’s fiscal challenges and to promote national security, economic stability, and the continued growth and prosperity of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B6398144DC447789FCB000AA06592F3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>It no longer makes sense to rely on sequestration as a forcing mechanism for a balanced solution. The costs to our Government and to the economy are too great.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF9CA572CFEBC4B6A959CAC2DC1CC135B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Under sequestration, damaging cuts would be applied, through fiscal year 2021, to a wide variety of discretionary spending programs to achieve $1.2 trillion in savings, forestalling the sound planning needed for prudent and meaningful investments in national security, the workforce, transportation infrastructure, education, health care, public safety, housing, innovation, small business development, and many other facets of enduring national strength.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H740D6706659F4DEEB1A7CA27EDC5D3E4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Even the prospect of sequestration is disruptive to regular order and to the congressional appropriations process, and it fosters damaging economic uncertainty, while short-term solutions only suspend the prospect and continue to undermine the certainty needed for economic recovery.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4C2EAFDC9FDC4BBABB9149368E439A16"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are to—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H6AE1266EF01B4D3AB085749B0E49D0F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>eliminate sequestration resulting from the failure of the Joint Select Committee on Deficit Reduction; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDE99C7074BEE459696F1637D1287CD6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>offer the Federal Government, industry, and the American people the predictability that economic recovery demands.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H58713A83257A4542A006664F32A93A1B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Repeal of section 251A sequestrations</header>
 <subsection id="HE74C220BA99C4DF4932FC1238EA90B16"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repealer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 251A of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 is repealed.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H426A7C3726B24806935A2EA8818E7137"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The item relating to section 251A in the table of contents set forth in section 250(a) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 is repealed.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


