<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6755F1E5207F43AC9F537987CC5B2DAA" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 770 IH: American Innovation $1 Coin Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 770</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170131">January 31, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint coins in recognition of American innovation and
			 significant innovation and pioneering efforts of individuals or groups
			 from each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, and the United
			 States territories, to promote the importance of innovation in the United
			 States, the District of Columbia, and the United States territories, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB263064F97AF49AF8738536EE1E095C5" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE7AFA84BF3334A1FACDC041F7A477B93" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Innovation $1 Coin Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7F1A60F214004CCCA8F49AD754F23468"><enum>2.</enum><header>American innovation $1 coin program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5112 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting after subsection (v) the following new subsection:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HAD051B3365B94AAFB796CD9573C5D3F5" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H78CA826DEFD042F884BB0213790E335C"><enum>(w)</enum><header>Redesign and issuance of $1 coins honoring innovation, innovators, and pioneers from each State,
			 the District of Columbia, and each territory</header>
					<paragraph id="HCBEF7AD056AB46A897498681EB21A3D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Redesign beginning in 2018</header>
 <subparagraph id="H28DFE11E64334FB8B6B82E3B5CBB6D14"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (d)(1) and subsection (d)(2) and in accordance with the provisions of this subsection, during the 14-year period beginning on January 1, 2018 (or such later date as provided under subparagraph (B)(ii)), the Secretary of the Treasury shall mint and issue $1 coins to be known as <quote>American Innovation $1 coins</quote>, that—</text>
 <clause id="H2E3C7F28AED4403F831808F23ACA5DD2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have designs on the obverse selected in accordance with paragraph (2)(A); and</text> </clause><clause id="HE5CB79C809D144DD9A3528CC5CC5FC21"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have a design on the reverse selected in accordance with paragraph (2)(B).</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBF016C910E14A939B21CD710BFD7137"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Continuity provisions</header>
 <clause id="H525C4ED1C2D24C83AA7DB80E4E19CDB7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall continue to mint and issue $1 coins honoring Native Americans and their contributions in accordance with subsection (r).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD7844F5536B340C698A5F90F80287944"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>First year</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), if the Secretary finds that it is not feasible and cost-effective to mint and issue American Innovation $1 coins beginning in 2018, the Secretary may mint and issue $1 coins bearing the designs of such Presidential $1 coins issued pursuant to subsection (n) that the Secretary determines to be appropriate. If any such Presidential $1 coin design bore the inscription <quote>In God We Trust</quote> incused on the edge, the Secretary shall modify the design to place that inscription on the coin’s obverse only, and such modification may be done without review by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee nor consultation with the Commission of Fine Arts.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B99D257D9D743EB8E23A38EE0E092C8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Definition of territory</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>territory</quote> means the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC72789CC67C6482DA85E09CA53865361"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Design requirements</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (d)(1) and subsection (d)(2), the $1 coins issued in accordance with paragraph (1)(A) shall meet the following design requirements:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDBDFDCFA89C6441AAFE1400C8EEEB927"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Coin obverse</header><text>The design on the obverse of each coin issued under this subsection shall contain—</text> <clause id="H46CA1C56B9C140CF9C26963DCA314977"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a design symbolic of Liberty; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H71691349B013404BAEB2740DF6681ED6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the inscription <quote>In God We Trust</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05C33919EE5A4F9A82D63D4211A58AEB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Coin reverse</header><text>The design on the reverse of each coin issued under this subsection shall bear the following:</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H38C1D4CACC8843E883D0142E396EC702"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An image or images emblematic of one of the following from one of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, or the territories of the United States:</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="HA9CDCECA5FE5449A8882C33B2D7E1BD1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A significant innovation.</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HA0360DCAAB244869A43DB34028F64CEF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>An innovator or pioneer.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H2121227EC4344652AF63D2803DD89226"><enum>(III)</enum><text>A group of innovators or pioneers.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H58ED51C01D344B7AAD3C89E7FAB79443"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The name of the State, the District of Columbia, or territory, as applicable.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAAA99FE151C24114AC4C51E22EBEFFEB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The inscriptions <quote>$1</quote> and <quote>United States of America</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88A700A57F1F407C98257699FCA02335"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Edge-incused inscriptions</header> <clause id="HB9F43742D3494F2D8E2220B354903C38"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The inscription of the year of minting or issuance of the coin and the inscription <quote>E Pluribus Unum</quote> shall be edge-incused into the coin.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9BCD54FD6E8F4F249F4D58DAD3F9F398"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Preservation of distinctive edge</header><text>The edge-incusing of the inscriptions under clause (i) on coins issued under this subsection shall be done in a manner that preserves the distinctive edge of the coin so that the denomination of the coin is readily discernible, including by individuals who are blind or visually impaired.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C1AF941E14041D89F7401B08C220D96"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Issuance of coins commemorating innovation, innovators, and pioneers</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9C421690AD994A2A9B8F25A911DD68D1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Order of issuance</header><text>The coins issued under this subsection commemorating either an innovation, an individual innovator or pioneer, or a group of innovators or pioneers, from each State, the District of Columbia, or a territory shall be issued in alphabetic order of the State, the District, or territory represented, starting with Alabama.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F9EADC80428478889FF278986C88C88"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Issuance of coins commemorating four innovations, innovators, and pioneers during each of 14 years</header>
 <clause id="H9B4FB5CC741E466AA11693D1D0136581"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Four $1 coin designs as described in this subsection shall be issued during each year of the period referred to in paragraph (1) until one coin featuring one innovation, an individual innovator or pioneer, or a group of innovators or pioneers, from each of the States, the District of Columbia, and territories has been issued.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2B49D3DD2AC9416D9F2E78F51CBF6330"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Number of coin designs in each year</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe, on the basis of such factors as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, the number of $1 coins that shall be issued with each of the designs selected for each year of the period referred to in paragraph (1).</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H08D3B98D5069447F98E7F23DCCEFB126"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Application in event of the admission of additional States</header><text>Notwithstanding clause (i), if any additional State or territory is admitted into the Union before the end of the 14-year period referred to in paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Treasury may issue $1 coins, in accordance with this subsection during any one year of such 14-year period, in addition to the four $1 coins issued during such year in accordance with clause (i).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1C431CD43C6D44D0AA099D67DD57E184"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Application in the event of independence</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (3)(B)(i), if any State or territory becomes independent or otherwise ceases to be a State or territory of the United States before $1 coins are minted pursuant to this subsection, the subsection shall cease to apply with respect to such State or territory.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0D86B98F81142ABB98BF51B38E56AD5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Selection of concept and design</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD561ED2AE26D4EED9A2A56FA013034DF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Concept</header><text>With respect to each State, the District of Columbia, and each territory to be honored with a coin under this subsection, the selection of the significant innovation, innovator or pioneer, or group of innovators or pioneers to be borne on the reverse of such coin shall be made by the Secretary of the Treasury, after consultation with the Governor or other chief executive of the State, the District of Columbia, or territory with respect to which a coin is to be issued under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9B62CC335D854005AFF630931A9FDC40"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Design</header><text>Each of the designs required under this subsection shall be selected by the Secretary after—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HBEB92A5A17724D4C9E60C552E7DBAAF6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consultation with—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H7E8BF2ED66354B3DA1D99A7D7C7BD6CB"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Governor or other chief executive of the State, the District of Columbia, or territory with respect to which a coin is to be issued under this subsection; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HBC92E74F61FB4C468EADD0AE06147FC7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Commission of Fine Arts; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HEE38452BD0F5408CA90A5E7BB1943391"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>review by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H330B567C25FE4A02BC0C4CE87022C525"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Selection and approval process</header><text>Designs for $1 coins under this subsection may be submitted in accordance with the design selection and approval process developed by the Secretary in the sole discretion of the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1C564B41FDD346BAA6CE6284323EC235"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Standards</header><text>Because it is important that the Nation’s coinage and currency bear dignified designs of which the citizens of the United States can be proud, the Secretary shall not select any frivolous or inappropriate design for any $1 coin minted under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H318235B0E20448A1B57F7ED584CF8124"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Prohibition on certain representations</header><text>No head and shoulders portrait or bust of any person, living or dead, and no portrait of a living person may be included in the design of any coin issued under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A60550D477740B388F05D9BC853EBFF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Treatment as numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136, all $1 coins minted under this subsection shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFBEFD85348EB4625A25BC37E83C707D1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Issuance of numismatic coins</header><text>The Secretary may mint and issue such number of $1 coins of each design selected under this subsection in uncirculated and proof qualities as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H073DE7332C3A470096613AC6A72B8A30"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Termination of program</header><text>The issuance of coins under this subsection shall terminate when one innovation, an individual innovator or pioneer, or a group of innovators or pioneers, from each State, the District of Columbia, and each territory has been honored and may not be resumed except by an Act of Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


