<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB8A8AE0F4B3B4F51B605B08B64EDE960" key="H" public-private="public">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3606 IH: Overdraft Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3606</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Truth in Lending Act to establish fair and transparent practices related to the marketing and provision of overdraft coverage programs at depository institutions, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form> 
<legis-body id="H681CF78338904053AB441091B30410E8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFB6CA59FD6694C26B07CAF214CBE4915" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Overdraft Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HBD3437F1480E48C49A633B1D2A81953F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header> <subsection id="H100DEE87EA69457994CC897D008BA8E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>The Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA186428C107D4F1697F609928FED1F3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Overdraft coverage is a form of short-term credit that depository institutions provide for consumer transaction accounts. Historically, depository institutions covered overdrafts for a fee on an ad hoc basis.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4D321AE45024E76B3C6716C70D7E7AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With the growth in specially designed software programs and in consumer use of debit cards, overdraft coverage for a fee has become more prevalent.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8251E3656A2A4FD38922493D5C06B15C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Many depository institutions offer a range of overdraft options but aggressively encourage consumers to consent to the most expensive option, where a high flat fee is collected for every individual overdraft transaction.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF257CAD813EE4311A31A7C5E838F9971"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Most depository institutions collect a high flat fee, including for small dollar transactions, each time the institution covers an overdraft, in some cases impose multiple overdraft coverage fees within a single day, and many charge additional fees for each day during which the account remains overdrawn.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB534E796C7174DB2A524F20E3BCD4058"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Such abusive practices in connection with overdraft coverage fees have deprived consumers of meaningful choices about their accounts and placed significant financial burdens on low- and moderate-income consumers.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5A0C08CFD2A445BBB778DE2C131CDB12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>It is the purpose of this Act to protect consumers by limiting abusive overdraft coverage fees and practices, and by providing meaningful disclosures and consumer choice in connection with overdraft coverage fees.</text> </subsection></section>
<section id="H117C059873AE4C7BAA2403C2F2C4B801"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header> 
<subsection id="HAFCF7BE9D38E4195A943486108EA7403"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Additional definitions</header><text>Section 140B of the Truth in Lending Act, as added by section 4, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F396477D1A04CA6B38E7DB454EC401D" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HD7C426B378AB4BFDA230EC49000CCABC"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Definitions relating to overdraft coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE4D17B2568DD4A66A624A5D9C77909C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Check</header><text>The term <term>check</term> has the same meaning as in section 3(6) of the Check Clearing for the 21st Century Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5001">12 U.S.C. 5001</external-xref> et seq.), other than a travelers check.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3101BC2034634AEAA2EA777F8AFAE048"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Depository institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>depository institution</term> has the same meaning as in clauses (i) through (vi) of section 19(b)(1)(A) of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/461">12 U.S.C. 461(b)(1)(A)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7C63469EEAFD4E4E889521E5D1945177"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nonsufficient fund fee</header><text>The term <term>nonsufficient fund fee</term> means a fee or charge assessed in connection with an overdraft for which a depository institution declines payment.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H3CA6471E7C734B1E9287FB178DE28EC8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Overdraft</header><text>The term <term>overdraft</term> means, in a withdrawal by check or other debit from a consumer transaction account in which there are insufficient or unavailable funds in the account to cover such check or debit, the amount of such withdrawal that exceeds the available funds in the account.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8C5242532DCF4080BC428CB029A5CA31"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Overdraft coverage</header><text>The term <term>overdraft coverage</term> means the payment of a check presented or other debit posted against a consumer transaction account by the depository institution in which such account is held, even though there are insufficient or unavailable funds in the account to cover such checks or other debits.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB11C78A998745A7A8B538636B91B7C1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Overdraft coverage fee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>overdraft coverage fee</term> means any fee or charge assessed in connection with overdraft coverage, or in connection with any negative account balance that results from overdraft coverage, unless such fee or charge is imposed in connection with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H42D946F9AB534676A604813C61E496AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an extension of credit through an overdraft line of credit program where such fee or charge was considered a finance charge under this title as in effect immediately prior to the enactment of the Overdraft Protection Act of 2017; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF18866B5F91B435F9594591C2B2EEB1F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any transfer from an account linked to another transaction account.</text> </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Such fee shall be considered a <term>finance charge</term> for purposes of section 106(a), but shall not be included in the calculation of the rate of interest for purposes of section 107(5)(A)(vi) of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1757">12 U.S.C. 1757(5)(A)(vi)</external-xref>).</continuation-text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HC8A02CDC038042A8977EE3D36010BC5A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Overdraft coverage program</header><text>The term <term>overdraft coverage program</term> means a service under which a depository institution assesses an overdraft coverage fee for overdraft coverage.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H1EB48C7038CB44A991950C72993142C1"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Transaction account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>transaction account</term> has the same meaning as in section 19(b)(1)(C) of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/461">12 U.S.C. 461(b)(1)(C)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection>
<subsection id="HDF9D8860BB3C476CB9FF44F7C0451A7F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 107(5)(A)(vi) of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1757">12 U.S.C. 1757(5)(A)(vi)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, other than an overdraft coverage fee, as defined in section 140B(o) of the Truth in Lending Act</quote> after <quote>inclusive of all finance charges</quote>.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H8F288D3D496942A9A69653BFC0C9D5E6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Fair marketing and provision of overdraft coverage programs</header> <subsection id="H1F87F671E57849A9A9D961CDA0EE2EDA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 2 of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1631">15 U.S.C. 1631</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBF6FCDC72F5C443C9DFFE46CFF2ED869" style="USC"> 
<section id="HD3EBC7D5730F47658EE3BECA8FC252A3"><enum>140B.</enum><header>Overdraft coverage program disclosures and consumer protection</header> 
<subsection id="H76A5F6A741EB419C8045333B92FC5328"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><text>No depository institution may engage in acts or practices in connection with the marketing of or the provision of overdraft coverage that are unfair, deceptive, or designed to evade the provisions of this section.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HB0FCEE2D9BB24DD8A0978C9EB8387FF2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Marketing disclosures</header><text>Each depository institution that provides or offers to provide overdraft coverage with respect to transaction accounts held at that depository institution shall clearly and conspicuously disclose in all marketing materials for such overdraft coverage—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCAE6299C3A4148AA881B8C8EB098A95F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any overdraft coverage fees with respect to such overdraft coverage; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F0A54DB75B5437A9DF6E00D7F2F34C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that by not opting in to such overdraft coverage—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAD8B07035E8D47B6B19363BDEF0B2A67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a consumer’s transaction may be declined if there are insufficient funds in the related transaction account; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5EC610D52D444B0491484CF5C7D73B7D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the consumer will not be charged a fee if such transaction is declined.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H5357DE48206444C888EB9B631150145F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consumer consent opt-In</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A depository institution may charge overdraft coverage fees with respect to the use of an automatic teller machine or point of sale transaction only if the consumer has consented in writing, in electronic form, or in such other form as is permitted under regulations of the Bureau.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HD39B8501C60F4ACDB8E7667CB1E8FF69"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consumer disclosures</header><text>Each depository institution shall clearly disclose to each consumer covered by an overdraft protection program of that depository institution—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDFBC1D8508224CFDA6BA103D776E472D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that—</text> <subparagraph id="H38266DCE634E4CE1BEF7F0BD4C230057"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the consumer may be charged for not more than one overdraft coverage fee in any single calendar month and not more than 6 overdraft coverage fees in any single calendar year, per transaction account; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H500666FD2DAC4D42A37C0D5209852288"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the depository institution retains the discretion to pay (without assessing an overdraft coverage fee) or reject overdrafts incurred by the consumer beyond the numbers described in subparagraph (A);</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FE5BF7B33E64C27AD1231086FF23AB2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the overdraft coverage fee as an annual percentage rate, so as to permit consumers to meaningfully compare the overdraft coverage to alternative forms of overdraft options and other sources of credit;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD818B430AFCC4CB7AFA938D6CC6B5202"><enum>(3)</enum><text>information about any alternative overdraft products that are available (such as linked accounts, lines of credit, and alerts), including a clear explanation of how the terms and fees for such alternative services and products differ; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H715B6C88D8004985AE655B6DD95F3F07"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other information as the Bureau may require, by rule.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H346DA4804D3F435C848D5C25F5089EE5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Periodic statements</header><text>Each depository institution that offers an overdraft coverage program shall, in each periodic statement for any transaction account that has an overdraft coverage program feature, clearly disclose to the consumer the dollar amount of all overdraft coverage fees and nonsufficient fund fees charged to the consumer for the relevant period and year to date.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H7713087C628246BF851CC9C560DE7E9F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exclusion from account balance information</header><text>No depository institution may include the amount available under the overdraft coverage program of a consumer as part of the transaction account balance of that consumer.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HB226907F0F904D1F8E6861366331C16C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Prompt notification</header><text>Each depository institution shall promptly notify consumers, through a reasonable means selected by the consumer, when overdraft coverage has been accessed with respect to the account of the consumer, not later than on the day on which such access occurs, including—</text> <paragraph id="H658595B315BC4F83B4E4709235A833E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date of the transaction;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3A1349D9FBCA4E3E9B38015E2560FBFD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the type of transaction;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE07471F71F54415B8AE8AA338F01C628"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the overdraft amount;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H79D7A9BCB72D45B6B5ED37E9AA9986E7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the overdraft coverage fee;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H1630C99E281B45279E43A4FB105FAC72"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the amount necessary to return the account to a positive balance; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4540213E73954DDCB04EAECA777E049E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>whether the participation of a consumer in an overdraft coverage program will be terminated if the account is not returned to a positive balance within a given time period.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCEC988E469B74DFA9FFB58D90961E79B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Terminated or suspended coverage</header><text>Each depository institution shall provide prompt notice to the consumer, using a reasonable means selected by the consumer, if the institution terminates or suspends access to an overdraft coverage program with respect to an account of the consumer, including a clear rationale for the action.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H3DBFB26942CF49EB88EF5CBE25F8595B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Overdraft coverage fee limits</header> 
<paragraph id="H80F2DE70725E40F2941F7CB740FD7FD6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice and Opportunity To Cancel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each depository institution shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H56EF778ACB254FF492DDBC2B65A6235F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>warn any consumer covered by an overdraft coverage program who engages in a transaction through an automated teller machine or a branch teller if completing the transaction would trigger overdraft coverage fees, including the amount of the fees; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE9C3F14158534A49AF7CD5B1EA8C3E6B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide to the consumer the opportunity to cancel the transaction before it is completed.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE4B21BCDA9884CABB0E65C9E8D1314E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>A depository institution may charge not more than one overdraft coverage fee in any single calendar month, and not more than 6 overdraft coverage fees in any single calendar year, per transaction account.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H40BD4264B51B469EA420D6B6C58BD0DB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reasonable and proportional overdraft coverage fees</header> 
<subparagraph id="HA693FF1727CE44C08378A5A715468F0B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount of any overdraft coverage fee that a depository institution may assess for paying a transaction (including a check or other debit) shall be reasonable and proportional to the amount of the overdraft.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB836CD9BAF2B492DB1B59A8BA135A838"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Safe harbor rule authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau, in consultation with the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the National Credit Union Administration Board, may issue rules to provide an amount for any overdraft coverage fee that is presumed to be reasonable and proportional to the amount of the overdraft.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H1B127E4C12FB496BB149C3B639C4AFCF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Posting order</header><text>In order to minimize overdraft coverage fees charged to consumers, each depository institution shall post transactions with respect to transaction accounts in such a manner that the consumer does not incur avoidable overdraft coverage fees.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0A5F3C091F234222A3AE25E1A8545F2A"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Debit holds</header><text>No depository institution may charge an overdraft coverage fee on any category of transaction, if the overdraft results solely from a debit hold amount placed on a transaction account that exceeds the actual dollar amount of the transaction.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H5AEC23C6D0784B0691337C42A629A0DF"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Nondiscrimination for not opting In</header><text>In implementing the requirements of this section, each depository institution shall provide to consumers who have not consented to participate in an overdraft coverage program, transaction accounts having the same terms, conditions, or other features as those that are provided to consumers who have consented to participate in such overdraft coverage program, except for features of such overdraft coverage.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H18A0A220022A4BDA9CC7475101421386"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Nonsufficient fund fee limits</header><text>No depository institution may charge any nonsufficient fund fee with respect to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2B8E5E2C58A040D3991EF2124CD6760F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any transaction at an automated teller machine; or</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H90CAC361ADEE408FB8E53D5880DFBA89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any debit card transaction.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2D6CD2C226014CBA8F3B84840A71B783"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Reports to consumer reporting agencies</header><text>No depository institution may report negative information regarding the use of overdraft coverage by a consumer to any consumer reporting agency (as that term is defined in section 603 of the Fair Credit Reporting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1681a">15 U.S.C. 1681a</external-xref>)) when the overdraft amounts and overdraft coverage fees are repaid under the terms of an overdraft coverage program.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H82484265642543418AB943D03ADF0998"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>No provision of this section may be construed as prohibiting a depository institution from retaining the discretion to pay, without assessing an overdraft coverage fee or charge, an overdraft incurred by a consumer.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection>
<subsection id="H53F54865A4104F97B1259CA7103FB095"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for chapter II of the Truth in Lending Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 140A the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB419A29893184B569C75CE24DF32AEF6" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">140B. Overdraft coverage program disclosures and consumer protection.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section> <section commented="no" id="H42322F60C58041A6845E2BD0FF93C861"><enum>5.</enum><header>Regulatory authority of the Bureau</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 24 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <term>Bureau</term>) shall issue such final rules and publish such model forms as necessary to carry out section 140B of the Truth in Lending Act, as added by this Act.</text> </section>
<section commented="no" id="HE2AC221EB6A54B9A8A508CC00C2FC874"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective date</header> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H802C58044F2744BFBFCCF61D19EFF816"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, whether or not the rules of the Bureau under this Act or such amendments are prescribed in final form.</text> </subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HD1E7877067F843A6A62870D118190B1F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Moratorium on fee increases</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H7F8CCC7E3111453CA05EFDC312ED10AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 1-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, no depository institution may increase the overdraft coverage fees or charges assessed on transaction accounts for paying a transaction (including a check or other debit) in connection with an overdraft or for nonsufficient funds.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H3F656217FE154328A799101D3192CD0D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>As used in this section, the terms <term>depository institution</term>, <term>overdraft</term>, <term>overdraft coverage fee</term>, <term>transaction account</term> and <term>nonsufficient fund fee</term> have the same meanings as in section 140B(o) of the Truth in Lending Act, as added by this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

