<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H48B4CF605F814555A00F1F0BB7A51CBF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2843 IH: Medicaid and CHIP Quality Improvement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2843</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170608">June 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend titles XI and XIX of the Social Security Act to establish a comprehensive and nationwide
			 system to evaluate the quality of care provided to beneficiaries of
			 Medicaid and the Children’s Health Insurance Program and to provide
			 incentives for voluntary quality improvement.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8602E3587790439EA396367FE843257E" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA7069C2FBFF84FD9AFFFE0C773404ACC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicaid and CHIP Quality Improvement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2ED96447233F424F8B487E3F4FAC859B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD8F792F233644A7788DDE67B449EB04E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Despite the fact that Federal and State governments spend hundreds of billions of dollars every year on care for Americans through the Medicaid and CHIP programs, there is no nationwide, systematic method of reporting, collecting, evaluating, or improving the quality of care across all payment and delivery systems (fee-for-service, managed care, primary care case management, or other mechanisms).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE01E131621641E5AC8BD519F7573845"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Although the quality of care delivered through Medicaid health plans is frequently measured, there is no method or mechanism to systematically improve the quality of care provided to all Medicaid and CHIP beneficiaries.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H566593E66D414BA0952AF522919082A2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For the majority of Medicaid and CHIP enrollees who are served by primary care case management or fee-for-service arrangements, there are no Federal requirements for comparable quality monitoring or improvement. Thus there currently is no ability to make fair assessments across all modes of care for Medicaid and CHIP enrollees.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A1FE6BE06C848228FB0B68212AD9C41"><enum>(4)</enum><text>State flexibility and the resulting opportunities for innovation are hallmarks of the partnership between Federal and State governments in the Medicaid and CHIP programs. Without a way to systematically measure quality, however, policymakers cannot know which innovations are the most effective.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HB6311C7A13454F02AF0B2754709F3ED8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Measuring and reporting on comparable health care quality measures for all persons enrolled in
			 Medicaid</header>
 <subsection id="H7E0DC1749B7D46579E799A339905E269"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Quality assurance standards</header><text>Section 1932(c)(1)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396u-2">42 U.S.C. 1396u–2(c)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or comparable primary care case management services providers described in section 1905(t) as well as health care services furnished in fee-for-service settings or other delivery systems</quote> after <quote>1903(m)</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC6E911FA5E954E8089FA31F14E312AD3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adult health quality measures</header><text>Section 1139B of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320b-9b">42 U.S.C. 1320b–9b</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA8C0A3D0EBC44647BAF077D59391F26E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H49C36DDBADB9437E99216F3945BF8AD8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (4) and (5) as paragraphs (5) and (6), respectively; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5810965D26DB4E5DA0CB5723C8E27BEF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3), the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H969A97A371684E388E938148CF48D1C7" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HB80FFD547BD84084BAEA803F620087C6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Quality reporting for medicaid eligible adults</header><text>Beginning not later than January 1 of the calendar year that begins on or after the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Medicaid and CHIP Quality Improvement Act of 2017</short-title>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall require States to use the measures and approaches identified in paragraph (3) to report on the initial core set of quality measures for Medicaid eligible adults identified in paragraph (2), subject to revisions made in accordance with paragraph (6)(B). Such reporting shall be stratified by delivery system, including managed care organizations under section 1932, benchmark plans under section 1937, primary care case management services providers described in section 1905(t), health care services in fee-for-service settings, and other delivery systems, except that the Secretary may determine that reporting on certain measures should not be stratified by delivery system because such stratification would not be feasible or the delivery systems are not comparable with respect to the application of such measures. In addition to the stratification required under the previous sentence, the Secretary shall have the discretion to further stratify reporting on certain measures based on factors such as eligibility category, income level, or other differentiating factors that could have an impact on the comparability of the measure.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H99453CE7743A46D19469A2D93CCA15C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> <subparagraph id="H37E5310E24A543849390F9E8B76486B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>under the such plan</quote> and all that follows through <quote>subsection (a)(5)</quote> and inserting <quote>under such plan or waiver, including measures described in subsection (b)(2), subject to revisions made in accordance with subsection (b)(6)(B)</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2967C20AC91740A190F6DD14E8C8CB3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B), by inserting <quote>, or comparable primary care case management services providers described in section 1905(t), as well as health care services furnished in fee-for-service settings or other delivery systems</quote> after <quote>section 1937</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1279590B4AFA474395A19FD965940A06"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting before the period the following: <quote>, including analysis of comparable quality measures for Medicaid eligible adults who receive their health services through managed care, primary care case management, and fee-for-service settings or other delivery systems</quote>.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2FB7511D3CA495AB2913FC20B9603AD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pediatric health care measures</header>
 <paragraph id="H131A6A8FD21D495A9034D78B1F0C56D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1139A of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320b-9a">42 U.S.C. 1320b–9a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H4B1D9CE6806045A2A93FA65822D2586E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <clause id="H0B0D319B40B54775850F2010648935F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (5) through (8) as paragraphs (6) through (9), respectively; and</text> </clause><clause id="H77D1EF3045A145869B708C9B26FF6419"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0D6A33CD17B4B0AAF5722FE9A5872F7" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HFD3CB12903F14019A7475CA0D82EB8B9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reporting of pediatric health care measures</header><text>Beginning not later than January 1 of the calendar year that begins on or after the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Medicaid and CHIP Quality Improvement Act of 2017</short-title>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall require States to use the measures and approaches identified in paragraph (4) to report on the initial core child health care quality measures established under this subsection and as such measures subsequently are updated under subsection (b)(5). Such reporting shall be stratified by delivery system, including managed care organizations under section 1932, benchmark plans under sections 1937 and 2103, primary care case management services providers described in section 1905(t), health care services in fee-for-service settings, and other delivery systems, except that the Secretary may determine that reporting on certain measures should not be stratified by delivery system because such stratification would not be feasible or the delivery systems are not comparable with respect to the application of such measures. In addition to the stratification required under the previous sentence, the Secretary shall have the discretion to further stratify reporting on certain measures based on factors such as eligibility category, income level, or other differentiating factors that could have an impact on the comparability of the measure.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48B5EEEA21C04BCA9725C36C0C490169"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <clause id="H32BB5E73A5F94D5DAAC2BCCD36275888"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>measures described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(6)</quote> and inserting <quote>the core measures described in subsection (a), as revised in accordance with subsection (b)(5)</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0B95D4E6D85A4220A099FF3D6DBC0E8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B), by inserting before the period the following: <quote>, or comparable primary care case management services providers described in section 1905(t), as well as healthcare services furnished in fee-for-service settings or other delivery systems</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDF9081C0E1A44F709FE09C0C6F2254DC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting before the period the following: <quote>, including analysis of comparable quality measures for children eligible for medical assistance under title XIX or child health assistance under title XXI who receive their health services through managed care, primary care case management, and fee-for-service settings or other delivery systems</quote>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAC495BF276E47BA8DAA4C3D89B50F3F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall take effect as if included in the enactment of section 1139A of the Social Security Act, as added by section 401(a) of the Children’s Health Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/3">Public Law 111–3</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1B5CEF0456E246A6B538B6019E884884"><enum>4.</enum><header>Performance bonuses for significant achievement in Medicaid and CHIP quality performance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1903 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC93F1005D704578B1D17FC7E170F615" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="HA06043EE761F41F98B739EC8E3560A00"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Performance bonus for quality performance achievement</header>
 <paragraph id="HD49453CF94204DB7975A717F30D3198A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a Medicaid Quality Performance Bonus fund for awarding performance bonuses to States for high attainment and improvement on a core set of quality measures related to the goals and purposes of the Medicaid program under this title.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H38E06DF73E6B42ABA59AF3C6A4F6ABC1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Quality performance bonus methodology</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Medicaid and CHIP Quality Improvement Act of 2017</short-title>, the Secretary shall establish a methodology for awarding Medicaid quality performance bonuses to States not less than annually in accordance with paragraph (3) and subject to the availability of appropriations. Medicaid quality performance bonuses shall be awarded on the basis of the annual State reports required under sections 1139A and 1139B and in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0D6BF1FE89234DF589DE209B7EA25504"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Quality performance measurement bonuses</header><text>Medicaid quality performance bonuses shall be awarded to the following 10 States:</text> <subparagraph id="H9D38870684C34A7F8B5F8262ACE4830D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The top 5 States achieving the designation of superior quality performing State under criteria established by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H884C28B1634B45159E9FE3562BA4F10A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The 5 States that—</text> <clause id="HC2DFA213E337426D8930F5A7F06714B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are not among the States described in subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8C5203D21DFB4F618B48D6669C395252"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>demonstrate the greatest relative level of annual improvement in quality performance under criteria established by the Secretary.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H43D72AF9262043B687E73E10069F88F5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Initial appropriation</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1C46E5C6A7C2439281993581B11D90AE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The total amount of Medicaid quality performance bonuses made under this subsection for all fiscal years shall be equal to $500,000,000, to be available until expended.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5427EECA4D7C4995A742C0BA06D7B801"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Budget authority</header><text>This paragraph constitutes budget authority in advance of appropriations Acts and represents the obligation of the Secretary to provide for the payment of amounts provided under this paragraph.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6AA5F4DEE4148B998B42E929F6DAEF6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Use of quality performance bonus funds</header>
 <subparagraph id="H73669FDAB2224CB9B226C07585416E7E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Designation for quality improvement activities</header><text>As a condition of receiving a Medicaid quality performance bonus under this subsection, a State shall agree to designate at least 75 percent of the bonus funds paid to the State under this subsection for a fiscal year for the development and operation of quality-related initiatives that will directly benefit providers or managed care entities participating in the State plan under this title or under a waiver of such plan, including—</text>
 <clause id="HFC84E49B66CE4F248EC565ECE6FCD741"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pay-for-performance programs;</text> </clause><clause id="HA118309F5E4447909897CC4160F5E42A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>collaboration initiatives that have been demonstrated to improve performance on quality;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC632F254ED904F2EA4681715029F7321"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>quality improvement initiatives, including those aimed at improving care for special and hard-to-reach populations, and those directed to managed care entities; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF8BCE2AB97454E4F9CB4DDE4C743AA8F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>such other Secretary-approved activities and initiatives that a State may pursue to encourage quality improvement and patient-focused high value care.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD756643E3EEB438DAE0256BC6B4652F2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State option to establish criteria</header><text>A State may establish criteria for the State performance program carried out under subparagraph (A) that limits the award to a particular provider or entity type, that limits application to a specific geographic area, or that directs incentive programs for quality related activities for specific populations, including individuals eligible under this title and title XVIII and hard-to-reach populations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68FF6C655DE54413908F57A77656EEF1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Remaining bonus funds</header><text>A State may designate up to 25 percent of the bonus funds paid to the State under this subsection for a fiscal year for activities related to the goals and purposes of the State program under this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


