<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H596DD2D76BCD4F24B1F018AF30E88218" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 433</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170111">January 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Secretary of Energy from planning, developing, or constructing a defense waste repository until the Nuclear Regulatory Commission has made a final decision with respect to the construction authorization application for the Yucca Mountain Nuclear Waste Repository.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCFF6FED3A2F8479D9EE459B593490797" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H00C3248FFB8142FCA6E4D999D26BCEE3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sensible Nuclear Waste Disposition Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB141294BB0374E1988FB1FF307272D56"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H42241F351D1E47B2BDE045FBE9BAB1C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Nuclear Waste Policy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10101">42 U.S.C. 10101</external-xref> et seq.) designated the Yucca Mountain site as the sole site to dispose of high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC64DE60BD1E49E880E1EB61E248ECA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to such Act, in 1985 President Ronald Reagan determined that atomic energy defense waste is required to be disposed of in a common repository with commercial spent nuclear fuel.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H852311DA92D2448F9468BE92802DB8E8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy submitted the license application for the Yucca Mountain Nuclear Repository to the Nuclear Regulatory Commission on June 3, 2008.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6E977133B1A142EEA74D18E264795589"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission issued the safety evaluation report which found that the Yucca Mountain site could meet all regulatory standards for 1,000,000 years.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA8D5ED339F864666ACF69BC2E9F1D868"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On December 16, 2016, the Department of Energy released a draft plan titled <quote>Draft Plan for a Defense Waste Repository</quote> stating that the Department of Energy will seek to construct a repository to store defense high level nuclear waste.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF47EEC07CA9C401E9DBB3B18E2F58BB3"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The taxpayers of the United States have already paid more than $3,700,000,000 to dispose of high-level radioactive waste from atomic energy defense activities at the Yucca Mountain site.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H3E72EEF4ADCB4FCEBBB87696FEFB6FFE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation on planning, development, or construction of defense waste repository</header> 
<subsection id="H743F0EAF93DF415494949EEF7FAC3942" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy may not take any action relating to the planning, development, or construction of a defense waste repository until the date on which the Nuclear Regulatory Commission publishes a final decision on an application for a construction authorization for a repository under section 114(d) of the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10134">42 U.S.C. 10134(d)</external-xref>).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H6D66CC67BED841A7B5A330518E8B3EF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF8AD2412A4764171B736E7CE1BF41EEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>atomic energy defense activity</term>, <term>high-level radioactive waste</term>, <term>repository</term>, and <term>spent nuclear fuel</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 2 of the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10101">42 U.S.C. 10101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7137CCEF1E44759B675297E437CC39C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>defense waste repository</term> means the repository for high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel derived from the atomic energy defense activities of the Department of Energy, as described in the draft plan of the Department titled <quote>Draft Plan for a Defense Waste Repository</quote> published on December 16, 2016.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

