<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H14C6019603FA4B29919D36A5E028D267" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2220 IH: Military Pay Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2220</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170427">April 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To appropriate such funds as may be necessary to ensure that members of the Armed Forces, including
			 reserve components thereof, and supporting civilian and contractor
			 personnel continue to receive pay and allowances for active service
			 performed when a Government shutdown occurs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF8DC778CF720463DBAA4DCF15FDE0049" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD8CD299E712E48B99B237CB9ACD4A7DF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Pay Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H60AB52A0DA634E3C902F6152043F190C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Emergency appropriation of funds to provide pay and allowances for members of the Armed Forces and supporting civilian and contractor personnel during Government shutdown</header> <subsection id="H84378FEA6D9A4BB5B48EC84D9DCE3F43"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Emergency Appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During a Government shutdown, the Secretary of the Treasury shall make available to the Secretary of Defense (and the Secretary of Homeland Security in the case of the Coast Guard), out of any amounts in the general fund of the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, such amounts as the Secretary of Defense (and the Secretary of Homeland Security in the case of the Coast Guard) determines to be necessary to continue to provide the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF6E383AFD30A4799B29F899CE3BBA6C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pay and allowances (without interruption) to the following:</text> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB9DC917685E43EFB5F86E0BE3D1CC81"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard, including reserve components thereof, who perform active service during the Government shutdown.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98748BF82F0B4418AB4A4FF7172C7DCA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the discretion of the Secretary of Defense, such civilian personnel of the Department of Defense who are providing support to the members of the Armed Forces described in paragraph (1) as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB70CA78AE4740A898DACC0656468266"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the discretion of the Secretary of Defense, such personnel of contractors of the Department of Defense who are providing direct support to the members of the Armed Forces described in paragraph (1) as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB4295A20163C4C6D97C74ED203B1B7F9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funding necessary to prevent interruptions or delays in the performance of domestic disaster relief and recovery operations by military, civilian, and contractor personnel during the Government shutdown.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3256811734634611B5934DFEF8A62433"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Government shutdown defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Government shutdown</term> means any portion of a fiscal year for which funds have not been appropriated for the purposes specified in subsection (a) for the entire fiscal year and an Act or joint resolution making continuing appropriations for such purposes for that portion of the fiscal year is not in effect.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


