<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBF1B9142894847E3B4F08D899CF3B0CF" key="S" public-private="public" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 601 RS: Reinforcing Education Accountability in Development Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 116</calendar><congress>115th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 601</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20170130">January 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date>June 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S310">Mr. Corker</sponsor>, with amendments</action-desc><action-instruction>Omit the part struck through and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enhance the transparency and accelerate the impact of assistance provided under the Foreign
			 Assistance Act of 1961 to promote quality basic education in developing
			 countries, to better enable such countries to achieve universal access to
			 quality basic education and improved learning outcomes, to eliminate
			 duplication and waste, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA3CCFE529CA24766858B8C52831D4AE8" style="OLC"><pagebreak></pagebreak>
		<section id="H8DE7A0DE24C64F72ADD6F3E381AA000B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="HFC892ABAB1B346948975E4F81E67D8BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reinforcing Education Accountability in Development Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>READ Act</short-title></quote> .</text> </subsection><subsection id="H5CDC29F3703244098252D00F19B69C72"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry idref="HA3CCFE529CA24766858B8C52831D4AE8" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA3CCFE529CA24766858B8C52831D4AE8" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA3CCFE529CA24766858B8C52831D4AE8" level="section">Sec. 3. Assistance to promote sustainable, quality basic education.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA3CCFE529CA24766858B8C52831D4AE8" level="section">Sec. 4. Comprehensive integrated United States strategy to promote basic education.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA3CCFE529CA24766858B8C52831D4AE8" level="section">Sec. 5. Improving coordination and oversight.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA3CCFE529CA24766858B8C52831D4AE8" level="section">Sec. 6. Monitoring and evaluation of programs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA3CCFE529CA24766858B8C52831D4AE8" level="section">Sec. 7. Transparency and reporting to Congress.</toc-entry></toc>
			</subsection></section><section id="H54551ADBEBB0410AB66BD7D2BAFD7AE6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header>
 <subsection id="HAA0B99CDDC6A4C5E8BC6A751D970B2CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H33EDF6E84CBA4A8CBB255E510AF88EC6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H78B2C89D73DC4E30A39237E9E91858A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H248C565C2B8E4B0AAFB4876A38FA6671"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B7E9974A26C4E82804AA54F819855A1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C7E4F00AD524D09950CA4118CB65948"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other definitions</header><text>In this Act, the terms <term>basic education</term>, <term>marginalized children and vulnerable groups</term>, <term>national education plan</term>, <term>partner country</term>, and <term>relevant Executive branch agencies and officials</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 105(c) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as added by section 3.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HCE7AE3E2A5FC46AB895D9148EB061955"><enum>3.</enum><header>Assistance to promote sustainable, quality basic education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 105 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151c">22 U.S.C. 2151c</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4D7FAE9D2254DA2BFF8A8236AE5E297" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H76C4FAECD9054DA5A2459FC7A17A4466"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assistance To promote sustainable, quality basic education</header>
 <paragraph id="H0B04B9E0A6E04547BC3E811ABE79D53B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="HB0092B36B2294AA1BB9E04CDC8F4218E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Basic education</header><text>The term <term>basic education</term> includes—</text>
 <clause id="HDE5FE11D06664AFE806E59CFCC72864C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>measurable improvements in literacy, numeracy, and other basic skills development that prepare an individual to be an active, productive member of society and the workforce;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H80B97421DFE14C7BADBC4E057BA64798"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>workforce development, vocational training, and digital literacy informed by real market needs and opportunities and that results in measurable improvements in employment;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFEED563E68BF4972AA350FD4C43D8B56"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>programs and activities designed to demonstrably improve—</text> <subclause id="H08D5C3728716449FB15EA8F0513AB366"><enum>(I)</enum><text>early childhood, preprimary education, primary education, and secondary education, which can be delivered in formal or nonformal education settings; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H25EF9B2255704B2DA72A417C48E5188F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>learning for out-of-school youth and adults; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H5D386D6BDB364A9D8835B38F097256DA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>capacity building for teachers, administrators, counselors, and youth workers that results in measurable improvements in student literacy, numeracy, or employment.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55D50A748BC84D359D87AB18DF5CE2F1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Communities of learning</header><text>The term <term>communities of learning</term> means a holistic approach to education and community engagement in which schools act as the primary resource center for delivery of a service to the community at large, leveraging and maximizing the impact of other development efforts and reducing duplication and waste.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC084AE060EA640D8A8F956418F867662"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Gender parity in basic education</header><text>The term <term>gender parity in basic education</term> means that girls and boys have equal access to quality basic education.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D542B6668C84C03B8CBCEFD1315E3D7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Marginalized children and vulnerable groups</header><text>The term <term>marginalized children and vulnerable groups</term> includes girls, children affected by or emerging from armed conflict or humanitarian crises, children with disabilities, children in remote or rural areas (including those who lack access to safe water and sanitation), religious or ethnic minorities, indigenous peoples, orphans and children affected by HIV/AIDS, child laborers, married adolescents, and victims of trafficking.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC123FEA72234BB381C884284F8FF934"><enum>(E)</enum><header>National education plan</header><text>The term <term>national education plan</term> means a comprehensive national education plan developed by partner country governments in consultation with other stakeholders as a means for wide-scale improvement of the country’s education system, including explicit, credible strategies informed by effective practices and standards to achieve quality universal basic education.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CB20AA1F6684BCBB6C1AE9C65EF7006"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Nonformal education</header><text>The term <term>nonformal education</term> means organized educational activities outside the established formal system, whether operating separately or as an important feature of a broader activity, that are intended to provide students with measurable improvements in literacy, numeracy, and other basic skills development that prepare an individual to be an active, productive member of society and the workforce.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H692F5090AA5942A9B941471B8F3E8493"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Partner country</header><text>The term <term>partner country</term> means a developing country that participates in or benefits from basic education programs under this subsection pursuant to the prioritization criteria described in paragraph (4), including level of need, opportunity for impact, and the availability of resources.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37F5C1DBA7EE4B459365A8F1CDFFF3E8"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Relevant executive branch agencies and officials</header><text>The term <term>relevant Executive branch agencies and officials</term> means the Department of State, the United States Agency for International Development, the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Labor, the Department of Education, the Department of Agriculture, and the Department of Defense, the Chief Executive Officer of the Millennium Challenge Corporation, the National Security Advisor, and the Director of the Peace Corps.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51E1DDF0D96A45EE851659D771C6106F"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Sustainability</header><text>The term <term>sustainability</term> means, with respect to any basic education program that receives funding pursuant to this section, the ability of a service delivery system, community, partner, or beneficiary to maintain, over time, such basic education program without the use of foreign assistance.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB1F7D91B58F45469700688B3D5C7CE9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, it shall be the policy of the United States to work with partner countries, as appropriate, other donors, multilateral institutions, the private sector, and nongovernmental and civil society organizations, including faith-based organizations and organizations that represent teachers, students, and parents, to promote sustainable, quality basic education through programs and activities that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC4C43E2250AA4DB2856F575F8700A49F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take into consideration and help respond to the needs, capacities, and commitment of developing countries to achieve measurable improvements in literacy, numeracy, and other basic skills development that prepare an individual to be an active, productive member of society and the workforce;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A7E67DDD29B4F918B03CAEA720AA992"><enum>(B)</enum><text>strengthen educational systems, promote communities of learning, as appropriate, expand access to safe learning environments, including by breaking down specific barriers to basic education for women and girls, ensure continuity of education, including in conflict settings, measurably improve teacher skills and learning outcomes, and support the engagement of parents in the education of their children to help partner countries ensure that all children, including marginalized children and other vulnerable groups, have access to and benefit from quality basic education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE12A355CF1747A192B21DF782E4737C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promote education as a foundation for sustained economic growth and development within a comprehensive assistance strategy that places partner countries on a trajectory toward graduation from assistance provided under this section with clearly defined benchmarks of success that are used as requirements for related procurement vehicles, such as grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H205407EFFE984DECBE4005091008EE23"><enum>(D)</enum><text>monitor and evaluate the effectiveness and quality of basic education programs in partner countries.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H858E6310A47A4543AE51B476A53D79B1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Principles</header><text>In carrying out the policy referred to in paragraph (2), the United States shall be guided by the following principles of aid effectiveness:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3D42DC72966F4504BED9467D941D4A53"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Alignment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance provided under this section to support programs and activities under this subsection shall be aligned with and advance United States foreign policy and economic interests.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20EC06ED73014CCF8D9924FC0E74A6E6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Country ownership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the greatest extent practicable, assistance provided under this section to support programs and activities under this subsection should be aligned with and support the national education plans and country development strategies of partner countries, including activities that are appropriate for and meet the needs of local and indigenous cultures.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1705754A9FF248E9A2AB39F4FCCA7D15"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Coordination</header>
 <clause id="HB7F4C61C29654FBE91000CCEC085DD42"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance provided under this section to support programs and activities under this subsection should be coordinated with and leverage the unique capabilities and resources of local and national governments in partner countries, other donors, multilateral institutions, the private sector, and nongovernmental and civil society organizations, including faith-based organizations and organizations that represent teachers, students, and parents.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB4F1D8C05F9843AEA44399CBC5FBE97E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Multilateral programs and initiatives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance provided under this section to support programs and activities under this subsection should be coordinated with and support proven multilateral education programs and financing mechanisms, which may include the Global Partnership for Education, that demonstrate commitment to efficiency, effectiveness, transparency, and accountability.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6A8942644284393B71390CFE8BF9A2F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Efficiency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall seek to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of assistance provided under this section to support programs and activities under this subsection by coordinating the related efforts of relevant Executive branch agencies and officials.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCF57BF8FB9D49FB8287E7EF4A5ECA43"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Effectiveness</header><text>Programs and activities supported under this subsection—</text> <clause id="H96EFB7A401EA4B57B430CABEC7677ADB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be consistent with the policies and principles set forth in this subsection;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4F1068B17D6F40D4A363D1B28D70F7BF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be designed to achieve specific, measurable goals and objectives that are directly related to the provision of basic education (as defined in this section); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6D65DACA83D44301BE08D745B1042550"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>shall include appropriate targets, metrics, and indicators that—</text> <subclause id="H2A680AF4909041DFBF851554037D2EB2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>move a country along the path to graduation from assistance provided under this subsection; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H36C15EBA018E4D2A931726080D6CC9F5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>can be applied with reasonable consistency across such programs and activities to measure progress and outcomes.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1AD9BA7F843443BA7E9DF08AD05FBA6"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Transparency and accountability</header><text>Programs and activities supported under this subsection shall be subject to rigorous monitoring and evaluation, which may include impact evaluations, the results of which shall be made publically available in a fully searchable, electronic format.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DC0FF56821F488EAE87CCA2F7B05F1B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Priority and other requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall ensure that assistance provided under this section to support programs and activities under this subsection is aligned with the foreign policy and economic interests of the United States and, subject to such alignment, priority is given to developing countries in which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3558953434E449328FBF91F834D8FFF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>there is the greatest need and opportunity to expand access to basic education and to improve learning outcomes, including for marginalized and vulnerable groups, particularly women and girls to ensure gender parity in basic education, or populations affected by conflict or crisis; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E3A7248644144A1983BFA913CDED315"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such assistance can produce a substantial, measurable impact on children and educational systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section id="H89554E99F6C24A799081EAED58EF0680"><enum>4.</enum><header>Comprehensive integrated United States strategy to promote basic education</header> <subsection id="HD990967ED4074A60AEB7DA063050726F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy required</header><text><deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">Not later than October 1, 2017, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a comprehensive United States strategy to be carried out during fiscal years 2018 through 2022 to promote quality basic education in partner countries by—</deleted-phrase> <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a comprehensive United States strategy to be carried out during the following five fiscal years to promote quality basic education in partner countries by—</added-phrase></text>
 <paragraph id="H862052A0EEAB4FABA4807C7319103B69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>seeking to equitably expand access to basic education for all children, particularly marginalized children and vulnerable groups; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69E003721B0D45D2A7947EE387DAFC45"><enum>(2)</enum><text>measurably improving the quality of basic education and learning outcomes.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8D891F1C9D0F4B9CBDE1150B67FD7B52"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement To consult</header><text>In developing the strategy required under subsection (a), the President shall consult with—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFB129C5897FA41CAB0408BAA5A889DCC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the appropriate congressional committees;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF665E129855C49738CA59482D058BD02"><enum>(2)</enum><text>relevant Executive branch agencies and officials;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H856F6926AAF541A78C37E931859CD482"><enum>(3)</enum><text>partner country governments; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA33B004C2758405B9C201FC8117B014F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>local and international nongovernmental organizations, including faith-based organizations and organizations representing students, teachers, and parents, and other development partners engaged in basic education assistance programs in developing countries.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H182AB82DFCDB4422B1833903A0DBFCF6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public comment</header><text>The President shall provide an opportunity for public comment on the strategy required under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H24FD7DE73C884005985FE4DD48693873"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="H1F5D9EE11BDF44869699F0F2B76FABC3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be developed and implemented consistent with the principles set forth in section 105(c) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as added by section 3; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDDC72169285846DB8392DE41C2935415"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall seek—</text> <subparagraph id="HBB48A62182B34F2EB57B5116824E03D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to prioritize assistance provided under this subsection to countries that are partners of the United States and whose populations are most in need of improved basic education, as determined by indicators such as literacy and numeracy rates;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2518D34BC72A4A9DBC5C344DF321D0D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to build the capacity of relevant actors in partner countries, including in government and in civil society, to develop and implement national education plans that measurably improve basic education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H655303CE20CB4397BBE1EE633E433ECB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to identify and replicate successful interventions that improve access to and quality of basic education in conflict settings and in partner countries;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F2846CC0C1D4B018FDFDF3090622194"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to project general levels of resources needed to achieve stated program objectives;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H316D1471434741B3BAF49B80CD3E81D2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to develop means to track implementation in partner countries and ensure that such countries are expending appropriate domestic resources and instituting any relevant legal, regulatory, or institutional reforms needed to achieve stated program objectives;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E0CA6AB58DD4BD99141ED11624AC52C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to leverage United States capabilities, including through technical assistance, training, and research; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98F87BD565BF45D4A97B577D192AEC49"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to improve coordination and reduce duplication among relevant Executive branch agencies and officials, other donors, multilateral institutions, nongovernmental organizations, and governments in partner countries.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFDBA0A15F42C4C618F35FC25AE419185"><enum>5.</enum><header>Improving coordination and oversight</header>
 <subsection id="H671896AA69F3424FBCC0AEC7A618AC0B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Senior Coordinator of United States International Basic Education Assistance</header><text>There is established within the United States Agency for International Development a Senior Coordinator of United States International Basic Education Assistance (referred to in this section as the <quote>Senior Coordinator</quote>). The Senior Coordinator shall be appointed by the President, shall be a current USAID employee serving in a career or noncareer position in the Senior Executive Service or at the level of a Deputy Assistant Administrator or higher, and shall serve concurrently as the Senior Coordinator.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H48F9F5F431F342B7BCEFE596F8546C55"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header>
 <paragraph id="H7BCF7FC2309D4678A076209206152796"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Senior Coordinator shall have primary responsibility for the oversight and coordination of all resources and activities of the United States Government relating to the promotion of international basic education programs and activities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA0F4F1AE26CD45F2A4725EB9C1BA9B46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specific duties</header><text>The Senior Coordinator shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H9708242540AC4AD8A9A76E72284A3912"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilitate program and policy coordination of international basic education programs and activities among relevant Executive branch agencies and officials, partner governments, multilateral institutions, the private sector, and nongovernmental and civil society organizations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03AA957694A84446A50C7E551771F840"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop and revise the strategy required under section 4;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BB886DC3ADA46A1B88BCB17B90CC97E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>monitor, evaluate, and report on activities undertaken pursuant to the strategy required under section 4; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64F42A09993E4310AE25EADCF643147A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establish due diligence criteria for all recipients of funds provided by the United States to carry out activities under this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E33EFF05E1A4C60A7D7ED02F5FE1E2E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Offset</header><text>In order to eliminate duplication of effort and activities and to offset any costs incurred by the United States Agency for International Development in appointing the Senior Coordinator under subsection (a), the President shall, after consulting with appropriate congressional committees, eliminate a position within the United States Agency for International Development (unless otherwise authorized or required by law) that the President determines to be necessary to fully offset such costs and eliminate duplication.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HD9254C9B18A4460593619435593FF82B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Monitoring and evaluation of programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President shall seek to ensure that programs carried out under the strategy required under section 4 shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD38D3EDF8A8748739F9196DCF3F2D449"><enum>(1)</enum><text>apply rigorous monitoring and evaluation methodologies to determine if programs and activities provided under this subsection accomplish measurable improvements in literacy, numeracy, or other basic skills development that prepare an individual to be an active, productive member of society and the workforce;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1ABDA54D31F45BBBD1B487374C91A80"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include methodological guidance in the implementation plan and support systemic data collection using internationally comparable indicators, norms, and methodologies, to the extent practicable and appropriate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FDB268C3F9941D7916E802B6912941F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>disaggregate all data collected and reported by age, gender, marital status, disability, and location, to the extent practicable and appropriate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF86BEF95E8B4E50892CA83AE5BB128A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>include funding for both short- and long-term monitoring and evaluation to enable assessment of the sustainability and scalability of assistance programs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C4C5624E5BA4D4292ECB5C281E4357E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>support the increased use and public availability of education data for improved decision making, program effectiveness, and monitoring of global progress.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H785D043DE9C645F1B2FF4107C5139919"><enum>7.</enum><header>Transparency and reporting to Congress</header>
 <subsection id="H5844E4892B9C4EC08693E2548E81A048"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual report on the implementation of strategy</header><text><deleted-phrase reported-display-style="strikethrough">Not later than each March 31 immediately following a fiscal year during which the strategy developed pursuant to section 4(a) was carried out, the President shall—</deleted-phrase> <added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">Not later than 180 days after the end of each fiscal year during which the strategy developed pursuant to section 4(a) is carried out, the President shall—</added-phrase> </text>
 <paragraph id="HCDD51DEE6FEC4EF098B45B0249E22FAB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that describes the implementation of such strategy; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC110E861833B4F7E809586EC9EAC13F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make the report described in paragraph (1) available to the public.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE7B6480369114654A655443568F0D3E1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB58998E98AB04F4E90AF3DDC06E3E743"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the efforts made by relevant Executive branch agencies and officials to implement the strategy developed pursuant to section 4, with a particular focus on the activities carried out under the strategy;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2EAC42CBBE8C49C78F0530F173DDB563"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the extent to which each partner country selected to receive assistance for basic education meets the priority criteria specified in section 105(c) of the Foreign Assistance Act, as added by section 3; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C68FE8639C54347995C5698C109B2BB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of the progress achieved over the reporting period toward meeting the goals, objectives, benchmarks, and timeframes specified in the strategy developed pursuant to section 4 at the program level, as developed pursuant to monitoring and evaluation specified in section 6, with particular emphasis on whether there are demonstrable student improvements in literacy, numeracy, or other basic skills development that prepare an individual to be an active, productive member of society and the workforce.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>June 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Reported with amendments</action-desc></endorsement></bill>


