<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5A640415FA8443348361F89EA0CFBBC6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4705 IH: Me Too Congressional Ethics Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4705</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171220">December 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to require the automatic referral to the
			 congressional ethics committees of the disposition of any allegation that
			 an employing office of the House of Representatives or Senate violated
			 part A of title II of such Act.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7525937791F44B5E81CD252C9732709F" style="OLC">
 <section id="H59190BDB032B42BF80B558297D02D07F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Me Too Congressional Ethics Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5DA51E69171B4B58B46A5EF75F1EB0D5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Automatic referral to congressional ethics committees of disposition of allegations of violations of Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 involving congressional offices</header> <subsection id="H6A12DD1E241B4408ADE1FCF6A19AD7AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Automatic referral</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 416(e) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1416">2 U.S.C. 1416(d)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA236F3616324E7BBCFB97F18EEC5354" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H5A92C977D0C5402A8F07F8B04D77A025"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Automatic referrals to Congressional Ethics Committees of dispositions of allegations involving
			 employing offices of House or Senate</header>
 <paragraph id="H1017448E7D0040E3A0BFD12D14976499"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Referral</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the final disposition under this title of an allegation that an employing office of the House of Representatives or an employing office of the Senate has committed a violation of part A of title II, the Executive Director shall refer the allegation to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H77B7384755D64C1E928F9CB20450985D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Ethics of the House of Representatives, in the case of an employing office of the House; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1E7B842AC6542D0AEA5B427CC12D00D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate, in the case of an employing office of the Senate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF220D31D11C46A08F101E365F68C4F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Access to records and information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Executive Director refers an allegation to a Committee under paragraph (1), the Executive Director shall provide the Committee with access to the records of any hearings or decisions of the hearing officers and the Board under this title, and any information relating to an award or settlement paid, in response to such allegation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED61EC8706FC4C2FB41DABE59F55A95A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Permitting covered employee to waive referral</header><text>At the request of the covered employee filing an allegation described in paragraph (1), the Executive Director shall waive paragraph (1) or paragraph (2) with respect to the allegation or the records and information in response to the allegation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8651AC039C3A410689BC443717F199B9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Final disposition described</header><text>In this subsection, the <quote>final disposition</quote> of an allegation means any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HFBAF9303C78641CA82D378EA134D79BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The payment of an award or settlement.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H446330EAF815420484CA08F8ED787B55"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A final decision of a hearing officer under section 405(g).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F4DF790FC8D480585758701F613F2E9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A final decision of the Board under section 406(e).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC430736159E402980EF9CD6918DAE0E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A final decision in a civil action under section 408.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H49DD283ABA9440BFAAA755CEB3F7FE08"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Actions by congressional ethics committees</header> <paragraph id="HBB3501283DF4483B9080E10B4D73702F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mandatory initiation of investigation</header><text>If the Executive Director of the Board of Compliance refers an allegation to the Committee on Ethics of the House of Representatives or the Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate under section 415(d) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (as amended by subsection (a)), such Committee shall promptly initiate an investigation into the allegation and take such actions in response to the investigation as may be appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2944E1377504232BCDC8933ACA546A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Protection of identity of individuals making allegations</header><text>If a Committee to which an allegation is referred under paragraph (1) issues a report with respect to the allegation, the Committee shall ensure that the report does not disclose the identity of the individual who made the allegation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H45BD32425D8745F786C3F54F2399893C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section and the amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


