<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA9F764BC377A45FBB33A3B672193400C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1554 IH: To include information concerning a patient’s opioid addiction in certain medical records.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1554</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170315">March 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney of West Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To include information concerning a patient’s opioid addiction in certain medical records.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H09ACD93D03AF4A2B9773BA6B891E5498" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5B6200232CA14894A3AD1B25E88FE6B8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote>Jessie’s Law</quote>.</text> </section><section id="HCA88A8E556224583B78D56038F974CA9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Inclusion of opioid addiction history in patient records</header> <subsection id="H32B879CCA89D404BAF0A119D39546B5F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Development of standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall develop and disseminate standards to provide information to hospitals and physicians relating to prominently displaying the history of opioid addiction in the medical records (including electronic health records) of any patient who has provided information about such addiction to a health care provider.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB4E328C78BE64C4EBB565C2AB44CDA53"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The standards developed under subsection (a) shall take into account the following:</text> <paragraph id="H337B0EE938C645C0A144738F37F19D50"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The potential for addiction relapse or overdose death if opioid medications are prescribed to an individual recovering from opioid addiction.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H73EB6867C6E04A9C9A2B84F9A3D66D74"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The need to display the past opioid addiction of a patient in a manner similar to other potentially lethal medical concerns, including drug allergies and contraindications.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D21E67649FB41B88CD1B49821A4A44B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The need for information about past opioid addiction to be prominently displayed when a physician or medical professional is prescribing medication.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25A03A7B1DC140FA83A8E039AF3EF2B6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The need for a variety of medical professionals, including physicians, nurses, and pharmacists, to have access to information described in this section when prescribing or dispensing opioid medication to ensure that the medication is medically appropriate given the history of addiction of the patient.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


