<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBBBFA79F59954C4DA79A4DB51FA5DE2C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1523 IH: District of Columbia Local Prosecutor Establishment Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1523</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170313">March 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To assign the responsibility for conducting prosecutions for violations of the laws of the District
			 of Columbia to the head of a local prosecutor’s office designated under
			 local law of the District of Columbia.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA2E0535278C54F15B4130B6B78AE6BD7" style="OLC">
 <section id="H07285A9C2BAB4E03937728ACC53BEB5C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>District of Columbia Local Prosecutor Establishment Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H36CDF7BAF85A4EE1A0D186E8AB4B7F4A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Responsibility of local prosecutor’s office for conduct of all District of Columbia prosecutions</header> <subsection id="HF5BBE62474EA4BDBA7801940AEE1B266"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 23–101, D.C. Official Code, is amended by striking subsections (a) through (f) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HD0741066F05C447B9091FC86326CD5CE">
 <subsection id="H9CA24EB20C734D9098C843136F65294F"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Prosecutions for violations of all police or municipal ordinances or regulations of the District of Columbia and for violations of all penal statutes of the District of Columbia in the nature of police or municipal regulations shall be conducted in the name of the District of Columbia by the head of the local prosecutor’s office or the assistants of the head of such office, except as may otherwise be provided in any such ordinance, regulation, or statute.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8955826077C94B908ED1C7ACFDB70356"><enum>(b)</enum><text>An indictment or information brought in the name of the United States in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia may include charges of offenses prosecutable by the District of Columbia if the head of the local prosecutor’s office consents to the inclusion of such charges in writing.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF0FEBB72A3C144A5AF8F5ED69572DB72"><enum>(c)</enum><text>An indictment or information brought in the name of the District of Columbia in the Superior Court of the District of Columbia may be joined for trial in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia with an indictment or information brought in that court if the offenses charged therein could have been joined in the same indictment or information and if the head of the local prosecutor’s office consents to such joinder.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD4E193A2771F45C4BD126B702A5CC8ED"><enum>(d)</enum><text>In this section, the <quote>local prosecutor’s office</quote> is the office designated under local law of the District of Columbia as the office responsible for conducting prosecutions under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA65C2BEA51FE40198C8131E46B3B1CD2"><enum>(e)</enum><text>Nothing in this section shall affect the authority of the Attorney General of the United States or the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia to exercise jurisdiction concerning violations of the laws of the United States.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HCC33BBA0AFB44157BDE079DEAB56AE07"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="HB9580DDC07ED428086C53E8D27664BBD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text>Section 23–104, D.C. Official Code, is amended by striking <quote>Corporation Counsel</quote> each place it appears in subsections (a)(1), (b), and (d), and inserting <quote>head of the local prosecutor’s office (as defined in section 23–101(d))</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H215AB65BCF6B46489841B2603D3496D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Proceedings to establish previous convictions</header><text>Section 23–111(a)(1), D.C. Official Code, is amended by striking <quote>Corporation Counsel</quote> and inserting <quote>head of the local prosecutor’s office (as defined in section 23–101(d))</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA9160DBC9C374D9FA9EA9C7539600554"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition of prosecutor</header><text>Section 23–501(3), D.C. Official Code, is amended by striking <quote>Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia</quote> and inserting <quote>head of the local prosecutor’s office (as defined in section 23–101(d))</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H39B9CD7D8413401FBB712F328EA8556F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Disposition of property seized under search warrant</header><text>Section 23–525, D.C. Official Code, is amended by striking <quote>Corporation Counsel for the District of Columbia</quote> and inserting <quote>head of the local prosecutor’s office (as defined in section 23–101(d))</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H78D0EA5505D74E30AB4AD989F2FE4B95"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Deposit of seized currency</header><text>Section 23–532(b)(1), D.C. Official Code, is amended by striking <quote>Corporation Counsel for the District of Columbia</quote> and inserting <quote>head of the local prosecutor’s office (as defined in section 23–101(d))</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD33AA1D014C34E1AB552EF7BAC092022"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Consultation in promulgation of regulations regarding warrant and arrest procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 23–533, D.C. Official Code, is amended by striking <quote>Corporation Counsel</quote> and inserting <quote>head of the local prosecutor’s office (as defined in section 23–101(d))</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B7D0C71DA4741299388B7B42CD518DA"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Recommendations by Pretrial Services Agency regarding release or detention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sixth sentence of section 23–1303(a), D.C. Official Code, is amended by striking <quote>Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia</quote> and inserting <quote>head of the local prosecutor’s office (as defined in section 23–101(d))</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC19EC6EA011B4275B309556406491EB7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to violations of District of Columbia ordinances, regulations, and statutes which occur after the expiration of the 6-month period which begins on the date on which a local law of the District of Columbia which designates the local prosecutor’s office for purposes of section 23–101(d), D.C. Official Code (as amended by subsection (a)) takes effect.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


