<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4CDBC7E5C0F042D58703CDEF4410CF33" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 135 IH: Cyber Privacy Fortification Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 135</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170103">January 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect cyber privacy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H09A3574531C24B3DB4F1FA98FC0319CB" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7401251F40EB476EBB1B4AC5782A0BBC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cyber Privacy Fortification Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><title id="H6DF0D787883248AEA67174DB283D64D2"><enum>I</enum><header>Data Breach Notification</header> <section id="H58FAAEF990694219A0683535748C06B2"><enum>101.</enum><header>Failure to provide notice of security breaches involving sensitive personally identifiable information</header> <subsection id="H871E4A5878B64B62870000B884B07B94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/47">Chapter 47</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4287F435E1C4022B1A285C2C2F49C72" style="USC">
						<section id="H3CEF919DBE254115AEB3EA353E57AA8A"><enum>1041.</enum><header>Failure to provide notice of security breaches involving sensitive personally identifiable
			 information</header>
 <subsection id="H2E2C3A3577154125B1288579A3612CFD"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever, having a covered obligation to provide notice of a security breach involving sensitive personally identifiable information, knowingly fails to do so, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4C94C3AA2A1245A5BC4BABEE680B3738"><enum>(b)</enum><text>As used in this section—</text> <paragraph id="H26E05C4F1BD34F77B54E78A2D28EB71C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered obligation</term>, with respect to providing notice of a security breach, means an obligation under Federal law or, if the breach is in or affects interstate or foreign commerce, under State law;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H48BA702023E34C5C960E625A33FC0919"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>sensitive personally identifiable information</term> means any electronic or digital information that includes—</text> <subparagraph id="HD77535D40E2147AD9AE02C6E945E0465"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual’s first and last name, or first initial and last name, or address or phone number in combination with any one of the following data elements where the data elements are not protected by a technology protection measure that renders the data element indecipherable—</text>
 <clause id="H6227820FD2A7407DAADD96E82E95D1A0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a nontruncated social security number, driver’s license number, state resident identification number, passport number, or alien registration number;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H912786944F4B4359A0A38FBC69F5619E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>both—</text> <subclause id="H806A9AC66ED349BE8797D3B52CD66F16"><enum>(I)</enum><text>mother’s maiden name, if identified as such; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA0699714E4B5452791C8F643187E4626"><enum>(II)</enum><text>month, day, and year of birth; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H65DC13CBAC9D41C38083084987E95683"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>unique biometric data such as a fingerprint, voice print, a retina or iris image; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05167038F6C74C57B15E9FC8D9612925"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a financial account number or credit or debit card number in combination with any security code, access code or password that is required for an individual to obtain credit, withdraw funds, or engage in a financial transaction by means of such number;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H37E8319307C34A4ABD4861971DB56FFE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>security breach</term> means a compromise of the security, confidentiality, or integrity of computerized data that there is reason to believe has resulted in improper access to sensitive personally identifiable information; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H19674F8247BA4986833CD773ED603A83"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>improper access</term> means access without authorization or in excess of authorization.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H41BC47E496754FBAB549DADD82DBDB9D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/47">chapter 47</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A7E906132804723BB71AC54090DB848" style="USC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry level="section">1041. Concealment of security breaches involving personally identifiable information.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection><subsection id="HB1CAE1129E744258B290134ACAEA8038"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Obligation To report</header>
 <paragraph id="H50AE14B4E4204229990EC45F80073E09"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person who owns or possesses data in electronic form containing a means of identification and has knowledge of a major security breach of the system containing such data maintained by such person, must provide prompt notice of such breach to the United States Secret Service or Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E5915AF872F4795ACB321F79885DD68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication of list of notifications</header><text>The Secret Service and the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall annually publish in the Federal Register a list of all notifications submitted the previous calendar year and the identity of each entity with respect to which the major security breach occurred.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC33F40EEC490497B8336F2334DFA6F6D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H88D73A2E30244B90B906B024C2A1BD2A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>major security breach</term> means any security breach involving—</text>
 <clause id="H3C6E065D64B34CE195F7FC561E6C93DF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means of identification pertaining to 10,000 or more individuals is, or is reasonably believed to have been acquired;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H89DC1E7B289743E38F24446776C349EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>databases owned by the Federal Government; or</text> </clause><clause id="H6A03DABA9A2E4ECCB535DA5E3F5152AD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>means of identification of Federal Government employees or contractors involved in national security matters or law enforcement; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B82921EE22E4275AE5FCCC2B98B3C36"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>means of identification</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1028 of title 18, United States Code.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H557C7BE67F1D454F9646D0B0223532EA"><enum>II</enum><header>Non-criminal privacy enforcement and privacy impact statements</header> <section id="H779B4BB9C66A41BBBE628CDF6E6C853F"><enum>201.</enum><header>Enforcement by Attorney General and State authorities</header> <subsection id="HFB14E6BE2A354A22913D6D8773BB38B1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of <term>authorized entity</term></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As used in this section, the term <term>authorized entity</term> means the Attorney General, with respect to any conduct constituting a violation of a Federal law enacted after the date of the enactment of this Act relating to data security and engaged in by a business entity, and a State Attorney General with respect to that conduct to the extent the conduct adversely affects an interest of the residents of a State.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="HF617DC339A754771B3D53575BA4ED2DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header>
 <paragraph id="H6B4244B6A7C54E209FB1C04E09261846"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Generally</header><text>An authorized entity may in a civil action obtain a civil penalty of not more than $500,000 from any business entity that engages in conduct constituting a violation of a Federal law enacted after the date of the enactment of this Act relating to data security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H58C19AD0DEA645CFAA765B6B340FC7DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for intentional violation</header><text>If the violation described in subsection (a) is intentional, the maximum civil penalty is $1,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD571E81DD93245C39827BEDE94FAC2E4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Injunctive relief</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An authorized entity may, in a civil action against a business entity that has engaged, or is engaged, in any conduct constituting a violation of a Federal law enacted after the date of the enactment of this Act relating to data security, obtain an order—</text>
 <paragraph id="H19E2F0F55FE1467B8DD3B922CA784DA8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enjoining such act or practice; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A854DE1675F47248DD775814B1D133E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enforcing compliance with that law.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC94731A51430470C91E42AF5DA366776"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Other rights and remedies</header><text>The rights and remedies available under this section do not affect any other rights and remedies available under Federal or State law.</text>
				</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H20213ED5626A4400AC241BF24CF5A412" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>202.</enum><header>Coordination of State and Federal efforts</header>
				<subsection id="HF7A2551F46E848BC859781FD2F301FDC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notice</header>
 <paragraph id="HA3A59FE72FCF408E8DB5BC05B5102C09"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State consumer protection attorney may not bring an action under section 201, until the attorney general of the State involved provides to the Attorney General of the United States—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H68FE17C92DAD4F568DD8BAE1E6C85E43"><enum>(A)</enum><text>written notice of the action; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H805D4A2C5A9C4A879163F598E3EFF5C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a copy of the complaint for the action.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3A198CA88464BE0B48BAE25864D58B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Paragraph (1) does not apply with respect to the filing of an action by an attorney general of a State under this section if the State attorney general determines that it is not feasible to provide the notice described in such subparagraph before the filing of the action, in such a case the State attorney general shall provide notice and a copy of the complaint to the Attorney General at the time the State attorney general files the action.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H47EB93F4E8DC403DA49B42FCFC35EC57"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal proceedings</header><text>The Attorney General may—</text> <paragraph id="HA34D7460FCD2400491240D3D1A8BAED0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>move to stay any non-Federal action under section 201, pending the final disposition of a pending Federal action under that section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A8DD189B74641F781FBE50D4F889DE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>initiate an action in an appropriate United States district court and move to consolidate all pending actions under section 201, including State actions, in that court; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8929CFA15DB94B07AC56EE48330F972A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>intervene in a State action under section 201.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E6E624909B2445184D5720402CB0FE9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pending proceedings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Attorney General institutes a proceeding or action for a violation of a Federal law enacted after the date of the enactment of this Act relating to data security, no authority of a State may, during the pendency of such proceeding or action, bring an action under this section against any defendant named in such criminal proceeding or a civil action against any defendant for any violation that is alleged in that proceeding or action.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3F94DB11FD1E48D7A8BDBF8FB41F13D2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As used in this section, the term <term>State consumer protection attorney</term> means the attorney general of a State or any State or local law enforcement agency authorized by the State attorney general or by State statute to prosecute violations of consumer protection law.</text>
				</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2AD210326F104CC2A8B537F295C1F8C2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>203.</enum><header>Requirement that agency rulemaking take into consideration impacts on individual privacy</header>
 <subsection id="H0961D138E55641ABAC75E09AF192FA86"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding after section 553 the following new section:</text> <quoted-block id="HDAAD4BD598314C20AFFA9B483F08CEDF" style="USC"> <section id="H8AC386AA6751446E8D67475426E74BE1"><enum>553a.</enum><header>Privacy impact assessment in rulemaking</header> <subsection id="HFF62ECDB4E284E0FBB762073410288CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial privacy impact assessment</header> <paragraph id="H72797399887C4AF7AC7E6EBD992676C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Whenever an agency is required by section 553 of this title, or any other law, to publish a general notice of proposed rulemaking for a proposed rule, or publishes a notice of proposed rulemaking for an interpretative rule involving the internal revenue laws of the United States, and such rule or proposed rulemaking pertains to the collection, maintenance, use, or disclosure of personally identifiable information from ten or more individuals, other than agencies, instrumentalities, or employees of the Federal Government, the agency shall prepare and make available for public comment an initial privacy impact assessment that describes the impact of the proposed rule on the privacy of individuals. Such assessment or a summary thereof shall be signed by the senior agency official with primary responsibility for privacy policy and be published in the Federal Register at the time of the publication of a general notice of proposed rulemaking for the rule.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H72C5F45CA1E144DEB9636CD6D021FCF1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each initial privacy impact assessment required under this subsection shall contain the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HB8EAE8FAD8204E0A997CCABC633FFD4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description and analysis of the extent to which the proposed rule will impact the privacy interests of individuals, including the extent to which the proposed rule—</text>
 <clause id="H3E5B75BF2B7749309083413424B70355"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides notice of the collection of personally identifiable information, and specifies what personally identifiable information is to be collected and how it is to be collected, maintained, used, and disclosed;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFB1D032BD6F2414182AFF39F5D5E0733"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>allows access to such information by the person to whom the personally identifiable information pertains and provides an opportunity to correct inaccuracies;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6CA8F556EAE54A2FBE078AE9B1191D25"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prevents such information, which is collected for one purpose, from being used for another purpose; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4A90EC4B5CB14EB1BB0B0587849C6B34"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides security for such information, including the provision of written notice to any individual, within 14 days of the date of compromise, whose privacy interests are compromised by the unauthorized release of personally identifiable information as a result of a breach of security at or by the agency.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC999DB0CD7FA4944B19EA9A905BC385B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of any significant alternatives to the proposed rule which accomplish the stated objectives of applicable statutes and which minimize any significant privacy impact of the proposed rule on individuals.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB01582B761524A6AA1FFBF8CC9AA2BE6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Final privacy impact assessment</header>
 <paragraph id="HA8200A8782C84E57A9F69B18D66A1905"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Whenever an agency promulgates a final rule under section 553 of this title, after being required by that section or any other law to publish a general notice of proposed rulemaking, or promulgates a final interpretative rule involving the internal revenue laws of the United States, and such rule or proposed rulemaking pertains to the collection, maintenance, use, or disclosure of personally identifiable information from ten or more individuals, other than agencies, instrumentalities, or employees of the Federal Government, the agency shall prepare a final privacy impact assessment, signed by the senior agency official with primary responsibility for privacy policy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H64CEAE8F694D40D1AC90AC57DFD87508"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each final privacy impact assessment required under this subsection shall contain the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H49DA6ACCBC2C424293D669BEF020A909"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description and analysis of the extent to which the final rule will impact the privacy interests of individuals, including the extent to which such rule—</text>
 <clause id="H64A286624B504BA79D267BED097B24A0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides notice of the collection of personally identifiable information, and specifies what personally identifiable information is to be collected and how it is to be collected, maintained, used, and disclosed;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA7A5349DF0644E34A53B403FC7846768"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>allows access to such information by the person to whom the personally identifiable information pertains and provides an opportunity to correct inaccuracies;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7A4066C687F044049F754F3C0E97BB51"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prevents such information, which is collected for one purpose, from being used for another purpose; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H57DCCAD18ABF48688DD63B8D10FB00A2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides security for such information, including the provision of written notice to any individual, within 14 days of the date of compromise, whose privacy interests are compromised by the unauthorized release of personally identifiable information as a result of a breach of security at or by the agency.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17CB937D02314A2AA09CAC1F861F7619"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A summary of any significant issues raised by the public comments in response to the initial privacy impact assessment, a summary of the analysis of the agency of such issues, and a statement of any changes made in such rule as a result of such issues.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF148244853964EC5BF7D7C9612D17699"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of the steps the agency has taken to minimize the significant privacy impact on individuals consistent with the stated objectives of applicable statutes, including a statement of the factual, policy, and legal reasons for selecting the alternative adopted in the final rule and why each one of the other significant alternatives to the rule considered by the agency which affect the privacy interests of individuals was rejected.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F241C5E5D4F4880AD3BF15EF2CF2451"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability to public</header><text>The agency shall make copies of the final privacy impact assessment available to members of the public and shall publish in the Federal Register such assessment or a summary thereof.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6233528932DA4E0D85726168524F7ECF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waivers</header>
 <paragraph id="H6449C8312C7F46F6BC3AF41AA23D56F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Emergencies</header><text>An agency head may waive or delay the completion of some or all of the requirements of subsections (a) and (b) to the same extent as the agency head may, under section 608, waive or delay the completion of some or all of the requirements of sections 603 and 604, respectively.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA38D6619FDA34A9C8203EDBF4B926ED2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National security</header><text>An agency head may, for national security reasons, or to protect from disclosure classified information, confidential commercial information, or information the disclosure of which may adversely affect a law enforcement effort, waive or delay the completion of some or all of the following requirements:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD29AF680B49D4855BC675AA2C272D0CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement of <internal-xref idref="H72797399887C4AF7AC7E6EBD992676C4" legis-path="553a.(a)(1)">subsection (a)(1)</internal-xref> to make an assessment available for public comment, provided that such assessment is made available, in classified form, to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate, in lieu of making such assessment available to the public.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B669D5ACC59444D9CB6FC27619BC810"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement of <internal-xref idref="H72797399887C4AF7AC7E6EBD992676C4" legis-path="553a.(a)(1)">subsection (a)(1)</internal-xref> to have an assessment or summary thereof published in the Federal Register, provided that such assessment or summary is made available, in classified form, to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate, in lieu of publishing such assessment or summary in the Federal Register.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88BC64F7D3F94F038BFBA6E1C45C0DC5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of <internal-xref idref="H7F241C5E5D4F4880AD3BF15EF2CF2451" legis-path="553a.(b)(3)">subsection (b)(3)</internal-xref>, provided that the final privacy impact assessment is made available, in classified form, to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate, in lieu of making such assessment available to the public and publishing such assessment in the Federal Register.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1CBBF224E333418385C129F2AAFCD899"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Procedures for gathering comments</header><text>When any rule is promulgated which may have a significant privacy impact on individuals, or a privacy impact on a substantial number of individuals, the head of the agency promulgating the rule or the official of the agency with statutory responsibility for the promulgation of the rule shall assure that individuals have been given an opportunity to participate in the rulemaking for the rule through techniques such as—</text>
 <paragraph id="H54500A7EFA284CCDAC1139585D297F0E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the inclusion in an advance notice of proposed rulemaking, if issued, of a statement that the proposed rule may have a significant privacy impact on individuals, or a privacy impact on a substantial number of individuals;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA39BFE532A63481EB7217741B66B7110"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the publication of a general notice of proposed rulemaking in publications of national circulation likely to be obtained by individuals;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE63CD770DE64653941DD35B0DD57603"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the direct notification of interested individuals;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3237FF3C062A469AB785AD86F64869C6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the conduct of open conferences or public hearings concerning the rule for individuals, including soliciting and receiving comments over computer networks; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB86AB94BC8124ABD8428D74B56481ED0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the adoption or modification of agency procedural rules to reduce the cost or complexity of participation in the rulemaking by individuals.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7FC60F7D8CA6432B820956DAD0230CAD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Periodic review of rules</header>
 <paragraph id="HF3F68171C89146528D41943FD0F683FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each agency shall carry out a periodic review of the rules promulgated by the agency that have a significant privacy impact on individuals, or a privacy impact on a substantial number of individuals. Under such periodic review, the agency shall determine, for each such rule, whether the rule can be amended or rescinded in a manner that minimizes any such impact while remaining in accordance with applicable statutes. For each such determination, the agency shall consider the following factors:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H50E53C73B2CC456EA0F933887056D625"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The continued need for the rule.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF4553C1964C4BA69FCB38459DEF913B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The nature of complaints or comments received from the public concerning the rule.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FEC3CB3EE7847F0AF793D7464D17274"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The complexity of the rule.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DB10D5CBBB447E1AD7B7B30781AEEBB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The extent to which the rule overlaps, duplicates, or conflicts with other Federal rules, and, to the extent feasible, with State and local governmental rules.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0758BE15245437FA13B15F08F151A74"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The length of time since the rule was last reviewed under this subsection.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FAB875C3F6A47239AE8100059E370DC"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The degree to which technology, economic conditions, or other factors have changed in the area affected by the rule since the rule was last reviewed under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB792546295224E179DC8BF77B7318964"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Plan required</header><text>Each agency shall carry out the periodic review required by <internal-xref idref="HF3F68171C89146528D41943FD0F683FF" legis-path="553a.(e)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> in accordance with a plan published by such agency in the Federal Register. Each such plan shall provide for the review under this subsection of each rule promulgated by the agency not later than 10 years after the date on which such rule was published as the final rule and, thereafter, not later than 10 years after the date on which such rule was last reviewed under this subsection. The agency may amend such plan at any time by publishing the revision in the Federal Register.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H159850CF2313435AAA15652DE4B793E0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual publication</header><text>Each year, each agency shall publish in the Federal Register a list of the rules to be reviewed by such agency under this subsection during the following year. The list shall include a brief description of each such rule and the need for and legal basis of such rule and shall invite public comment upon the determination to be made under this subsection with respect to such rule.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58687A5A449C4BADB92507EF6AE8DE59"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Judicial review</header>
 <paragraph id="HA2DEFB83022B4E7CA0D01490B06CD1A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For any rule subject to this section, an individual who is adversely affected or aggrieved by final agency action is entitled to judicial review of agency compliance with the requirements of subsections (b) and (c) in accordance with chapter 7. Agency compliance with <internal-xref idref="H1CBBF224E333418385C129F2AAFCD899" legis-path="553a.(d)">subsection (d)</internal-xref> shall be judicially reviewable in connection with judicial review <internal-xref idref="HB01582B761524A6AA1FFBF8CC9AA2BE6" legis-path="553a.(b)">of subsection (b)</internal-xref>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H387E073E56144BEDB3E08A60FF238FED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text>Each court having jurisdiction to review such rule for compliance with section 553, or under any other provision of law, shall have jurisdiction to review any claims of noncompliance with subsections (b) and (c) in accordance with chapter 7. Agency compliance with <internal-xref idref="H1CBBF224E333418385C129F2AAFCD899" legis-path="553a.(d)">subsection (d)</internal-xref> shall be judicially reviewable in connection with judicial review<internal-xref idref="HB01582B761524A6AA1FFBF8CC9AA2BE6" legis-path="553a.(b)"> of subsection (b)</internal-xref>.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H271008AC0CBC4D379161E2354ED1479C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations</header>
 <subparagraph id="H8836A2CDF8784B9A966A0E9CEA88B926"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An individual may seek such review during the period beginning on the date of final agency action and ending 1 year later, except that where a provision of law requires that an action challenging a final agency action be commenced before the expiration of 1 year, such lesser period shall apply to an action for judicial review under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47749F02820744C18059B836C80D955B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case where an agency delays the issuance of a final privacy impact assessment pursuant to <internal-xref idref="H6233528932DA4E0D85726168524F7ECF" legis-path="553a.(c)">subsection (c)</internal-xref>, an action for judicial review under this section shall be filed not later than—</text> <clause id="H703EFB31EE724A23BCFBFE2661770DBD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>1 year after the date the assessment is made available to the public; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0C77D711ED5746A5BABBC8B45A19E8A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>where a provision of law requires that an action challenging a final agency regulation be commenced before the expiration of the 1-year period, the number of days specified in such provision of law that is after the date the assessment is made available to the public.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EF6E104F00247D8BA12B109D385FEB4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>In granting any relief in an action under this subsection, the court shall order the agency to take corrective action consistent with this section and chapter 7, and may—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE80EA718E1DE40A7AEDB0BFE0E812AF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>remand the rule to the agency; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA260D450345F448288FCAFD0FF56DB46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>defer the enforcement of the rule against individuals, unless the court finds that continued enforcement of the rule is in the public interest.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE72653AC4964C2598D0596FDC7995BD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection limits the authority of any court to stay the effective date of any rule or provision thereof under any other provision of law or to grant any other relief in addition to the requirements of this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9564BFF8215479ABF0B9701899C1230"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Record of agency action</header><text>In an action for the judicial review of a rule, the privacy impact assessment for such rule, including an assessment prepared or corrected pursuant to <internal-xref idref="H2EF6E104F00247D8BA12B109D385FEB4" legis-path="553a.(f)(4)">paragraph (4)</internal-xref>, shall constitute part of the entire record of agency action in connection with such review.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9AC640086F20424CBDA0693DC41C54C8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Exclusivity</header><text>Compliance or noncompliance by an agency with the provisions of this section shall be subject to judicial review only in accordance with this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H113BBD0225474480A146D2B614A453E5"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this subsection bars judicial review of any other impact statement or similar assessment required by any other law if judicial review of such statement or assessment is otherwise permitted by law.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B6D4E701F124D3696F62E5E1047ABB6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>personally identifiable information</term> means information that can be used to identify an individual, including such individual’s name, address, telephone number, photograph, social security number or other identifying information. It includes information about such individual’s medical or financial condition.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection><subsection id="H3DC8CE8FA8E54256948E94C01A7CD60C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Periodic review transition provisions</header>
 <paragraph id="H338B865936D041109C7D294C8BD096FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial plan</header><text>For each agency, the plan required by subsection (e) of section 553a of title 5, United States Code (as added by <internal-xref idref="H0961D138E55641ABAC75E09AF192FA86" legis-path="2.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>), shall be published not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H02F2B119BD814CAC96F24D6473F0717A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review period</header><text>In the case of a rule promulgated by an agency before the date of the enactment of this Act, such plan shall provide for the periodic review of such rule before the expiration of the 10-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act. For any such rule, the head of the agency may provide for a 1-year extension of such period if the head of the agency, before the expiration of the period, certifies in a statement published in the Federal Register that reviewing such rule before the expiration of the period is not feasible. The head of the agency may provide for additional 1-year extensions of the period pursuant to the preceding sentence, but in no event may the period exceed 15 years.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F1AD843D0104798838C46469A07209D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Congressional review</header><text>Section 801(a)(1)(B) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2B8AC960376841A383EDE881368E0B59"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (iii) and (iv) as clauses (iv) and (v), respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD200E8A71A1941AB8D2138231616E7AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (ii) the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block id="H6C0B8F80A70E44029647E4A49A6161C5"> <clause id="H17774F78CA8147A893B8E5B29244E9A4" indent="up2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the agency’s actions relevant to section 553a;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H45FF13E4203147368603C0A5E28D255C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding after the item relating to section 553 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H3B552F177B9849F4BE9BC6BD81E18300" style="USC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">553a. Privacy impact assessment in rulemaking.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill>


