<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8202294A520F4B0790C6A48BDC18B272" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3587 IH: Battling Russian Intelligence Baiting Efforts Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3587</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the collection and assessment of intelligence regarding the efforts of foreign
			 powers to gain influence through the financial interests of the President
			 and close family members and associates of the President.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2FD5454B0B5841F88E75B75F4182C32D" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD29139035636412084508AD45FE9B96D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Battling Russian Intelligence Baiting Efforts Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BRIBE Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2FC4B3E3C7534F459D398C233AC3B644" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Collection and assessment of intelligence regarding the efforts of foreign powers to gain influence through the financial interests of the President and close family members and associates of the President</header> <subsection id="HBE92C2923F224A6C97C9DD5E1C905A57"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="H8E522831D3F744B6B6783BB5A4F47700"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Article I, section 9, clause 8 of the United States Constitution (commonly known as the <quote>Emoluments Clause</quote>) prohibits acceptance of gifts by the President from a foreign state.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9126E2543714F2490D7127069F03D94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The purpose of the emoluments clause is to prevent foreign corruption of the workings of the United States Government.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D4F9C49E9F747198E2A0128FAA8B353"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Pursuant to a 2009 opinion by the Office of Legal Counsel, corporations owned or controlled by a foreign government are presumptively foreign states under the Emoluments Clause.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC91ED7E3715B458490B92A210C9F3A32"><enum>(4)</enum><text>President Donald J. Trump maintains a business network, the Trump Organization, that has financial interests around the world and negotiates and concludes transactions with foreign states and entities that are extensions of foreign states.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF30E56F07A4D45E08508654AC67E1FC4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Office of Government Ethics has expressed concerns regarding ongoing conflicts of interest between President Trump and his business concerns and intermingling of the Trump Organization and the work of Government. Examples of potential Trump conflicts include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBB8192A5507D45A290416F6B477418F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>President Trump received long sought trademarks for the Trump Organization by the Chinese government the day after reversing his position on the <quote>one-China</quote> policy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6633904CF11E40AB91E5D4248E97DC7E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Saudi Arabia, as the Wall Street Journal recently reported, spent $270,000 at the Trump Hotel in Washington, DC, as part of a lobbying effort to roll back legislation that allows family members of 9/11 attack victims to sue the Saudi government.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5C9F2384ED04F7FBE168F0E3DEF03BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>During the transition, Jared Kushner, the President’s son-in-law and White House senior adviser, met with Sergey N. Gorkov, chief of Vnesheconombank (VEB), in what the White House described as part of routine diplomatic encounters. Gorkov’s bank has been used as a frequent cover for Russian intelligence service operatives, and Gorkov indicated that he met with Kushner in Kushner’s capacity as the chief executive of Kushner Companies.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA5E09A78B564CCF923EB8FDC5E62B11"><enum>(D)</enum><text>In February, in its first major real estate transaction after Trump’s inauguration, the Trump Organization sold a $15,800,000 penthouse apartment in Trump Tower to Chinese-American business executive Xiao Yan Chen, who has been directly linked to a front group for Chinese military intelligence through the misleadingly innocuous-sounding China Arts Foundation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B9E705DDF0C414ABCE3544034D9A401"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H3635EBDE056C4DE29005023B0FD204BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>President Trump’s foreign interests and his unwillingness to divest his holdings creates a possibility of foreign corruption, exactly the purpose of the emoluments clause;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4089AB82554A41E28D215E27D9892AAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>foreign governments appear to be calculating that directing money and favorable treatment toward projects, properties, and interests affiliated with President Trump and Jared Kushner is an easy way to secure foreign policy gains; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE303EBFE1C241FE8479ABE3AAC358A0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>President Trump’s foreign entanglements, to the extent they enhance possibility of foreign corruption, constitute a national security challenge to the United States.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE2788E4D222E481DBF07238BB00EC5A3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Collection and assessment of intelligence regarding foreign powers influence relating to financial
			 interests of covered persons</header>
 <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38D0E30CE732441D8303F737DC68F05B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to title V of the National Security Act of 1947, the intelligence community is authorized to collect and, as appropriate, disseminate intelligence regarding efforts by a foreign power to influence, or to take any actions as a result of, a financial interest of a covered person. Such actions include, but are not limited to, the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9D9D6F2185F44A028CDA6E1452023356"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Granting favorable treatment to a covered business or organization as a means to curry favor with the administration.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45C0D1E671B9426BAD2A936163AD2A4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Granting of trademarks or other benefits to members of the President’s family.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82501D3BEE684ABD958E96761DD24348"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Giving a covered business or organization favorable regulatory or other preferential treatment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37023C1BD92A482B9FB732D8F602D9BB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Renting or buying properties owned or operated by a covered business or organization.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2FF902733BF400A8BFA36F791389699"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Investing in concerns operated by a covered business or organization.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE77035545F814750903BC74F5451D5D4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Lending money to or otherwise facilitating financial transactions on behalf of a covered business or organization.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB2F6F05240D44FEBCE5845B3509C8FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Intelligence assessments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after receipt of intelligence, the Director of National Intelligence shall assess whether a foreign power is attempting to influence, or to take any actions as a result of, a financial interest of a covered person.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H109B805D7FC34056BEEA913752B438B4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Congressional notification requirements</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1A461771BE2F4A20BE8E0B81AAB3FB50"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notification of intelligence assessments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 10 days after making an assessment under paragraph (2), the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a report on the assessment made, including the specific intelligence upon which the assessment is based.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8452F82E6B44431BAD0C25CA512312DA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice of previously collected intelligence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of National Intelligence shall make available to the congressional intelligence committees any intelligence obtained during the period beginning on January 19, 2017, and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act, indicating that a foreign power or foreign interest provided to a covered business or organization favorable regulatory or other preferential treatment or provided an emolument as a means to curry favor.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H40231A4FD4EE42FF9450F195860889DC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deadline for implementing guidelines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence shall issue guidelines to the intelligence community regarding the collection of intelligence described in this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD2DF1E867E264BE1AFD743A52E7C86A1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H30FBFA03CFE5445FB205E940EB0EC074"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered person</quote> means—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HF52F94E96D6E4AF9B79EBB5C1F63AA78"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H32FC6E137BEC4BA08F81BBFACB61A5E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Vice President;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HD074118C67A644B3A0D0BBAEAE23C5E8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a child of the President or Vice President; or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HA1DE15A2AF2F4D9EBA2D1C1804E3D24C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a close relative of the President or Vice President, including an in-law.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2500B5DE960D439685D7E5F895E09857"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered business or organization</quote> means—</text> <clause id="H142DA5682BC34DFF8212C11BCD960074"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Trump Organization; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5B7E249D3ED040F8BAE3067E103EAF52"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an organization or business controlled by or associated (including known shell companies) with a covered person, any member of the President’s family, or any close associate of the President.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2C40530435054A739D57E8F73449720E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <quote>financial interest</quote> means a financial interest of the President, the Vice President, the spouse of the President or Vice President, or a minor child of the President or Vice President, as applicable, that—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HCD1C436B750B478E815D9A07907BE380"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">would constitute a financial interest described in subsection (a) of section 208 of title 18, United States Code—</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H171F95CB74754D2AA6AF299078664C1F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if—</text> <item commented="no" id="H08B226A652434F1D857D3B8A634B5851"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for purposes of such section 208, the terms <quote>officer</quote> and <quote>employee</quote> included the President and the Vice President; and</text>
 </item><item commented="no" id="H7812CA0B567944868F96137118AD92FB"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President or Vice President, as applicable, participated as described in subsection (a) of such section 208 in relation to such financial interest; and</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H79074EA3594543D3A7EC5D435D8E6CD0"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determined without regard to any exception under subsection (b) of such section 208; or</text> </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H5D44A644A30C43D4B7869ACEF8CC559F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may constitute a present, emolument, office, or title, of any kind whatever, from any king, prince, or foreign state (including from an entity owned or controlled by a foreign government), within the meaning of article I, section 9 of the Constitution of the United States.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H94B266F01BD04A4F88135E7F152750BD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The term <quote>intelligence community</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 ( <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


