<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAC74A5B09B1C42E28BFCF479D413012A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4029 IH: Accurate Income Measure Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4029</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171012">October 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Education to make reasonable adjustments to earnings data for graduates
			 of cosmetology gainful employment programs.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HCB2040C71CC8440C93825ABDDEAF2A3B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H04931203F9BD4CE28496E4BCDA80D07E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accurate Income Measure Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>AIM Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H09BEDFD2622F48518191CD3C9AD57D48"><enum>2.</enum><header>Adjustments to rule relating to gainful employment</header> <subsection id="H83BAD34B9924403ABD83A5C49B495324"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Adjustments to rule</header><text>For any rule promulgated by the Department of Education relating to title IV of the Higher Education Act, Program Integrity, Gainful Employment (including 79 Fed. Reg. 64890 (October 31, 2014), and any other related rule that may be promulgated by the Department) (referred to in this Act collectively as the <quote>Rule</quote>), the Secretary shall ensure that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H53A43F36DB6745EBA624A224259030E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for covered programs, any earnings data for graduates utilized in the Rule shall recognize the finding of the United States District Court in the case titled <quote>American Association of Cosmetology Schools v. DeVos (Civil Action No.: 17–0263 (RC))</quote> that the use of Social Security Administration earnings data alone as a measure of graduate earnings is problematic, and shall reasonably account for estimated under-reporting of earned income by graduates; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA01AA05D9E934149A689B882CC9C3F3E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any institution offering a covered program may appeal a zone or failing debt to earnings rate by submitting, as alternate earnings data, the most current earnings data issued by the Bureau of Labor Statistics for the most relevant geographical region, at no higher than the 50th percentile, for the Standard Occupational Classification code, or combination of such codes, in which graduates were placed in or found employment.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6C2D2EE8BBA4F319C35581BC7F12EBA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><text>Until the date on which the Secretary issues the adjustments to the Rule required under subsection (a)—</text>
 <paragraph id="H820BC91498284DA39C49770AEAD23A8F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all covered programs shall be exempt from the Rule;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H739353AA5D0D4FA6B72EDEE1F332FC0E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary shall not publish final debt-to-earnings rates for covered programs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H863A46FBD5FF49B1AD42782D783A21B3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>notwithstanding any other provision of law, institutions of higher education providing covered programs shall not be required to report the debt-to-earnings rates of covered programs on any consumer disclosures relating to gainful employment; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5088F82DB10F4D2382261C9081FE10F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Secretary shall not determine any covered program ineligible to participate in programs authorized under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070</external-xref> et seq.) due to the application of the Rule.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09AE3843F32642A280B28824A30EFA8B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Secretary, jointly with the Commissioner of the Internal Revenue Service, shall carry out a study to develop a method of adjusting earnings data under the Rule to account for the underreporting of income by graduates of covered programs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H02C15BE1697F4F3CBB594EBB943E2CB6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H8BC96F08A7E94C748E427BADA4C2168B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered program</header><text>The term <term>covered program</term> means an educational program that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCBD7C5856DC94165BD9390544EE236BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is designed to lead to gainful employment (as that term is used in sections 101(b) and 102(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(b)</external-xref>; 1002(b)); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA41273CE31EE4968ABBC868D12E1F7CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is identified by Department of Education Classification of Instructional Program codes 12.0401 through 12.0499, 51.3306, or 51.3501.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDDDC3A84AAF4FEABC299E502DB760EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> means an institution described in section 101(b) or section 102(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(b)</external-xref>; 1002(b)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2A67251132A347658A6786EEEC7C2849"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

