<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H28B2281A243D44AE9E7F5C45CB7C84AB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4458 IH: To amend the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to prohibit the use of public funds for the payment of a settlement or award under such Act in connection with a claim arising from sexual harassment committed by a Member of Congress, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4458</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171128">November 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to prohibit the use of public funds for the
			 payment of a settlement or award under such Act in connection with a claim
			 arising from sexual harassment committed by a Member of Congress, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HAB307B436D9F47FF869793BEE79EDE0B" style="OLC">
		<section id="H7A59F6CA2A2A49498837582D7838B02F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibiting use of public funds for payment of settlements and awards under Congressional
			 Accountability Act in sexual harassment claims involving Members of
			 Congress</header>
 <subsection id="H645309B6A557405DA04D7B0BC8254C7F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 415 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1415">2 U.S.C. 1415</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC09F49842D66439B81B863747258C8C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>subsection (c)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (c) and (d)</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA82A6CB4A6B541EDADA50E1C22DA7E33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H715DDDE2215F44A4960BE3C953F455CA" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H282E7D43C2BF4647A33712C46C1053F5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No use of public funds for payments of awards and settlements in connection with acts of sexual harassment committed by Members of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds of the Treasury of the United States may be used for the payment of an award or settlement under this Act in connection with a violation of section 201(a)(1) if the violation consists of an act of sexual harassment committed personally by a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress) or a Senator.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBD99616FF761496E88F97F3542414719"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to settlements and awards paid on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HF24D2F08A5C349E68C3E839DEE1D135A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Mandatory consideration by ethics committees of expulsion of Members of Congress committing acts of
			 sexual harassment under Congressional Accountability Act</header>
 <subsection id="H12347DDCB0AD410088540690CC0D91BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mandatory consideration of question of expulsion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title V of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1431">2 U.S.C. 1431</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H372A78CE1D1548E9BEA84DCEB91A9332"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 509 as section 510; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H57FBE5354F6146F7A9020F77A3CD9AD0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 508 the following new section:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H177259F11A4742B1987880F477DA9C7C" style="OLC"> <section id="HBE65718CE40C4B37A60B77986A992200"><enum>509.</enum><header>Mandatory consideration by ethics committees of question of expulsion of Members of Congress committing acts of sexual harassment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If it is determined in any final decision entered under section 405(g) or 406(e), or in any decision in a civil action brought under section 408, that a violation of section 201(a)(1) occurred which consisted of an act of sexual harassment committed personally by a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress) or a Senator, or if the payment of an award or settlement under this Act is ordered in connection with a violation of section 201(a)(1) which consists of such an act—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7FF1CC2E46C6427C97CCF285692F7D74"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of an act committed by a Member of the House, the Committee on Ethics of the House of Representatives shall conduct an investigation and issue a report on the question of whether the Member should be expelled from the House; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DC3FAE8DAC54D7F9CF3DEDBC22DC879"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of an act committed by a Senator, the Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate shall conduct an investigation and issue a report on the question of whether the Senator should be expelled from the Senate.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C9AFFA656A3407CB2DD32C25EF555B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6587C58CB3884A5F8F38D26A69283605"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating the item relating to section 509 as relating to section 510; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E6238B540AD4639915722A53937C35D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after the item relating to section 508 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB68DCD402207455DADE2411FA9BDD457" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 509. Mandatory consideration by ethics committees of question of expulsion of Members of Congress committing acts of sexual harassment.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC21041827DC14DFEBC2F92FC2F5C82D1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to acts occurring before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


