<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H89CDC7FB986C4429B3BDF5581F15F86F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4553 IH: Terrorist Screening and Targeting Review Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4553</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171205">December 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000580">Mr. Garrett</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a review of the authorization, funding, management, and operation of the National
			 Targeting Center and the Terrorist Screening Center, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HBA1906545D264D1BB45A7596B0B85537" style="OLC">
 <section id="H80849142D4C048FBA3DA114308E95CD0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Terrorist Screening and Targeting Review Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9426A4A9FF6848588B0B50A75A58A27E"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO review of the National Targeting Center and the Terrorist Screening Center</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a review of the authorization, funding, management, and operation of the National Targeting Center (NTC) established under section 411(g)(4) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (6 USC 211(g)(4)) and the Terrorist Screening Center (TSC) established under Homeland Security President Directive 6. Such review shall include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H703F43E539524E7FB48339F99C15D9D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An identification of any weaknesses or gaps in coordination between the NTC and TSC.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE9AA665BA6B4D7A9B42FFE2361852F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An identification of any unnecessarily duplicative or overlapping efforts between the NTC and TSC.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF75ADED188154B61B435F6EB2FD6127D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recommendations on how the NTC and TSC may better support and complement one another.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCA281B50CB24402283C7B0E6D81BA30E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A cost-benefit analysis of congressional authorization of the TSC.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


