<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4462315FEAF84E21950C8CF332F19C9F" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 427 IH: Collaborative Academic Research Efforts for Tourette Syndrome Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 427</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170110">January 10, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the expansion, intensification, and
			 coordination of the programs and activities of the National Institutes of
			 Health with respect to Tourette syndrome.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H471A878DB0E5411C8A8BE0C13B55F7FE" style="OLC">
 <section id="H132096C7B9D74628B0CEEE505643A8DA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Collaborative Academic Research Efforts for Tourette Syndrome Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE5E95C13B18046AB8025DD6DF0A017A2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Programs of the National Institutes of Health relating to Tourette syndrome</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title IV of the Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 409J (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/284q">42 U.S.C. 284q</external-xref>) the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H204C976EA3FC4052919ECE9064463DBA" style="OLC">
				<section id="HBDDDC793D06840AD90BDFC32DAAECADF"><enum>409K.</enum><header>Expansion, intensification, and coordination of activities with respect to Tourette syndrome</header>
 <subsection id="H5C4B7B2530BA46419EBF46D900E6D097"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of NIH, shall expand, intensify, and coordinate the programs and activities of the National Institutes of Health with respect to scientific and clinical research on Tourette syndrome.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="HCCCA3D5FE585499F99F20B3CB6CA9678"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Data collection</header>
 <paragraph id="HDDE49BC4165B44EA946CF9B7DD12B750"><enum>(1)</enum><header>System</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall develop a system to collect data on Tourette syndrome, including epidemiologic information with respect to the incidence, prevalence, and impact of Tourette syndrome in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H20AA348AC91C4E2293675D7E3C3F226D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Broad and narrow definitions</header><text>The data collection system under paragraph (1) shall provide for the collection of primary data on Tourette syndrome, including related data on the various conditions known to be comorbid with Tourette syndrome.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H31D2B52ADB4F4EABB6D88FDDDCF7097C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Collection by population and geographical region</header><text>The data collection system under paragraph (1) shall provide for the collection of data on the availability of medical and social services for individuals with Tourette syndrome and their families and the disaggregation of such data by population and geographical region.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3167314C38BB4BF6B5A32E0BF67F6ADC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Collaborative Research Centers for Tourette Syndrome</header>
 <paragraph id="H0526B0E287294FC0A29357608F112A27"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall award grants and contracts to public or nonprofit private entities to pay all or part of the cost of planning, establishing, improving, and providing basic operating support for Collaborative Research Centers for Tourette Syndrome.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45351941D68342A29DB7C71D38EFBD83"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Research</header><text>Each center under paragraph (1) shall conduct basic and clinical research into Tourette syndrome. Such research should include investigations into the cause, diagnosis, early detection, prevention, control, and treatment of Tourette syndrome. The research conducted by such centers, as a group, shall include research in the fields of developmental neurobiology, neuroscience, genetics, psychology, and pharmacology.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H0ED3013E442E4BE39FA529D16BAD0CFE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Services for patients</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9D85882A222B468698452605705B0126"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A center under paragraph (1) may expend amounts provided under such paragraph to carry out a program to make individuals aware of opportunities to participate as subjects in research conducted by the centers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D86994A5BEB429483B0A89A6151CCEF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Referral and costs</header><text>A program under subparagraph (A) may, in accordance with such criteria as the Secretary may establish, provide to the subjects described in such subparagraph, referrals for health and other services, and such patient care costs as are required for research.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDDEF8E4A8454A7FA1E09079E7D67E74"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Availability and access</header><text>The extent to which a center can demonstrate availability and access to clinical services shall be considered by the Secretary in decisions about awarding grants and contracts to applicants which meet the scientific criteria for funding under this subsection.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7650BAFC7C164E0A943E1B1853A4D1A1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Organization of Collaborative Research Centers for Tourette Syndrome</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE7041E26EF8A4B5092DC6D3908064268"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A center under paragraph (1) may—</text> <clause id="H14F47FC38B2A44C69D54E2C07F27D7BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>use the facilities of a single institution; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0F4BB914D33A4354B49CB497CF3A3752"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be formed from a consortium of cooperating institutions and patient advocacy groups in order to maximize the scope of the center’s services and geographic coverage.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63BD3D206EE54DC4B5168E0EFD0488B4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligibility requirements</header><text>To be eligible to make facilities so available (as described in subparagraph (A)(i)) or participate in such a consortium (as described in subparagraph (A)(ii)), an institution or group shall meet such requirements as the Secretary may prescribe.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H98C2D164BBEA4681AF9CCC7F19757828"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Number of centers; duration of support</header>
 <subparagraph id="H97D33DF9A9614958AEC1E29CE19C9CFD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall provide for the establishment of not fewer than 4 and not more than 6 centers under paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H149FFBD6BC334C67B7875BAEBBAEBBFE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Geographical distribution</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="H1E044702257D453CB7869387A352DD86"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensure that each of the centers established under paragraph (1) is located in a different region of the United States than other such centers; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA0DEA79A03244F4B81DC773657D2391C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>encourage the formation of such centers from a consortium of entities (as described in paragraph (4)(A)(ii)) covering multiple regions or States.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B73019F582A46A6B53F1A69A1E78117"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Support for a center established under paragraph (1) may be provided under this section for a period not to exceed 5 years. Such period may be extended for one or more additional periods not exceeding 5 years if the operations of such center have been reviewed and approved by an appropriate technical and scientific peer review group established by the Secretary and if such group has recommended to the Secretary that such period should be extended.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C79FB77BDA24B7CBA1BD40CE71A31C4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Research on symptomology and treatment</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall award grants on a competitive, peer-reviewed basis for research on—</text>
 <paragraph id="H076E8CC3BC1543719D5F470B13681730"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the full range of symptomology within the Tourette syndrome clinical spectrum; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H98EF7B89DAB64EBE8E6DFDE5F047FEF4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the efficacy of treatment options for particular patient subpopulations.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H865204E22BAC4B30BC0DD532C35A9A11"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Of the amounts made available to carry out the programs and activities of the National Institutes of Health for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall designate a portion of such amounts for carrying out the programs and activities of the National Institutes of Health with respect to Tourette syndrome.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


