<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC73E78697F3D43F3A14AE18A532F12A6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2648 IH: Veterans Transition Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2648</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170524">May 24, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to ensure that the requirements that new Federal employees
			 who are veterans with service-connected disabilities are provided leave
			 for purposes of undergoing medical treatment for such disabilities apply
			 to certain employees of the Veterans Health Administration, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1841E3A2632E42308739B1B1A05410B2" style="OLC">
 <section id="HDF45DA6276B34FCEB4EB8090A924AD6D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Transition Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA933E98D2D7A4FE598041EF90F2D5B75"><enum>2.</enum><header>Application of Federal leave policy for disabled veterans to employees of Veterans Health Administration and restatement of existing leave transfer program</header> <subsection id="H30E2C5D4A1C54457A558B8A5E2860CEF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/74">chapter 74</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7423">section 7423</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H96CE3D310FB74F4DB23AB59CE4A06451" style="USC">
					<section id="H4EC59164401C4987BFE7C8E3BDA32BA5"><enum>7423A.</enum><header>Personnel administration: leave</header>
						<subsection id="H6105D46EF6A04A4896348D8C73D65060"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Leave transfer program</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H89BB6731B6964F4F995AA6458CA3A366"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall establish a leave transfer program for the benefit of health-care professionals in positions listed in section 7401(1) of this title. The Secretary may also establish a leave bank program for the benefit of such health-care professionals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF38E0B32F5E9443B8BDF79DF39DB814D" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To the maximum extent feasible—</text> <subparagraph id="HE68102E62C004A0BAC958EB181B3267F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the leave transfer program shall provide the same or similar requirements and conditions as are provided for the program established by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management under subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFB1D4020261402C8524741708D42F64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any leave bank program established pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be consistent with the requirements and conditions provided for agency leave bank programs in subchapter IV of such chapter.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3F4E178F9E746B9AE0D376B9CB73267" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Participation by a health-care professional in the leave transfer program established pursuant to paragraph (1), and in any leave bank program established pursuant to such paragraph, shall be voluntary. The Secretary may not require any health-care professional to participate in such a program.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H6F81CD2712924CFEB53A0D8C5737E35C" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4116C4C6268940F4900A26DFF786B341"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary and the Director of the Office of Personnel Management may enter into an agreement that permits health-care professionals referred to in paragraph (1) to participate in the leave transfer program established by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management under subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5 or in any leave bank program established for other employees of the Department pursuant to subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5, or both.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8935B834188F4670BC9D8FFAAEF4E69F" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Participation of such health-care professionals in a leave transfer program or a leave bank program pursuant to an agreement entered into under subparagraph (A) shall be subject to such requirements and conditions as may be prescribed in such agreement.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H998FECBAA18149FCBBCF0ACF5D8B56B0" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Secretary is not required to establish a leave transfer program for any personnel permitted to participate in a leave transfer program pursuant to an agreement referred to in paragraph (4).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E15086D3B914457B02CB057BA47D297"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of Federal leave policy for disabled veterans</header><text>Section 6329 of title 5 shall apply to all health-care professionals in positions listed in section 7401(1) of this title.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6F2AF2D182F142C9B675ABEBFA6D5CBB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal of transferred authority</header><text>Section 7423 of such title is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD3876C5C7A85469D9F8DD92CD1D55933"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (e); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF291FD6B520845469214C83124CE1379"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (f) as subsection (e).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D892EDDF4544B99A90E8DE032355F32"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 74 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7423 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HEFFFC4C15D5C40FAAF2F654D22C63689" style="USC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry idref="H4EC59164401C4987BFE7C8E3BDA32BA5" level="section">7423A. Personnel administration: leave.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


