<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE987BA6B474543BC9F728625517E0BA2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2695 IH: Environmental Justice Small Grants Program Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2695</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001200">Mr. McEachin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish an Office of Environmental Justice in the Environmental Protection Agency and to authorize an environmental justice small grants program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H92B8311F499C4A0E91DB5DA2CC2B2F46" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H66775540DD29416BB7907D3C5D58D136" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Environmental Justice Small Grants Program Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H14C58B6D517E45F694F71EA0C9FF4CB9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC2225D46B4E74096BFA88B2A3FBD9011"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Despite Executive Order 12898 (relating to <quote>Federal Actions to Address Environmental Justice in Minority Populations and Low-Income Populations</quote>), communities of color, low income communities, people with limited English proficiency, indigenous peoples, and people living with disabilities experience the impacts of climate change at a disproportionate rate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4157DC7EAA374E27BD7078EE330A207E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Environmental Protection Agency formed the Environmental Justice Small Grants Program to support and empower frontline communities that are working on solutions to the disproportionate impacts of climate change. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E84242949AC45D3A313C361F7341C59"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Between 2000 and 2015, the Environmental Protection Agency, through the Environmental Justice Small Grants Program, awarded more than 630 small grants to assist with the cost of conducting research and education, as well as developing community-based solutions.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HEA96D6E9B50044F19AC972D28C4AE2BE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Office of Environmental Justice</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is established in the Environmental Protection Agency an Office of Environmental Justice, which shall be headed by a Director.</text></section> 
<section id="HD2E6814A63FC4BC48040FDA18F79F431"><enum>4.</enum><header>Environmental justice small grants program</header> 
<subsection id="HDF3CDB52F0D640698EE64740BC2DEBA8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Environmental Justice shall establish an environmental justice grant program to make grants to eligible entities in accordance with this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H86EE4AFA1D0F451E9BC93D859DA023C8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Director may make a grant under this section, in an amount not to exceed $50,000, to an eligible entity to carry out an environmental justice project.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H4D8A1C77A69D4796917A2F02F2C4833B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H5DCA6CB8094D421F9C710F51D7EA8E66"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affected community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>affected community</term> means a community that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H39961B4B2E8E4B0682D764332C730AF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may be disproportionately affected by environmental harms and risks; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3E8BCA7CB16245519F0226F21477F147"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is affected by a local environmental or public health issue that is identified in an application for a grant under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H85FA3EAB9E0A4D8CA1BB8DA52CDE76A2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H893DC8F97F16464CB3FBB6F6D45F745D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an entity that—</text> 
<clause id="H8C2EE8D1E802407D89FBA7F6F7CD7BFB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is an organization (including an environmental justice network, a faith-based organization, and an organization affiliated with a religious institution)—</text> <subclause id="H22AF9957F7D0458FA746507BAC7960EB" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H78D6DCB0FA5A4DCDA1AA8DF371AF93FA"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognized as a nonprofit organization by the government of the State, territory, commonwealth, or federally recognized Tribe with jurisdiction over the area in which it is located;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HB41236EE439A47B9B611BE880D03EF16"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>demonstrates that it has worked directly with the affected community, as determined by the Director; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H762EBCE184724277A3FC7B8B88A5547A" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is located in the State, territory, or commonwealth, or area over which a federally recognized Tribe has jurisdiction, in which the proposed environmental justice project is located; </text></clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8476ABDDD3FB44A28BEE49AD9E950B7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a federally recognized Tribal government with jurisdiction over the area in which the proposed environmental justice project is located; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEDD1291CA6F544C6B72874E65B04AC3F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a Tribal organization that demonstrates that it has worked directly with the affected community, as determined by the Administrator.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAC1C660797C401CA76B5F64EE497BF6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Environmental justice project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>environmental justice project</term> means a project consisting of activities designed to empower and educate an affected community to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2A78C776C23F43AFB94EABF0A9FB5395"><enum>(A)</enum><text>understand environmental and public health issues; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D72E651E68F4A609DEBD736465086B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify ways to address those issues at the local level.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H26BE0D0554B64D5FBA88067F9D3D5E7F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $16,000,000 for each fiscal year.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

