<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H28031F1B22D54625BBF853C2A7B5EE24" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 758</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170131">January 31, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize veterans who are entitled to educational assistance under the Post-9/11 Educational Assistance Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs to use such entitlement to participate in a career transition internship program for veterans.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H18DCF39BA2AD4EDE967BF96A67CBB171" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDF0C6ADC1CF541439AFE9AF0C290EA3C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>GI Internship Program Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFF093FF2B1B4423B9F6F2A9AB9EAC78B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Program on provision of career transition services to young veterans</header> <subsection id="H4CCB0D37EFAE406C98B0EFB726BE795B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H411FD4783F5F44B3B8F02131733A93A0" style="USC"> 
<section id="H630F33EA4FCC414198B694338D38237C"><enum>3320.</enum><header>Career transition internship program</header> 
<subsection id="H56310938431341DEB081A619B0E7B35C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The internship program described in subsection (b) shall be deemed to be an approved program of education for purposes of this chapter.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5054A3D494AB444D95ACA9BF2C08997E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Internship program</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish a program to match individuals entitled to educational assistance under this chapter with eligible employers providing internships for the purpose of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H94EDBFC52EFE48148F81A091FEB966DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>providing such individuals with work experience in the civilian sector;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H16FF2901DC674109B8CBD745C80916AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">addressing the growing skills gap in the United States economy;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAA7947509F7C4C2196DB0949B97AB696"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increasing the marketable skills of such individuals; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA35F5A614394604AA8C232C1E071487"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assisting such individuals in obtaining long-term employment.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9BA162EA09784DC7BC620CF19DEBE28B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible employers</header> 
<paragraph id="H80CFA603CE044DF79CF2774EF55746DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of the program, an eligible employer is an employer determined by the Secretary to meet such criteria for participation in the program as the Secretary shall establish for purposes of the program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA02523F2DDA9466CA80C8C5FDF219435"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Past performance on certain matters</header><text>The criteria established by the Secretary under paragraph (1) may include past performance of an employer with respect to the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF48B18E9757D44DBBFF58DE25FEFB2FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Job training, basic skills training, and related activities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1F8DE3DD84674D12B66EEAA590F331AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Financial accountability.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H28FCC52AC2DD4AD283862A9A0DF20855"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Demonstrated need to hire, desire to grow, and plan to grow.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8F18C5595A194CF9BC5F090913CED96B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Demonstrated high potential for growth and long-term job creation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2B8076F08C14463B9133078C5E9AD851"><enum>(3)</enum><header>For-profit and not-for-profit employers</header><text>The employers determined by the Secretary to be eligible employers under paragraph (1) may include both for-profit and not-for-profit employers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D74A222ED8649A8A082BBEF03F9AE42"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Small business concerns</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining employers to be eligible employers under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall ensure that small business concerns (under the meaning given that term under section 3(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632(a)</external-xref>)) are afforded opportunities to participate in the program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H810A1FDAD0574C2DBEE9F67AFE01ADB6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Manufacturing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining employers to be eligible employers under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall give special consideration to employers in the manufacturing sector.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2CE45D12A36B44848BE15392D119C812"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The following employers may not be determined to be eligible employers under paragraph (1):</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEFBCC9B063944815B723F105C2A7101E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An agency of the Federal Government or a State or local government.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6525DB5799594430B83B232B99DB8E85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An employer that has previously participated in the program and, as determined by the Secretary, failed to abide by any requirement of the program.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2846389D5C124622B8A91087FBECA345"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An employer that cannot give an assurance to the Secretary at the time of application for participation in the program under subsection (f), and in such manner as the Secretary shall specify pursuant to that subsection, on each matter as follows:</text> <clause id="HD8F768012A894F53A25295B98AA4E13A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>That the employer has not been investigated or subject to a case or action by the Federal Trade Commission during the 180-day period ending on the date the employer would otherwise commence participation in the program.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H04633614AA344C9DA7CD6A0EBA4D7437"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>That the employer has been in good standing with a State business bureau during the period described in clause (i).</text></clause> <clause id="HD3B32CCC0F7442D189922EE8AAB8DAF0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>That the employer is not delinquent with respect to payment of any taxes or employer contributions described under sections 3301 and 3302(a)(1) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3301">26 U.S.C. 3301</external-xref> and 3302(a)(1)).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9F474D06843A4F18B28B54B6A94E5F0F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>That the employer would not request the placement of an additional eligible individual under the program, if after such additional placement, the number of eligible individuals placed in internships at such employer under the program would constitute more than 10 percent of the eligible employer’s workforce. For purposes of the previous sentence, being an intern under the program placed at an employer shall be considered part of the employer’s workforce.</text></clause> <clause id="H0D3F5FCBF1734FDCAD55841FA52066F2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>That the employer has the intention of retaining eligible participants after such participants have completed participation in the program.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5DB91592ED8C4EE98F77B9C62A5CAE1F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Internships</header> 
<paragraph id="H4B09883275754A8383C12513D1817BE4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For each individual entitled to educational assistance under this chapter whom the Secretary approves for participation in the program established under subsection (b), the Secretary shall attempt to place such individual in an internship on a full-time basis with an eligible employer that the Secretary has approved for participation in the program. For each month such an individual participates in such an internship on a full-time basis, the Secretary shall pay to the individual the amount of educational assistance described in section 3313(g)(3)(B) of this title.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H80FFD8A67BDE4061BE1C46479CFC1874"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Each internship under the program shall be for a period of at least 180 days but not more than one year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H091EF8C3E8B24653AD608BAB5EDD9D6F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Employment status</header><text>For purposes of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>), an individual placed in an internship with an eligible employer under the program shall be considered an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs and not the eligible employer during the period of such internship under the program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0DBA456888AA48BB8ACA39DED8B9F753"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relation to other federal assistance</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, pay received by an individual under this subsection may not be used in any calculation to determine the eligibility of such individual for any Federal program for the purpose of obtaining child care assistance.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF900ECF6F3249258D50238E4EB4FCCD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>For each month that an individual participates in an internship under the program established by subsection (b), the individual and the eligible employer providing the internship shall submit to the Secretary certification that the individual worked at least 35 hours each week for the eligible employer performing functions that provided the individual with valuable experience.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD747CD04DFAD41A19CE2D4058D2EF833"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Participation</header> <paragraph id="H7D5CF26FA66F452CBD028A73F323A7BD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header> <subparagraph id="HF07EBF1C2C094F21A9855CA5B251AE7A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible employer or individual seeking to participate in the program shall submit to the Secretary an application therefor at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary shall specify.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H73B4058243D046899736A1E9231315FD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements for eligible employers</header><text>An application submitted by an eligible employer under subparagraph (A) shall include a certification or other information, in such form and manner as the Secretary shall specify, on each of the assurances required by subsection (c)(5)(C), including the assurance that the employer has the intention of retaining eligible participants after they have completed participation in the program as provided in clause (v) of that subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H100933D2BB0C4CB9A4525F990BE717E6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Time of application for certain eligible individuals</header><text>A member of the Armed Forces on active duty who expects to be entitled for educational assistance under this chapter may submit an application to participate in the program not earlier than 180 days before the date on which the member expects to be discharged or released from the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H910DBC89437B4F929086224F4ABEA471"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The Secretary shall review each application submitted by an applicant under paragraph (1) and approve or disapprove the applicant for participation in the program.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4BF7846654AB42FCA53AFC8336FC8F56"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Outreach</header> <paragraph id="HF13E6D43E9A3441E8EEBB9F245557833"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Labor shall jointly carry out a program of outreach to inform eligible employers and eligible individuals about the program and the benefits of participating in the program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA1A2D67F6FE5457FAD5E70528CA809EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Internet portal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Labor shall work together to create and publicize an Internet website to serve as a portal for eligible individuals and eligible employers to learn about the program and apply.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84CC949BB41E444BA2C3B09B3FC9D7A1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Included locations and groups</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Labor shall ensure that any outreach program and activities conducted under paragraph (1) include, to the extent practicable, rural communities, tribal lands of the United States, Native Americans, and tribal organizations (as defined in section 3765 of title 38, United States Code).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H90CB2B919BF64CBAAF387B6823B5C81B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Minimization of burdens on participating employers</header><text>The Secretary shall take such measures as may be necessary to minimize administrative burdens incurred by eligible employers due to participation in the program and to ensure that employer participation in the program is at no cost to the employer.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H00F6B851ABDA48F39CB793FE0C7894E6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph id="HF25695DFC6F044799326A9246017657E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the completion of the first year of the program and not later than 90 days after the completion of the second and third years of the program, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H32D744982142463BBEB8523CE73AE2AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HB9498D5E9139441EA408EB5BAB1513CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An evaluation of the program.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H855A19787999498A93923472D365F96F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number and characteristics of participants in the program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7973D15D7A514FA3A370201A0E9E67D9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The number and types of internships in which individuals were placed under the program.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H449B89603C47432AB87CE1DDF2D9406F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The number of individuals who obtained long-term full-time unsubsidized employment positions after participation in the program, the hourly wage and nature of such employment, and if available, whether such individuals were still employed in such positions three months after obtaining such positions.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H52EC5EE7CD004B56A17D47A3C5426328"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An assessment of the effect of the program on earnings of the individuals who participated and the employment of such individuals.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE92944A9C49D421C8F5112B7D1BE2D38"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Such recommendations for legislative and administrative action as the Secretary may have to improve the program, to expand the program, or to improve the employment of individuals entitled to educational assistance under this chapter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H9A77F2C461FC494B82FEAB4E8F3D3A2B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 3319 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8FEB557660264AEDB0439340C64C74A9" style="USC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">3320. Career transition internship program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

