<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC6752489A9F24576AD576664135415B9" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1467 IH: Seat Egress in Air Travel Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1467</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170309">March 9, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to prescribe regulations
			 establishing minimum standards for space for passengers on passenger
			 aircraft, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H92D40D74E52F4B088579DFE3384F569C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H319F37FB075D46BC970B79C364A4004F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Seat Egress in Air Travel Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SEAT Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB4071AD6640641619D438696B1D6A173"><enum>2.</enum><header>Regulations relating to space for passengers on aircraft</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7B09C7D49B2C4E36BD301AF6C8FFAF17"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Air carrier defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>air carrier</term> means an air carrier (as defined in section 40102 of title 49, United States Code) that transports passengers by aircraft as a common carrier for compensation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD6EA483ACA994B27AE1229F7EEB02781"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations relating to space for passengers on aircraft</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall prescribe regulations—</text>
 <paragraph id="H57CA04B71B21434C8E58807EAD2D0680"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establishing minimum standards for space for passengers on passenger aircraft, including the size, width, and pitch of seats, the amount of leg room, and the width of aisles on such aircraft for the safety and health of passengers; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9BA1483E9A0B46D1A40588F554206D97"><enum>(2)</enum><text>requiring each air carrier to prominently display on the website of the air carrier the amount of space available for each passenger on passenger aircraft operated by the air carrier, including the size, width, and pitch of seats, the amount of leg room, and the width of aisles on such aircraft.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36A2FEA0EDA6421B8B81E788D5356226"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text>In prescribing the regulations required under subsection (b), the Administrator shall consult with the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, passenger advocacy organizations, physicians, and ergonomic engineers.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


