<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6C11392E46D64736A5AC24BBA2E1E4E4" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3494 IH: National Care Corps Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3494</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170727">July 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a National Care Corps, and to authorize grants
			 for local care corps programs, through which qualified volunteers provide
			 care, companionship, and other services to individuals in need, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF20A38C66548454089108017A67C7522" style="OLC">
 <section id="H70A1819EB7A6472A8F3AF4AB89FC794E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Care Corps Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDDA58AA6638546578A3BCF48B8787321"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Care Corps; local care corps programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254b">42 U.S.C. 254b</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0A23000266984BCF9BBE1FC6D694BA43"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating the second subpart XI (relating to a community-based collaborative care network program) as subpart XII;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC68B4C5872D42CBB6427D40D48BF563"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating the second section 340H (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/256i">42 U.S.C. 256i</external-xref>) as section 340I; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H83E8E1E7475149169DE75D083C1F442F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H040EA9FE20DF4841A53E9A51479C2AF8" style="OLC">
					<subpart id="HEA9B2E6C25F64F2F80339E42964A167F"><enum>XIII</enum><header>National Care Corps; local care corps programs</header>
						<section id="H21683A09DC3844BFB300B4611F2C581A"><enum>340J.</enum><header>National Care Corps</header>
							<subsection id="HABA3660526CB40F39716F34EC7B88F3D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
 <paragraph id="H4BBEB377706F472FA73F993457AF79D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Department of Health and Human Services a program to be known as the <quote>National Care Corps</quote> through which Corps volunteers provide approved services to individuals in need via participation in local care corps programs.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H9813002C4EBC45C091D745550CF2C534"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Staff</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA44E37A151A94FE5BA8F8B97FF4F0E45"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appointment of Director</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Administration for Community Living, shall appoint a Director of the Corps.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA850D2A69A94ED6810030155B78CFD5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duties of Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall—</text> <clause id="HE8A8F1475B6D4AF9B5A82BC8D486CA6A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>design, develop, and administer Corps programs;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFA68066E28F846FC8BC4695ADACF23D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>manage the daily operations of the Corps; and</text> </clause><clause id="HDBED993AE7FD48C1B97AAB1AD338026E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">report to the Administrator of the Administration for Community Living.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H177AAE91DE7244CF9FD5AEE2B130B708"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authority to employ staff</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director may employ such staff as is necessary to carry out this subpart.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C59E7E2534849CE83B47D9C58B58E51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection and eligibility of volunteers</header> <paragraph id="HC7072C052761476D8CF2B0AAD7E45D33"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The Director shall select eligible individuals as Corps volunteers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DECBF0D562946468B4C8E66E22ED172"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible Individuals</header><text>To be eligible to serve as a volunteer in the Corps, an individual shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H102CE3773E134FB8BFA4989DCE19CA81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be at least 18 years of age on or before December 31 of the calendar year in which the individual begins participation in the Corps;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE86C7781B2B743D28CD1FCA85BA7787A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>agree to participate in the Corps for a period of not more than 24 months, consisting of not more than 2 terms of up to 12 months;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2B0672B96FF48C582B8B9CAFFE2A86E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>submit an application to the Director at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Director may require;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD436364E98FE4C7CB1F2B8EC6C6D4897"><enum>(D)</enum><text>pass a criminal background check as described in paragraph (3); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD57EB399854F4C3597503DD390DE67B6"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agree to comply with such terms and conditions as the Director may require.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H529E8AF2A5D94A629AB0ED793D838ADF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Criminal background check</header>
 <subparagraph id="H108D86E220D64FFF8F28C846B8958F12"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Before selecting any individual to serve as a volunteer in the Corps, the Director shall request a criminal background check of such individual on a nationwide basis.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF54E16C3663A4351BCD6338A80791BA0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Volunteer prohibitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual shall be ineligible to be a Corps volunteer if—</text> <clause id="H7D5C96FC1BC1496A881F0D2DE86D8B8E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such individual refuses to consent to the criminal background check; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD2F8E8E6A84C46459D8316F8E761F536"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the criminal background check does not demonstrate to the Director’s satisfaction that such individual is fit for Corps service.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4ABBD3BCA12D44A491B1B1805C686697"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorized benefits for Corps volunteers</header>
 <paragraph id="HCD2609A07AAE45EFB92C777BF229C399"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall provide for Corps volunteers to receive allowances, health insurance, and post-service educational awards authorized by this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H657A174F9146447A85B0FD0E49AD7E71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allowances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall provide each Corps volunteer with such living, travel, and leave allowances, and such housing, transportation, supplies, equipment, and subsistence as the Director determines to be necessary for the volunteer’s maintenance and to ensure the volunteer’s health and capacity to serve effectively.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H939B83748A464016A4727C38AF880B63"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Health insurance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall provide for each Corps volunteer to receive health insurance coverage meeting the requirements of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5000A">section 5000A(f)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H18CEEB3A4A74462097918FB66575444D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Post-Service Educational Award</header>
 <subparagraph id="HCB2C0E810FB144E6BE595603FF6ABFDE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Director shall establish an educational award for Corps volunteers.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA1934D94F3141E6ABD6F270533272B0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amounts</header> <clause id="HE468A69EEB48459CB0AEB4FCE821F701"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Number of awards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Corps volunteer may receive up to 2 educational awards under this paragraph, one for each term of service as a volunteer.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1F44886413604E0796F11026220C47F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amount for full term of service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a Corps volunteer who completes a term of full-time service in the Corps for a period of 12 months, as determined by the Director, such volunteer shall receive an educational award having a value equal to the maximum amount of a Federal Pell Grant under section 401 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a</external-xref>) that a student eligible for such grant may receive in the aggregate (without regard to whether the funds are provided through discretionary or mandatory appropriations) for the award year.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H97208E4D367D411E9D992CC05C3E6566"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Incentive To pursue a degree in a health care profession</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a Corps volunteer who commits to using his or her educational award (or awards, if applicable) under this paragraph for completion of a degree, certificate, or training in a health care profession, or in a social services profession related to the delivery of long-term services and supports to individuals in need, the value of such awards shall be twice the value that would otherwise be applicable under clause (ii).</text>
										</clause><clause id="H0C1F2112430746308DC401BDEAD5D6D2"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Amount for Other Periods of Service</header>
 <subclause id="H3E768B294E93486EBCD86ADBE189277E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>In the case of a Corps volunteer who completes less than a 12-month term of full-time service in the Corps, as determined by the Director, such volunteer may receive a portion of the educational award described in clause (ii) or (iii) (as applicable) that corresponds to the quantity of service actually completed by the volunteer.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9F7BEDED873147C1BA8AA5B3E8B8089F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>In the case of a Corps volunteer who completes more than 12 months of full-time service in the Corps, and less than 24 months of such service, as determined by the Director, such volunteer may receive, for the portion of service exceeding 12 months, a portion of the educational award described in clause (ii) or (iii) (as applicable) that corresponds to the quantity of service actually completed by the volunteer</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B5D91FBF1C74877BCF6120E9B95C92C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Uses of Award</header><text>An educational award shall be used to pay—</text> <clause id="HCAC9F572FF804C32B4ABCADA4EE69AEC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>costs of attendance at an institution of higher education; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H422428289E5B48A992EABF7FB19E8086"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">government or commercial loans received by an individual for the cost of attendance at an institution of higher education.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1F471C42AE7404A8A122A169C0D4D16"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph:</text> <clause id="H201F623A7C054BD0B02FCB40478EFAD9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Cost of Attendance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cost of attendance</term> has the meaning given such term by section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ll">20 U.S.C. 1087ll</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H84662D6EE8C243C3810D4C79AD6A186F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Institution of Higher Education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term under subsection (a) or (b) of section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4A9CB201CA264E8A809079B784D56AD4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal hiring preference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a Corps volunteer who completes at least one term of full-time service in the Corps for a total period of 12 months or more, as determined by the Director, such volunteer shall be eligible for appointment in the competitive service in the same manner as Peace Corps volunteers as prescribed in Executive Order No. 11103 (April 10, 1963).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DAEDA8C646C47F88E001EF323D56FEB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Director shall issue any regulations that the Director determines to be necessary to carry out this subsection.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5021DC5272364F279F6F10D5C238A8B1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Assignment of Corps volunteers</header>
								<paragraph id="H31355270A4564B89AA8BB1F3A3DAEC08"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assignment</header>
 <subparagraph id="H19E025F62D8346A3AF56D9FEC9CD252A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Director shall assign each Corps volunteer to participate in a local care corps program.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFF97B65E5D74F2EB6E5E0154D88F11D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Priority of Assignment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In assigning Corps volunteers to local care corps programs, the Director shall—</text>
 <clause id="H8F33EE3EE68E4D9EB79B6F7B2F28BFA6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>take into consideration the population and geographic preferences of the volunteers; and</text> </clause><clause id="H2D466080D60540A6B2279935B620A293"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assign not less than 20 percent of volunteers to programs that serve geographic areas in which the Director determines there is a shortage of approved services available for individuals in need, with priority given to low-income and minority populations.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3BFC325763F4C68B68242B724D94510"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Services provided by Corps volunteers</header>
 <subparagraph id="HAB028DA301FC4E35B06AC1CF093D83B3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Director shall assign Corps volunteers only for providing approved services to individuals in need through participation in local care corps programs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2C6AEC24E964EF190DC31BF2DC3971B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Approved Services</header><text>Approved services are services provided directly to individuals in need in home-based or community-based settings that—</text>
 <clause id="HE15A7C0B767843FDACD3ED36D6075D39"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">result in person-to-person, supportive relationships with each individual served;</text> </clause><clause id="H6BA296670E174E75B0A0256FA38887B3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support the achievement and maintenance of the highest level of independent living for each individual in need;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE4671F1FBC8F414AB89FC60980929E38"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are supported by appropriate orientation, training, and supervision; and</text> </clause><clause id="HDFED46B21F6F49B1AA7ADC4004A70247"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are provided in support of, or in coordination with, a caregiver, if applicable.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B23274BACEA4141A8FA665EC58A529D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Prohibited Services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In performing duties as a Corps volunteer, no volunteer shall provide—</text> <clause id="H054956A392FA475E94135A52E5EF5D5E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>professional medical services;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H73E265FCAA2841CE8F2C8165958E747B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>administrative support services to a local Corps program;</text> </clause><clause id="H6867AB1587614284BF8C120591A0CA7B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>financial services;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF33B3DDA81BC4BB29C0624922EEE70BD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>care in an institutional setting;</text> </clause><clause id="H1FAE4E5F8D544C518C8B4B5AB3933203"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">care prohibited under State law; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H523AD45F20DA4C61BA9692729CBB67B8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any other services determined by the director to be inconsistent with the purposes of the Corps.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08092B6C63B14BE59744DD703F60F2AC"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Guidance Regarding Scope of Services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall issue guidance describing the scope of services that may be provided by Corps volunteers. In issuing such guidance, the Director shall provide for a public notice and comment period of not less than 60 days before issuing the guidance in final form.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE7C8638F4D54C3FBEBDFD6518B0633E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Training and standards of conduct</header>
 <paragraph id="H6F67510CA9D74DD59B8628C70FDECBB8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pre-Assignment Training Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall develop a training program that provides Corps volunteers with instruction in the skills necessary to carry out an assignment in a local care corps program. Such training program shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2BD22DC25B4D451BB58D421DBD1360D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at least 40 hours of instruction for each Corps volunteer for each term (of 12 months or less) to be served in the Corps by the volunteer;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A2404B519304B27A44954F992B65293"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">additional training for volunteers whose assignment requires skills that are particularly complex, including those necessary to serve individuals with physical, cognitive, or behavioral impairments;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC580354E8FA2450B8A04CDED29672577"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appropriate training in the prevention of abuse, neglect, and exploitation; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D6D0FA6EF624318BD6C0A715E7A18D4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other requirements the Director determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H49C95811A3044DF2A56915D15B9E5B1D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Standards of Conduct</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall establish and enforce standards to promote proper conduct and discipline within the Corps.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDE29161B7A47475083955434F2BFD7EF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Status of Corps volunteers under Federal law</header>
 <paragraph id="H283652F7ECBF48A3954A1C0C11654CC6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, Corps volunteers shall not, by reason of their status as volunteers, be treated as Federal employees or be subject to the provisions of law relating to Federal employment.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="H03542FF7DD044CE1B56A2195B2BA82F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Work-related injuries</header>
 <subparagraph id="HCB362C29D9434FD4B28AF01EA5A7115E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/81">chapter 81</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, relating to the compensation of Federal employees for work injuries, Corps volunteers shall be treated as employees of the United States within the meaning of the term <term>employee</term>, as defined in section 8101 of such title.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8463C62DB12A40EE8E13D4A98FCA0984"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>In the application of the provisions of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/81">chapter 81</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, to a Corps volunteer, the volunteer shall not be treated to be in the performance of duty while absent from the volunteer’s assigned post of duty unless the absence is authorized in accordance with procedures prescribed by the Director.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9969B4DF88124A6991510154DF4AA2A3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tort claims procedure</header><text>A Corps volunteer shall be treated as an employee of the United States for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, relating to tort claims liability and procedure.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D733DF6C4C740EA9BAE28A1B4507ADA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Administration for Community Living, shall transmit to Congress at least once in each fiscal year a report on the Corps. At minimum, such report shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD6B4F28BE69B44AF85E0A104C4B8A07B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the population served by each local care corps program during the preceding fiscal year, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H168C3167C97A41F4B351453379E1D9F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an estimate of the number of individuals served in each State, disaggregated by race, ethnicity, age, disability, and socioeconomic status; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB79AB6131A60471A9027982543DF528B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identification of the type of settings in which the services were provided;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5556A89224544C23B3515866279898C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an evaluation of Corps operations; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99FED4B914D74B4B972EC84AD53CB46D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations, if any, for improving Corps operations.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H18364A0EDA7E4D4F8650114764E45134"><enum>340J–1.</enum><header>Grants for local care corps programs</header> <subsection id="H2BE2B1F132EA472CAAF294FCC1889CBB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director may award grants to eligible entities described in subsection (b) to establish and implement a local care corps program through which Corps volunteers perform approved services for individuals in need as described in section 340J(d)(2).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB18FA1BAB5EB46A6B1AD36433675708D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall be a public or private nonprofit entity that is—</text>
 <paragraph id="H38EA05ED13A743969998D6300C63374E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>part of the aging network, as defined in section 102(5) of the Older Americans Act of 1965;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0630B63A8B34192A517C22C74A1D2B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a time-banking or volunteer organizing agency that has expertise in delivering home- and community-based long-term services and supports to individuals in need;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B95EE158858422D82E62E21D33EC15B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a State, county, or local government; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA9E73F31F8CE45D4B61744E7EBA312BA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other entity that has expertise in delivering home- and community-based long-term services and supports to individuals in need, as determined to be appropriate by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD3471149A1D541228BE75A9E6E8D257D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other requirements</header><text>Local care corps programs shall—</text> <paragraph id="H6782CFCB482C4CEB9BFBEE1B693072C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct in-person orientation and training for Corps volunteers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H103B7A12E8EA43F6AB970426F47F5C8F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop and monitor volunteer assignments, which shall include selecting the individuals in need to be served by Corps volunteers, matching volunteers to assignments, and supervising volunteers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H38DE4BF15A724B2DBBFB8374A624E988"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain records and prepare reports as required by the Director;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1302426CFDC344118A2A7878A4FA9AD8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide regular opportunities for Corps volunteers to collaborate and engage with peer Corps members focused on sharing field experiences and best practices; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD008A6479784A9DBA8E4A7A6FD200B4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>carry out any other activities determined to be appropriate by the Director.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDE1F13A402924BA9952F6ED9594DD2A9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To seek a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H844B6AA0AF78402A9197F7AD97AB53BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information and assurances as the Secretary may require; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7A49A6C0A204B38AEFD98317371DA2A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include in such application a description of the scope of the services proposed to be provided through the entity’s local care corps program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H57F12FB79A644BA185B90DE3F35674FD"><enum>340J–2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this subpart:</text> <paragraph id="HB775BA569B22452794BAEB673D0AF513"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Corps</header><text>The term <term>Corps</term> means the National Care Corps established under section 340J.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD275C58C1E4647A88B8359F19F703E73"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the National Care Corps appointed under section 340J(a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H725F7BDCBEFE4492B12ACB0F94ECBE05"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Individual In Need</header><text>The term <term>individual in need</term> means an individual who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9BA318EE9B8F4E6D8EF5583CA94B5F29"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is at least 65 years of age or has a disability as defined in section 3 of the Americans With Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9913CE573C049AAB51048906401719A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has difficultly with self-care or living independently; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA48A94BAFC34C1589BED5DDE51F521E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meets such other criteria as the Director determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9F0A5D12DFB4527BEF443629C4FCA0E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Local Care Corps Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>local care corps program</term> means a program funded with a grant awarded under section 340J–1.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H644FEB4D0BE14C2A85F7825AF9D15260"><enum>340J–3.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <subsection id="H1967A63C9F8348A0B9F7CEA4C7544131"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this subpart, there is authorized to be appropriated $350,000,000 for each of the fiscal years beginning after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>National Care Corps Act of 2017</short-title>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEB174FE5290548318ED4C9EF150A84CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Continued Availability of Funds</header><text>Amounts authorized to be appropriated under subsection (a) for a fiscal year are authorized to remain available for that fiscal year and the subsequent fiscal year.</text></subsection></section></subpart><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


