<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7D0595B3981D445B93F9627BD03A5593" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4638 IH: National Commission on Scleroderma and Fibrotic Diseases Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4638</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171213">December 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster of New Hampshire</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a National Commission on Fibrotic Diseases.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H446B616EA0E64E588C6CDDE216D9F0CA" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0179B365D20844A99136E3B2EDBF24D1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short Title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Commission on Scleroderma and Fibrotic Diseases Act of 2017</short-title></quote> .</text> </section><section id="HAAC6008DB57647F79AEDD868E8E85826"><enum>2.</enum><header>National commission on fibrotic diseases research</header> <subsection id="H26BB3113AA4D485388330F1258F59473"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby established, within the National Institutes of Health (in this section referred to as <quote>NIH</quote>), a National Commission on Fibrotic Diseases (in this section referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>) to evaluate and make recommendations regarding improvements to the coordination and advancement of NIH-supported research activities related to fibrosis and fibrotic diseases, which may include scleroderma as a prototypical condition that can cause fibrosis in various organs.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HD9F01FD1467F4CEEB1FA76D79BAD154F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <paragraph id="H8D06F07619244D5A97C12FFDFB645136"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall be composed of the following voting members:</text> <subparagraph id="HDE6814E5C86E443C9C56D199FCB0B4E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Director of NIH, or the designee of such director.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0175A13498A46F3B31CFA38F31E0E56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Directors of the following Institutes, or the designees of such directors:</text> <clause id="HC4F8706A22A04E9499760195B6D94D60"><enum>(i)</enum><text>National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H96732D6AF0AE4D7CA33FC4460306DE57"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute.</text> </clause><clause id="H757E31204E414020914FA0F4C8731B45"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive, and Kidney Diseases.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6D30BC32188443AAACE99CC135373713"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>National Human Genome Research Institute.</text> </clause><clause id="HE0093894C19840078424EE7089DB30AA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Any other Institutes or Centers with an active fibrotic disease research portfolio.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6E7FE87AD13842A6B2012A3FB6B082E3"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Twelve additional voting members appointed under paragraph (2).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H81387E6E36534A23AA2C3DCBE37EB996"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional members</header><text>The Commission shall include additional voting members, as may be appointed by the Director of NIH, with expertise in the prevention, care, and epidemiology of any of the diseases and complications described in subsection (a), including one or more such members from each of the following categories:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC5C3496182994AA2AB1EA491C0ACBDE1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Leading scientists or physicians with research expertise in the conditions described in subsection (a).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2A22AA3350D445DB2DD8611563C6BB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Patient and advocates with a perspective on the conditions described in subsection (a).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H78D4576F9BFD4DDE9A9B2AD87111BD89"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The members of the Commission shall select a chairperson from the members appointed under paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5621E7317204740A71EC039EC21A052"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Commission shall meet at least three times a year, with the first meeting occurring not later than April 1, 2019.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H267F35C1E68B4F8E8254715F4847ABF3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>A vacancy on the Commission shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointments.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1B2DDA5EE7BA4138AE39E9321CFE9454"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The duties of the Commission are the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HBB32C5112EBF46A0B37568E83A09B4F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To study the incidence, duration, and mortality rates of fibrotic diseases as described in subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB88B294EC50944E190D6A498F447BEA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To evaluate facilities and resources for the diagnosis, prevision, and treatment of fibrotic diseases described in subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF00D0E976BB548278DDEE6E17D7465F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To develop a long-range plan for the use and organization of national resources to effectively advance research and effectively deal with fibrotic diseases as described in subsection (a), including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5CCAB46F24CD46CE9F212DE8E306B4BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a comprehensive research plan, which prioritizes fibrosis opportunities that have cross-cutting value and require coordination across multiple Institutes and Centers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE08378CB6E7A495C922278E067CA6FC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>topic-specific research recommendations for each organ or system as impacted by fibrotic diseases described in subsection (a); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2EDA27529F7404C8B5CC7C20AC11505"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an overview of common themes and specific steps for implementation.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H681214F1367144E9810980482117E314"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To make recommendations, as appropriate, to the Director of NIH and Congress with respect to the study, evaluation, and long-range plan described in the preceding paragraphs of this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80F9032542334486877AFFAC115D664A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Operating plan</header><text>Not later than 90 days after its first meeting, the Commission shall submit to the Director of NIH and the Congress an operating plan for carrying out the duties of the Commission as described in subsection (c). Such operating plan may include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H41FB0D319611447EA2AF8998600A74CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of specific activities that the Commission plans to conduct for purposes of carrying out the duties described in each of the paragraphs in subsection (c);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H796A02AAC9DD45F185FC7B427B79B810"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a plan for completing the activities;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H331172E585BC43B285FA199B3CCFDDF8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a list of members of the Commission and other individuals who are not members of the Commission who will need to be involved to conduct such activities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B5111DDD5BC410AA5CEA38FF49F3179"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an explanation of NIH Institute and Center involvement and coordination needed to conduct such activities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CA33DCB183944A484268020C5702AA3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a budget for conducting such activities; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD0C29AD15955477D97CC73BADFF533DC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>other information that the Commission deems appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB1DD3FBDD005405F87881875B17C091A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the Commission’s first meeting, the Commission shall submit to the Director of NIH and the Congress a final report containing all of the findings and recommendation required by subsection (c).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE45DA8F1DEB64A5F81F8F98001A5581C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The Commission shall terminate 60 days after submitting its final report, but not later than September 30, 2022.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


