<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6C11392E46D64736A5AC24BBA2E1E4E4" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3493 IH: Care Corps Demonstration Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3493</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170727">July 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize grants for local care corps programs through
			 which qualified volunteers provide care, companionship, and other services
			 to seniors and individuals in need, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF20A38C66548454089108017A67C7522" style="OLC">
 <section id="H70A1819EB7A6472A8F3AF4AB89FC794E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Care Corps Demonstration Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDDA58AA6638546578A3BCF48B8787321"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for local care corps programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254b">42 U.S.C. 254b</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0A23000266984BCF9BBE1FC6D694BA43"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating the second subpart XI (relating to a community-based collaborative care network program) as subpart XII;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC68B4C5872D42CBB6427D40D48BF563"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating the second section 340H (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/256i">42 U.S.C. 256i</external-xref>) as section 340I; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H83E8E1E7475149169DE75D083C1F442F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H040EA9FE20DF4841A53E9A51479C2AF8" style="OLC">
					<subpart id="HEA9B2E6C25F64F2F80339E42964A167F"><enum>XIII</enum><header>Local care corps programs</header>
						<section id="H21683A09DC3844BFB300B4611F2C581A"><enum>340J.</enum><header>Grants for local care corps programs</header>
 <subsection id="H2BE2B1F132EA472CAAF294FCC1889CBB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award grants to eligible entities described in subsection (b) to establish and implement a local care corps program through which eligible volunteers described in subsection (c) perform approved care services described in subsection (d).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB18FA1BAB5EB46A6B1AD36433675708D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall be a public or private nonprofit entity that is—</text>
 <paragraph id="H38EA05ED13A743969998D6300C63374E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>part of an aging network, as defined in section 102(5) of the Older Americans Act of 1965;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0630B63A8B34192A517C22C74A1D2B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a time-banking or volunteer organizing agency that has expertise in delivering home- and community-based long-term services and supports to older adults and people with disabilities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B95EE158858422D82E62E21D33EC15B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a State, county, or local government; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA9E73F31F8CE45D4B61744E7EBA312BA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other entity that has expertise in delivering home- and community-based long-term services and supports to older adults and people with disabilities, as determined to be appropriate by the Secretary.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H723DE2CDAA3B42F99B56E93AD5007782"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible volunteers</header>
 <paragraph id="HE52AFDA851864DF0BF3369A301C636C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligibility criteria</header><text>To be eligible to serve as a volunteer in a local care corps program funded through a grant under this section, an individual shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H33823F0A7B6C43C4A998000842F63926"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be at least 18 years of age on or before December 31 of the calendar year in which the individual begins participation in the program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87D0E918B3A64447B4B54E09F613221B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>agree to participate in the program for a period of not more than 24 months, consisting of not more than 2 terms of up to 12 months;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CCF97308384420ABDAFE01C55B8A6B6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>submit an application to the grantee at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the grantee may require;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE1B8126ED844D68A3D8B30E30A84B1B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>pass a criminal background check as described in paragraph (2); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09DECE1F099A4E418C33402E4DB55DFF"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agree to comply with such terms and conditions as the grantee may require.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8C4104E40A849B6A41A849FF0CF9A14"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criminal background check</header>
 <subparagraph id="H5591AF2152D546D6A141E402A50FC491"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before selecting any individual to serve as a volunteer in a local care corps program funded through a grant under this section, the grantee shall request a criminal background check of such individual on a nationwide basis.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E8DA5F1ADB444DDAD873192FCC8D7A4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Volunteer prohibitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual shall be ineligible to be a volunteer in such program if—</text> <clause id="HDBE5398DD82544578C04E246FCB8BE1E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the individual refuses to consent to the criminal background check; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9DEDF050F19241558FF60B395A4B5DE7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the criminal background check does not demonstrate to the grantee’s satisfaction that the individual is fit for service in such program.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA33F8B7DD82841B390BDB12E9E2ACEF3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Approved care services</header>
 <paragraph id="HAB837EF00A5F4EED90EA8E47FEFDC69A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out a local care corps program funded through a grant under this section, the grantee shall assign volunteers only for providing services—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8E5940CE878F4AB98B451D72AE0E1DC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that are approved care services described in paragraph (2); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EA25526FA17459CAEF80671C87BC2D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">within one or more populations that—</text>
 <clause id="H06E9D92CBCC54FC3B35B0D6949B4A014"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have a shortage of such approved care services; or</text> </clause><clause id="H2F83905F91A54FD48148D8D565AF0FCC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consist primarily of low-income or minority individuals.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D37F87A6ABA4EE88E5B45BA47EE60E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approved care services</header><text>Approved care services are services provided directly to individuals in need (as defined in paragraph (5)) in home-based or community-based settings that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB24F338D262943BCB4104810EE657ED1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">result in person-to-person, supportive relationships with each individual served;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E78404BA725421D9B9FBA5BA631137F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support the achievement and maintenance of the highest level of independent living for each individual in need;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD48EA3ABEEC4AB8954457FCE043DD41"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are supported by appropriate orientation, training, and supervision; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8ABDB91D3D6C40AFA537F3D944743B7E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are provided in support of, or in coordination with, a caregiver, if applicable.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5D95E7716CA48C6A20FF3F0F2F01816"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibited Services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In performing duties as part of a local care corps program funded through a grant under this section, no volunteer shall provide—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFFE8F2C0300646269C805C953A0E80F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>professional medical services;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8377E7F558234D939F097EC7977C3FBC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>administrative support services of the program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB4FCEA264FA4E328726D51B9E552635"><enum>(C)</enum><text>care in an institutional setting;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H997CE342B0C34420B92D90A2CD40D893"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">care prohibited under State law;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5F9CA18B14D4229AAB36BFF767922BE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>financial services; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF25AC70F0CA84DD98CD73CBEB5C456D3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other services determined by the Secretary to be inconsistent with the purposes of local care corps programs funded under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6ED3326F85984B1E893D38261A1A6B77"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Guidance regarding scope of services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue guidance describing the scope of services that may be provided by volunteers as part of a local care corps program funded through a grant under this section. In issuing such guidance, the Director shall provide for a public notice and comment period of not less than 60 days before issuing the guidance in final form.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA3C51339E2D4A0FA3D75CBF83FFF520"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Individual in need</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>individual in need</term> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="H7D7E0FB653504B949AC2881F10F45B06"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is at least 65 years of age or has a disability as defined in section 3 of the Americans With Disabilities Act of 1990;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAD2BD5FF14F47E89775B6254B246D64"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has difficulty with self-care or living independently; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA01C2999F3D74FCDACCBEC2A6916008C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meets such other criteria as the grantee determines to be appropriate.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA697FDF7D5794A6AA4D1F85CAD4EF9EA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Training and standards of conduct</header>
 <paragraph id="HD20E5EF3ACEE4510933940E486B33EC2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pre-assignment training program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition on receipt of a grant for a local care corps program under this section, an eligible entity shall agree to develop a training program that provides volunteers in such program with instruction in the skills necessary to carry out an assignment in the program. Such training shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HACF178D9D04D45489CC3EF48DC2D5C0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at least 40 hours of instruction for each volunteer for each term (of 12 months or less) to be served in such program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B8A9B2FFE824533A440BEEBEB1F10CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">additional training for volunteers whose assignment requires further instruction; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07BCB435F83D4237B228AFC13D4DB956"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other training the grantee determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0771AF2C363B444294CF77CE1D61FD91"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Standards of Conduct</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition on receipt of a grant for a local care corps program under this section, an eligible entity shall agree to establish and enforce standards to promote proper conduct and discipline within such program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0BF745EC06754C339AB264DECF4C1A4F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorized benefits for volunteers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition on receipt of a grant for a local care corps program under this section, an eligible entity shall agree to the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2072D56F5910482782EE4D5D00E05A0A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The eligible entity will provide for volunteers participating in the program to receive allowances, health insurance, and post-service educational awards, in accordance with this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A1697575B2F4CBEB138FCA6F8F2DCB3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allowances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The eligible entity will provide for each volunteer to receive such living, travel, and leave allowances, and such housing, transportation, supplies, equipment, and subsistence as the eligible entity determines to be necessary for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H326286506BD84C778FD911FA20DD7BF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the volunteer’s maintenance; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H887B1EEE4EAD43788C38FF54FE94A0E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to ensure the volunteer’s health and capacity to serve effectively.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H97554315761543FC9B3D988E9C024318"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Health insurance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The eligible entity will provide for each volunteer to receive health insurance coverage meeting the requirements of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5000A">section 5000A(f)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="HF67EA1D1B5B74CB59647A362AAC05B4B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Post-Service Educational Award</header>
 <subparagraph id="HAA700C65A379473B8D627D43D721C371"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The eligible entity will establish an educational award for volunteers.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AFF15BEDBB44B82ABC8EA01A1F8E03B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amounts</header> <clause id="HEAA5BB8381814363BC1B160448869ABB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Number of awards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A volunteer may receive up to 2 educational awards under this subsection, one for each term of service as a volunteer.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7449BB18871345B6B7FC743464515E9D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amount for full term of service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a volunteer who completes a term of full-time service in the program for a period of 12 months, as determined by the eligible entity, such volunteer shall receive an educational award having a value of $6,000 for the award year.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HF716A4C460C644E4A64326EB92991120"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Incentive To pursue a health care profession</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a volunteer who commits to using an educational award (or awards, if applicable) under this subsection for completion of a degree, a certificate, or training in a health care profession, or in a social services profession related to the delivery of long-term services and supports to older adults and people with disabilities or to their caregivers, the value of such awards shall be $10,000 for the award year.</text>
										</clause><clause id="H906545B4E39644A5B4A33C7EB0741A5A"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Amount for Other Periods of Service</header>
 <subclause id="H58069B8885D241EAA9A4B403234D1F5C"><enum>(I)</enum><header>First 12 months</header><text>In the case of a volunteer who completes less than a 12-month term of full-time service in the program, as determined by the eligible entity, such volunteer may receive a portion of the educational award described in clause (ii) or (iii) (as applicable) that corresponds to the quantity of service actually completed by the volunteer.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H998308A18E8F447F94660009021E7034"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Second 12 months</header><text>In the case of a volunteer who completes more than 12 months of full-time service in the program, and less than 24 months of such service, as determined by the eligible entity, such volunteer may receive, for the portion of service exceeding 12 months, a portion of the educational award described in clause (ii) or (iii) (as applicable) that corresponds to the quantity of service actually completed by the volunteer.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93A602A163E340D3B5A047331BA29A6A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Uses of Award</header><text>An educational award under this subsection shall be used to pay—</text> <clause id="H735DD14F75354207B5F45BABFB6ABDB9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>costs of attendance at an institution of higher education; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5A3B2088509E468499440CA8298F5E22"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">government or commercial loans received by an individual for the cost of attendance at an institution of higher education.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4CBBC4D3597404A9C8B4EE55E9A8F5E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph:</text> <clause id="HFFE8DA5C8FD9475EAC88E752F83E625F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cost of attendance</term> has the meaning given such term by section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD6F7587B239F4B1E8F4C2697C851E099"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term under subsection (a) or (b) of section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDE1F13A402924BA9952F6ED9594DD2A9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Application process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To seek a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall—</text> <paragraph id="H844B6AA0AF78402A9197F7AD97AB53BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information and assurances as the Secretary may require; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7A49A6C0A204B38AEFD98317371DA2A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include in such application a description of the scope of the services proposed to be provided through the entity’s local care corps program.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B3A5271007B43688F027B41F861DBAA"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="H3DB9E63BA07D4036BDAE49A402CDD958"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports to Secretary</header><text>As a condition of receipt of a grant under this section for a local care corps program, an eligible entity shall agree to submit annual reports to the Secretary including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE93EFCDA1387485F8C1558EEAB4EFF5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the population served by the eligible entity through the grant during the preceding fiscal year, including—</text>
 <clause id="H00E8F68B47AF425698E6C7D73B6A7976"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an estimate of the number of individuals served, disaggregated by race, ethnicity, age, socioeconomic status, and disability status; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2B4EEB37C0594D988D88509BD68F9BDC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identification of the type of settings in which the services were provided;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8990186A07E44EC9A71F0CCA145F24F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an evaluation of program operations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4FFCF39479D4793907D75033D178586"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations, if any, for improving programs funded under this section.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2BDA7743D5A4E70B0D88019F5AC8483"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than the end of fiscal year 2021, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Congress on local care corps programs funded under this section, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFD082A0ED8144819A67E34BE9D1CE6C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>summaries of the information submitted to the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (1); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41F52F51EEF445BB91E16BBD25853276"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations, if any, for improving programs funded under this section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAEF3576C3A7D4B83A71E550665D267CC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section></subpart><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


