<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4A16285FE7084185A32DF487E6DF0961" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1386 IH: To direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish a pilot program to assess the operational benefits of remote air traffic control towers, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1386</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170307">March 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish a pilot program to assess the operational
			 benefits of remote air traffic control towers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7B11035D61224E799CE4C945875D28C6" style="OLC">
		<section id="HC7B679A148AA4C45BB1FA6E11E990A0F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Remote tower pilot program for rural or small communities</header>
 <subsection id="HC06CD4D0B6DE4657BB2A471AA7360DDB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall establish a pilot program under which, upon approval of an application submitted by an operator of a public-use airport, the Secretary shall install and operate at the airport a remote air traffic control tower in order to assess the operational benefits of remote air traffic control towers.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1AA4175E37A740B8B7C19F37D8E97D08"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>The operator of an airport seeking to participate in the pilot program shall submit to the Secretary for approval an application that is in such form and contains such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H8C9EB3E61A044DC5B39B7B98314D3969"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header>
 <paragraph id="H76105EB213AB4F81815EAFDE6513F70D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Selection of airports</header><text>From among the applications submitted under subsection (b), the Secretary, after consultation with representatives of labor organizations representing operators and employees of the air traffic control system, shall select for participation in the pilot program 7 airports as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEA5AC7DC6BA34FA881ABBA3F3E0B578B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>One nonhub, primary airport.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H367D5948DD4D4175BC520CEA9BC7AEB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Three nonprimary airports without existing air traffic control towers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H719EE777260F42939327C325D30F8699"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Two airports with air traffic control towers participating in a program established under section 47124 of title 49, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H728DEAC12B7744329216AD19EBF2D0D8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>One airport selected at the discretion of the Secretary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFCFA79D2E8444E28A8E2D1EC33EFB94"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority selection</header><text>In selecting from among the applications submitted under subsection (b), the Secretary shall give priority to applicants that can best demonstrate the capabilities and potential of remote air traffic control towers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H660AA2DF9F424662A14542138D8441F9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority to reallocate airport selection</header><text>If the Secretary receives an insufficient number of applications, the Secretary may reallocate the distribution of airport sites described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H469F4345911C43D4A8596BD23ED5F204"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Multiple remote facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If practicable and necessary, the 3 remote air traffic control towers installed at nonprimary airports pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) may co-locate remote facilities to assess the benefits and efficiencies of consolidating such facilities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDB855EB4858F4A72A7508E0988D7FF9B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Asset classification</header><text>A remote air traffic control tower, including ancillary equipment, installed with Government funds pursuant to this section shall be considered to be an air navigation facility.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H0D2403201DA747EA96D54D8B9165B5E0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Safety risk management panel</header>
 <paragraph id="H8ED7A0C2C38E4736B9090701786605F2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Safety risk management panel meeting</header><text>Prior to the operational use of a remote air traffic control tower, the Secretary shall convene a safety risk management panel for the tower to address any safety issues with respect to the tower.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF0B857478B2042EAB257F8AD2EFB3C41"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Safety risk management panel best practices</header><text>The safety risk management panels shall be created and utilized in a manner similar to that of safety risk management panels previously established for remote air traffic control towers, taking into account best practices that have been developed.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB0802B2686174675AF9160B443A07973"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header>
 <paragraph id="H38E7F3324731416CA4FE7C95299D744D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text> <subparagraph id="H3C1CB488DBCF41C49D7C8F85DF4C5287"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Air navigation facility</header><text>The term <quote>air navigation facility</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 40102(a) of title 49, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12370EBB36FA40A2896C76E86FA8F0BF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Remote air traffic control tower</header><text>The term <quote>remote air traffic control tower</quote> means a remotely operated air navigation facility, including all necessary system components, that provides the functions and capabilities of an air traffic control tower.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H181F4286571C4DEB865E1106078CC124"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability of other definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the terms <quote>nonhub airport</quote>, <quote>primary airport</quote>, <quote>public-use airport</quote>, and <quote>reliever airport</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 47102 of title 49, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63AAA86219B8478EA1F8B2F07B3BCA10"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The pilot program shall terminate on the day that is 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


