<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H14CF827ACA8C4EBDA38246C7F1535EE6" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2725 IH: Student Loan Lower Interest Rate and Lower Monthly Payment Refinancing Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2725</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000592">Mr. Rokita</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for the refinancing of certain Federal student
			 loans.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H22BB5B7B4CAC41AB9B4EBCAB55C8FACF" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1F81D9FBDED149029D2F1935D6443959" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Student Loan Lower Interest Rate and Lower Monthly Payment Refinancing Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7BC8EACBFE6F4F09A49EEAE2B8CAE3F8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Refinancing program</header> <subsection id="H6D42C7EF942848F9A10971B41014D471"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authority</header><text>Part C of title I of the Higher Education Act of 1965 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HFB8EC565904C4B77A47903FB298836DE" style="OLC">
					<section id="H7A38E31097964245A900B3259FBFA3DF"><enum>138A.</enum><header>Refinancing certain Federal student loans</header>
 <subsection id="HA45DF06E5A7B479DA46B33C6E07CCBC4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To enable State, private and nonprofit lenders to make loans at lower market-based variable interest rates to all eligible borrowers for the purpose of refinancing existing student loan debt incurred pursuant to parts B, D, and E, of title IV, there are hereby made available, in accordance with the provisions of this title and title IV, such sums as may be necessary to insure a portion of each loan, as set forth in this part, and to otherwise make payments consistent with the terms in this part.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H010CCA9AB7984D54AB8AD42982F33D5B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Discrimination by creditors prohibited</header><text>No agency, organization, institution, bank, credit union, corporation, or other lender who regularly extends, renews, or continues credit or provides insurance under this part shall exclude from receipt or deny the benefits of, or discriminate against any borrower or applicant in obtaining, such credit or insurance on the basis of race, national origin, religion, sex, marital status, age, or handicapped status.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H2C8E5C4CD1CA4116B40067A050AE0E20"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Designation</header>
 <paragraph id="H7BA7928590E74FC787632C5A1D2F47A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The program established under this part shall be referred to as the <quote>Student Loan Lower Interest Rate and Lower Monthly Payment Refinancing Program</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4D6106A644BC481AB80F4C204A7CCB0C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Refinancing loans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this part, loans made to borrowers under this part that, except as otherwise specified in this part, have the same terms, conditions, and benefits as loans made to borrowers under section 428C, shall be known as <quote>Refinancing Loans</quote>.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1EC063CB68C54AD99BE0C73ACA9B3900"><enum>138B.</enum><header>Refinancing certain Federal student loans</header>
 <subsection id="HC694EBEAE2BD4F698803B73E5C97F4FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the Student Loan Lower Interest Rate and Lower Monthly Payment Refinancing Act, the Secretary shall establish a process under which eligible lenders may receive loan insurance from the Secretary for the purpose of extending, upon the receipt of an application from an eligible borrower, a loan to refinance one or more eligible loans, in accordance with the provisions of this section.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="HFDBE6769BD8B4806A5BFCC4745A734DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header>
 <paragraph id="H16A963662E604753A43383014A859E3E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition of eligible borrower</header><text>For the purpose of this section, the term <term>eligible borrower</term> means a borrower who—</text> <subparagraph id="HB878D50F59F54B9E909620F7F68DE124"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has one or more eligible loans;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5F66F5BF876470C93683F15C0DB19F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not subject to a judgment secured through litigation with respect to a loan under this title or to an order for wage garnishment under section 488A; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFD75F7FB47243AA9B6566D95625516D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>at the time of application for a Refinancing Loan—</text> <clause id="H81B37D8DFE09420CB0CF884F42356F59"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is in repayment status as determined under section 428(b)(7)(A);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H55B71FF954134F03A5CFF6961EB975DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is in a grace period preceding repayment; or</text> </clause><clause id="H811024EA426545DDA4FBA0856CB9C385"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is a defaulted borrower who has made arrangements to repay the obligation on the defaulted loans satisfactory to the holders of the defaulted loans.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H55C3132B0645484883BD5C7A99E51056"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>An individual’s status as an eligible borrower under this section terminates upon receipt of a Refinancing Loan under this section, except that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBBC7BE220F2B47CFA32618809D99C6E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual who receives eligible loans after the date of receipt of the Refinancing loan may receive a subsequent Refinancing Loan;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA443507AFE954B18B7A5255C411B5D2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>eligible loans received prior to the date of a Refinancing Loan may be added during the 180-day period following the making of the Refinancing Loan;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECD091283F5A41299ED7FB3BF8A3EF5A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>eligible loans received following the making of the Refinancing Loan may be added during the 180-day period following the making of the Refinancing Loan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5588EC773A244D8A0537EF634F1EF7C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>eligible loans received prior to the date of the first Refinancing Loan may be added to a subsequent Refinancing Loan.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H809C9F2CCC8844DEABE82408B12DC2B6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible lenders</header><text>Entities eligible to make Refinancing Loans, and receive default insurance from the Secretary, shall be either—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H55178F69E5C74125861E556259E8579D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State agencies described in subparagraphs (D) and (F) of section 435(d)(1);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE2DF037E0EC45FD8EB95DC7706A871B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other eligible lenders described in subparagraphs (A) and (J) of such section, which made or held loans prior to July 1, 2010; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BFBD069D840439F922A495B439231B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other entity that prior to July 1, 2010, made or held a loan as a beneficiary of an eligible lender trustee agreement under part B of title IV.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H337040DC756A47F1A8A02B6F6ED4CE82"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible loans</header><text>For the purposes of this section, <quote>eligible loans</quote> shall include any loan made, insured or guaranteed under parts B, D, and E of title IV.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B1D191DD534430C96E4352C6408EAB9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Refinancing eligible loans</header><text>Upon application of an eligible borrower, an eligible lender shall repay directly to the existing holder of each of that eligible borrower’s eligible loans with the proceeds of a Refinancing Loan in an amount equal to the sum of the unpaid principal, accrued unpaid interest, and late charges of the original eligible loans in order to discharge the eligible borrower from any remaining obligation to the existing holder with respect to the original eligible loans.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H9A4AF974E56E46EDB2946E6C35BFF64C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interest rates</header>
 <paragraph id="H4C8626AAE7F1401E9E05F195282B4DEA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the current interest rates of the eligible loans being refinanced, the interest rate for the Refinancing Loan, shall be a variable rate equal to no more than—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H69B4956748F0422BB973BF621CDFD925"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the calendar quarter beginning on July 1, 2015, and each subsequent calendar quarter, the daily average of 1-month London Inter Bank Offered Rate (LIBOR) for United States dollars in effect for each of the days in the prior calendar quarter as compiled and released by the British Bankers Association, plus</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E8BBD95C0D34346B137DF2D3F53B6EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>3.5 percent per annum.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DCD67131A634B4DB830C858E00F755C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adjustable rate</header><text>The applicable rate of interest determined under paragraph (1) for a Refinancing Loan under this section shall adjust on the first day of each calendar quarter for the period of the loan.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC43D31D371FD4A5795831E1CC340AE66"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Insurance</header>
 <paragraph id="HE16450E5E2E44D6A82C4FD9E2912426A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Default insurance</header><text>The Secretary shall provide default insurance on Refinancing Loans and shall upon presentment with a defaulted Refinancing Loan shall pay an amount, as set for below, to the eligible lender in exchange for all rights, title and interest to the Refinancing Loan.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H828B2EF5263F47E89531DB08DD506F5A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Default</header>
 <subparagraph id="HAC71A6B29A73415AB7FB253E6BE25E18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Refinancing Loan is in default and eligible for an insurance payment, if the Refinancing Loan has, experienced at least 270 consecutive days of nonpayment; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FC3196051214DE1A17E1C126CF004C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such state of nonpayment is not caused by application of a deferment or forbearance as described in section 435.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB0282F744E144998937696B3862F9409"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Phase-out of default insurance coverage</header><text>To the extent an eligible lender provides the Secretary with a defaulted eligible loan, the Secretary shall pay to the eligible lender an amount equal to—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H1A84F916CB644DB09FF8EAFD4ECC4CD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for a default occurring in the first 5 years from the date of disbursement of the Refinancing Loan made, the Secretary shall insure 97 percent of the unpaid principal and accrued interest and fees;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD0360A4661464DA9BE2660DDA54F1B67"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a default occurring in the second 5 years (years 6 through 10) from the date of disbursement of the Refinancing Loan, the Secretary shall insure 87 percent of the unpaid principal and accrued interest and fees; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9C3CC0637CAC491BBD99B38E4394241F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a default occurring at any point after the tenth year after disbursement of the Refinancing Loan, the Secretary shall insure 77 percent of the unpaid principal and accrued interest.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0506D263F59749429D3DEB209DDA569B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Insurance fees paid to the secretary</header><text>In lieu of any other fees or charges by the Secretary associated with loans under this part, eligible lenders shall pay to the Secretary—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF4534B23D2AC4018894ED73EF227ECE2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a Default Insurance Fee equal to 0.50 percent of the disbursed loan amount; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1F3465CC9DF49B3A8C2C926DC53305D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a Monthly Insurance Fee payable each month calculated on annual basis equal to 1.05 percent of the average principal plus accrued unpaid interest for the prior month of the Refinancing Loans disbursed under this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAFDBF09396DD4F84A2EE396EDC6E9D7F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>No special allowance</header><text>No special allowance under section 438 shall be paid with respect to the portion of any Refinancing Loan.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H33E14E1D4B744067A5F678309DA38FC2"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Terms and conditions of refinancing loans</header>
 <paragraph id="HBEA8B40AB56A456D9F4F4CB0E0EB0661"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A Refinancing Loan made under this section shall have the same terms and conditions as the loans authorized under section 455, except as otherwise provided in this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H745CF3A81D5F419E87D97D8B87919D5D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No automatic extension of repayment period</header><text>Refinancing a loan under this section may, at the behest of the eligible borrower, result in the extension of the duration of the repayment period of the loan. In addition, a borrower may, at the time of making the Refinancing Loan, enroll in any repayment plan for which the eligible borrower is eligible in accordance with section 455(d)(3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H535B143C2144477FA8B4E1608E807413"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Borrower benefits</header><text>Eligible lenders may offer any borrower benefits, including interest rate and principal reductions as desirable in connection with Refinancing Loans. In addition to such benefits, and any other benefits required of Consolidation loans authorized under section 455—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2E196FCEF1924F5388A4EC51B7575B68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Refinancing Loans may, to the extent offered under the Direct Loan Program, also offer—</text> <clause id="H1976C5F1D2424F1DB865DBA528DA8444"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an income contingent repayment plan;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H09D6ED3681AF45DE9F074D8ACDFD9D5C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an income-based repayment plan;</text> </clause><clause id="H9994D653AED54A9DBC8346533230EE73"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a Pay As You Earn (PAYE) Repayment Plan; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF32FBFD5B054490C9A0D24A95D3EFE7B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the public service loan forgiveness program under section 455(m); and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D588D8368C043F6A8A6E34B5AD7C72D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Refinancing Loans shall, to the extent offered under the Direct Loan Program, also offer—</text>
 <clause id="H87F97C781C394EABA51E4ADCCA47AC92"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the benefit for active duty service members benefit offered under section 455(o);</text> </clause><clause id="H35AA09A5666F4E96977412169FACB6A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>deferment as provided for in section 435;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC6D6B9A1F46F4BCCAB7A6CC41946C739"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>forbearance as provided for in section 435; and</text> </clause><clause id="H9512983915634C8EA97CA9F294078FC2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>discharge for disability or death of the borrower.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A631F70B7A0404D9481D005CD42B2E1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Loan discharge</header><text>In the case of loans discharged under income contingent repayment, income-based repayment, or public service loan forgiveness, or for disability or death of the borrower, the Secretary shall, upon such discharge, pay to the eligible lender an amount equal to the unpaid principal and accrued interest.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HF2922D2EE1D44C54B2167B5121E7F17C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H13F4BCBDE47E4DADB603148E8BC0E9AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Part B</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 428C(a)(3)(B)(i) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1078-3">20 U.S.C. 1078–3(a)(3)(B)(i)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H06D8CABAC2B0472AAEBAFDE44D1044F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subclause (I)—</text> <clause id="H4B776C816C4A4711ACE47754518A16B9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, section 138A,</quote> after <quote>An individual’s status as an eligible borrower under this section</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCD170E119157476F87945EE46DE7E5A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>both sections</quote> and inserting <quote>each such section</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H61DB134F8CE442198287AD2BF1EC08D4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, a Refinancing Loan under section 138A,</quote> after <quote>upon receipt of a consolidation loan under this section</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BA80FB8CFC04482B670F1F3E9BD9675"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subclause (III), by striking the semicolon and inserting <quote>; and</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3476CDA67EF040A8948FF6AC3E1AF657"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subclause (IV), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a period; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08F4189B9AA748F9997B8EB7969C90C6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking subclause (V).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B3107B2201A44A0B5F790786A950613"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Part D</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 455 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5FFEB1E5F0C7483BB781A413917B420D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H49ABD83EC50C4C5FB90149854B6BF6B8" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H732FF71F70A6427693499804A48E24FA"><enum>(4)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB766486862E944B995974DAC3EF7EABC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Consolidation of Refinancing Loans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provisions of this part, eligible borrowers may consolidate Refinancing Loans authorized under section 138A into a Direct Consolidation Loan in the event that the interest rate on each such Refinancing Loan exceeds 6.875 percent for the quarter.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6F04B6FEF2644C98F9D3DDB8958AF73" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligibility period</header><text>Any application for a Consolidation Loan that includes Refinancing Loans under this paragraph must be received by the Secretary by the end of a quarter during which the Refinancing Loan interest exceeds 6.875 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53744EBAE1054544A0D862A73A935D52"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67AD0567055A46AC833CA00F83FBB78D" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HB315FEC7D16343A29DAF3AD2CFE94101"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Repayment terms for federal family education loans</header> <paragraph id="H47EEF350DAB9482E9A06C3F2125FF1EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicability of programs available under this section</header><text>The Secretary shall apply subsections (d), (e), (f), (l), (m), and (o) to all loans made under part B as if such loans were made under this part.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1122796CDDF2485FA6703D60C721448A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment of balance and interest</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall pay to the holder of a loan made under part B the amount of principal, interest, or special allowance payments necessary to apply subsections (d), (e), (f), (l), (m), and (o) to such loan, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H72317892EC9547C59ADF296CE81121F7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Offset</header>
 <subsection id="H3F68676F9BA34EE587420631268E0AF4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public service loan forgiveness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 455(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H0F7969EC04884C029737A53D2A2188D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in paragraph (2)(B), the Secretary</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF2559C795F9E4A2F8EB15FA829329845"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="H9B1E664695C5417EB697194D97EE73B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>After the</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91369C3A77AA4F48B1399D147C3A5A3C" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H6179AF2DBEB84948AC47B0489120406E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), after the</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF049B9930FB74B148F8899B719E376C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding after subparagraph (A) the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H723B5787AFA7470C9E7A2AD11EB1595F" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H5FB3A5C6EEA742FAA20D56F536299E32"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Cap on loan cancellation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any eligible Federal Direct Loans made to a new borrower on or after July 1, 2017, the Secretary may cancel, in accordance with subparagraph (A), up to $57,500 of the obligation on such loans.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB677921C201046A5A857538DAC78EB89"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Income-Based repayment</header><text>Section 493C of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1098e">20 U.S.C. 1098e</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7A2CD6F36B8404CAB022ACEBAB19B67" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HD0C7B6F8B6314B6BBF9F7E727DA8EE02"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Special terms for new borrowers On and after July 1, 2017</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (e)(2) shall not apply with respect to any loan made to a new borrower on or after July 1, 2017, for enrollment in a graduate or professional program.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


