<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H49536F850BF04675BC46A9726AC03F4A" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1677 IH: Caesar Syria Civilian Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1677</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170322">March 22, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. McMorris Rodgers</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To halt the wholesale slaughter of the Syrian people, encourage a negotiated political settlement,
			 and hold Syrian human rights abusers accountable for their crimes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H1111C085EC654384ACDE9460CAC2894F" style="OLC">
		<section id="H481BCCF1C0114002A7030F7BD93FFB27" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title and table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="HC4F1662F59FC4D3784B4010D42A654B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Caesar Syria Civilian Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H5376519137754F638015435103359D0D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H481BCCF1C0114002A7030F7BD93FFB27" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8FD9DA5B2ABD4B75BCB762DE4FBC8E0A" level="section">Sec. 2. Sense of Congress.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H49742A569A6A40ED95D90B35189FB3F4" level="section">Sec. 3. Statement of policy.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5A90F77DD84C4B29BE386DFC1433E634" level="title">Title I—Additional actions in connection with the national emergency with respect to Syria</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H97FE0A838A4A4C87B553706794DE5822" level="section">Sec. 101. Sanctions with respect to Central Bank of Syria and foreign persons that engage in
			 certain transactions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H549B7DC293AF4F8B9B2F27315B97B0C5" level="section">Sec. 102. Prohibitions with respect to the transfer of arms and related materials to Syria.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H20189BC16EE14572B4C3D39E9286957B" level="section">Sec. 103. Rule of construction.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H35D45C5C01CC4A2BB051B11544B01FF7" level="section">Sec. 104. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HEF69DEC7AA4B494CA438F18CF180BE92" level="title">Title II—Amendments to Syria Human Rights Accountability Act of 2012</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H9D8FA9E78A7E4ABF89942FC7573C74CE" level="section">Sec. 201. Imposition of sanctions with respect to certain persons who are responsible for or
			 complicit in human rights abuses committed against citizens of Syria or
			 their family members.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H3D68E203821C4FD7867FA75E5ECAACF1" level="section">Sec. 202. Imposition of sanctions with respect to the transfer of goods or technologies to Syria
			 that are likely to be used to commit human rights abuses.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF29E77FE96B44452AA6251C684A2D07B" level="section">Sec. 203. Imposition of sanctions with respect to persons who hinder humanitarian access.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA131DD50251A45449D577596850A6434" level="section">Sec. 204. Report on certain persons who are responsible for or complicit in certain human rights
			 violations in Syria.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA962744E775646FB8065A26CC8D1F6FD" level="title">Title III—Reports and waiver for humanitarian-related activities with respect to Syria</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HFF29F03C2A064639882A5512B77C30C3" level="section">Sec. 301. Report on monitoring and evaluating of ongoing assistance programs in Syria and to the
			 Syrian people.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H13A0A0D63EE24518A39955B9B01DE409" level="section">Sec. 302. Assessment of potential methods to enhance the protection of civilians.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD553D78C637449AA921E1563C682793B" level="section">Sec. 303. Assistance to advance a comprehensive relief and recovery strategy in Syria.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBE4AB8839A344045A7CE2DB1CF136245" level="section">Sec. 304. Assistance to support entities taking actions relating to gathering evidence for
			 investigations into war crimes or crimes against humanity in Syria since
			 March 2011.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H62192F1444AA481F80C1FFC79A45BC26" level="title">Title IV—Suspension of sanctions with respect to Syria </toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H7A054F435CA9413F9DED403FAD73620E" level="section">Sec. 401. Suspension of sanctions with respect to Syria.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H6670CE5B93C2408097892D3D0E5ADA5E" level="section">Sec. 402. Waivers and exemptions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5E44215E8B6D4621A1F0D3EB46E44E26" level="title">Title V—Regulatory authority, cost limitation, and sunset</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H591195A7A3124001A8A2C99BAE632BFC" level="section">Sec. 501. Regulatory authority.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H84F21B353DB044ECA96C03034B16E367" level="section">Sec. 502. Cost limitation.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD058BD9F5D724ABC93E05296BB7C7CD5" level="section">Sec. 503. Authority to consolidate reports.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBB6AD10E3E3E4D5C8958D1BEBAC46106" level="section">Sec. 504. Sunset.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="H8FD9DA5B2ABD4B75BCB762DE4FBC8E0A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HDD68AF279D434219BAC69835A0E60EE9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Bashar al-Assad’s murderous actions against the people of Syria have directly contributed to the deaths of more than 480,000 civilians, led to the destruction of more than 50 percent of Syria’s critical infrastructure, and forced the displacement of more than 14,000,000 people, precipitating one of the worst humanitarian crises in more than 60 years;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE19907EFDBE44C45B0292A04D8CAD48C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">international actions to protect vulnerable populations from attack by uniformed and irregular forces associated with the Assad regime, including Hezbollah, on land and by air, including through the use of barrel bombs, chemical weapons, mass starvation, industrial-scale torture and execution of political dissidents, sniper attacks against pregnant women, and the deliberate targeting of medical facilities, schools, residential areas, and community gathering places, including markets, have been insufficient to date;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F6168F715D04B1783D69E2F17F26D69"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assad’s use of chemical weapons, including chlorine, against the Syrian people violates the Chemical Weapons Convention;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFC02C7F443494B5E9077CCBFA3555D09"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">violent attacks resulting in death, injury, imprisonment or threat of prosecution against humanitarian aid workers and diplomatic personnel, as well as attacks on humanitarian supplies, facilities, transports, and assets, and acts to impede the access and secure movement of all humanitarian personnel are in violation of international humanitarian law and impede the lifesaving work of humanitarian organizations and diplomatic institutions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E3959DA4E3246B9BD2E97E3104C6E2A"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assad’s continued claim of leadership and war crimes in Syria have served as a rallying point for the extremist ideology of the Islamic State, Jabhat al-Nusra, and other terrorist organizations.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H49742A569A6A40ED95D90B35189FB3F4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States that all diplomatic and coercive economic means should be utilized to compel the government of Bashar al-Assad to immediately halt the wholesale slaughter of the Syrian people and to support an immediate transition to a democratic government in Syria that respects the rule of law, human rights, and peaceful co-existence with its neighbors.</text>
		</section><title id="H5A90F77DD84C4B29BE386DFC1433E634"><enum>I</enum><header>Additional actions in connection with the national emergency with respect to Syria</header>
			<section id="H97FE0A838A4A4C87B553706794DE5822"><enum>101.</enum><header>Sanctions with respect to Central Bank of Syria and foreign persons that engage in certain
			 transactions</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H4B93D710E40E42ACBD25A213B056F542"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Application of certain measures to Central Bank of Syria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsections (a) and (b) of section 402, the President shall apply the measures described in section 5318A(b)(5) of title 31, United States Code, to the Central Bank of Syria.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="HBF3A735014314AC893287D6935A429AD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Blocking property of foreign persons that engage in certain transactions</header>
 <paragraph id="H3A902D7056044F56AD16EE0ED2DFEC7D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on and after the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall impose on a foreign person the sanctions described in subsection (c) if the President determines that such foreign person has, on or after such date of enactment, knowingly engaged in an activity described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA51638E843349AB97434E9F97AA6289"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities described</header><text>A foreign person engages in an activity described in this paragraph if the foreign person—</text> <subparagraph id="H0C6482A3840548F9BC8D0CEA87B83E51"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knowingly provided significant financial, material or technological support to (including engaging in or facilitating a significant transaction or transactions with) or provided significant financial services for—</text>
 <clause id="H53648D3CA976449D85ED37C41E3F58BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Government of Syria (including Syria’s intelligence and security services or its armed forces or government entities operating as a business enterprise) and the Central Bank of Syria, or any of its agents or affiliates; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H25E1A41850AF4FFDBAD335CE6AA34E13"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a foreign person subject to sanctions pursuant to—</text> <subclause id="H5F0E8850D81A4CAFB855411C5583A631"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) with respect to Syria or any other provision of law that imposes sanctions with respect to Syria; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA1F12934E05846EDB7DC22F5C91D35CF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a resolution that is agreed to by the United Nations Security Council that imposes sanctions with respect to Syria;</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CA80E3CE3BC4B5DA61CFA4DD67BFB41"><enum>(B)</enum><text>knowingly—</text> <clause id="H7E5670F9B8FF44B0A8E571FD178133E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sold or provided significant goods, services, technology, information, or other support that could directly and significantly facilitate the maintenance or expansion of Syria’s domestic production of natural gas or petroleum or petroleum products of Syrian origin in areas controlled by the Government of Syria;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H961A117C5F6E4D73B57911ACF6FB778E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>sold or provided to Syria crude oil or condensate, refined petroleum products, liquefied natural gas, or petrochemical products that have a fair market value of $500,000 or more or that during a 12-month period have an aggregate fair market value of $2,000,000 or more in areas controlled by the Government of Syria;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBAC438F8ECC44508A2CCB82AF57DD841"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sold or provided civilian aircraft or spare parts, or provides significant goods, services, or technologies associated with the operation of aircraft or airlines to any foreign person operating in areas controlled by the Government of Syria; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1CD275E4EB2B484AABFCCB2CDB336E8A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sold or provided significant goods, services, or technology to a foreign person operating in the shipping (including ports and free trade zones), transportation, or telecommunications sectors in areas controlled by the Government of Syria;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H840CCB03520F4AC1A428569E798A0B16"><enum>(C)</enum><text>knowingly facilitated efforts by a foreign person to carry out an activity described in subparagraph (A) or (B);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A4213325DE94D92996516965F79B037"><enum>(D)</enum><text>knowingly provided loans, credits, including export credits, or financing to carry out an activity described in subparagraph (A) or (B); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3755477EB7154BE8898F46B9A991292A"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is owned or controlled by a foreign person that engaged in the activities described in subparagraphs (A) through (C).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA559141479F548B8A8475B55707C916B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sanctions against a foreign person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sanctions to be imposed on a foreign person described in subsection (b) are the following:</text> <paragraph id="HA76AECDC8DFF4619A47BB02B582A190C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall exercise all powers granted by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) (except that the requirements of section 202 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>) shall not apply) to the extent necessary to freeze and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H650A0F3000E74C2493121428C030ACD6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aliens ineligible for visas, admission, or parole</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE92B150CC58340428B1E48D9557227C0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien who the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) knows, or has reason to believe, meets any of the criteria described in subsection (a) is—</text>
 <clause id="H121775B1261145D59CDFF671DE2F1C01"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text> </clause><clause id="H791FA62DFD4342D3A2D94EAD5B63F86F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2B32E126C5D34696ABC40185D776195A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B93ED408038404CB1F3504E825B30D6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header>
 <clause id="H927A1E8EB1D446F5AB5BF2E1E5B88F16"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) shall revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien who meets any of the criteria described in subsection (a) regardless of when issued.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H49616401E0B64BCC8106D38C38278A25"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under clause (i)—</text> <subclause id="HE3EC0E9D3FDE4D9C9CDE343FC61CA4FE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall take effect immediately; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HBD8CBBD18DCE404C9F5DD7B79C9CCBD3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7711FDF9A9546EEA0AB2534902F1EAC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception to comply with United Nations Headquarters Agreement</header><text>Sanctions under paragraph (2) shall not apply to an alien if admitting the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F40AEBF7367482E93B933ABF6D30CDB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that knowingly violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations promulgated under section 501(a) to carry out paragraph (1) of this subsection to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that knowingly commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of that Act.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H549B7DC293AF4F8B9B2F27315B97B0C5"><enum>102.</enum><header>Prohibitions with respect to the transfer of arms and related materials to Syria</header>
				<subsection id="HC87846042E094A6880325D0C8F011CD4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sanctions</header>
 <paragraph id="HBC0CC3AB50754F89922266A931AAFDE8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on and after the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall impose on a foreign person the sanctions described in subsection (b) if the President determines that such foreign person has, on or after such date of enactment, knowingly exported, transferred, or provided significant financial, material, or technological support to the Government of Syria to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4CEE194761714A5D82B104C0FE261C07"><enum>(A)</enum><text>acquire or develop chemical, biological, or nuclear weapons or related technologies;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7B625D1D8FF4FAF81A3C2559AAB1876"><enum>(B)</enum><text>acquire or develop ballistic or cruise missile capabilities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD72DD55F8BB04AABAA4D82615CE29A35"><enum>(C)</enum><text>acquire or develop destabilizing numbers and types of advanced conventional weapons;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB699E6D2745D4B2BA4EED520BB4B216E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acquire defense articles, defense services, or defense information (as such terms are defined under the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2751">22 U.S.C. 2751</external-xref> et seq.)); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC15F7815AE44E81B1798E4784C4AB62"><enum>(E)</enum><text>acquire items designated by the President for purposes of the United States Munitions List under section 38(a)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2778">22 U.S.C. 2778(a)(1)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF360BAF737F4CE4B79B6348925181E6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability to other foreign persons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sanctions described in subsection (b) shall also be imposed on any foreign person that—</text> <subparagraph id="HDED5CAD9468146D4B1CEF3753FFC430E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a successor entity to a foreign person described in paragraph (1); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67E9C79697EC4059B7F227F6A16223F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is owned or controlled by a foreign person described in paragraph (1).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2620AB0AD5A346E8AA4EF055CDF5E5E4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions against a foreign person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sanctions to be imposed on a foreign person described in subsection (a) are the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA563C8BEBB894670B39C908A857BF559"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall exercise all powers granted by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) (except that the requirements of section 202 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>) shall not apply) to the extent necessary to freeze and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HF5AEDB9205314591A6108BC93F4B5158"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aliens ineligible for visas, admission, or parole</header>
 <subparagraph id="H14CB72EBEC494BE198BCB408D0345E1B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien who the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) knows, or has reason to believe, meets any of the criteria described in subsection (a) is—</text>
 <clause id="HA9253E63C425475CB7184CCEA8EEFB6F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text> </clause><clause id="HE55DE52857DD47F8B0BB95BD08FAAD9E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H29ACF182024340FF83556F75B1F12DDC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF350C16686E4F8E9DECB18F9634977D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header>
 <clause id="HDEC2A0FC2CA343CF91395E67B48B3A3B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) shall revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien who meets any of the criteria described in subsection (a) regardless of when issued.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H475FB232CDC5416384C53A8FBD166257"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under clause (i)—</text> <subclause id="H5AD99E97FD6640EA9C2D12BD56EF76C0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall take effect immediately; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC66BBAECB0654EA480FEB5A22845C758"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H924418AFAACE41DDA06FDA68575F268D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception to comply with United Nations Headquarters Agreement</header><text>Sanctions under paragraph (2) shall not apply to an alien if admitting the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H86A77217969647349A31306AF8CC5EEF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out this section shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H20189BC16EE14572B4C3D39E9286957B"><enum>103.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The sanctions that are required to be imposed under this title are in addition to other similar or related sanctions that are required to be imposed under any other provision of law.</text>
 </section><section commented="no" id="H35D45C5C01CC4A2BB051B11544B01FF7"><enum>104.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H2D5B895EA58E4381A64809A53CF7BE5D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admitted; alien</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>admitted</term> and <term>alien</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9597873195624FE7A9531199AF8439C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Financial, material, or technological support</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>financial, material, or technological support</term> has the meaning given such term in section 542.304 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section was in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCABCC3A84FEF4E51BEE8F8FC5A2957C0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>foreign person</term> means any citizen or national of a foreign country, or any entity not organized solely under the laws of the United States or existing solely in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2E2E02FA276949599B139E638461F333"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Government of Syria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Government of Syria</term> has the meaning given such term in section 542.305 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section was in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9F38D3C3F4D74C0589811268873B481E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>knowingly</term> has the meaning given such term in section 566.312 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section was in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7C7AB7698304E28A1198D26D23F9A9E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means an individual or entity.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCDD4A0D6B95F410DB17EE227C439EC9A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Petroleum or petroleum products of Syrian origin</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>petroleum or petroleum products of Syrian origin</term> has the meaning given such term in section 542.314 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section was in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCDBFCD5F127441F2ADBB1CAEC8570A84"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Significant transaction or transactions; significant financial services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A transaction or transactions or financial services shall be determined to be a significant for purposes of this section in accordance with section 566.404 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section was in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF5D4DDA641184CC79C248B4C2AC7BD08"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Syria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Syria</term> has the meaning given such term in section 542.316 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section was in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE1BD934295014ADF9CAFEBC55A2B0F25"><enum>(10)</enum><header>United States person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>United States person</term> means any United States citizen, permanent resident alien, entity organized under the laws of the United States (including foreign branches), or any person in the United States.</text>
				</paragraph></section></title><title id="HEF69DEC7AA4B494CA438F18CF180BE92"><enum>II</enum><header>Amendments to Syria Human Rights Accountability Act of 2012</header>
			<section id="H9D8FA9E78A7E4ABF89942FC7573C74CE"><enum>201.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to certain persons who are responsible for or complicit in
			 human rights abuses committed against citizens of Syria or their family
			 members</header>
 <subsection id="H8991B27904F14DE38A2EBC98AD9CF15C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 702(c) of the Syria Human Rights Accountability Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8791">22 U.S.C. 8791(c)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA97135C7A03F458AB24F535C6F8F058B" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="H26A3F808A4EE4185BF2978ADD1668AE3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header>
 <paragraph id="HC6A25DCE9E654AACB7E4CE77BEED4160"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall exercise all powers granted by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) (except that the requirements of section 202 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>) shall not apply) to the extent necessary to freeze and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of a person on the list required by subsection (b) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H39724254079F4A14B1204E67045349AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aliens ineligible for visas, admission, or parole</header>
 <subparagraph id="H906F03E85CC3465EBEBCF88DE395C01F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien who the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) knows, or has reason to believe, meets any of the criteria described in subsection (b) is—</text>
 <clause id="H98726A2C5C0843D6925F2256D9B9F6F4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text> </clause><clause id="H8B69CB78FE8B467FB615D5CD36D89860"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H65514CAB4F2347349F5442D5CB859608"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC417FCE80A44906B58F5EED87F02ADC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header>
 <clause id="H36A6D33662E64470BDD6A2A33AF1A01F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) shall revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien who meets any of the criteria described in subsection (b) regardless of when issued.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDF95F27316804D6FB4A26C0BC586F274"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under clause (i)—</text> <subclause id="H32AA374DCAAC4CF7A8FF5485F6A9B82B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall take effect immediately; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H56216D7B11E24AC8BF2C0B85788CD3DA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H152D01D70F694288B481ADD7E6E78EA4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this section or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out this section shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3695E9CC8AA14953ABA0A2450608092F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text>The President shall, not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, promulgate regulations as necessary for the implementation of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H246FD4DDB5AC4567979A29DAD76E6623"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Exception to comply with United Nations Headquarters Agreement</header><text>Sanctions under paragraph (2) shall not apply to an alien if admitting the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4EB7AD695CF412B8845808BE0DBF5A0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the President to impose additional sanctions pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.), relevant Executive orders, regulations, or other provisions of law.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7284EE1EB484461BB010388C1B8C1AB2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Serious human rights abuses described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 702 of the Syria Human Rights Accountability Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8791">22 U.S.C. 8791</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF661043957E84C7397789F27D76E0FC7" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H44251DC4B197475ABB89332ED6282B67"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Serious human rights abuses described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In subsection (b), the term <term>serious human rights abuses</term> includes—</text> <paragraph id="H390D1734A15E4E9186CFD790983F10B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the deliberate targeting of civilian infrastructure to include schools, hospitals, markets, and other infrastructure that is essential to human life, such as power and water systems; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0994D5572FC542F1AFA7EFD63F84D61F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the deliberate diversion, hindering, or blocking of access for humanitarian purposes, including access across conflict lines and borders.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5E4960BAEB5F4BD48369AFF08E450EF7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply with respect to the imposition of sanctions under section 702(a) of the Syria Human Rights Accountability Act of 2012 on after such date of enactment.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H3D68E203821C4FD7867FA75E5ECAACF1"><enum>202.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to the transfer of goods or technologies to Syria that are
 likely to be used to commit human rights abuses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 703(b)(2)(C) of the Syria Human Rights Accountability Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8792">22 U.S.C. 8792(b)(2)(C)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7937CF6BF0594297906D3AE2B800BC4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H115AC5FE312C4D9AB6C70F54AAF89A45"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C790FCB3AE64E6398ED671C5A45E6C8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E836FDF33734F8B81BCADB363D27F8B" style="OLC"> <clause id="HBEC3C6BEFD434B2A827856238EB2103F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any article designated by the President for purposes of the United States Munitions List under section 38(a)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2778">22 U.S.C. 2778(a)(1)</external-xref>); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCA7F9E1B9FCE4621AA024EBF4795E1C4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other goods or technologies that the President determines may be used by the Government of Syria to commit human rights abuses against the people of Syria.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HF29E77FE96B44452AA6251C684A2D07B"><enum>203.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to persons who hinder humanitarian access</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Syria Human Rights Accountability Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8791">22 U.S.C. 8791</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H218A5503B7F4436B9DA78CA07FF21934"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating sections 705 and 706 as sections 706 and 707, respectively;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H150961399116403487BFD570BEEC8717"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 704 the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A255797A614437E9C4736B3B5DEE953" style="OLC"> <section id="HD440D887359E40D4B7971C25DED0AA75"><enum>705.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to persons who hinder humanitarian access</header> <subsection id="H8691EF8AF3894385AA0A0E94145F33CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall impose sanctions described in section 702(c) with respect to each person on the list required by subsection (b).</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H907823BA1A63484A85361E7424E8300E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>List of persons who hinder humanitarian access</header>
 <paragraph id="HD39B474064684BE6A9084177F42FBFF0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of the Caesar Syria Civilian Protection Act of 2017, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a list of persons that the President determines have engaged in deliberate diversion, hindering, or blocking of access for humanitarian purposes for the United Nations, its specialized agencies and implementing partners, national and international nongovernmental organizations, and all other actors engaged in humanitarian relief activities in Syria, including through the deliberate targeting of such humanitarian actors and activities in Syria and across conflict lines and borders.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF95D533C25B4471C8A9F0FAF3969641D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates of list</header><text>The President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an updated list under paragraph (1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE541F9D7C0B84DE79E8BB3F13EC2CF11"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 300 days after the date of the enactment of the Caesar Syria Civilian Protection Act of 2017 and every 180 days thereafter; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F49FE476B464A2D93248B0B6E2CBE6B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as new information becomes available.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0003C152F1664CF29A0AB376DE925304"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form of report; public availability</header> <subparagraph id="H7E127D47A7414C7380BD89E213384BBC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The list required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F83FAA1525A4FB6AF375DC7EB062E91"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The unclassified portion of the list required by paragraph (1) shall be made available to the public and posted on the Web sites of the Department of the Treasury and the Department of State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3013E3C15A874EC88C9EAE0350ABEF1F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 706 (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>or 704</quote> and inserting <quote>704, or 705</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="HA131DD50251A45449D577596850A6434"><enum>204.</enum><header>Report on certain persons who are responsible for or complicit in certain human rights violations in Syria</header> <subsection commented="no" id="HB430992E113A4DDE83EDDB9DA2FB4884"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a detailed report with respect to whether each person described in subsection (c) is a person that meets the requirements described in section 702(b) of the Syria Human Rights Accountability Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8791">22 U.S.C. 8791(b)</external-xref>) for purposes of inclusion on the list of persons who are responsible for or complicit in certain human rights abuses under such section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3FDAC76156BB4A69BBD65A0D0F1115B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Justification</header><text>The President shall include in the report required by subsection (a) a description of the reasons why any of the individuals described in subsection (c) do not meet the requirements described in section 702(b) of the Syria Human Rights Accountability Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8791">22 U.S.C. 8791(b)</external-xref>), including information on whether sufficient credible evidence of responsibility for such abuses was found.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H1DCD2F0DB89E42D6B51D9413145F8A9A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Persons described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The persons described in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph id="HC7B4B27777094EAB96731A79AB5504DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Bashar Al-Assad.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7B76F679BD7143F2AC8630EB4F76265C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Asthma Al-Assad.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB85CFAC895548848E329A7F84BD7A68"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Rami Makhlouf.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA16B31C438D494480D2FF77F5F9E2CC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Bouthayna Shaaban.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H82532E1563964B6B9EF191199EDF4A33"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Walid Moallem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7A64E84381A4E3EA5DFCAA49AC58B34"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Ali Al-Salim.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H67CBA89019FA49B1BD12A51462D47DF8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Wael Nader Al-Halqi.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0AF0409F0EBB4BB0AE4DFF43C82A2FF8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Jamil Hassan.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4482532C69B240AAAC8D50931AA49977"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Suhail Hassan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8C82DAA0BA141A1A3D2159301AE1B1F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Ali Mamluk.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H704C460D5AE04C80BAC598572BD9EC4B"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Muhammed Khadour, Deir Ez Zor Military and Security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BBE42FA331F4AA79EC4AAC46EAA5965"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Jamal Razzouq, Security Branch 243.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9073DC3DF3CA4832819BAF44CA301030"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Munzer Ghanam, Air Force Intelligence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E7843118D0E43B58770E157C695E76C"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Daas Hasan Ali, Branch 327.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0AC9F2ED4273402C9A548CEBB9F06BB9"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Jassem Ali Jassem Hamad, Political Security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08AC9289694F4540A1F97B9C1CF010A3"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Samir Muhammad Youssef, Military Intelligence.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDAE6AF606E04285A46DE25A4AD9FC39"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Ali Ahmad Dayoub, Air Force Intelligence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF98CD1B6B1CE40B4BE7970799BFC93C1"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Khaled Muhsen Al-Halabi, Security Branch 335.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H579197747B5C4991B6831A60FE1C46DA"><enum>(19)</enum><text>Mahmoud Kahila, Political Security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H656E7B700D2B43719C125C340C7D3480"><enum>(20)</enum><text>Zuhair Ahmad Hamad, Provincial Security.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DD47DF344364440833E28A94AA4835C"><enum>(21)</enum><text>Wafiq Nasser, Security Branch 245.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HECD56C91615645F29F738F7DE19EA6F3"><enum>(22)</enum><text>Qussay Mayoub, Air Force Intelligence.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H867C0375663B4084859BF4EE7143050B"><enum>(23)</enum><text>Muhammad Ammar Sardini, Political Security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2CE5FC495EFA433DA47DAA92197C8121"><enum>(24)</enum><text>Fouad Hammouda, Military Security.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H840728C576EA475E84E86C3AEE61E94F"><enum>(25)</enum><text>Hasan Daaboul, Branch 261.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F3C9DC0F41C4910BD73843FDE0A8348"><enum>(26)</enum><text>Yahia Wahbi, Air Force Intelligence.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C9C88B406954AC4905EE83214017996"><enum>(27)</enum><text>Okab Saqer, Security Branch 318.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H563120844F3E405FA5587B4C26F558CA"><enum>(28)</enum><text>Husam Luqa, Political Security.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF33132321D54972AD6E03C6FFD70CCF"><enum>(29)</enum><text>Sami Al-Hasan, Security Branch 219.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBAF5BE2D62B948C08E26725242E3E45C"><enum>(30)</enum><text>Yassir Deeb, Political Security.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9BF79B4E5D20462F9CD97C88428B2D34"><enum>(31)</enum><text>Ibrahim Darwish, Security Branch 220.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H42248F3E675446409733898F5DBC9CCC"><enum>(32)</enum><text>Nasser Deeb, Political Security.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H757F6842ECAF4CB3AC1A3D1A29CE1F0C"><enum>(33)</enum><text>Abdullatif Al-Fahed, Security Branch 290.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DB7F40F3F2B4991B476E0C579953544"><enum>(34)</enum><text>Adeeb Namer Salamah, Air Force Intelligence.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD59500FE3F8C4D9E91E8F1BE46363567"><enum>(35)</enum><text>Akram Muhammed, State Security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE45B4A32B0AF4C8FAD36273AF6C4A7C2"><enum>(36)</enum><text>Reyad Abbas, Political Security.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CE4DF1EC38F4D61BA46852EBD99BD53"><enum>(37)</enum><text>Ali Abdullah Ayoub, Syrian Armed Forces.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB798AE9E59F40DDB79D48925AD3CAF7"><enum>(38)</enum><text>Fahd Jassem Al-Freij, Defense Ministry.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC8BE4C5C0E040359B027C0092D57B63"><enum>(39)</enum><text>Issam Halaq, Air Force.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE50292287144F4CBE47A113CB4916C2"><enum>(40)</enum><text>Ghassan Al-Abdullah, General Intelligence Directorate.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0D623FD52E8434E8C179820678347F3"><enum>(41)</enum><text>Maher Al-Assad, Republican Guard.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H90AA90B765564D638E3EFEBA2AB55F1E"><enum>(42)</enum><text>Fahad Al-Farouch.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7FB58CC6A7A1492495693B72018ECC9C"><enum>(43)</enum><text>Rafiq Shahada, Military Intelligence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAAB2423C0444E9680F7AE1596128754"><enum>(44)</enum><text>Loay Al-Ali, Military Intelligence.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFAEBB355096C4C71B8A36F763EEB2D98"><enum>(45)</enum><text>Nawfal Al-Husayn, Military Intelligence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H15F162BEA1DA45B5AC0AFAE797BCD1BE"><enum>(46)</enum><text>Muhammad Zamrini, Military Intelligence.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7B747F2B486B4203ABC4F85433CE7CA8"><enum>(47)</enum><text>Muhammad Mahallah, Military Intelligence.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC621580BFC0846EFB4448B70EA8D44D3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form of report; public availability</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HDBA3A80D7A90497E95B2FCC87E218ECC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The list required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex if necessary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H251BBBE16AFC449293AE0928A8F8018C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The unclassified portion of the list required by paragraph (1) shall be made available to the public and posted on the Web sites of the Department of the Treasury and the Department of State.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA89E90E01067424189410014034AC676"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H9576ACBB06314E0189045FDECE826850"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Ways and Means, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3CAB3913C32543A0B90F67AD1DD5B5A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="HA962744E775646FB8065A26CC8D1F6FD"><enum>III</enum><header>Reports and waiver for humanitarian-related activities with respect to Syria</header>
			<section id="HFF29F03C2A064639882A5512B77C30C3"><enum>301.</enum><header>Report on monitoring and evaluating of ongoing assistance programs in Syria and to the Syrian
			 people</header>
 <subsection id="H76ABE04ED56E47A9B0677487F4B9F1A3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on the monitoring and evaluation of ongoing assistance programs in Syria and for the Syrian people, including assistance provided through multilateral organizations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1B2657EDF5134A59A3F7F7125479D08B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H3AF356F1356948E8912C3EB12953EFA5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the specific project monitoring and evaluation plans, including measurable goals and performance metrics for assistance in Syria;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB94BC72324AE4B4E8750E3A942355692"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the memorandums of understanding entered into by the Department of State, the United States Agency for International Development, and their respective Inspectors General and the multilateral organizations through which United States assistance will be delivered that formalize requirements for the sharing of information between such entities for the conduct of audits, investigations, and evaluations; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEADEFA5F99B94DE38DD39C58386384D3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the major challenges to monitoring and evaluating such programs.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H13A0A0D63EE24518A39955B9B01DE409"><enum>302.</enum><header>Assessment of potential methods to enhance the protection of civilians</header> <subsection id="HE34D2AB8DEDF4943BB8C7EC22A9BDE5B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committee a report that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFA000254B85C4C2C87E80112D9CF4330"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assesses the potential effectiveness, risks, and operational requirements of the establishment and maintenance of a no-fly zone over part or all of Syria, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0A5685A086DE4BC8AA68C8EBDB62D237"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the operational and legal requirements for United States and coalition air power to establish a no-fly zone in Syria;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6B0D1B9ED574BBEA493B1648EE7A23B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the impact a no-fly zone in Syria would have on humanitarian and counterterrorism efforts in Syria and the surrounding region; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC9EE8428C5D4C1FA42F793CF4901A81"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the potential for force contributions from other countries to establish a no-fly zone in Syria;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA211E7041D48409CA66F664C364D0BA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assesses the potential effectiveness, risks, and operational requirements for the establishment of one or more safe zones in Syria for internally displaced persons or for the facilitation of humanitarian assistance, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H650529FC67AB4F8888D0CE855C6AFF99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the operational and legal requirements for United States and coalition forces to establish one or more safe zones in Syria;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D77B78020B24D1C8FF89340DE0AB731"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the impact one or more safe zones in Syria would have on humanitarian and counterterrorism efforts in Syria and the surrounding region; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2967824848834347959501EA3BD283EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the potential for contributions from other countries and vetted non-state actor partners to establish and maintain one or more safe zones in Syria; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D37BCA4569F413482160911DAD662C5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assesses the potential effectiveness, risks, and operational requirements of other non-military means to enhance the protection of civilians, especially civilians who are in besieged areas, trapped at borders, or internally displaced.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA388FBEFA44462BBDFF22E34C54F8E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex if necessary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE1C39A2645DA4F36A49641D5F1584940"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subsection (a) shall be informed by consultations with the Department of State, the United States Agency for International Development, the Department of Defense, and international and local organizations operating in Syria or in neighboring countries to alleviate the suffering of the Syrian people.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF8713E4979DE45A5A15E00B10A3BB9F0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H1D2A9E8D8BAE42CEB6E8DCB3FBA0C302"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H60F3E4436825489FB14FFBBBB91EEC2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD553D78C637449AA921E1563C682793B"><enum>303.</enum><header>Assistance to advance a comprehensive relief and recovery strategy in Syria</header> <subsection id="H2F84E33CF4884D28895B99677C433836"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6463A2BF10904FAC8B9754B6AC968065"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Government of Syria is in violation of numerous United Nations Security Council resolutions regarding the provision of humanitarian assistance to the people of Syria; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF6FFEBADDC2438EA37864460AA870E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Government of the Russian Federation, as a guarantor of prospective cessations of hostilities in Syria, is complicit in the humanitarian crisis in Syria due to its failure to enforce such United Nations Security Council resolutions.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA622BC5C80DE472391B3775D207F04F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization for assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President is authorized to provide assistance to advance a comprehensive relief and recovery strategy in Syria that includes the policy objectives described in subsection (c). The President shall coordinate the provision of assistance under this subsection with other donors, international organizations, international financial institutions, and international and local nongovernmental organizations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE9371B79C72D42EA9A4900007BCB6614"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Policy objectives described</header><text>The policy objectives described in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph id="HE53C89D69C1A4E0D91A7F256276131F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To meet immediate humanitarian needs in Syria and in neighboring countries hosting significant numbers of Syria refugees.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7686A35ED5C0463892B5C91A6ED42B66"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To support the peaceful resolution of the conflict and the establishment of an inclusive, democratic government in Syria that demonstrates respect for the rule of law, human rights, religious freedom, and peaceful co-existence with its neighbors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H935D99FE7EC54F6BA38D7F6F8C74F72D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To build the capacity of legitimate local councils and leaders inside Syria such that they may provide basic services in areas liberated from the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5C29DDC2BAFA4846A9962E71654FCC1B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To support the inclusion and participation of women, minorities, business leaders, civil society organizations, and traditional and religious leaders, including from religious minority groups, in peace processes and transitional governance arrangements in Syria.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC27FB24F3D146859BD78A49DC3B9DE0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To work to ensure that any transitional arrangements or future governments in Syria reflect commitments to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H79D288DF2EEE4C12A3D1129A1F4C8EAF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inclusive and representative democracy;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24021B44A3D24CB69F312708B1394D69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>open and transparent governance;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D518A2AC9C9469C993BFC4B42141ACE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>respect for the rule of law, human rights, and religious freedom;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85BD112A835D4EEA927EC2DB9DA291DF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>accountability and reconciliation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BFDCDE0D7D74D7A9F256672281D3C74"><enum>(E)</enum><text>ending the violence and supporting peace and security throughout the country;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD70A7CDCD9240ECA2B257C494E7CAB4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>stability and peaceful co-existence throughout the region; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H168C8B418D0D402DBD7D5AED3D8FEC3F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>relief, recovery, and reconstruction throughout the country, including the rehabilitation and reintegration of former combatants.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4065BD3C44AC4DF79A77F89310975B3B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To build the capacity of legitimate governing institutions following a democratic transition in Syria.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4150E242D22241C38D58F9276162351A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>To ensure that the Syria Reconstruction Trust Fund, a multi-donor trust fund established in 2013 to which the United States is a contributing member, continues to function as a suitable mechanism through which United States contributions can leverage the support of other donors for the delivery of essential services in Syria, particularly in areas liberated from the Assad regime or ISIS control, until such mechanism is no longer necessary or appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3DB8304C71CD4C379A70E56924CFB61E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination with other donor nations</header><text>The United States should work with other donor countries, on a bilateral and multilateral basis, to increase donor contributions to multilateral mechanisms that meet immediate humanitarian needs in Syria and accomplish the policy objectives described in subsection (c).</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HBE4AB8839A344045A7CE2DB1CF136245"><enum>304.</enum><header>Assistance to support entities taking actions relating to gathering evidence for investigations
			 into war crimes or crimes against humanity in Syria since March 2011</header>
 <subsection id="H3B16F69155F24C07A3B3F454DE6B1AB8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Democracy, Human Rights and Labor and the Assistant Secretary for International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs, is authorized to provide assistance to support entities that are conducting criminal investigations, building Syrian investigative capacity, supporting prosecutions in national courts, collecting evidence and preserving the chain of evidence for eventual prosecution against those who have committed war crimes or crimes against humanity in Syria, including the aiding and abetting of such crimes by foreign governments and organizations supporting the Government of Syria, since March 2011.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H18AC559CCCEE43F6945247CC79B1A8F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a detailed report on assistance provided under subsection (a).</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="H62192F1444AA481F80C1FFC79A45BC26"><enum>IV</enum><header>Suspension of sanctions with respect to Syria </header>
			<section id="H7A054F435CA9413F9DED403FAD73620E"><enum>401.</enum><header>Suspension of sanctions with respect to Syria</header>
				<subsection commented="no" id="H7BBF920308A34A7B9425208A9708082A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Suspension of sanctions</header>
 <paragraph id="HFA226D541F9340DFB84A0B277FB02646"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Negotiations not concluding in agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President determines that internationally recognized negotiations to resolve the violence in Syria have not concluded in an agreement or are likely not to conclude in an agreement, the President may suspend, as appropriate, in whole or in part, the imposition of sanctions otherwise required under this Act or any amendment made by this Act for a period not to exceed 120 days, and renewable for additional periods not to exceed 120 days, if the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees in writing a determination and certification that the Government of Syria has ended military attacks against and gross violations of the human rights of the Syrian people, specifically—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEF6C6F5AA624408FB6461CE00368BB02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the air space over Syria is no longer being utilized by the Government of Syria and associated forces to target civilian populations through the use of incendiary devices, including barrel bombs, chemical weapons, and conventional arms, including air-delivered missiles and explosives;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A52193434454C03A64AEE61406EA115"><enum>(B)</enum><text>areas besieged by the Assad regime and associated forces, including Hezbollah and irregular Iranian forces, are no longer cut off from international aid and have regular access to humanitarian assistance, freedom of travel, and medical care;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71DB37A4B97147DAA749E8EA7A66DFD2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Government of Syria is releasing all political prisoners forcibly held within the Assad regime prison system, including the facilities maintained by various security, intelligence, and military elements associated with the Government of Syria and allowed full access to the same facilities for investigations by appropriate international human rights organizations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FA1B2E80E2D406EB60AC9695BF4D5B6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the forces of the Government of Syria and associated forces, including Hezbollah, irregular Iranian forces, and Russian government air assets, are no longer engaged in deliberate targeting of medical facilities, schools, residential areas, and community gathering places, including markets, in flagrant violation of international norms.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A8BC6882DC74D21A5AA4036C3D8E814"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Negotiations concluding in agreement</header>
 <subparagraph id="H039EC0263ED54559BD03DEC302E78CAE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial suspension of sanctions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President determines that internationally recognized negotiations to resolve the violence in Syria have concluded in an agreement or are likely to conclude in an agreement, the President may suspend, as appropriate, in whole or in part, the imposition of sanctions otherwise required under this Act or any amendment made by this Act for a period not to exceed 120 days if the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees in writing a determination and certification that—</text>
 <clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F974B7E73B64FFCB7E17909438206D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case in which the negotiations are likely to conclude in an agreement—</text> <subclause id="HB605FA21B6AD4CC9A0F0978280F2010C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Government of Syria, the Syrian High Negotiations Committee or its successor, and appropriate international parties are participating in direct, face-to-face negotiations; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HDE960AB388B84698B469DD72AD885664"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the suspension of sanctions under this Act or any amendment made by this Act is essential to the advancement of such negotiations; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H2B5BA9EDEA59439296E2730107442376"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Government of Syria has demonstrated a commitment to a significant and substantial reduction in attacks on and violence against the Syrian people by the Government of Syria and associated forces.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71DC0D2A7C044A20A15D82AECEA7FFEB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Renewal of suspension of sanctions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may renew a suspension of sanctions under subparagraph (A) for additional periods not to exceed 120 days if, for each such additional period, the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees in writing a determination and certification that—</text>
 <clause id="HC5D45EA424AA4A3FA71A827397C69ACB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the conditions described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (A) are continuing to be met;</text> </clause><clause id="HA79479C5992E4EA9AECC5EE34F215FEE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the renewal of the suspension of sanctions is essential to implementing an agreement described in subparagraph (A) or making progress toward concluding an agreement described in subparagraph (A);</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H91274B1E9AE64C948D4806AD36F7F00F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Government of Syria and associated forces have ceased attacks against Syrian civilians; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HF57D8E2F6F144496AE3CD90954057A32"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Government of Syria has publically committed to negotiations for a transitional government in Syria and continues to demonstrate that commitment through sustained engagement in talks and substantive and verifiable progress towards the implementation of such an agreement.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0B29394D7DC4B26BE93CCC94B6D4391"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Briefing and reimposition of sanctions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3ED9BE4788A4498097C357814D40DD6E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees a determination and certification in the case of a renewal of suspension of sanctions under paragraph (2)(B), and every 30 days thereafter, the President shall provide a briefing to the appropriate congressional committees on the status and frequency of negotiations described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEEDDEE907D8D4337B7458D9BA7AF6576"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Re-imposition of sanctions</header><text>If the President provides a briefing to the appropriate congressional committees under subparagraph (A) with respect to which the President indicates a lapse in negotiations described in paragraph (2) for a period that equals or exceeds 90 days, the sanctions that were suspended under paragraph (2)(B) shall be re-imposed and any further suspension of such sanctions is prohibited.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4ADCD35EF33841988F4C3C1E7C1ADA15"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HDBFDE7A575854F3DA2CF90ACCB12200E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Ways and Means, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49F08458BBCD4D95BD357D49F12472D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0EE303B9F5A64DC0BA02D8C60AA03357"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress To be considered for determining a transitional government in Syria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that a transitional government in Syria is a government that—</text> <paragraph id="H24F077FDC93D45AE923A6CBEF08E5F72"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is taking verifiable steps to release all political prisoners and provided full access to Syrian prisons for investigations by appropriate international human rights organizations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD24640F5FEFB4AE08C6CC17E070FFA87"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is taking verifiable steps to remove former senior Syrian Government officials who are complicit in the conception, implementation, or cover up of war crimes, crimes against humanity, or human rights abuses from government positions and any person subject to sanctions under any provision of law;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9958C67988D843BA89C22FAE65388CD0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is in the process of organizing free and fair elections for a new government—</text> <subparagraph id="H249915AA58304B699ADDC64326687CB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to be held in a timely manner and scheduled while the suspension of sanctions or the renewal of the suspension of sanctions under this section is in effect; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5586818C86C4DF08605C54AD3EADD01"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to be conducted under the supervision of internationally recognized observers;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFACD23ACB33244FB8AA446040B995587"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is making tangible progress toward establishing an independent judiciary;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4796BB7B89B74096B5A4CAA46E646584"><enum>(5)</enum><text>is demonstrating respect for and compliance with internationally recognized human rights and basic freedoms as specified in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F19AE13381F4ABFABDE70B7127844E8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>is taking steps to verifiably fulfill its commitments under the Chemical Weapons Convention and the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons and is making tangible progress toward becoming a signatory to Convention on the Prohibition of the Development, Production and Stockpiling of Bacteriological (Biological) and Toxin Weapons and on their Destruction, entered into force March 26, 1975, and adhering to the Missile Technology Control Regime and other control lists, as necessary;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1159598DF8B43BB9EEEF00A0C84D067"><enum>(7)</enum><text>has halted the development and deployment of ballistic and cruise missiles; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9889B77432C54403BF6C3CC0DD0156D4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>is taking verifiable steps to remove from positions of authority within the intelligence and security services as well as the military those who were in a position of authority or responsibility during the conflict and who under the authority of their position were implicated in or implicit in the torture, extrajudicial killing, or execution of civilians, to include those who were involved in decisionmaking or execution of plans to use chemical weapons.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6670CE5B93C2408097892D3D0E5ADA5E"><enum>402.</enum><header>Waivers and exemptions</header>
 <subsection id="HB6ADACCBBC1B4EDCBB7AC3ED0BF8BDE9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text>The following activities and transactions shall be exempt from sanctions authorized under this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H64620757BF4D4D9995EC792F4A4ABB03"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091</external-xref> et seq.), or to any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DC51B29258445CF89F0037C0A1EC970"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any transaction necessary to comply with United States obligations under—</text> <subparagraph id="H53C3229058494C93ABE96FA6F9DBF708"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Agreement between the United Nations and the United States of America regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58A2D6BE6A454AC9A809E85A614588E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Convention on Consular Relations, done at Vienna April 24, 1963, and entered into force March 19, 1967.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD61ADE40B9CA4868975AE3841F85D759"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Humanitarian and democracy assistance waiver</header>
 <paragraph id="H31EFA9EFA8194022B672D66328D4D1EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be the policy of the United States to fully utilize the waiver authority under this subsection to ensure that adequate humanitarian relief or support for democracy promotion is provided to the Syrian people.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82E802DD3CCA450D90C3AFE1C1D9EEA5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (5), the President may waive, on a case-by-case basis, for a period not to exceed one year, and renewable for additional periods not to exceed one year, the application of sanctions authorized under this Act with respect to a person if the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees a written determination that the waiver is necessary for purposes of providing humanitarian assistance or support for democracy promotion to the people of Syria.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDD290C73EB364C4E9A78C5E7213CCF87"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Content of written determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A written determination submitted under paragraph (1) with respect to a waiver shall include a description of all notification and accountability controls that have been employed in order to ensure that the activities covered by the waiver are humanitarian assistance or support for democracy promotion and do not entail any activities in Syria or dealings with the Government of Syria not reasonably related to humanitarian assistance or support for democracy promotion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCA5510899382410D89DF6BF0167C8AC4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Clarification of permitted activities under waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may not impose sanctions authorized under this Act against a humanitarian organization for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9FF49F9FCBAC47D0A035BF4355A4062A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>engaging in a financial transaction relating to humanitarian assistance or for humanitarian purposes pursuant to a waiver issued under paragraph (1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC840798AEE4A43BF968AE995CCFDBFFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transporting goods or services that are necessary to carry out operations relating to humanitarian assistance or humanitarian purposes pursuant to such a waiver; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02844B80049C4B819AEE765CA091C7E6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>having incidental contact, in the course of providing humanitarian assistance or aid for humanitarian purposes pursuant to such a waiver, with individuals who are under the control of a foreign person subject to sanctions under this Act or any amendment made by this Act unless the organization or its officers, members, representatives or employees have engaged in (or the President knows or has reasonable ground to believe is engaged in or is likely to engage in) conduct described in section 212(a)(3)(B)(iv)(VI) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)(B)(iv)(VI)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3B3B251F85944D5AB41A4EF8ADA3A44"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Exception to waiver authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may not exercise the waiver authority under paragraph (2) with respect to a foreign person who has (or whose officers, members, representatives or employees have) engaged in (or the President knows or has reasonable ground to believe is engaged in or is likely to engage in) conduct described in section 212(a)(3)(B)(iv)(VI) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)(B)(iv)(VI)</external-xref>).</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H22E2FD1B8FF0437C8D64B25FEAE40880"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header>
 <paragraph id="H9CA15657BD6D44AC94E253AB18AABF29"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may, on a case-by-case basis and for periods not to exceed 120 days, waive the application of sanctions under this Act with respect to a foreign person if the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that such waiver is vital to the national security interests of the United States.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAD7763F9FF7B48DF94EBD6B81C9E5BFE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC91D529DD7614443AE3E855C59BBEC33"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Before waiver issued</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 days before the issuance of a waiver under paragraph (1) is to take effect, the President shall notify and brief the appropriate congressional committees on the status of the foreign person involvement in activities described in this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2288719DB0CE4FFCABE974BA686DDC2C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>After waiver issued</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the issuance of a waiver under paragraph (1), and every 120 days thereafter if the waiver remains in effect, the President shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on the status of the foreign person’s involvement in activities described in this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H638D812E6BB141BEB03E9E16F343347A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HCD46F9BD290E41B9B2CBECE33CD5CA78"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Ways and Means, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF19C239EF1A0423790BE26D50DAD0EAE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H42ED20D035B243DCAC3C5067CF661733"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Codification of certain services in support of nongovernmental organizations’ activities authorized</header>
 <paragraph id="HA5B4FA78117744FC949F1D17BDBF5590"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), section 542.516 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (relating to certain services in support of nongovernmental organizations’ activities authorized), as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act, shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3A8EDBB2C95645C3BFD3CA351BE47348"><enum>(A)</enum><text>remain in effect on and after such date of enactment; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C599FBBC2FB4573BACE0745303B35C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a nongovernmental organization that is authorized to export or reexport services to Syria under such section on the day before such date of enactment, shall apply to such organization on and after such date of enactment to the same extent and in the same manner as such section applied to such organization on the day before such date of enactment.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H519E7ACC80BE4B599B92771C90D00CB5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 542.516 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as codified under paragraph (1), shall not apply with respect to a foreign person who has (or whose officers, members, representatives or employees have) engaged in (or the President knows or has reasonable ground to believe is engaged in or is likely to engage in) conduct described in section 212(a)(3)(B)(iv)(VI) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)(B)(iv)(VI)</external-xref>).</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE4E6E9EFEDBA401EA8395DDFEB3B0650"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Strategy required</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H42CD3F91E7B944749BD1937D1B990090"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report containing a strategy to ensure that humanitarian organizations can access financial services to ensure the safe and timely delivery of assistance to communities in need in Syria.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H876AFABFBE71408B86648596BEF87C57"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration of data from other countries and nongovernmental organizations</header><text>In preparing the strategy required by paragraph (1), the President shall consider credible data already obtained by other countries and nongovernmental organizations, including organizations operating in Syria.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H248BC919D9DF44E0BF8EBDA26C9DC43C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The strategy required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H5E44215E8B6D4621A1F0D3EB46E44E26"><enum>V</enum><header>Regulatory authority, cost limitation, and sunset</header>
			<section id="H591195A7A3124001A8A2C99BAE632BFC"><enum>501.</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header>
 <subsection id="H33E5CFB086054B019BFBC8AD57651EF6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall, not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, promulgate regulations as necessary for the implementation of this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFF3AF995E12943859DE5C02F059573E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than 10 days before the promulgation of regulations under subsection (a), the President shall notify and provide to the appropriate congressional committees the proposed regulations and the provisions of this Act and the amendments made by this Act that the regulations are implementing.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6562501DF92740C7817528E5B01400AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="HA7BAACA8D0794A80B527EDB9B86C3BB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H73EAC669097E424AA1D9C23AE7A51660"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H84F21B353DB044ECA96C03034B16E367"><enum>502.</enum><header>Cost limitation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this Act and the amendments made by this Act. Such requirements shall be carried out using amounts otherwise authorized.</text>
 </section><section commented="no" id="HD058BD9F5D724ABC93E05296BB7C7CD5"><enum>503.</enum><header>Authority to consolidate reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any reports required to be submitted to the appropriate congressional committees under this Act or any amendment made by this Act that are subject to a deadline for submission consisting of the same unit of time may be consolidated into a single report that is submitted to appropriate congressional committees pursuant to such deadline. The consolidated reports must contain all information required under this Act or any amendment made by this Act, in addition to all other elements mandated by previous law.</text>
 </section><section id="HBB6AD10E3E3E4D5C8958D1BEBAC46106"><enum>504.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall cease to be effective beginning on December 31, 2021.</text> </section></title></legis-body> </bill> 

