<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE2084908D89B40F6894A22061AB6C667" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4125 IH: Comprehensive Student Achievement Information Act of 2017 </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4125</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171025">October 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000584">Mrs. Love</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for comprehensive student achievement
			 information.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9AEBA837CE234731AB2EC90E5559C8F0" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB4388E90B40E4745B8235A6A6160AA57" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Comprehensive Student Achievement Information Act of 2017 </short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H138A0791D9E5422EA8E98D9220B14971"><enum>2.</enum><header>Consumer information about completion or graduation times</header> <subsection id="H501C5A217F7448B28E0F1163C731DBE0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transparency in college tuition for consumers</header><text>Section 132(i)(1)(J) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1015a">20 U.S.C. 1015a(i)(1)(J)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H733B6EAF3904477EA834E4669B6329A7" style="OLC">
					<subparagraph id="HD460540821BB41108DC41C0094117514"><enum>(J)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7F4E2D70E0F6444CBFF0CD08161C432F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>For programs of study 4 years of length or longer—</text> <subclause id="H6E3C6623E0E54CDE82D46EC8244A770B" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the percentages of first-time, full-time, degree- or certificate-seeking undergraduate students enrolled at the institution who obtain a degree or certificate within each of the times for completion or graduation described in subclauses (I) through (III) of clause (ii);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFE5F5E3ECCD94385A91AA305337E09F5" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the percentages of first-time, part-time, degree- or certificate-seeking undergraduate students enrolled at the institution who obtain a degree or certificate within each of the times for completion or graduation described in subclauses (I) through (III) of clause (ii);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H52E4880E79654A9CBB9FAC2ACC743AF3" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the percentages of non-first time, full-time, degree- or certificate-seeking undergraduate students enrolled at the institution who obtain a degree or certificate within each of the times for completion or graduation described in subclauses (I) through (III) of clause (ii); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD2F9C51CA61F4E36A26ACC252D408715" indent="up1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the percentages of non-first-time, part-time, degree- or certificate-seeking undergraduate students enrolled at the institution who obtain a degree or certificate within each of the times for completion or graduation described in subclauses (I) through (III) of clause (ii).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H068CD5FC99CB41ABB2B5BED42F311EC9" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The times for completion or graduation described in clause (i) are—</text> <subclause id="H0061A7441B96443D9E66A894908E1987"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the normal time for completion of, or graduation from, the student’s program;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF9BB3B51388A40DCB8E2C6ABBA73B1E5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>150 percent of the normal time for completion of, or graduation from, the student’s program; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H1143FCBD679545BD882EEF9CC89E2133"><enum>(III)</enum><text>200 percent of the normal time for completion of, or graduation from, the student’s program.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H9C6A3816358B4121BC6354612F5174B2" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For programs of study less than 4 years—</text> <subclause id="H5C49AFD4A2434EF7B9F3739F15F0AB56"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the percentages of first-time, full-time, degree- or certificate-seeking undergraduate students enrolled at the institution who obtain a degree or certificate within each of the times for completion or graduation described in subclauses (I) through (IV) of clause (iv);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H20BF5A0FB9C54386BF913BC8E1F17442"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the percentages of first-time, part-time, degree- or certificate-seeking undergraduate students enrolled at the institution who obtain a degree or certificate within each of the times for completion or graduation described in subclauses (I) through (IV) of clause (iv);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8863BC4CECE046BEA2998CC2C9026F6B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the percentages of non-first-time, full-time, degree- or certificate-seeking undergraduate students enrolled at the institution who obtain a degree or certificate within each of the times for completion or graduation described in subclauses (I) through (IV) of clause (iv); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4DD56F372F564F3A89BB9D1E0AA41457"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the percentages of non-first-time, part-time, degree- or certificate-seeking undergraduate students enrolled at the institution who obtain a degree or certificate within each of the times for completion or graduation described in subclauses (I) through (IV) of clause (iv).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H8F78DBE120C3441A9A59A91713736D98" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The times for completion or graduation described in clause (iii) are—</text> <subclause id="H8AAA61EE05D24BC7ADADC7A761528DD5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the normal time for completion of, or graduation from, the student’s program;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA946FD3552D0469CBFB5F28B2CB8F8A1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>150 percent of the normal time for completion of, or graduation from, the student’s program;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HCFB355D9630C4ACAA7BDB2CC36BC457D"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">200 percent of the normal time for completion of, or graduation from, the student’s program; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB116CCA919D343A49DB83EACA13F4238"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>300 percent of the normal time for completion of, or graduation from, the student’s program.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HAE810CFE58C740489920BF86C70D3CF0" indent="up1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>In making publicly available the percentages described in this subparagraph, the Secretary shall display each percentage in a consistent manner and with equal visibility.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC1D15CCDBF2B4E248A03105632E875A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Institutional and financial assistance information for students</header><text>Section 485(a)(1)(L) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092">20 U.S.C. 1092(a)(1)(L)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5AF7D9CDE2654AB9A69CD88C2112A965" style="OLC">
 <subclause id="HC814B6BD9C984E04BD615CEE95E8F792"><enum>(L)</enum><text>the completion or graduation rates described in section 132(i)(1)(J);</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

