<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB12CB716559F4FD480C81DD8EA0AC101" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2167 IH: Acre In, Acre Out Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2167</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170426">April 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for no net increase in the total acreage of certain Federal land under the jurisdiction
			 of the Bureau of Land Management, the National Park Service, the United
			 States Fish and Wildlife Service, or the Forest Service, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H213430B9F29D401D9B70937CCE9AC1AA" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE9456F6F55DA475DAF639A91D3D0B666" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Acre In, Acre Out Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC0BF7F799D6A4942AED4EEA044EF3148" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>No net increase in certain Federal lands</header> <subsection id="H7E543B78B2CE461EB8D0B760ECC4B6E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For acquisition of land by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture that would result in a net increase of total land acreage under the jurisdiction of the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the Bureau of Land Management, or the Forest Service, the Secretary concerned shall offer for sale an equal number of acres of Federal land that is under the same jurisdictional status.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H65C68C050A234CFD8F6449FD50633BB5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to easements acquired—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HAC0ACF0908F84F7CA54B7004198885B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by the Secretary of the Interior to facilitate management of Federal lands; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCEFC7D0AAFCC4E778DB99CF0DB4EF82D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by the Secretary of Agriculture to facilitate management of Federal lands.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5DF826E33197437A93CAFC5FDE688FCC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consideration</header> <paragraph id="HD8ADD1EAA4C3473CACF9F85E267C6942"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Land sold pursuant to subsection (a) shall be offered for sale—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2D9E19B1FD59447682ADD0EE665D3038"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at fair market value (based on local comparable sales); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8F9AB8470AC43368F0BD592922D822C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at a price that is reduced by 10 percent each month if the land is not sold or under contract to be sold by the date that is 6 months after the land was first offered for sale.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2247DD87C7A9495C954E2EF0CE3533D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Time periods during which land is under contract for sale or withdrawn from the market shall not be counted for the purposes of price reduction under paragraph (1)(B).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE72BE86F24E4D63A860A0F8BECCD04C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Existing rights</header><text>The sale of Federal lands pursuant to this section shall be subject to valid existing rights.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H98C4934CF4B4418EB5187DAF1CD2B719"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale of lands</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All net proceeds from the sale of Federal lands pursuant to this section shall be deposited directly into the Treasury for reduction of the public debt.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


