<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2C81D106BCA84AF0AC17DEA93C87741D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4412 IH: To amend the Military Selective Service Act to provide that a registrant for selective service may indicate at the time of registration a desire to be classified as a conscientious objector.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4412</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171115">November 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Military Selective Service Act to provide that a registrant for selective service may
			 indicate at the time of registration a desire to be classified as a
			 conscientious objector.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB28ADF22B0E4492ABAA27BC867735C5E" style="OLC">
		<section id="H62F2A431E2AF472B8AF691ADD278BD2B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Authority of registrant for selective service to indicate at the time of registration a desire to
			 be classified as a conscientious objector</header>
 <subsection id="HBBBBFCDDA38F4E18A1F26A1C000BA9BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority and supporting statement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3 of the Military Selective Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3802">50 U.S.C. 3802</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E0D4156C7FA4E3ABDF5E5127F79CE96" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H23C1AD8EFC724FDB8A24D4F5E141AD17"><enum>(c)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2A91D78E03DF4FD2A47CF80019F21CC4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (a) shall authorize a person registering under this section to indicate at the time of registration that the person desires to be classified—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3DC062D4F63D484489B4E7557B9D1C9A" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as being conscientiously opposed (by reason of religious, ethical, or moral belief) to participation in combatant military training and service in the Armed Forces; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45991BBE6CDB444A9A34FC3FACDED8E5" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as being conscientiously opposed (by reason of religious, ethical, or moral belief) to participation in war in any form and to participation in both noncombatant and combatant military training and service in the Armed Forces.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1673C9479BDC4451BF830DF74FD3E1B0" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notice shall be provided on registration forms that the indication by a registrant under paragraph (1) of a desire to be classified in a manner described in such paragraph—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3E8223707AAF42B0B207A21399B280E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not binding on the United States; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FE883369A26441AB2E485EB89E6C983"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not assure that the registrant will be so classified pursuant to section 6(j).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F05C5D27E9D41B68958DFEED65F3E4D" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of Selective Service may allow a registrant under paragraph (1) who indicates a desire to be classified in a manner described in such paragraph to submit a written statement in support of such classification. The written statement shall be in any format that the Director determines appropriate. The Director shall take steps to ensure that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H140D557C03B04F51A7427982BFA3C65D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any such statement is included in the registrant’s record; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2FDF8E1561E4722A6814BF9F891651F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the receipt of such a statement is noted on any record of registration provided to the registrant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H46C5F7D8DBF9468093882A1E8712C699"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date and application of amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (c) of section 3 of the Military Selective Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3802">50 U.S.C. 3802</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a), shall apply to registrations under such section occurring after the end of the one-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


