<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5D09CB31D583405FAD2A44585A5E61DF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2986 IH: Good for the Gander Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2986</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170621">June 21, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to restrict Members of Congress who
			 represent a State with a premium age band waiver, approved under the
			 amendments made by the American Health Care Act of 2017, to the highest
			 age band premium for health insurance coverage that is available under the
			 waiver.</official-title></form>
 <legis-body id="H03DAB6ECCDC24CDDB814545E8BA991E1" style="OLC"><section id="id4F1A1187AE8A472C95DB4262CB7C80D4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Good for the Gander Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF94C59924B5646A5B54090E1C838E857" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restricting access of certain Members of Congress, who represent a State with an AHCA approved premium age band waiver to the highest age band premium for health insurance coverage available under the waiver</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1312(d)(3) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18032">42 U.S.C. 18032(d)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H61F75370E0BE4F7CAACB43CD9D77FAE1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)(i), by inserting <quote>except as provided in subparagraph (E),</quote> after <quote>Notwithstanding any other provision of law,</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD03C811C5CC5417D94C7756FC8FE68C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12A1B5B5AA7E4CEAB4349A5B901245C8" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H1639EC48D4A94E3EAA1F416FC1A4052C"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Limiting coverage of Members of Congress representing States with an AHCA age band waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State that has a waiver approved and in effect under section 2701(b) of the Public Health Service Act, as added by section 136(a) of the American Health Care Act of 2017, for the purpose described in paragraph (1)(A) of such section 2701(b) (relating to a selection of a larger age band for premiums), a Member of Congress who represents such State (or a district in the State)—</text>
 <clause id="HC0AEC65E5F724116A1A28B0D8915FFCA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not eligible, with respect to the Member’s services as a Member of Congress, to receive coverage under any health benefits plan under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, and is not eligible for any Government contribution under such chapter with respect to any health benefits plan (including health insurance coverage described in clause (ii)); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H109116C6CC3B47A59ADF4F54346ED43B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is eligible to enroll in health insurance coverage in the individual market in the State under this Act and under such waiver, <italic></italic>but only in such coverage (offered in the area in which the Member resides) with the highest age band premium for the coverage selected in such area at the time of enrollment (or reenrollment).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


