<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HEBB20560D0D848DFB472817934BF5568" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1770 IH: OPEN Government Data Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1770</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170329">March 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To expand the Government’s use and administration of data to facilitate transparency, effective
			 governance, and innovation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H03727A3B8C9D4E8F81C6C471D0BFC5A4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H95FF878C992A4ADC87075F6DEF03F2ED" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Open, Public, Electronic, and Necessary Government Data Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>OPEN Government Data Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3628AF6F38EA43EEBBC2177FFD3258E1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header> <subsection id="H5301DC7D55864F95945D6E341131879A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD894B536E744484A94F380A5CCCF2E8F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Federal Government data is a valuable national resource. Managing Federal Government data to make it open, available, discoverable, and usable to the general public, businesses, journalists, academics, and advocates promotes efficiency and effectiveness in Government, creates economic opportunities, promotes scientific discovery, and most importantly, strengthens our democracy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H168B1B983931435E999B9474CD6733EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Maximizing the usefulness of Federal Government data that is appropriate for release rests upon making it readily available, discoverable, and usable—in a word: open. Information presumptively should be available to the general public unless the Federal Government reasonably foresees that disclosure could harm a specific, articulable interest protected by law or the Federal Government is otherwise expressly prohibited from releasing such data due to statutory requirements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69FD8730917E446789443ED4EDD3E244"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government has the responsibility to be transparent and accountable to its citizens.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H571C23F6FEA7473E852298DF53B74DA8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Data controlled, collected, or created by the Federal Government should be originated, transmitted, and published in modern, open, and electronic format, to be as readily accessible as possible, consistent with data standards under this Act or otherwise permitted by law.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA314C8CEF5354CA6929A84708363FFE7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The effort to inventory Government data will have additional benefits, including identifying opportunities within agencies to reduce waste, increase efficiencies, and save taxpayer dollars. As such, this effort should involve many types of data, including data generated by applications, devices, networks, and equipment, which can be harnessed to improve operations, lower energy consumption, reduce costs, and strengthen security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H81F8B34D74D947E79D94EE3933293C88"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Communication, commerce, and data transcend national borders. Global access to Government information is often essential to promoting innovation, scientific discovery, entrepreneurship, education, and the general welfare.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H24B93CCF4F8B44E19045C22127FB9A98"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3561 of title 44, United States Code, as added by section 4.</text>
		</section><section id="H78720F3F50324281B3C2C8BDC930601B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Open Government data</header>
 <subsection id="H8784ECC07E0346FA8B828726D26A0229"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">Chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83860963D29240C7B005A6B5C271C67B" style="USC"> <subchapter id="H8606000C87EA4A1E888CF66B028B8B19" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Open government data</header> <section id="HDE15E4D48C454822A596EB34DD2A6226"><enum>3561.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">As used in this subchapter—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE8860FE264554609A4357B2CAE1490DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>agency</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HDDF22EA82C444E8BAE4337EBB1D45A04"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term in section 3502; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6C414CCEB49446AA60B5389BB893B88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes the Federal Election Commission;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H68F243E90D2F4E1C98AA2F238C980135"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>data</term> means recorded information, regardless of form or the media on which the data is recorded;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H708E9BBB6D6B4F9185AE57230A2CBFF9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>data asset</term> means a collection of data elements or data sets that may be grouped together;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H32E20DBDDB59487C9E297143F8AF93D7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEEC7D8EF9FE845EEAEFBF2963D525101"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>Enterprise Data Inventory</term> means the data inventory developed and maintained pursuant to section 3563;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H044CDC0A97024E00B89E793551086298"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the terms <term>information resources management</term>, <term>information system</term>, and <term>information technology</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 3502;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5D59E08B7F4D4D0A9A89B3FF7ACEBA26"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>machine-readable</term> means a format in which information or data can be easily processed by a computer without human intervention while ensuring no semantic meaning is lost;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H62B0A893649D4D3B93AC84387C1C859B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the term <term>metadata</term> means structural or descriptive information about data such as content, format, source, rights, accuracy, provenance, frequency, periodicity, granularity, publisher or responsible party, contact information, method of collection, and other descriptions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H257B1CB75CB74D919CA7D91B5B3FFB9C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the term <term>nonpublic data asset</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H501CD0D7AE9F430298780148F83D9C30"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a data asset that may not be made available to the public for privacy, security, confidentiality, regulation, or other reasons as determined by law; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9310067304B40A2AD96908D68168E13"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes data provided by contractors that is protected by contract, license, patent, trademark, copyright, confidentiality, regulation, or other restriction;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6D7CDCBCEA643BBB212D898B0AFFF74"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the term <term>open Government data asset</term> means a data asset maintained by the Federal Government that is—</text> <subparagraph id="H2F0161CFF57E44DAA7207472D0AB6246"><enum>(A)</enum><text>machine-readable;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86FDDEBD10B146D1AE2164ABC44390F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>available in an open format;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H873D3784F09244989920E2431CC5D929"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not encumbered by restrictions that would impede use or reuse; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2CC92C62B25A4A35B1A668D1E4C232D4"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">based on an underlying open standard that is maintained by a standards organization;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6FD39BC693AC427EBD42BA9A9DD4D354"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>open license</term> means a legal guarantee applied to a public data asset that the data asset is made available—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H517578E4C8FC492B8081508063EC7D7A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at no cost to the public; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H140E59AF7B7242348028877188E54E3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with no restrictions on copying, publishing, distributing, transmitting, citing, or adapting; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3C4952435A814E25A9F454DAA056BA79"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the term <term>public data asset</term> means a data asset maintained by the Federal Government that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2A3A7FE9C33A489AB35C07DC9A76F8FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may be released to the public;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H806B228D07EE426E97269D48CA2F0421"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been released to the public in an open format and is discoverable through a search of Data.gov or any successor to Data.gov; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5069D4C3EA9E4850A01BC8311D8333CE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is part of the worldwide public domain or, if necessary, published with an open license.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="H9C5EAEBAD2884FE6A80ADC75683DC8E3"><enum>3562.</enum><header>Requirements for Government data</header> <subsection id="H9C71A417B20C4145BA8D1A7194F918DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Machine-Readable data required</header><text>Open Government data assets made available by an agency shall be published as machine-readable data.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H53EC3C5F22F64E6C8A17A7EC12DC8673"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Open by default</header><text>When not otherwise prohibited by law, and to the extent practicable, public data assets and nonpublic data assets maintained by the Federal Government shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H13D1E0D6F2BC4E6C962F4B189909DF80"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be available in an open format; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D93B84369A045DA96B87EA5C4A57E37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be available under open licenses.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB87B307529CF4BEC858DACE71829C49B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Open license or worldwide public domain dedication required</header><text>When not otherwise prohibited by law, and to the extent practicable, open Government data assets published by or for an agency shall be made available under an open license or, if not made available under an open license and appropriately released, shall be considered to be published as part of the worldwide public domain.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC020CFDC5E484D5985E68A496C99C46B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Innovation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agency may engage with nongovernmental organizations, citizens, nonprofit organizations, colleges and universities, private and public companies, and other agencies to explore opportunities to leverage the public data assets of the agency in a manner that may provide new opportunities for innovation in the public and private sectors in accordance with law and regulation.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="HC6699334312A46F285D01CF594C46B85"><enum>3563.</enum><header>Enterprise data inventory</header>
							<subsection commented="no" id="H0E2FE24964864210A967F4151D52E080"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Agency data inventory required</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HD88AB207572A41FA8469FC3E82589059"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to develop a clear and comprehensive understanding of the data assets in the possession of an agency, the head of each agency, in consultation with the Director, shall develop and maintain an enterprise data inventory (in this section referred to as the <quote>Enterprise Data Inventory</quote>) that accounts for any data asset created, collected, under the control or direction of, or maintained by the agency after the effective date of this section, with the goal of including all data assets, to the extent practicable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDD84101595B245FBAC35E94618A47E87"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Enterprise Data Inventory shall include each of the following:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H141DA89D554D459DB1B8AD04FAE600B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data assets used in agency information systems (including program administration, statistics, and financial activity) generated by applications, devices, networks, facilities, and equipment, categorized by source type.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDCBC9A0317A54519982492A5306B2FC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Data assets shared or maintained across agency programs and bureaus.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7EB22E4B7BE84DBF9347D3A09006D2A6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Data assets that are shared among agencies or created by more than 1 agency.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4BC2A9E7516E42C6B0B256CD9D6EACA2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A clear indication of all data assets that can be made publicly available under section 552 of title 5 (commonly known as the <quote>Freedom of Information Act</quote>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H657AFF41AC7441ED82A6E6BCE112EAAC"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of whether the agency has determined that an individual data asset may be made publicly available and whether the data asset is available to the public.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8A3ED8D62CAE4DB3A97A5191F2C3ACEF"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nonpublic data assets.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF07A1728E681476598CD33E1A96E406C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Open Government data assets.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H33794B2CC99E4E72BCD7661869914677"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief Information Officer of each agency shall use the standards provided by the Director issued pursuant to subsection (c) to make public data assets included in the Enterprise Data Inventory publicly available in an open format and under an open license.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF67A04C9C9254F0192C1A302C7BADF96"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Standards for Enterprise Data Inventory</header><text>The Director shall issue standards for the Enterprise Data Inventory, including—</text> <paragraph id="H86DD2E4E01A646F898E24079A2B77FBC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a requirement that the Enterprise Data Inventory include a compilation of metadata about agency data assets; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H462BAD4BA7F849AD9B91217C77B578BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>criteria that the head of each agency shall use in determining whether to make a particular data asset publicly available in a manner that takes into account—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H19DD8CFF35A64CBE949D5437333A821A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the expectation of confidentiality associated with an individual data asset;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE5E0DB0478A455CB83B700C31EA3366"><enum>(B)</enum><text>security considerations, including the risk that information in an individual data asset in isolation does not pose a security risk but when combined with other available information may pose such a risk;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE53446C7A274389BB03AF32BC425E92"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the cost and benefits to the public of converting the data into a manner that could be understood and used by the public;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H790274C72511456AB421B7D1D41CBAC4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the expectation that all data assets that would otherwise be made available under section 552 of title 5 (commonly known as the <quote>Freedom of Information Act</quote>) be disclosed; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EFADEFB6B9D48E593D9D1C648B0A253"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other considerations that the Director determines to be relevant.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H53CCE088FEA541589E4A91D1090FFB18"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Nonpublic data assets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nonpublic data assets included in the Enterprise Data Inventory may be maintained in a nonpublic section of the inventory.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HBCFB618DA73C43008865422DA216822F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Availability of Enterprise Data Inventory</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief Information Officer of each agency—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H1A4E9DAA02C2477E8141C597966A90FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall make the Enterprise Data Inventory available to the public on Data.gov;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H20DD7451DBF143FDA637DB8739CCC4C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall ensure that access to the Enterprise Data Inventory and the data contained therein is consistent with applicable law and regulation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFFA0F2C5B4A94DF893041A5439F760EA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may implement paragraph (1) in a manner that maintains a nonpublic portion of the Enterprise Data Inventory.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF4363D3DFE25497D8FC63C9D28F116E4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regular updates required</header><text>The Chief Information Officer of each agency shall—</text> <paragraph id="H1009BCC3263F4BD8AE52F78ED0FCE3E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, complete the Enterprise Data Inventory for the agency not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAEF3037F886F4165A24101C542EE3BD7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>add additional data assets to the Enterprise Data Inventory for the agency not later than 90 days after the date on which the data asset is created or identified.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H210D0358A38848C4945FACE30C49BF62"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Use of existing resources</header><text>When practicable, the Chief Information Officer of each agency shall use existing procedures and systems to compile and publish the Enterprise Data Inventory for the agency.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="H3908261015844E879A1435FC870DF754"><enum>3564.</enum><header>Federal agency responsibilities</header>
 <subsection id="H710CDAC72F6E4B05B0DE66AE13E64DAF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Information resources management</header><text>With respect to general information resources management, each agency shall—</text> <paragraph id="H8BE368DCF4AC411390C94B905AD00C40"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve the integrity, quality, and utility of information to all users within and outside the agency by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5B7F708ED1C64EC295C66F72CA5FC5A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>using open format for any new open Government data asset created or obtained on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H187FA223E7CB43599989135C5468EAA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, encouraging the adoption of open format for all open Government data assets created or obtained before the date of enactment of this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2C5E2CBA88C41BCBC4C4D6CA21C1E14"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in consultation with the Director, develop an open data plan that, at a minimum and to the extent practicable—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA74EA8324C764B149D7C1EFB8733C7CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>requires the agency to develop processes and procedures that—</text> <clause id="H2D85310013D046E0BD77106A8469CCE8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>require each new data collection mechanism to use an open format; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5B0AD14445BA4B5499D505D65E26E03A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>allow the agency to collaborate with non-Government entities, researchers, businesses, and private citizens for the purpose of understanding how data users value and use open Government data assets;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBB83C26C79D4CF4810206B9E0ADFC2D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifies and implements methods for collecting and analyzing digital information on data asset usage by users within and outside of the agency, including designating a point of contact within the agency to assist the public and to respond to quality issues, usability, recommendations for improvements, and complaints about adherence to open data requirements;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F7F163E212041B5B78992F22618F4AF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>develops and implements a process to evaluate and improve the timeliness, completeness, accuracy, usefulness, and availability of open Government data assets;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD307A06535D041EF93D3D170FF0C587D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>requires the agency to update the plan at an interval determined by the Director;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38280497869B435890351CFA348E7906"><enum>(E)</enum><text>includes requirements for meeting the goals of the agency open data plan including technology, training for employees, and implementing procurement standards, in accordance with existing law, that allow for the acquisition of innovative solutions from the public and private sectors; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF612065D0BED4C2D8FB62E4DC850AB8B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>prohibits the dissemination and accidental disclosure of nonpublic data assets.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H94524C5C59F24EBA8A4C73B4A35BA85F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information dissemination</header><text>With respect to information dissemination, each agency—</text>
 <paragraph id="H896BE885107B4189B84A2128C885F84E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall provide access to open Government data assets online;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD78B650476104F30AAC92F46F9C87688"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall take the necessary precautions to ensure that the agency maintains the production and publication of data assets which are directly related to activities that protect the safety of human life or property, as identified by the open data plan of the agency required under subsection (a)(2); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB2FE699927B4DD5B4211F4479795D76"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may engage the public in using open Government data assets and encourage collaboration by—</text> <subparagraph id="H507DECF53D8C40F886D5C4F619208CD5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publishing information on open Government data assets usage in regular, timely intervals, but not less than annually;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC7F1C25AA2F4828BB9BF6A3F376B429"><enum>(B)</enum><text>receiving public input regarding priorities for the analysis and disclosure of data assets to be published;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H997B01F05516474BBFE8236A252F230A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assisting civil society groups and members of the public working to expand the use of open Government data assets; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5F77CFDF01C47EF97C59605460D1547"><enum>(D)</enum><text>hosting challenges, competitions, events, or other initiatives designed to create additional value from open Government data assets.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE0928D9BC3624B4FAB22898111117272"><enum>3565.</enum><header>Additional Chief Information Officer responsibilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Chief Information Officer of each agency, or other appropriate official designated by the head of an agency, is responsible for—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HAC4624740D434CBD890809D26C5E1C04"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data asset management, format standardization, sharing of data assets, and publication of data assets for the agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H55B1176BF9384C9DBCE4E2B9FACCEFCE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the compilation and publication of the Enterprise Data Inventory for the agency required under section 3563;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7C94D2307A22404B88835E08D8915D07"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensuring that agency data conforms with open data best practices;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB1F6014351E04220B2EC7BE3BC43D04B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engaging agency employees, the public, and contractors in using open Government data assets and encourage collaborative approaches to improving data use;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE8E02F30BEBA4848888501DCBC13445E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supporting the agency Performance Improvement Officer in generating data to support the function of the Performance Improvement Officer described in section 1124(a)(2) of title 31;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H102A341C3888414CB524278AA0AE7188"><enum>(6)</enum><text>reviewing the information technology infrastructure of the agency and the impact of the infrastructure on making data assets accessible to reduce barriers that inhibit data asset accessibility;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA9F50ED51AE642B29C245947A17C3BC6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>ensuring that, to the extent practicable, the agency is maximizing its own use of data, including data assets used in agency information systems (including program administration, statistics, and financial activity) generated by applications, devices, networks, facilities, and equipment, categorized by source type and such use is not otherwise prohibited, to reduce costs, improve operations, and strengthen security and privacy protections; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H24B5CB406CCC4B81B9106A793D5119DD"><enum>(8)</enum><text>identifying points of contact for roles and responsibilities related to open data use and implementation as required by the Director.</text>
							</paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="HCAD9C4498E7E493DB93ACA027BE0B799"><enum>3566.</enum><header>Technology portal</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H4805BB555EB646318B810487EB79655E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Data.gov required</header><text>The Administrator of General Services shall maintain a single public interface online as a point of entry dedicated to sharing open Government data assets with the public.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9965FCC59560465FA755DBA9DDF9AB19"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination with agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall determine, after consultation with the head of each agency and the Administrator of General Services, the method to access any open Government data assets published through the interface described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H0979EF33585B4CAB96DC54140110B2E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special provisions</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H402C8E8D64064266BEB0D50BFEA48721"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Notwithstanding section 8, section 3562 of title 44, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall take effect on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act and shall apply with respect to any contract entered into by an agency on or after such effective date.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H19D9D0027C65419D914CCA46337E7713"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of open data assets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of each agency shall ensure that any activities by the agency or any new contract entered into by the agency meet the requirements of section 3562 of title 44, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA58101C2C274D7CB81F3A75C6411543"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Deadline for technology portal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the effective date of this Act, the Administrator of General Services shall meet the requirements of section 3566 of title 44, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9987748047D04130BCDB32F28E6197FE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5BAEDF6C99214752A6494A0E9CCFB56A" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry level="subchapter">SUBCHAPTER III—Open Government Data</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">3561. Definitions.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">3562. Requirements for Government data.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">3563. Enterprise data inventory.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">3564. Federal agency responsibilities.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">3565. Additional Chief Information Officer responsibilities.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">3566. Technology portal.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H019F2F6430C445DFB735298A4ABA0CC3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Evaluation of agency analytical capabilities</header>
 <subsection id="HE4AC73D129354AC98F398702140C1BFF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Agency review of evaluation and analysis capabilities; report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Chief Operating Officer of each agency shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives, and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget a report on the review described in subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB4EBF700CA344D7B8DD99066B9652096"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements of agency review</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall assess the coverage, quality, methods, effectiveness, and independence of the evaluation, research, and analysis efforts of an agency, including each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HBF111D6B30D3492F946D75438EF69B25"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A list of the activities and operations of the agency that are being evaluated and analyzed and the activities and operations that have been evaluated and analyzed during the previous 5 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6122D1E100FF49CDBFB2D5B3A565EB16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The extent to which the evaluations, research, and analysis efforts and related activities of the agency support the needs of various divisions within the agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H81C0F324E8114AE18C87859D3EF7F46C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The extent to which the evaluation research and analysis efforts and related activities of the agency address an appropriate balance between needs related to organizational learning, ongoing program management, performance management, strategic management, interagency and private sector coordination, internal and external oversight, and accountability.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD6CD86F060D4F5DA3D9F4557DA41B6B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The extent to which the agency uses methods and combinations of methods that are appropriate to agency divisions and the corresponding research questions being addressed, including an appropriate combination of formative and summative evaluation research and analysis approaches.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8926E2A0B054153921335F1926D0AB5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The extent to which evaluation and research capacity is present within the agency to include personnel, agency process for planning and implementing evaluation activities, disseminating best practices and findings, and incorporating employee views and feedback.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0640E43D66B04421A8F6BA8742E5A953"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The extent to which the agency has the capacity to assist front-line staff and program offices to develop the capacity to use evaluation research and analysis approaches and data in the day-to-day operations.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF1D13EC66E644A7086661DF8E854D497"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO review of agency reports</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that summarizes agency findings and highlights trends from the reports submitted pursuant to subsection (a) and, if appropriate, recommends actions to further improve agency capacity to use evaluation techniques and data to support evaluation efforts.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H536DA1F473784F019F092C32A921AF34"><enum>6.</enum><header>Online repository and additional reports</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H7298F7C88A97467A812E82D5608D6575"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repository</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall collaborate with the Office of Government Information Services and the Administrator of General Services to develop and maintain an online repository of tools, best practices, and schema standards to facilitate the adoption of open data practices, which shall—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H304024735B9D4B4BA98282751EEDF071"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include definitions, regulation and policy, checklists, and case studies related to open data, this Act, and the amendments made by this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H600465817061465886463B3707C59523"><enum>(2)</enum><text>facilitate collaboration and the adoption of best practices across the Federal Government relating to the adoption of open data practices.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE80595126DFD46F19C0B8619F3437490"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives a report that identifies—</text>
 <paragraph id="H44788FDA7B0D46B38327F7F0C057F7ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the value of information made available to the public as a result of this Act and the amendments made by this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46FCF9EF5D6B4300B0D609C6BB781287"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether it is valuable to expand the publicly available information to any other data assets; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3FD61A3BAD948AE8190F4950EC73D0C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the completeness of the Enterprise Data Inventory at each agency required under section 3563 of title 44, United States Code, as added by section 4.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD1468E74D6234269B71F1CB4C550D40F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Biennial OMB report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the effective date of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall electronically publish a report on agency performance and compliance with this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5198B41321444750BD1846C0E288C8A0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Agency CIO report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the effective date of this Act and every year thereafter, the Chief Information Officer of each agency shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives a report on compliance with the requirements of this Act and the amendments made by this Act, including information on the requirements that the agency could not meet and what the agency needs to comply with those requirements.</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H778932404A4F4D5F8077D32BB705AA6E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, shall be construed to require the disclosure of information or records that are exempt from public disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Freedom of Information Act</quote>).</text>
 </section><section id="HAD77A302AF6F4D03B1A145A2A58F37C6"><enum>8.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act, and the amendments made by this Act, shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


