<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1D221EE5FFB2467E945DF547B7B39B97" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3347 IH: Viewer Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3347</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170720">July 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish an additional fund in the Treasury to ensure consumers do not lose access to
			 over-the-air broadcast television as a result of the reorganization of
			 broadcast television spectrum, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H464B27F421184D4BAD883B3799B3948B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H07A3603A041F46A49521BFCBE0072B69" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Viewer Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7F65E82DCA7E4AFC9E09744308FF8770"><enum>2.</enum><header>Consumer outreach campaign</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Commission $90,000,000 to conduct a consumer outreach campaign to raise awareness of changes to the television channels available to such consumers as a result of the reorganization of broadcast television spectrum carried out pursuant to section 6403(b) of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1452">47 U.S.C. 1452(b)</external-xref>).</text>
		</section><section id="HC1C7C70AA31A465AB38666A3B8BB885B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Viewer protection fund</header>
 <subsection id="H5FA0261F878D449C8DB3B3FD294F7EFF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the Viewer Protection Fund.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H03403E7EF28F4A42851BF71597B2C05F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000,000 to the Viewer Protection Fund.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H8CBA9B33949B445FA16047E3876FD072"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reserve source if TV Broadcaster Relocation Fund insufficient</header> <paragraph id="HDCA23DB13B954371844977CB314D591D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text>If the Commission makes the certification described in paragraph (2), amounts in the Viewer Protection Fund shall be available to the Commission to make reimbursements pursuant to subsection (b)(4)(A)(i) of section 6403 of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1452">47 U.S.C. 1452</external-xref>) in order to prevent a substantial number of consumers from losing access to the signals of broadcast television licensees that are reassigned from one channel to another channel under subsection (b)(1)(B) of such section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE75995E294EB454B9527031D41FA2CB6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>The certification described in this paragraph is a certification from the Commission to the Secretary of the Treasury that the funds available in the TV Broadcaster Relocation Fund established under subsection (d) of such section are likely to be insufficient to reimburse reasonably incurred costs described in subsection (b)(4)(A)(i) of such section.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6DD42696DE649B5953446E5400A8737"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relocation costs of radio stations for displacement of co-Located equipment</header>
 <paragraph id="H67DD9725DC944B3589298AE2708196BB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Commission makes the certification described in paragraph (2), amounts in the Viewer Protection Fund shall be available to the Commission to reimburse FM radio stations, in order to prevent a substantial number of consumers from losing access to such stations, for reasonable relocation costs that are incurred because of the displacement of co-located equipment from a tower or similar transmission facility due to the reorganization of television broadcast spectrum under subsection (b) of section 6403 of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1452">47 U.S.C. 1452</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H219F89850DA44C73A3B2FD902D0F8BB9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The certification described in this paragraph is a certification from the Commission to the Secretary of the Treasury that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3AEF9B9B7E1841039A944C70C9CBA09A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a substantial number of consumers will lose access to FM radio stations unless such stations are reimbursed for reasonable relocation costs described in paragraph (1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7667D5BBBD5548FFB6499B5B76641BF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Commission has made all necessary reimbursements under subsection (c) of this section, or no such reimbursements are necessary, in order to prevent a substantial number of consumers from losing access to the signals of broadcast television licensees that are reassigned from one channel to another channel under subsection (b)(1)(B) of such section 6403.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H68872E32FEAF4F0CA6D0577ACABD2C45"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reasonable costs of MVPDs</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HEBB28ABEFD5645088DD287F4EF33B935"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Commission makes the certification described in paragraph (2), amounts in the Viewer Protection Fund shall be available to the Commission to reimburse multichannel video programming distributors, in order to prevent a substantial number of consumers from losing access to signals of broadcast television licensees carried by such distributors, for reasonable costs incurred by such distributors in order to continue to carry such signals due to the reorganization of television broadcast spectrum under subsection (b) of section 6403 of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1452">47 U.S.C. 1452</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE74B2BF8E9C144D6948FDABCFCFE49D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The certification described in this paragraph is a certification from the Commission to the Secretary of the Treasury that—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H7817406252E140169AB5145BAB9B4A5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a substantial number of consumers will lose access to signals of broadcast television licensees carried by multichannel video programming distributors unless such distributors are reimbursed for reasonable costs described in paragraph (1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H20BBFA51AC794AC5BB4DE75CB056B937"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Commission has made all necessary reimbursements under subsection (c) of this section, or no such reimbursements are necessary, in order to prevent a substantial number of consumers from losing access to the signals of broadcast television licensees that are reassigned from one channel to another channel under subsection (b)(1)(B) of such section 6403.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6C395C8B64784EB2BD9DD641CD500436"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Funds made available to the Commission under this section shall only be available until the end of fiscal year 2022.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H8D246EB24A5E46B3964FE9FEC5F18378"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Unused funds</header>
 <paragraph id="H0C4E5BC028B8488391BE6D6E932C3A98"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Low-power television and television translator relocation costs</header><text>If the Commission makes the certification described in paragraph (2) of subsection (c), after the Commission makes the reimbursements under paragraph (1) of such subsection, amounts in the Viewer Protection Fund shall be available to the Commission to reimburse low-power television stations and television translator stations, in order to prevent a substantial number of consumers from losing access to such stations, for reasonable relocation costs that are incurred—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0A6D0F76F8DD4072A16D679B9FA4A845"><enum>(A)</enum><text>because of assignment of displacement channels to such stations by the Commission in the reorganization of television broadcast spectrum under section 6403(b) of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1452">47 U.S.C. 1452(b)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17CCFCFBFF2142C5B45964224C68E4EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after such assignment.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3A0286FEAB341D89594DB40371C6E75"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfer to general fund</header><text>If any amounts remain in the Viewer Protection Fund after the end of fiscal year 2022, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer such amounts to the general fund of the Treasury.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H1F5F62E0FA284CEEA0FB9F27FB87EFE6">
					<enum>(3)</enum>
					<header>Low-power television and television translator usage rights</header>
 <text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to alter the spectrum usage rights of low-power television stations or television translator stations.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H3E9335BB8B074935AFEB0F5AE5BCA077"><enum>4.</enum><header>Transition period</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall, by order, delegate to the Media Bureau of the Commission the authority to—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H613F9D9F00684BCAB8FAD5D4D4366461"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modify the transition period for relocation of specific broadcast television licensees in accordance with the reassignments of television channels made under section 6403(b) of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1452">47 U.S.C. 1452(b)</external-xref>), if the Bureau determines that such modification is necessary to ensure that no licensee is forced to stop broadcasting due to reasons outside the licensee’s control; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H321200E0E352418FAF37EA1AC4291BD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>impose appropriate penalties should a licensee fail or refuse to complete relocation within such transition period (as modified under paragraph (1)) other than for reasons outside the licensee’s control.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H3E65D0CD96A3402B8EC436208B268711"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H053DF316D6BF464587011A8BD076E359"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Broadcast television licensee</header><text>The term <quote>broadcast television licensee</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 6001 of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1401">47 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF4D1FAF6F6A48B798CF8F7B3FDC6F09"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <quote>Commission</quote> means the Federal Communications Commission.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H67F453EB312A41809DEA9116605369D7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Multichannel video programming distributor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>multichannel video programming distributor</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 602 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/522">47 U.S.C. 522</external-xref>).</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


