<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB4F6AFE78FE74696A11AF896CD12D871" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2126 IH: What Works to Move Welfare Recipients into Jobs Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2126</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170425">April 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To strengthen welfare research and evaluation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HCF3C25E2C80248378E8E7F43C8BF9B0B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H464CBA29D69A49A184C7A644F9F2E09E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>What Works to Move Welfare Recipients into Jobs Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63638995AE6146CCBBA5FBEBD959FF66" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strengthening welfare research and evaluation and development of a What Works Clearinghouse</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 413 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/613">42 U.S.C. 613</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB4068AE0CFDD4C45BD667F8DE0534285" style="OLC">
				<section id="H0C201B1B972B4CF7ACBA5C5C93E15885"><enum>413.</enum><header>Evaluation of Temporary Assistance for Needy Families and related programs</header>
 <subsection id="H50C1DAEDB2664D5A9ECB8C13A2193B57"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Evaluation of the impacts of TANF</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct research on the effect of State programs funded under this part and any other State program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 409(a)(7)(B)(i)) on employment, self-sufficiency, child well-being, unmarried births, marriage, poverty, economic mobility, and other factors as determined by the Secretary.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H41E8B5CDDF8E4129989FA3AC60BDAD36"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Evaluation of grants To improve child well-Being by promoting healthy marriage and responsible
 fatherhood</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct research to determine the effects of the grants made under section 403(a)(2) on child well-being, marriage, family stability, economic mobility, poverty, and other factors as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7BDFB35C3FFF406FAD0458094D28FDA5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Dissemination of information</header><text>The Secretary shall, in consultation with States receiving funds provided under this part, develop methods of disseminating information on any research, evaluation, or study conducted under this section, including facilitating the sharing of information and best practices among States and localities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA49436F8F27A4CC79791B7446E1EA899"><enum>(d)</enum><header>State-Initiated evaluations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State shall be eligible to receive funding to evaluate the State program funded under this part or any other State program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 409(a)(7)(B)(i)) if—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE90CFBD3F14541418BE5148CECCC9BEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the State submits to the Secretary a description of the proposed evaluation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H96951273B37F48639BB329C37AF6B7C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that the design and approach of the proposed evaluation is rigorous and is likely to yield information that is credible and will be useful to other States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DC2ED996A4247E4A120F10C1CA3A5E3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>unless waived by the Secretary, the State contributes to the cost of the evaluation, from non-Federal sources, an amount equal to at least 25 percent of the cost of the proposed evaluation.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8D42526658AB402782B5EC4B2168D51E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Census Bureau research</header>
 <paragraph id="HA222B17812ED4E7E9CF9AB7C4B2862D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Bureau of the Census shall implement or enhance household surveys of program participation, in consultation with the Secretary and the Bureau of Labor Statistics and make available to interested parties, to allow for the assessment of the outcomes of continued welfare reform on the economic and child well-being of low-income families with children, including those who received assistance or services from a State program funded under this part or any other State program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 409(a)(7)(B)(i)). The content of the surveys should include such information as may be necessary to examine the issues of unmarried childbearing, marriage, welfare dependency and compliance with work requirements, the beginning and ending of spells of assistance, work, earnings and employment stability, and the well-being of children.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H97F9A48451774776900553BD7E37E5B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out the activities specified in paragraph (1), the Bureau of the Census, the Secretary, and the Bureau of Labor Statistics shall consider ways to improve the surveys and data derived from the surveys to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA71D01F310034F78B83B0142BBDC1EDB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>address underreporting of the receipt of means-tested benefits and tax benefits for low-income individuals and families;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA0FFEBA103843519BA8559AD95067B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increase understanding of poverty spells and long-term poverty, including by facilitating the matching of information to better understand intergenerational poverty;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D313ED4E6984DA593212F1385969E90"><enum>(C)</enum><text>generate a better geographical understanding of poverty such as through State-based estimates and measures of neighborhood poverty;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66719793C8D8415BB27F46304A79851C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>increase understanding of the effects of means-tested benefits and tax benefits on the earnings of low-income families; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1331322E0A7047049C9452907F9BB754"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve how poverty and economic well-being are measured, including through the use of consumption measures.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H64666AF3D7954184A13FB857D67BF1ED"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Research and evaluation conducted under this section</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Research and evaluation conducted under this section designed to determine the effects of a program or policy (other than research conducted under subsection (e)) shall use experimental designs using random assignment or other reliable, evidence-based research methodologies that allow for the strongest possible causal inferences when random assignment is not feasible.</text>
					</subsection><subsection id="H0D2D52929ED94555B20ABA66CD5B3A83"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Development of what works clearinghouse of proven and promising approaches To move welfare
			 recipients into work</header>
 <paragraph id="H26FEDFA779054D0D90ABBD09DCAB21CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall develop a database (which shall be referred to as the <quote>What Works Clearinghouse of Proven and Promising Projects to Move Welfare Recipients into Work</quote>) of the projects that used a proven approach or a promising approach in moving welfare recipients into work, based on independent, rigorous evaluations of the projects. The database shall include a separate listing of projects that used a developmental approach in delivering services and a further separate listing of the projects with no or negative effects. The Secretary shall add to the What Works Clearinghouse of Proven and Promising Projects to Move Welfare Recipients into Work data about the projects that, based on an independent, well-conducted experimental evaluation of a program or project, using random assignment or other research methodologies that allow for the strongest possible causal inferences, have shown they are proven, promising, developmental, or ineffective approaches.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H60F11BAFE6214915A04CFDCFA569835C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria for evidence of effectiveness of approach</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor and organizations with experience in evaluating research on the effectiveness of various approaches in delivering services to move welfare recipients into work, shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4F252F35078B4349BD152904E21F38EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish criteria for evidence of effectiveness; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD837F823E28D46DCB14B1D410978F9DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that the process for establishing the criteria—</text>
 <clause id="HF58472C120D44DF4BBB13C4B1BBC9D0F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is transparent;</text> </clause><clause id="H575E45FF0F474BC1BC13E58455186F4E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is consistent across agencies;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H74B7E4CF06E347C8B02764F9DB5130AB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provides opportunity for public comment; and</text> </clause><clause id="H5B2C72D7209A4D5C9D876754B20073A1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>takes into account efforts of Federal agencies to identify and publicize effective interventions, including efforts at the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Education, and the Department of Justice.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCE1C13EADAA4800A9D7BE59606F19A3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="HD013AFD620EB400FACF620A1C66F4239"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Approach</header><text>The term <term>approach</term> means a process, product, strategy, or practice that is—</text>
 <clause id="H5DD7B92426F44AF9A407D2FFD38FC4EA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>research-based, based on the results of one or more empirical studies, and linked to program-determined outcomes; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9733809585DD4AEE91355B35DC2BD5BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>evaluated using rigorous research designs.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9A1ACA5E2834DAF8BAE5F9C6A52E664"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Proven approach</header><text>The term <term>proven approach</term> means an approach that—</text>
 <clause id="H8EB2C1A079D2494C85EFE90100003419"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meets the requirements of a promising approach; and</text> </clause><clause id="H59BD5144A5194FA38E0B1C55E9E8B6C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has demonstrated significant positive outcomes at more than 1 site in terms of increasing work and earnings of participants, reducing poverty and dependence, or strengthening families.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H005941ABE4794AE29BC2679EE1D48866"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Promising approach</header><text>The term <term>promising approach</term> means an approach—</text> <clause id="H9F546AE29E794A9CA9DFCAEFE1E789ED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that meets the requirements of subparagraph (D)(i);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1BC6D9DCC7D5429EB05B76E4ADCF838F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that has been evaluated using well-designed and rigorous randomized controlled or quasi-experimental research designs;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H486F6C930195437D9476F780882F3FB1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that has demonstrated significant positive outcomes at only 1 site in terms of increasing work and earnings of participants, reducing poverty and dependence, or strengthening families; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H560F5AE2FE1A462D9C4E88B3290957AA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>under which the benefits of the positive outcomes have exceeded the costs of achieving the outcomes.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H735C219D8D4C4247807364F69CEE71A0"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Developmental approach</header><text>The term <term>developmental approach</term> means an approach that—</text> <clause id="HD92F4C13BA444FA0A7EC9E3C92E9F10C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is research-based, grounded in relevant empirically based knowledge, and linked to program-determined outcomes;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9A1FFD08768E409AA79BE7C6802FE9E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is evaluated using rigorous research designs; and</text> </clause><clause id="HBD55C3ACCE0347999319CD6293B27889"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has yet to demonstrate a significant positive outcome in terms of increasing work and earnings of participants in a cost-effective way.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H5DED63E1EECB4943B1D737FA346A656A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendment made by this Act shall take effect on October 1, 2017.</text> </section></legis-body></bill> 

