<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H11B5313D8CF44879B3CF1B537C03F12E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3674 IH: Equity for Disaster Victims Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3674</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170905">September 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Small Business Act to allow small business concerns, homeowners, or nonprofit entities to use certain Superstorm Sandy grant funds or other disaster assistance received to repay certain disaster assistance provided by the Small Business Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBCE1F5F066A94B18977B563C6F7FD329" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4BCDE1B17FB44CCCB1F3E3A2F7A2A069" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Equity for Disaster Victims Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF382CD0C461A463D8727AA70629EE64D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Use of certain Superstorm Sandy grant funds for repayment of certain disaster assistance provided by the Small Business Administration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7(f) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(f)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBCD38E59664C435EB9C5A8BA8069EC11" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H800F077D3A184F5C9D9098AF90641DB7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Superstorm Sandy CDBG–DR grant funds</header> 
<subparagraph id="H843198F6730644AF8A96BFEE561F4467"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<clause id="H208C112CC7EF49D8934B9BD576BABFC0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Loans to repair, rehabilitate, or replace real property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A small business concern, homeowner, or nonprofit entity that received a loan pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(A) for the purpose of repairing, rehabilitating, or replacing real property damaged or destroyed by or as a result of Superstorm Sandy may receive Superstorm Sandy CDBG–DR grant funds only if such grant funds will be used to repay the principal and any interest accrued on the loan.</text></clause> <clause id="HCE7C4BB0A0C14B7894377ABDF1F8A979"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Loans to refinance a mortgage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A small business concern, homeowner, or nonprofit entity that received a loan pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(B) to refinance a mortgage or other lien against a home or business concern that was totally destroyed or substantially damaged by or as a result of Superstorm Sandy may receive Superstorm Sandy CDBG–DR grant funds only if the amount of such grant funds will be used to repay the amount received under such subsection (b)(1)(B).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0ACD3CDC7C824B4EBDD7C073AC0C5BB4"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Additional disaster assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A small business concern, homeowner, or nonprofit entity that received additional disaster assistance pursuant to subsection (b)(9) for a loan described in clause (i) or the refinancing described in clause (ii) may receive Superstorm Sandy CDBG–DR grant funds only if such grant funds will be used—</text> <subclause id="H9FE8CB1CFFA34BCDB0E40596250038A1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to repay the principal and any interest accrued on a loan described in clause (i); or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H99B0FDB7B14D489D8968A1677542BB73"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to repay the amount received from a loan described in clause (ii).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HECCEE8F11C3348A9B990A91F81705598"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Superstorm Sandy CDBG–DR grant funds</term> means amounts made available by the Department of Housing and Urban Development under the heading <quote>Department of Housing and Urban Development—Community Planning and Development—Community Development Fund</quote> in title X of the Disaster Relief Appropriations Act, 2013 (division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/2">Public Law 113–2</external-xref>; 127 Stat. 36) only for impacted and distressed areas resulting from a major disaster declared pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.) due to Superstorm Sandy for activities authorized under title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5301">42 U.S.C. 5301</external-xref> et seq.).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section commented="no" id="H103B83E164734142AF669DE6AC223D87"><enum>3.</enum><header>Use of other disaster assistance for repayment of certain disaster assistance provided by the Small Business Administration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7(b) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(b)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after paragraph (15) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11888231999941F2B1109E7BDF754FA5" style="OLC"> <paragraph commented="no" id="HEB1ED3A8088141DC97D1BA4A5B3DD75D"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Use of other disaster assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As determined by the Administrator, a small business concern, homeowner, or nonprofit entity who receives assistance pursuant to any other law (except for assistance received pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.)) to repair, rehabilitate, or replace real property damaged or destroyed by or as a result of a major disaster declared by the President under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>) on or after the date of enactment of this paragraph may use such assistance to repay the principal and any interest accrued on a loan or the amount of other assistance received under this subsection.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H6432108F14334E33AB2D82B652DE7799" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Treatment of funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding the sixth and tenth provisos under the heading <quote>Department of Housing and Urban Development—Community Planning and Development—Community Development Fund</quote> in title X of the Disaster Relief Appropriations Act, 2013 (division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/2">Public Law 113–2</external-xref>; 127 Stat. 37), to the extent that amounts are made available under such heading, the procedures preventing the duplication of benefits shall not apply with respect to such amounts used for the purposes of paragraph (2) of section 7(f) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(f)</external-xref>), as added by this Act.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

