<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H694FC91C9E7240D9A5A035980827D62E" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2142 EH: International Narcotics Trafficking Emergency Response by Detecting Incoming Contraband with Technology Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2142</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To improve the ability of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to interdict fentanyl, other synthetic opioids, and other narcotics and psychoactive substances that are illegally imported into the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H7C07F335ED164B7182F1D7018E8E121C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE820F47D66CB4F94B5A9CE3A6920D68C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>International Narcotics Trafficking Emergency Response by Detecting Incoming Contraband with Technology Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>INTERDICT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF6344C06DA504BC18C796BB11CB376BA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="HD2C7B61165FC44D3BF8908FC5637FCE2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chemical screening device</header><text>The term <quote>chemical screening device</quote> means an immunoassay, narcotics field test kit, infrared spectrophotometer, mass spectrometer, nuclear magnetic resonance spectrometer, Raman spectrophotometer, or other scientific instrumentation able to collect data that can be interpreted to determine the presence of fentanyl, other synthetic opioids, and other narcotics and psychoactive substances.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H826A3DB4DBAE44EAA27F36E80FADA210"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commissioner</header><text>The term <quote>Commissioner</quote> means the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H138DBBC248B246A38D19C7C54BFCE227"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Express consignment operator or carrier</header><text>The term <quote>express consignment operator or carrier</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 128.1 of title 19, Code of Federal Regulations (or any similar successor regulation).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H55B24C2853364F449DB67A7C3DB1D7B3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Interdiction of fentanyl, other synthetic opioids, and other narcotics and psychoactive substances</header> <subsection id="HEEE70B90F9B347B39BE2A47B866ED491"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Chemical screening devices</header><text>The Commissioner shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H95C8818715BD45A6995D9DA62181EEED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increase the number of chemical screening devices available to U.S. Customs and Border Protection officers over the number of such devices that are available on the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C4AB4C2365547FEA232C5E4D83DDD78"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make such additional chemical screening devices available to U.S. Customs and Border Protection officers as the Commissioner determines are necessary to interdict fentanyl, other synthetic opioids, and other narcotics and psychoactive substances that are illegally imported into the United States, including such substances that are imported through the mail or by an express consignment operator or carrier.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HEC64DCD22A5741DFB2E0BB5A2D64FDD3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Personnel to interpret data</header><text>The Commissioner shall dedicate the appropriate number of U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel, including scientists, so that such personnel are available during all operational hours to interpret data collected by chemical screening devices.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HF621715E8CDA414C9ADAB44C4AA20885"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Commissioner $9,000,000 to ensure that U.S. Customs and Border Protection has resources, including chemical screening devices, personnel, and scientists, available during all operational hours to prevent, detect, and interdict the unlawful importation of fentanyl, other synthetic opioids, and other narcotics and psychoactive substances.</text></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20171023" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives October 24, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


