<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0402A052A26940A4BB121BAC8D350AE3" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1791 IH: Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1791</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170329">March 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000578">Mr. Reichert</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area in the State of Washington, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA1891F63B65048BBB6A07201DDCFB877" style="OLC">
 <section id="H95D420EC1920430AAE6A654CB946FFC0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H2EB03A1A47EE4AC6B40711220D0E229B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes; construction</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H958A23063DAA4EBBA892E9473608F1FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to recognize the national importance of the natural and cultural legacies of the area, as demonstrated in the study entitled <quote>Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area Feasibility Study</quote> dated April 2012;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8252E1311E114021834DB28DAE26CE3E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to recognize the heritage of natural resource conservation in the Pacific Northwest and in the Mountains to Sound Greenway;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE52B27150C94D82B29948D2A323848C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to preserve, support, conserve, and interpret the legacies of natural resource conservation, community stewardship, and Indian tribes and nations from time immemorial, within the Mountains to Sound National Heritage Area;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E48FBC962A54769AB0A73B74B8F0D72"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to promote heritage, cultural, and recreational tourism and to develop educational and cultural programs for visitors and the general public;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7506CD9FC8B44D8B89A7E374796A076"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to recognize and interpret important events and geographic locations representing key developments in the creation of America, particularly the settlement of the American West and the stories of diverse ethnic groups, Indian tribes, and others;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBB74BBD6EF5A4F7DACF6E05D5B8A2BC9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to enhance a cooperative management framework to assist Federal, State, local, and Tribal governments, the private sector, and citizens residing in the Heritage Area in conserving, supporting, managing, and enhancing natural and recreational sites in the Heritage Area;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E1C09D84EC649BF98B7138C1A08C841"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to recognize and interpret the relationship between land and people, representing broad American ideals demonstrated through the integrity of existing resources within the Heritage Area; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B98D44B7DF94B168CF3995ED2B74856"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to support working relationships between public land managers and the community by creating relevant links between the National Park Service, the Forest Service, other relevant Federal agencies, Tribal governments, State and local governments and agencies, and community stakeholders within and surrounding the Heritage Area in order to protect, enhance, and interpret cultural and natural resources within the Heritage Area.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H8947FD35FD93487EB8CAFE7BD0F5CFB6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HE0AE4C0BB8ED4A47A27E77CA57188FFA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Heritage area</header><text>The term <quote>Heritage Area</quote> means the Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area established in this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H378E9E3CFF4A42D7879BA15695BDDE40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Local coordinating entity</header><text>The term <quote>local coordinating entity</quote> means the entity selected by the Secretary under section 4(d).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H390DBD328CD74AE680E132B280ADF156"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Management plan</header><text>The term <quote>management plan</quote> means the management plan for the Heritage Area required under section 5.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB382C56DC1C43B1ACC789777A48EB3A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <quote>Map</quote> means the map entitled <quote>Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area Proposed Boundary</quote>, numbered 584/125,484, and dated August 2014.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9CDC83A9B4EF4342948A3B8F858061D0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H05DF2A5B2DF04821A1ECB3D0FCAA6A03"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means the State of Washington.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB519940B77304016808C6EBBA022EECC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Tribe or tribal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>Tribe</quote> or <quote>Tribal</quote> mean any federally recognized Indian tribe with cultural heritage and historic interests within the proposed Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H7B99B4C015904BD18252049B611C58D9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Designation of the Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area</header>
 <subsection id="H3AB5C5B1861544FDA4E4107E0CE15259"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the State the Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H46A063C07F2146E8AAC9799AC2EBC551"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Boundaries</header><text>The Heritage Area shall consist of land located in King and Kittitas Counties in the State, as generally depicted on the map.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD256F941FC1E443E9958CB3A975C9F87"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service, the United States Forest Service, and the local coordinating entity.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAC38DF34C5DC41C884FB73493AC10F26"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Local coordinating entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall designate a willing local unit of government, Indian tribe, or a nonprofit organization to serve as the coordinating entity for the Heritage Area within 120 days of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HEFBF83EB01034A248F0E90FDB24F1A4C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Management plan</header>
 <subsection id="HFB853B61967D48F481B02FE1A1942D76"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the local coordinating entity shall submit to the Secretary for approval a proposed management plan for the Heritage Area.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB1C40ACD859444DAA9200A2856AA7267"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The management plan shall—</text> <paragraph id="HF56210EB5312438797C23C6B29087646"><enum>(1)</enum><text>incorporate an integrated and cooperative approach for the protection, enhancement, and interpretation of the natural, cultural, historic, scenic, and recreational resources of the Heritage Area;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2016583FEA048879B51E23B315B05F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>take into consideration Federal, State, Tribal, and local plans; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8EFA1E0EE054128AEC946DD5F812E9E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1E73FC2609E541479D73A3663E4B9951"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an inventory of the natural, historical, cultural, educational, scenic, and recreational resources of the Heritage Area, including an acknowledgment of the exercise of Tribal treaty rights, that relate to the national importance and themes of the Heritage Area that should be conserved and enhanced;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F29C31F21E4459D8B2120C2EC836ED0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of strategies and recommendations for conservation, funding, management, and development of the Heritage Area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DC9B294EAE14D5AB943C398DAF43139"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the actions that Federal, State, local, and Tribal governments, private organizations, and individuals have agreed to take to protect the natural, cultural, historical, scenic, and recreational resources of the Heritage Area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5421D20331D44DDBBC3FFFB5E938BF49"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a program of implementation for the management plan by the local coordinating entity, including—</text> <clause id="H43A59FAA3BD245F9B55E012157CA5B68"><enum>(i)</enum><text>performance goals; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4F44C12962464113A70D0FF2B292832B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>commitments for implementation made by partners;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30A92EBB29304963894C1D6E974B294B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the identification of sources of funding for carrying out the management plan;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CDE9AA814D54A55ACF751CFEB97CA78"><enum>(F)</enum><text>analysis and recommendations for means by which Federal, State, local, and Tribal programs may best be coordinated to carry out this section;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06A7C13C27A748F69940A91E64CA17E7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>an interpretive plan for the Heritage Area, including Tribal heritage;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3046B314A964A68A93C1B2B149095E2"><enum>(H)</enum><text>recommended policies and strategies for resource management, including the development of intergovernmental and interagency cooperative agreements to protect the natural, cultural, historical, scenic, and recreational resources of the Heritage Area; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5A21E7218C2428F961FF39BD53B2312"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a definition of the roles of the National Park Service, the Forest Service, other Federal agencies, and Tribes in the coordination of the Heritage Area and in otherwise furthering the purposes of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA0F48160963743028AF1CA67BF2C30B7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a proposed management plan is not submitted to the Secretary by the date that is 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the local coordinating entity shall be ineligible to receive additional funding under this Act until the date on which the Secretary receives and approves the management plan.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H10871267D37D42ACA8E95F4709DDAE25"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Approval or disapproval of management plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H945B287033BF483E98DBE27D45CF75B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of receipt of the proposed management plan, the Secretary, in consultation with the State and Tribal governments, shall approve or disapprove the management plan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD503BE2E1094EF6BC2B2AC64C3EC431"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria for approval</header><text>In determining whether to approve the management plan, the Secretary shall consider whether—</text> <subparagraph id="H5DF319CABA2E441A8E1EFCBB44DC7293"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the local coordinating entity has afforded adequate opportunity, including public hearings, for public and governmental involvement in the preparation of the management plan;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8179D138D874417EAA92D0F055163751"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the resource protection and interpretation strategies contained in the management plan, if implemented, would adequately protect the natural, cultural, historical, scenic, and recreational resources of the Heritage Area; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DC19704220B4F8B925890191357B35B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the management plan is consistent with the Secretary’s trust responsibilities to Indian tribes and Tribal treaty rights within the National Heritage Area.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD119776FB3146B5B7D90231E23CC332"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Action following disapproval</header><text>If the Secretary disapproves the management plan, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H159745D9600E4269AFF81FCAC7A71A0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advise the local coordinating entity in writing of the reasons for the disapproval;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCAAC7CB38944E2CB55E463D95308538"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make recommendations to the local coordinating entity for revisions to the management plan; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0937E41B8BC94977A5B8C49B71621DAA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the receipt of any revised management plan from the local coordinating entity, approve or disapprove the revised management plan.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H307CC13150BF480CAF145EF195331AAB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text>The Secretary shall review and approve or disapprove in the same manner as the original management plan, each amendment to the management plan that makes a substantial change to the management plan, as determined by the Secretary. The local coordinating entity shall not carry out any amendment to the management plan until the date on which the Secretary has approved the amendment.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HED168103FBFC423B95D69F122C62D5FA"><enum>6.</enum><header>Administration</header>
			<subsection id="HC03CBEC719654E1E8EBA123A16E0E102"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorities</header>
 <paragraph id="H32722ED65A4C4095919545C63B07E2D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of implementing the management plan, the Secretary and Forest Service may—</text> <subparagraph id="HBA2B141E66EF4E198CC4E3ABC9707E19"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide technical assistance for the implementation of the management plan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A1FFFBCEE7D4B7E91C2D9618142C006"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enter into cooperative agreements with the local coordinating entity, State and local agencies, Tribes, and other interested parties to carry out this Act, including cooperation and cost sharing as appropriate to provide more cost-effective and coordinated public land management.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2F39D118A214C069E23E8F6425F95CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination of authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority of the Secretary to provide technical assistance under this Act terminates on the date that is 15 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H636250D4336B47F7932DB87693A5983C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Local coordinating entity authorities</header><text>For purposes of implementing the management plan, the local coordinating entity may—</text> <paragraph id="H7FEBE48849F247B4BC5C6B9D83D0B5D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make grants to the State or a political subdivision of the State, Tribes, nonprofit organizations, and other persons;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H288B53F86761473E8C4187F2BEFA7CB5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enter into cooperative agreements with, or provide technical assistance to, Federal agencies, the State or political subdivisions of the State, Tribes, nonprofit organizations, and other interested parties;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC48426E0D69844ECAF7CC574C50DF34D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>hire and compensate staff, including individuals with expertise in natural, cultural, historical, scenic, and recreational resource protection and heritage programming;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83FC054A35A947DE8D87B47C6104231C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>obtain money or services from any source, including any money or services that are provided under any other Federal law or program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B8A176A843D4B3FABB9EB4BBE25C2E4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>contract for goods or services; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF26459727E2648BAA44A17C3B267B416"><enum>(6)</enum><text>undertake to be a catalyst for other activities that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H997537A92EA14DFE81C0D6CCE82DDEF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>further the purposes of the Heritage Area; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04994C24BFB343018DFF1D6CE162C150"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are consistent with the management plan.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4570D3E257C84CFD90727C877373FF09"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Local coordinating entity duties</header><text>The local coordinating entity shall—</text> <paragraph id="HAD845E86522145278FC960649EB241E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in accordance with section 5, prepare and submit a management plan to the Secretary;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD672CBA7F1464FEF8FD95F46D30EF3D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assist units of Federal, State, and local government, Tribes, regional planning organizations, nonprofit organizations, and other interested parties in carrying out the approved management plan by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBA8DA9ED1B4E4E79BE9DF4863E2B03C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carrying out programs and projects that recognize, protect, and enhance important resource values in the Heritage Area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7772EBF2C85945F99815D56DB5FEFE30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing and maintaining interpretive exhibits and programs in the Heritage Area;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A9437DD2AC041B6A0A2B88020A48526"><enum>(C)</enum><text>developing recreational and educational opportunities in the Heritage Area; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20E675BFF5324438849DF7705969316B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>increasing public awareness of, and appreciation for, the natural, cultural, historical, Tribal, scenic, and recreational resources of the Heritage Area;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5B32DA980364DBFAF4AB4D9263777D1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consider the interests of diverse units of government, Tribes, business, organizations, and individuals in the Heritage Area in the preparation and implementation of the management plan;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H465998F547B54208B90FD6179FFD70D9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>conduct meetings open to the public at least semiannually regarding the development and implementation of the management plan;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0C3EF0E78084DD4A83DDFBC5C9FB69B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourage, by appropriate means, economic viability that is consistent with the Heritage Area; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC47CC5EEA8804231A5B1BB394C0D6C8A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit a report to the Secretary every five years after the Secretary has approved the management plan, specifying—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4E6EECED8DDC4932A3B3D01BC2956D35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the expenses and income of the local coordinating entity; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H763E9241E744429790A436F4D994CD5A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">significant grants or contracts made by the local coordinating entity to any other entity over the 5-year period that describes the activities, expenses, and income of the local coordinating entity (including grants from the local coordinating entity to any other entity during the year that the report is made).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8039ACE6FE8045E8B6D88CA8E6E5DFBA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on acquisition of real property</header><text>The local coordinating entity may not acquire real property or interest in real property through condemnation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9D6BBAEFD961484D83422A3A5DF07C23"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of federal funds</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall preclude the local coordinating entity from using Federal funds available under other laws for the purposes for which those funds were authorized.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H7D9ADF27A97A406BACB47C1DA131D29A"><enum>7.</enum><header>Relationship to Tribal governments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall construe, define, waive, limit, affect any rights of any federally recognized Indian tribe and the Federal trust responsibility.</text>
		</section><section id="HEBC3FEFEDE644FACA1B5BBBA7E2AF04A"><enum>8.</enum><header>Relationship to other Federal agencies</header>
 <subsection id="HB1110F5D6D7F4704AF26170700428E4B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects the authority of a Federal agency to provide technical or financial assistance under any other law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDE941C88B3814EBFB137820AFF405197"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation and coordination</header><text>Any Federal agency planning to conduct activities that may have an impact on the Heritage Area is encouraged to consult and coordinate the activities with the local coordinating entity to the maximum extent practicable.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H34A46B4EB6DB4D74B9B3AF8AEBB70155"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other federal agencies</header><text>Nothing in this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H249D4EBA77DA4153A5290528CA3D27BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>modifies, alters, or amends any law or regulation authorizing a Federal agency to manage Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Federal agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB8F6F26E41764349B11B169F4571D5C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>limits the discretion of a Federal land manager to implement an approved land use plan within the boundaries of the Heritage Area; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H151647E2B7BE4729BBA94A0E853FFF83"><enum>(3)</enum><text>modifies, alters, or amends any authorized use of Federal land under the jurisdiction of a Federal agency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H746C6473CB14456A8B53657533BD1709"><enum>9.</enum><header>Private property and regulatory protections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, the proposed Mountains to Sound Greenway National Heritage Area, or resulting Plan shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA6CF7BFDFEDB4464BF257D9A69DB1524"><enum>(1)</enum><text>abridge the rights of any owner of public or private property, including the right to refrain from participating in any plan, project, program, or activity conducted within the Heritage Area;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0557509FE5A64FF7B6539F27FB04F86B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require any property owner—</text> <subparagraph id="HB845AE723C774C8EBB6BA46256E7A0A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to allow public access (including access by Federal, State, or local agencies) to the property of the property owner; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD24CC18D037F47A29458A931A5427A71"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to modify public access or use of property of the property owner under any other Federal, State, or local law;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEFBD22E3EDC461CA20AA725B10E1FDD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>alter any duly adopted land use regulation, approved land use plan, or other regulatory authority of any Federal, State, Tribal, or local agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DEA1768A7794CB6838B1500282114DB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>convey any land use or other regulatory authority to the local coordinating entity, including but not necessarily limited to development and management of energy or water or water-related infrastructure;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA73931E1080540D69F11850A7C66D862"><enum>(5)</enum><text>authorize or imply the reservation or appropriation of water or water rights;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE7AECB819EF7406DBDFE694E40CA8A6D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>diminish the authority of the State to manage fish and wildlife, including the regulation of fishing and hunting within the Heritage Area or the authority of Tribes to regulate their members with respect to such matters in the exercise of Tribal treaty rights;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8FAE0C5893544B2E82D1CBB71352E640"><enum>(7)</enum><text>create any liability, or affects any liability under any other law, of any private property owner with respect to any person injured on the private property;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2FCA064BC5704A29B6EFC8C75DED989C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>affect current or future grazing permits, leases, or allotment on Federal lands; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H19793BCB805C4E4DADA136ECF6F5C9D5"><enum>(9)</enum><text>affect the construction, operation, maintenance or expansion of current or future water projects, including water storage, hydroelectric facilities, or delivery systems.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H191D70DC8E6A4148834362958F8353FA"><enum>10.</enum><header>Evaluation and report</header>
 <subsection id="H9E0D32D9540A45C195FE72DABD1203D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 15 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HD8E0B1B91A0D4593BD1D4E8472A4AF54"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct an evaluation of the accomplishments of the Heritage Area; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9B926B2285A4BE4BBAE5D890DF378E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prepare a report in accordance with subsection (c).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB4FE2E25B4EB4AC28BA3CD97E1CF241E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>An evaluation conducted under subsection (a)(1) shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H331252DF2E504B48A53E97875164CEC8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assess the progress of the local coordinating entity with respect to—</text> <subparagraph id="HDCEB3C784F8E4C78BAA6C8D27F1B9FB0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accomplishing the purposes of the Heritage Area; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC20DDFBD69D64A5A8F23B8E36773947C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>achieving the goals and objectives of the management plan;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H88C5E301E8834BD8BEEDD520829D10FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>analyze the investments of Federal, State, Tribal, and local governments and private entities in the Heritage Area to determine the impact of the investments; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9BDEBB18176E43F188F69A137E37D55D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>review the management structure, partnership relationships, and funding of the Heritage Area for purposes of identifying the critical components for sustainability of the Heritage Area.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H74A0B760554943AD99BC51789A071C44"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Based on the evaluation conducted under subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report that includes recommendations for the future role of the National Park Service with respect to the Heritage Area.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


