<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H16B9FCFF561546FB885B9ED2CC1FBD05" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2536 IH: Renew America’s Schools Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2536</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170518">May 18, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for grants for energy efficiency improvements and renewable energy improvements at
			 public school facilities.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H68B9E88F223B4297B434A0A9AB750D59" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE19B6C19434E4AE1B099D1A892BA5AA4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Renew America’s Schools Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6AB2D4CD754D4D2BBBB22F0B688B72E6" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for energy efficiency improvements and renewable energy improvements at public school facilities</header> <subsection id="H1D6B32EBB5E247A8BD3D1BC6F51A1237"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H84AFCBDC0DAC42F4BAFDEFB05F1989BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a consortium of—</text> <subparagraph id="HD79DA36BF6124056A42508715DA838A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>one local educational agency; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE1C818B0E904DED9716F9AA7F9CF018"><enum>(B)</enum><text>one or more—</text> <clause id="H12A823E8E1294D758A25D91BBDC1AE56"><enum>(i)</enum><text>schools;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE91CDFD2B8E94677BF117E43AFA156F4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>nonprofit organizations;</text> </clause><clause id="H045AA21B5C9E4E4C85C9BE2921135BB4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for-profit organizations; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H61218A0A42B844018C215043D4211A89"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>community partners that have the knowledge and capacity to partner and assist with energy improvements.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H03F926BEFF8D4B78B652574FF6B5503A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Energy improvements</header><text>The term <term>energy improvements</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HCE5A45AECBFA4DF781C56FC191C28080"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any improvement, repair, or renovation, to a school that will result in a direct reduction in school energy costs including but not limited to improvements to building envelope, air conditioning, ventilation, heating system, domestic hot water heating, compressed air systems, distribution systems, lighting, power systems and controls;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BE3EB5C5A114F359D5C56F821F12113"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any improvement, repair, renovation, or installation that leads to an improvement in teacher and student health including but not limited to indoor air quality, daylighting, ventilation, electrical lighting, and acoustics; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB74D90D77E414ECBA929EDD909A921B1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the installation of renewable energy technologies (such as wind power, photovoltaics, solar thermal systems, geothermal energy, hydrogen-fueled systems, biomass-based systems, biofuels, anaerobic digesters, and hydropower) involved in the improvement, repair, or renovation to a school.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1225234597084D73A2E0441FD3787C47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>From amounts made available for grants under this section, the Secretary of Energy shall provide competitive grants to eligible entities to make energy improvements authorized by this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8DD4CAC07CEE4E4EBA00F6342BBC5A11"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making grants under this subsection, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that have renovation, repair, and improvement funding needs and are—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDA805D9DE96149B49E120AC5A6A7F893"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a high-need local educational agency, as defined in section 2102 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6602">20 U.S.C. 6602</external-xref>); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H002D99359D9F4CB2B42197E3190BF7D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a local educational agency designated with a metrocentric locale code of 41, 42, or 43 as determined by the National Center for Education Statistics (NCES), in conjunction with the Bureau of the Census, using the NCES system for classifying local educational agencies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAF46AF6141F8447AAA9C60058A558E5D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Competitive criteria</header><text>The competitive criteria used by the Secretary shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HBBF97289B30149328708A5468F2F827C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The fiscal capacity of the eligible entity to meet the needs for improvements of school facilities without assistance under this section, including the ability of the eligible entity to raise funds through the use of local bonding capacity and otherwise.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3EBE287FA77C44B0AE31ACF6FA7C70EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The likelihood that the local educational agency or eligible entity will maintain, in good condition, any facility whose improvement is assisted.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD1886DD4C48D4778997862DD928C24A9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The potential energy efficiency and safety benefits from the proposed energy improvements.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4FA5596C4C014FBCBC83ACC1771A61CE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an applicant must submit to the Secretary an application that includes each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7D1F5B7952A34622BB9FEF1EF84C734E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A needs assessment of the current condition of the school and facilities that are to receive the energy improvements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43ADDB59D2E0472785C70225AE9AE32E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A draft work plan of what the applicant hopes to achieve at the school and a description of the energy improvements to be carried out.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F20526EF8A446C8A7ACF8A0F7927F7D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the applicant’s capacity to provide services and comprehensive support to make the energy improvements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4CB408329F04852AF7BB70542BF8700"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of the applicant’s expected needs for operation and maintenance training funds, and a plan for use of those funds, if any.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H42742AE54F0E4FB8B09C1CAF5FAA6DE5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An assessment of the expected energy efficiency and safety benefits of the energy improvements.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H29D11396E13948EDA2C290788724F8BB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A cost estimate of the proposed energy improvements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB6EB651E0B854775AE5A42AFB3D6D048"><enum>(7)</enum><text>An identification of other resources that are available to carry out the activities for which funds are requested under this section, including the availability of utility programs and public benefit funds.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB54C92FCB8DD4E309BAD6CFAAA1F9207"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of grant amounts</header>
 <paragraph id="H123D6A26B4334820AF408AA68565F968"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The recipient of a grant under this section shall use the grant amounts only to make the energy improvements contemplated in the application, subject to the other provisions of this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE04A5469CEAB482B86AC25760D624437"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Operation and maintenance training</header><text>The recipient may use up to 5 percent for operation and maintenance training for energy efficiency and renewable energy improvements (such as maintenance staff and teacher training, education, and preventative maintenance training).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H401F0080A5F749B680A4A936074FCD6F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Audit</header><text>The recipient may use funds for a third-party investigation and analysis for energy improvements (such as energy audits and existing building commissioning).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F3E96752320457D9E9ED523D424DD04"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Continuing education</header><text>The recipient may use up to 1 percent of the grant amounts to develop a continuing education curriculum relating to energy improvements.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEE125DA8E7C74E71AA3323A7CFD18D28"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Contracting requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="H73CD92344E434AFE9FEEF9273C70EFE0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Davis-Bacon</header><text>Any laborer or mechanic employed by any contractor or subcontractor in the performance of work on any energy improvements funded by a grant under this section shall be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on similar construction in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor under subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code (commonly referred to as the Davis-Bacon Act).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H19D8F2EA037E4F4D9D145E7C39C23DF1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Competition</header><text>Each applicant that receives funds shall ensure that, if the applicant carries out repair or renovation through a contract, any such contract process—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1CB6EBF142944E5F83E5F91134D3EF7E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensures the maximum number of qualified bidders, including small, minority, and women-owned businesses, through full and open competition; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08D75216C5794A98AFF8FBCDFD74B9F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>gives priority to businesses located in, or resources common to, the State or the geographical area in which the project is carried out.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7453CC0335114215814F2DB56FE1EA6D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Each recipient of a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary, at such time as the Secretary may require, a report describing the use of such funds for energy improvements, the estimated cost savings realized by those energy improvements, the results of any audit, the use of any utility programs and public benefit funds and the use of performance tracking for energy improvements (such as the Department of Energy: Energy Star program or LEED for Existing Buildings).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEF47C54F9A5B4259B7A6786A793B39B8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>The Secretary shall develop and publish guidelines and best practices for activities carried out under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H96EFB413124046EFAAE04077F20F156F"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2023.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


