<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H569349261F4148F9909C437E5BF7B184" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1046 IH: Concrete Masonry Products Research, Education, and Promotion Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1046</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170214">February 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enable concrete masonry products manufacturers to establish, finance, and carry out a
			 coordinated program of research, education, and promotion to improve,
			 maintain, and develop markets for concrete masonry products.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF963FC37A73D47099802D7D96A5D56A4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H28ADF54D5A844848BEE4B96006D0B0FE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Concrete Masonry Products Research, Education, and Promotion Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HEC740616949C4A0C9749D29EC856DC41"><enum>2.</enum><header>Declaration of policy</header> <subsection id="HC6AD35A30E544BE0AC288EF8C096C2A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to authorize the establishment of an orderly program for developing, financing, and carrying out an effective, continuous, and coordinated program of research, education, and promotion, including funds for marketing and market research activities, that is designed to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBE1DFDA4C36248529278B0686F904E8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>strengthen the position of the concrete masonry products industry in the domestic marketplace;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H39D8BA54BAC741A3BBABF005E1C77C60"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintain, develop, and expand markets and uses for concrete masonry products in the domestic marketplace; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H89FAB1A33A994A04BF8913FFA8EB3CFC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promote the use of concrete masonry products in construction and building.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA6239DA8E5B64CAAAF89247EBD7BA99E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to provide for the control of production or otherwise limit the right of any person to manufacture concrete masonry products.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HEAB6B413FABF473C9C9743E06851AA08"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H71FFFC6D1F9D461A8D69E6435B1337B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Block machine</header><text>The term <term>block machine</term> means a piece of equipment that utilizes vibration and compaction to form concrete masonry products.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA5314A24A074E18982C80EF2B2F07FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Board</header><text>The term <term>Board</term> means the Concrete Masonry Products Board established under <internal-xref idref="HE224A076A9CA4AABA373E7049BCFC057" legis-path="5.">section 5</internal-xref>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7BB03FA47E0648ECAE4C155C2D5EE9DC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cavity</header><text>The term <term>cavity</term> means the open space in the mold of a block machine capable of forming a single concrete masonry unit having nominal plan dimensions of 8 inches by 16 inches.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0FC6F72A3C642FBA5F7EE3032AC45A6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Concrete masonry products</header><text>The term <term>concrete masonry products</term> refers to a broader class of products, including concrete masonry units as well as hardscape products such as concrete pavers and segmental retaining wall units, manufactured on a block machine using dry-cast concrete.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H66BF31131115439C8ABEDA533473D56F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Concrete masonry unit</header><text>The term <term>concrete masonry unit</term> means a concrete masonry product that is a manmade masonry unit having an actual width of 3 inches or greater and manufactured from dry-cast concrete using a block machine. Such term includes concrete block and related concrete units used in masonry applications.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0A1A014C8934E568FAD1F161FEE8A3A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Conflict of interest</header><text>The term <term>conflict of interest</term> means, with respect to a member or employee of the Board, a situation in which such member or employee has a direct or indirect financial or other interest in a person that performs a service for, or enters into a contract with, for anything of economic value.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70A4484A4C8B445FB3BE28DEDE68AB46"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Commerce.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEBBB01CDC662410D8F7F926E4BDF7D05"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Dry-Cast concrete</header><text>The term <term>dry-cast concrete</term> means a composite material that is composed essentially of aggregates embedded in a binding medium composed of a mixture of cementitious materials (including hydraulic cement, pozzolans, or other cementitious materials) and water of such a consistency to maintain its shape after forming in a block machine.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA60E6D91120A41DC97AEA47246512104"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>education</term> means programs that will educate or communicate the benefits of concrete masonry products in safe and environmentally sustainable development, advancements in concrete masonry product technology and development, and other information and programs designed to generate increased demand for commercial, residential, multifamily, and institutional projects using concrete masonry products and to generally enhance the image of concrete masonry products.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDC11FFE3EC41470B88721D8D435555D1"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Machine cavities</header><text>The term <term>machine cavities</term> means the cavities with which a block machine could be equipped.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H223D4A5DBE9B472E8060B5E1C715147D"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Machine cavities in operation</header><text>The term <term>machine cavities in operation</term> means those machine cavities associated with a block machine that have produced concrete masonry units within the last 6 months of the date set for determining eligibility and is fully operable and capable of producing concrete masonry units.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H220E940CD5E7432EA53D3EFBB3FBF310"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Manufacturer</header><text>The term <term>manufacturer</term> means any person engaged in the manufacturing of commercial concrete masonry products in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7868E67417444CCF80192BC2B1506AF9"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Masonry unit</header><text>The term <term>masonry unit</term> means a noncombustible building product intended to be laid by hand or joined using mortar, grout, surface bonding, post-tensioning or some combination of these methods.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF61AEC778C5F4839A75DF3567284ED7A"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Order</header><text>The term <term>order</term> means an order issued under section 4.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H89B2836ECBB74E698E957F30DBFA7B81"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means any individual, group of individuals, partnership, corporation, association, cooperative, or any other entity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8FE3D634F234E1AB258B2A33FEDDFC7"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Promotion</header><text>The term <term>promotion</term> means any action, including paid advertising, to advance the image and desirability of concrete masonry products with the express intent of improving the competitive position and stimulating sales of concrete masonry products in the marketplace.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD7AAC2A7B7C42FD82CFE8443310E957"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Research</header><text>The term <term>research</term> means studies testing the effectiveness of market development and promotion efforts, studies relating to the improvement of concrete masonry products and new product development, and studies documenting the performance of concrete masonry.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H64AB0803DD474A77831C679B568910DF"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H98D9B4A6263E41CA9383A8901F341D66"><enum>(19)</enum><header>United States</header><text>The term <term>United States</term> means the several States and the District of Columbia.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H07A02A2E2FF84846B68E0A49BC607AAA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Issuance of orders</header>
			<subsection id="H95BC17613C544F058127C5D00C24AC37"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="H9839ADF96F934685B0F96F3C5D7CCF73"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Issuance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, subject to the procedures provided in <internal-xref idref="HB081C332783244558BD430F35E12428F" legis-path="4.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>, shall issue orders under this Act applicable to manufacturers of concrete masonry products.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CF9126A52DD40458D9A539982C66DE1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>Any order shall be national in scope.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5DA7318C4E84CD1BC07A60213796794"><enum>(3)</enum><header>One order</header><text>Not more than one order shall be in effect at any one time.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB081C332783244558BD430F35E12428F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procedures</header> <paragraph id="H2B92A9001F494CCAAFE368937C0C02F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development or receipt of proposed order</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A proposed order with respect to the generic research, education, and promotion with regards to concrete masonry products may be—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H33A09C3985E644149D98C22C277059BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>proposed by the Secretary at any time; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A31CFFE5C8D4778B1835E24EC1E5F38"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requested by or submitted to the Secretary by—</text>
 <clause id="HF7500F1A4DB84BBA839DFD486C7CE9F7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an existing national organization of concrete masonry product manufacturers; or</text> </clause><clause id="H3DDA9DB5DA634BF78FE3CA8AD972A82F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any person that may be affected by the issuance of an order.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED7851297C514F18BC11469673DE52A9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication of proposed order</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines that a proposed order received in accordance with paragraph (1)(B) is consistent with and will effectuate the purpose of this Act, the Secretary shall publish such proposed order in the Federal Register not later than 90 days after receiving the order, and give not less than 30 days notice and opportunity for public comment on the proposed order.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HE75C59072F9541C08FCED8561F54BCDA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Issuance of order</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2A56DF8611444453B8A388448CEE9B88"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After notice and opportunity for public comment are provided in accordance with <internal-xref idref="HED7851297C514F18BC11469673DE52A9" legis-path="4.(b)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref>, the Secretary shall issue the order, taking into consideration the comments received and including in the order such provisions as are necessary to ensure that the order is in conformity with this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H378A9825B72D49939E0C070F979C5983"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If there is an affirmative vote in a referendum as provided in <internal-xref idref="HB8685325B1F74D62B84970055F3B691A" legis-path="7.">section 7</internal-xref>, the Secretary shall issue the order and such order shall be effective not later than 140 days after publication of the proposed order.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C79CC1929204016BCC51A820C8786F7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text>The Secretary may, from time to time, amend an order. The provisions of this Act applicable to an order shall be applicable to any amendment to an order.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE224A076A9CA4AABA373E7049BCFC057"><enum>5.</enum><header>Required terms in orders</header>
 <subsection id="H253EC08D07CE4356BF798E701B85F4A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any order issued under this Act shall contain the terms and provisions specified in this section.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H01140E713E2D4C2E950DCF76806E2C02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Concrete Masonry Products Board</header> <paragraph id="HFD88747526CF46EB94CCD1A111651704"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment and membership</header> <subparagraph id="H51910105E5D144B5B61DD2C92F914CF3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The order shall provide for the establishment of a Concrete Masonry Products Board to carry out a program of generic promotion, research, and education regarding concrete masonry products.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF5727DE043946CB94842EEE2C003D8A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <clause id="HC173B866FE344120B8718CC8779EF266"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Number of members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall consist of not less than 15 and not more than 25 members.</text> </clause><clause id="HB242476C24C8467182B6A81F5714E3C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The members of the Board shall be appointed by the Secretary from nominations submitted as provided in the order.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB03498FF94E8407590EB7145667BC412"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Board shall consist of manufacturers. No employee of an industry trade organization exempt from tax under paragraph (3) or (6) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">26 U.S.C. 501(c)</external-xref>) representing the concrete masonry industry or related industries shall serve as a member of the Board and no member of the Board may serve concurrently as an officer of the board of directors of a national concrete masonry products industry trade association. Only two individuals from any single company or its affiliates may serve on the Board at any one time.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2006D41F015F464C9EB97835B86A7497"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distribution of appointments</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2D86B36123EF4E5AB9B4073FF4F7DB02"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Representation</header><text>To ensure fair and equitable representation of the concrete masonry products industry, the composition of the Board shall reflect the geographical distribution of the manufacture of concrete masonry products in the United States, the types of concrete masonry products manufactured, and the range in size of manufacturers in the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD21E2E726ED94092B366CC6FFEB15BF2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Adjustment in board representation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Three years after the assessment of concrete masonry products commences pursuant to an order, and at the end of each 3-year period thereafter, the Board, subject to the review and approval of the Secretary, shall, if warranted, recommend to the Secretary the reapportionment of the Board membership to reflect changes in the geographical distribution of the manufacture of concrete masonry products and the types of concrete masonry products manufactured.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A942E3F7FCF4ACF9191BE5547173579"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nominations Process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may make appointments from nominations by manufacturers pursuant to the method set forth in the order.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7912733B6F6A43FABBF033DD8F8D45BF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Failure to appoint</header><text>If the Secretary fails to make an appointment to the Board within 60 days of receiving nominations for such appointment, the first nominee for such appointment shall be deemed appointed, unless the Secretary provides reasonable justification for the delay to the Board and to Congress and provides a reasonable date by which approval or disapproval will be made.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5401C31C835640038D0609C71E162C06"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Alternates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The order shall provide for the selection of alternate members of the Board by the Secretary in accordance with procedures specified in the order.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H88919C99D58D46A9B5375A3C205523BD"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Terms</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2CD190E12A04446E95E9EAB48DB945DB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members and any alternates of the Board shall each serve for a term of 3 years, except that members and any alternates initially appointed to the Board shall serve for terms of not more than 2, 3, and 4 years, as specified by the order.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EAA1179D2D4410F858CCEC9B5C29933"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on consecutive terms</header><text>A member or an alternate may serve not more than 2 consecutive terms.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8141154474F24733B48BFED569E2AB49"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Continuation of term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding <internal-xref idref="H6EAA1179D2D4410F858CCEC9B5C29933" legis-path="5.(b)(5)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref>, each member or alternate shall continue to serve until a successor is appointed by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H762EFC8FD89442CEA3DD59F91DEECCFD"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>A vacancy arising before the expiration of a term of office of an incumbent member or alternate of the Board shall be filled in a manner provided for in the order.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H47B3F335E92A42E5A4847356BE55F74C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Disqualification from Board service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The order shall provide that if a member or alternate of the Board who was appointed as a manufacturer ceases to qualify as a manufacturer, such member or alternate shall be disqualified from serving on the Board.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H96AC9D46A1134ADAA768DBBE801BFADF"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Compensation</header>
 <subparagraph id="H4892D2E394B0496A95763D2016904EB0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Members and any alternates of the Board shall serve without compensation.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20A9B2C873D44AFAA564B198DC07CE13"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>If approved by the Board, members or alternates shall be reimbursed for reasonable travel expenses, which may include per diem allowance or actual subsistence incurred while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Board.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H287CA7C5B61E4FD0A2A791CCD8E0EB0E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Powers and duties of the Board</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The order shall specify the powers and duties of the Board, including the power and duty—</text> <paragraph id="HADFC4631B8FE49F2B69E918F510AAF87"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to administer the order in accordance with its terms and conditions and to collect assessments;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H725EB976D6B546A29703331FF678914F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop and recommend to the Secretary for approval such bylaws as may be necessary for the functioning of the Board and such rules as may be necessary to administer the order, including activities authorized to be carried out under the order;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D0E2388497E4E2680231C81FAE06DB2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to meet, organize, and select from among members of the Board a chairperson, other officers, and committees and subcommittees, as the Board determines appropriate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1327AD4FB81A4474BF6E5F87B8782B50"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to establish regional organizations or committees to administer regional initiatives;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H30AD1DB239CA4C52ACC5104B5F3F9F9B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to establish working committees of persons other than Board members;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7E16C61A2374FF09956EFA553F337E5"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to employ such persons, other than the members, as the Board considers necessary, and to determine the compensation and specify the duties of the persons;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5BF660500C6945D68011C16223428FBC"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prepare and submit for the approval of the Secretary, before the beginning of each fiscal year, rates of assessment under <internal-xref idref="H8984C0519981491BA8BE422877B390B0" legis-path="6.">section 6</internal-xref> and an annual budget of the anticipated expenses to be incurred in the administration of the order, including the probable cost of each promotion, research, and information activity proposed to be developed or carried out by the Board;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1071BC9DACDC4B2C9D4A6DF93379865D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to borrow funds necessary for the startup expenses of the order;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6391DD73FB4046DA8B9F05C18857C428"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to carry out generic research, education, and promotion programs and projects relating to concrete masonry products, and to pay the costs of such programs and projects with assessments collected under <internal-xref idref="H8984C0519981491BA8BE422877B390B0" legis-path="6.">section 6</internal-xref>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H35260DFAC63C43BCA003F27419BD76DA"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to <internal-xref idref="H74BB0088ECBC438BA092270AD65C9514" legis-path="5.(e)">subsection (e)</internal-xref>, to enter into contracts or agreements to develop and carry out programs or projects of research, education, and promotion relating to concrete masonry products;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61B2DDDE8E484CF1B3781DC0412369A2"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to keep minutes, books, and records that reflect the actions and transactions of the Board, and promptly report minutes of each Board meeting to the Secretary;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1B3406B7CEB4578902E7B58C1465E4C"><enum>(12)</enum><text>to receive, investigate, and report to the Secretary complaints of violations of the order;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0634989FCC054C0AA90708D516BEA4C0"><enum>(13)</enum><text>to furnish the Secretary with such information as the Secretary may request;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H06757E057B72404DA6B5B48143D541AF"><enum>(14)</enum><text>to recommend to the Secretary such amendments to the order as the Board considers appropriate; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF6648CE1DC04DA5A808AFA0F1662D50"><enum>(15)</enum><text>to provide the Secretary with advance notice of meetings to permit the Secretary or the Secretary’s representative to attend the meetings.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC2AEC08A573442928907FDA1F192A3DB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Programs and projects; budgets; expenses</header>
				<paragraph id="H38818A97CA7A4DC5859C79D0E40E78B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Programs and projects</header>
 <subparagraph id="HEFD16CCCE95C46798E450099238F6005"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The order shall require the Board to submit to the Secretary for approval any program or project of research, education, or promotion relating to concrete masonry products.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA2230CECAC2409FACBFB60F0EF2548E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Statement required</header><text>Any educational or promotional activity undertaken with funds provided by the Board shall include a statement that such activities were supported in whole or in part by the Board.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H84D16C35700944FD8107D4CE077A94B3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Budgets</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2BC5581B5081470A994D3A914B4AEC99"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>The order shall require the Board to submit to the Secretary for approval a budget of the anticipated expenses and disbursements of the Board in the implementation of the order, including the projected costs of concrete masonry products research, education, and promotion programs and projects.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30AA6E95F50D46B6914A1D9D7F221C29"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The budget shall be submitted before the beginning of a fiscal year and as frequently as may be necessary after the beginning of the fiscal year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB9B1A20965F4DD6B20F505D9B4C8CBC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary fails to approve or reject a budget within 60 days of receipt, such budget shall be deemed approved, unless the Secretary provides to the Board and to Congress, in writing, reasonable justification for the delay and provides a reasonable date by which approval or disapproval will be made.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H829D41CA21E445A381504657E8A36F00"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administrative Expenses</header>
 <subparagraph id="HBA907A03AA5F46739E2F28FA60852535"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Incurring expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board may incur the expenses described in <internal-xref idref="H84D16C35700944FD8107D4CE077A94B3" legis-path="5.(d)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref> and other expenses for the administration, maintenance, and functioning of the Board as authorized by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H75EEECE877DE4911BE8BFF21B562CC5D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Payment of expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expenses incurred under <internal-xref idref="HBA907A03AA5F46739E2F28FA60852535" legis-path="5.(d)(3)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> shall be paid by the Board using assessments collected under <internal-xref idref="H8984C0519981491BA8BE422877B390B0" legis-path="6.">section 6</internal-xref>, earnings obtained from assessments, and other income of the Board. Any funds borrowed by the Board shall be expended only for startup costs and capital outlays.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C369D0CDE7D4CDD9B77E83468FE3A96"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation on spending</header><text>For fiscal years beginning 3 or more years after the date of the establishment of the Board, the Board may not expend for administration (except for reimbursement to the Secretary required under <internal-xref idref="H3FFAFFEA25C34D0CBA3C0A43E348AC9F" legis-path="5.(d)(3)(D)">subparagraph (D)</internal-xref>), maintenance, and functioning of the Board in a fiscal year an amount that exceeds 10 percent of the assessment and other income received by the Board for the fiscal year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FFAFFEA25C34D0CBA3C0A43E348AC9F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Reimbursement of Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The order shall require that the Secretary be reimbursed by the Board from assessments for all expenses incurred by the Secretary in the implementation, administration, and supervision of the order, including all referenda costs incurred in connection with the order.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H74BB0088ECBC438BA092270AD65C9514"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Contracts and agreements</header>
 <paragraph id="H3739ED1A0798434EA1C8DE74CAB4FF76"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The order shall provide that, with the approval of the Secretary, the Board may—</text> <subparagraph id="H5BD6FA0662B6436798C6774A52AA0AEA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enter into contracts and agreements to carry out generic research, education, and promotion programs and projects relating to concrete masonry products, including contracts and agreements with manufacturer associations or other entities as considered appropriate by the Secretary;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AAA9F24431D44919739618395BCE895"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enter into contracts and agreements for administrative services; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE29DBC2E8D85455B8743119DFF3C1CFC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>pay the cost of approved generic research, education, and promotion programs and projects using assessments collected under <internal-xref idref="H8984C0519981491BA8BE422877B390B0" legis-path="6.">section 6</internal-xref>, earnings obtained from assessments, and other income of the Board.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H98C652936F89413E8BC66A08004DFBD2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Each contract or agreement shall provide that any person who enters into the contract or agreement with the Board shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4D1079684F3D4DCE9B79607BC2D29FB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop and submit to the Board a proposed program or project together with a budget that specifies the cost to be incurred to carry out the program or project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BF3535452F14FE397136E879DDA379B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>keep accurate records of all transactions relating to the contract or agreement;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80665831E79C4022904C10BD39799665"><enum>(C)</enum><text>account for funds received and expended in connection with the contract or agreement;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7E1891AC6E74911B4CC72DB850486E3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>make periodic reports to the Board of activities conducted under the contract or agreement; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3DC1425266D464481069C2A97BF2A3E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>make such other reports as the Board or the Secretary considers relevant.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H01B474671A8240ACAB0148656A0753E1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Failure to approve</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary fails to approve or reject a contract or agreement entered into under <internal-xref idref="H3739ED1A0798434EA1C8DE74CAB4FF76" legis-path="5.(e)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> within 60 days of receipt, the contract or agreement shall be deemed approved, unless the Secretary provides to the Board and to Congress, in writing, reasonable justification for the delay and provides a reasonable date by which approval or disapproval will be made.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF80CC08A7824FBEA3DBB8D3D346B3A3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Books and records of Board</header>
 <paragraph id="H13DFA93C61C94282A8702A32AF494C4A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The order shall require the Board to—</text> <subparagraph id="H1213D3C44F99457A86393F9B2F50ADB3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain such books and records (which shall be available to the Secretary for inspection and audit) as the Secretary may require;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A42563A915842E2B3B7B31207E23C28"><enum>(B)</enum><text>collect and submit to the Secretary, at any time the Secretary may specify, any information the Secretary may request; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DC526EBBC94486DA4B0254BF0CB5F74"><enum>(C)</enum><text>account for the receipt and disbursement of all funds in the possession, or under the control, of the Board.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9434583A034B456DA70C8AB78EAB5A46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Audits</header><text>The order shall require the Board to have—</text> <subparagraph id="HE88E12A00A9447478F33F71CB2EB1F4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the books and records of the Board audited by an independent auditor at the end of each fiscal year; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H243C4BF9B0EC4831987C08AF773FC5CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a report of the audit submitted directly to the Secretary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H972AAAAD2A134F909E86F3262886D414"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Prohibited activities</header> <paragraph id="H8F18671D72244859930C348124058870"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to <internal-xref idref="HDC31DD0769DD40D5883F4C948A824355" legis-path="5.(g)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref>, the Board shall not engage in any program or project to, nor shall any funds received by the Board under this Act be used to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H501EDD1962C14B52AC5EF12711C731E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>influence legislation, elections, or governmental action;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09707BC9544A4016A30CEAD99A6C89F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engage in an action that would be a conflict of interest;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54E7FD9AB5C74BF7A121B880BE40668C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>engage in advertising that is false or misleading;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EDCFA5258964C9283D6B054F2BBBE28"><enum>(D)</enum><text>engage in any promotion, research, or education that would be disparaging to other construction materials; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H408F362775EF4F78978A9F913F617FDA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>engage in any promotion or project that would benefit any individual manufacturer.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC31DD0769DD40D5883F4C948A824355"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text><internal-xref idref="H8F18671D72244859930C348124058870" legis-path="5.(g)(1)">Paragraph (1)</internal-xref> does not preclude—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF24F8F53E6984C86871245B7D907B373"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the development and recommendation of amendments to the order;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BED71C7144C4283AB3710EDD3E6ECB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the communication to appropriate government officials of information relating to the conduct, implementation, or results of research, education, and promotion activities under the order except communications described in paragraph (1)(A); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEFC8C2421844F79BB18AB5F37C6F308"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any lawful action designed to market concrete masonry products directly to a foreign government or political subdivision of a foreign government.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H908EC0CE83064ACF95DFF7BF79F5641E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Periodic evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The order shall require the Board to provide for the independent evaluation of all research, education, and promotion programs or projects undertaken under the order, beginning 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act and every 3 years thereafter. The Board shall submit to the Secretary and make available to the public the results of each such evaluation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBC1A1638293B4147ACA154B8E14AC9EE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>The Board shall establish annual research, education, and promotion objectives and performance metrics for each fiscal year subject to approval by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1D2C37A609644A97B109B6690A57BCE0"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Biennial report</header><text>Every 2 years the Board shall prepare and make publicly available a comprehensive and detailed report that includes an identification and description of all programs and projects undertaken by the Board during the previous 2 years as well as those planned for the subsequent 2 years and detail the allocation or planned allocation of Board resources for each such program or project. Such report shall also include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA28EE48EF010493DAB76512BE4D10866"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Board’s overall financial condition;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H305B8FBDE7FE4CDDB341CFEB3CBC9327"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a summary of the amounts obligated or expended during the 2 preceding fiscal years; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H90C1EC58515F45F891AEB29F3C0F7DDB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of the extent to which the Board’s objectives were met according to the metrics required under subsection (i).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4D9E494EA2484ECB971D49D178509939"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Books and records of persons covered by order</header>
 <paragraph id="H646DA3C60DB24DBB8BAA9EDFA4639F9B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The order shall require that manufacturers shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HAE908AA20C914DB5B609FDF7F42F0323"><enum>(A)</enum><text>maintain records sufficient to ensure compliance with the order and regulations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H662995F1730C43DF90E3B5FFF8A13E85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make the records described in <internal-xref idref="HAE908AA20C914DB5B609FDF7F42F0323" legis-path="5.(i)(1)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> available, during normal business hours, for inspection by employees or agents of the Board or the Department.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H22EBB58DA60A4CBDBFC23C0CFBBC578B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Time requirement</header><text>Any record required to be maintained under <internal-xref idref="H646DA3C60DB24DBB8BAA9EDFA4639F9B" legis-path="5.(i)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> shall be maintained for such time period as the Secretary may prescribe.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H33BB4EB7CE344EF4926CBB31C599342C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Confidentiality of information</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HCE22863B165E4DFDB0ED4C5B4D15D2D3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, trade secrets and commercial or financial information that is privileged or confidential reported to, or otherwise obtained by the Board or the Secretary (or any representative of the Board or the Secretary) under this Act shall not be disclosed by any officers, employees, and agents of the Department or the Board.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCCE5393480D4FDD948089A50C189E35"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Suits and hearings</header><text>Information referred to in <internal-xref idref="HCE22863B165E4DFDB0ED4C5B4D15D2D3" legis-path="5.(i)(4)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> may be disclosed only if—</text> <clause id="HDEFA1539CB694F68A0F0AFF178095452"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary considers the information relevant; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF06DA3377BA54EECA01ADC41F0A63467"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the information is revealed in a judicial proceeding or administrative hearing brought at the direction or on the request of the Secretary or to which the Secretary or any officer of the Department is a party.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA499DBC83BC3412AB5F481BF33E1B038"><enum>(C)</enum><header>General statements and publications</header><text>This paragraph does not prohibit—</text> <clause id="H074F89570ABD4899811520B4D590B0E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the issuance of general statements based on reports or on information relating to a number of persons subject to an order if the statements do not identify the information furnished by any person; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H88889AAD76D645C6B1889CF5457A0B03"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the publication, by direction of the Secretary, of the name of any person violating any order and a statement of the particular provisions of the order violated by the person.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H262201813D5649EA94819557303AE710"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Any officer, employee, or agent of the Department of Commerce or any officer, employee, or agent of the Board who willfully violates this paragraph shall be fined not more than $1,000 and imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DC84457685541AA9E526FBE77FB9BF9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Withholding information</header><text>This subsection does not authorize the withholding of information from Congress.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8984C0519981491BA8BE422877B390B0"><enum>6.</enum><header>Assessments</header> <subsection id="H104BC468ED004717830A92778722B16B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessments</header><text>The order shall provide that assessments shall be paid by a manufacturer if the manufacturer has manufactured concrete masonry products during a period of at least 180 days prior to the date the assessment is to be remitted.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H649D9022529C49B29AE7885EA47F797A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Collection</header>
 <paragraph id="H521693538EA24F5B9AB8833D2A84E36B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Assessments required under the order shall be remitted by the manufacturer to the Board in the manner prescribed by the order.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBCAE85FC041A46ADBF1A2CB3610791B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The order shall provide that assessments required under the order shall be remitted to the Board not less frequently than quarterly.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9407E7E6596D46B1A425623B7FA0900D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Records</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of the remittance of assessments, manufacturers shall identify the total amount due in assessments on all sales receipts, invoices or other commercial documents of sale as a result of the sale of concrete masonry units in a manner as prescribed by the Board to ensure compliance with the order.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H577EB661DF7445868FAC4F010FF41C49"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assessment rates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to assessment rates, the order shall contain the following terms:</text> <paragraph id="H096CD69F58A54EECAFD2B2E25F51A519"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial rate</header><text>The assessment rate on concrete masonry products shall be $0.01 per concrete masonry unit sold.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H01B169C165404EB6A63C4AC592C516D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Changes in the rate</header>
 <subparagraph id="H18D9163DCB074E22B27DC4545FC75056"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authority to change rate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall have the authority to change the assessment rate. A two-thirds majority of voting members of the Board shall be required to approve a change in the assessment rate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC737047F47B4332B717EDF8B196AC90"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on increases</header><text>An increase or decrease in the assessment rate with respect to concrete masonry products may not exceed $0.01 per concrete masonry unit sold.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B2F91859D534D4AA3065F8986A270B7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Maximum rate</header><text>The assessment rate shall not be in excess of $0.05 per concrete masonry unit.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2D38CA325BB4333958645040EF6E2C3"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limitation on frequency of changes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The assessment rate may not be increased or decreased more than once annually.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C652A076A58435BB1132912D796346F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Late-Payment and interest charges</header>
 <paragraph id="H1894C5D538A14DB6B8D0E3A9F68AEF12"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Late-payment and interest charges may be levied on each person subject to the order who fails to remit an assessment in accordance with <internal-xref idref="H649D9022529C49B29AE7885EA47F797A" legis-path="6.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8958E7767B99471997728798FAFB2892"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rate</header><text>The rate for late-payment and interest charges shall be specified by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52FD07338015471FA1ED03C882617B2A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Investment of assessments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pending disbursement of assessments under a budget approved by the Secretary, the Board may invest assessments collected under this section in—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBEA379B99E1A4E4287DFEE0E0D387261"><enum>(1)</enum><text>obligations of the United States or any agency of the United States;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B3ACD2D5815401DAA892A21BA6ADCB1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>general obligations of any State or any political subdivision of a State;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1376C2D6F96A4EA7B1B87E810ACD2C88"><enum>(3)</enum><text>interest-bearing accounts or certificates of deposit of financial institutions that are members of the Federal Reserve System; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C18D3940A3D45B59885A33A66FE109B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>obligations fully guaranteed as to principal and interest by the United States.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H934D8996845E48C39D0F70FB92691F18"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Assessment funds for Regional Initiatives</header> <paragraph id="H51FB4CECCB524143916C719C83A13D41"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The order shall provide that no less than 50 percent of the assessments (less administration expenses) paid by a manufacturer shall be used to support research, education, and promotion programs and projects in support of the geographic region of the manufacturer.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H555A0EE2B09A4C858141FC7D32060935"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Geographic regions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The order shall provide for the following geographic regions:</text> <subparagraph id="HA8301ADF769B4CE1B3D7F1A80D548EE4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Region I shall comprise Connecticut, Delaware, the District of Columbia, Maine, Maryland, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New York, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, Vermont, and West Virginia.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93D7C88250394E7B8D7E2E38C3EDB5E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Region II shall comprise Alabama, Florida, Georgia, Mississippi, North Carolina, South Carolina, Tennessee, and Virginia.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64E582D1A0EB480788D3531112077E29"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Region III shall comprise Illinois, Indiana, Iowa, Kentucky, Michigan, Minnesota, Nebraska, North Dakota, Ohio, South Dakota, and Wisconsin.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CD5C82B859F49288FC766000B14171B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Region IV shall comprise Arizona, Arkansas, Kansas, Louisiana, Missouri, New Mexico, Oklahoma, and Texas.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22D34F2760D54F26AB4B50221D603FDB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Region V shall comprise Alaska, California, Colorado, Hawaii, Idaho, Montana, Nevada, Oregon, Utah, Washington, and Wyoming.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD9CCBC5DF1364B8983E9D5B04CAC3CAE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Adjustment of geographic regions</header><text>The order shall provide that the Secretary may, upon recommendation of the Board, modify the composition of the geographic regions described in <internal-xref idref="H555A0EE2B09A4C858141FC7D32060935" legis-path="6.(f)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB8685325B1F74D62B84970055F3B691A"><enum>7.</enum><header>Referenda</header>
			<subsection id="H42D1416A7C2B4CE9A23FA7C0E917FBCD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial Referendum</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H2F6D2859502A49AB80BF1C25DCEC8C66"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Referendum required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 60-day period immediately preceding the proposed effective date of the order issued under section 4, the Secretary shall conduct a referendum among manufacturers eligible under subsection (b)(2) subject to assessments under <internal-xref idref="H8984C0519981491BA8BE422877B390B0" legis-path="6.">section 6.</internal-xref></text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE57518D81ADF464AAC98B5491590486F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approval of order needed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The order shall become effective only if the Secretary determines that the order has been approved by a majority of manufacturers voting who also represent a majority of the machine cavities in operation of those manufacturers voting in the referendum.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5989E1B6A8924190976D1D47209D8512"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Votes permitted</header>
 <paragraph id="HC55C21A9009C419CB1DD3FB2400BF4B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each manufacturer eligible to vote in a referendum conducted under this section shall be entitled to cast one vote.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7903DDFBF9784428B1F2F39CFEE9FAFD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), a manufacturer shall be considered to be eligible to vote if the manufacturer has manufactured concrete masonry products during a period of at least 180 days prior to the first day of the period during which voting in the referendum will occur.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0EF3FAC8B2E64C98BAE126E20EA69557"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Manner of conducting referenda</header>
 <paragraph id="H8F079B4A5BE94AF4948CC474C6AD96A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Referenda conducted pursuant to this section shall be conducted in a manner determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H39A0FCB19EFF4A1997B8419982F967B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advance registration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A manufacturer who chooses to vote in any referendum conducted under this section shall register with the Secretary prior to the voting period, after receiving notice from the Secretary concerning the referendum under <internal-xref idref="H693970B15F324F5488BE163FE375FC41" legis-path="7.(c)(4)">paragraph (4)</internal-xref>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE6868F50FE93410999A2B9B28BB47BD0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Voting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish procedures for voting in any referendum conducted under this section. The ballots and other information or reports that reveal or tend to reveal the identity or vote of voters shall be strictly confidential.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H693970B15F324F5488BE163FE375FC41"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days before a referendum is conducted under this section with respect to an order, the Secretary shall notify all manufacturers, in such a manner as determined by the Secretary, of the period during which voting in the referendum will occur. The notice shall explain any registration and voting procedures established under this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDEAA4AFABAAF4EDB80B9BEBAB0B3CAA9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Subsequent referenda</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an order is approved in a referendum conducted under <internal-xref idref="H42D1416A7C2B4CE9A23FA7C0E917FBCD" legis-path="7.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, the Secretary shall conduct a subsequent referendum—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H3A9A3FD6EE334A1EA82258AF1CDDD9AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at the request of the Board, subject to the voting requirements of <internal-xref idref="H5989E1B6A8924190976D1D47209D8512" legis-path="7.(b)">subsections (b)</internal-xref> and (c), to ascertain whether eligible manufacturers favor suspension, termination, or continuance of the order; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H40F53801C31145E188C851DED9275049"><enum>(2)</enum><text>effective beginning on the date that is 5 years after the date of the approval of the order, and at 5-year intervals thereafter, at the request of 25 percent or more of the total number of persons eligible to vote under <internal-xref idref="H5989E1B6A8924190976D1D47209D8512" legis-path="7.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H817D7E10A46A4D588A941026394A5598"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Suspension or termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, as a result of a referendum conducted under <internal-xref idref="HDEAA4AFABAAF4EDB80B9BEBAB0B3CAA9" legis-path="7.(d)">subsection (d)</internal-xref>, the Secretary determines that suspension or termination of the order is favored by a majority of all votes cast in the referendum as provided in subsection (a)(2), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H78B28E108A39420C83EBA9B0458511AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the referendum, suspend or terminate, as appropriate, collection of assessments under the order; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC56B9D05003B4D12B234266FC9D5CDAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>suspend or terminate, as appropriate, programs and projects under the order as soon as practicable and in an orderly manner.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC08EC580395C49E99E7D4F2799BC1334"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Costs of referenda</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board established under an order with respect to which a referendum is conducted under this section shall reimburse the Secretary from assessments for any expenses incurred by the Secretary to conduct the referendum.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H7093DDE6B66B4B6B8D315FBCDFE7D55A"><enum>8.</enum><header>Petition and review</header>
			<subsection id="H7220876A0AF64F29B98B09A1BD405110"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Petition</header>
 <paragraph id="HCFC6BD304EB840709D689BA4F427E625"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person subject to an order issued under this Act may file with the Secretary a petition—</text> <subparagraph id="H0CDF185B9AEB4B0884860B3E24AAB22D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>stating that the order, any provision of the order, or any obligation imposed in connection with the order, is not established in accordance with law; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA4EAC49A63F400A9FE0C8C8FFEE094C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requesting a modification of the order or an exemption from the order.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE23420C4A965489A8099B06BF8D6B7B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hearing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall give the petitioner an opportunity for a hearing on the petition, in accordance with regulations issued by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD8A4638AEC2451DB46EB3C091179189"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ruling</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the hearing, the Secretary shall make a ruling on the petition. The ruling shall be final, subject to review as set forth in <internal-xref idref="HE0A17A3DD6CB47DBAFF091A59A3FF473" legis-path="8.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFBF7EA815DD44CB3AFA777D6104426AA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation on petition</header><text>Any petition filed under this subsection challenging an order, any provision of the order, or any obligation imposed in connection with the order, shall be filed not less than 2 years after the effective date of the order, provision, or obligation subject to challenge in the petition.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE0A17A3DD6CB47DBAFF091A59A3FF473"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review</header>
 <paragraph id="HE14EEC7C3240459B834178C09A075AD1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commencement of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The district courts of the United States in any district in which a person who is a petitioner under <internal-xref idref="H7220876A0AF64F29B98B09A1BD405110" legis-path="8.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> resides or conducts business shall have jurisdiction to review the ruling of the Secretary on the petition of the person, if a complaint requesting the review is filed no later than 30 days after the date of the entry of the ruling by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D3B4B4DD0044839A838B72CAAFD1626"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Service of process in proceedings under this subsection shall be conducted in accordance with the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD3E165CE4A9143E2A8956BDFE2DB48C7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Remands</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the court in a proceeding under this subsection determines that the ruling of the Secretary on the petition of the person is not in accordance with law, the court shall remand the matter to the Secretary with directions—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDA3FE5615E6D4ACFB934F01CB85B6FF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to make such ruling as the court shall determine to be in accordance with law; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7109C69FA2AE4E059F63BB621922044C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to take such further action as, in the opinion of the court, the law requires.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8D637528054A48D3A3BE31345174573E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The pendency of proceedings instituted under this section shall not impede, hinder, or delay the Attorney General or the Secretary from obtaining relief under <internal-xref idref="H00EAECDDD3714F5F8CE5480734C0F95A" legis-path="9.">section 9</internal-xref>.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H00EAECDDD3714F5F8CE5480734C0F95A"><enum>9.</enum><header>Enforcement</header>
 <subsection id="HC0B067F48127402A9D3C06E32F239B77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A district court of the United States shall have jurisdiction to enforce, and to prevent and restrain any person from violating, this Act or an order or regulation issued by the Secretary under this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H269A56B2E7094878BDB1FF47192B0FA3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Referral to Attorney General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A civil action authorized to be brought under this section shall be referred to the Attorney General of the United States for appropriate action.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H44EF3FBF798144A4ADB5AEDE62392ACB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil penalties and orders</header>
 <paragraph id="H9F807D02FC564924A6051DF8A3CD2A1B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who willfully violates an order or regulation issued by the Secretary under this Act may be assessed by the Secretary a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for each violation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7050C27E8A5A459296C7E9E4477C36AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Separate offense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each violation and each day during which there is a failure to comply with an order or regulation issued by the Secretary shall be considered to be a separate offense.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H076A11D9B51F4028B78B24AF433F3A0E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cease-and-desist orders</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to, or in lieu of, a civil penalty, the Secretary may issue an order requiring a person to cease and desist from violating the order or regulation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4873C0CA05B44AB5B654EA2BA41AE274"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice and hearing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No order assessing a penalty or cease-and-desist order may be issued by the Secretary under this subsection unless the Secretary provides notice and an opportunity for a hearing on the record with respect to the violation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3293BB10074945BC86AA6FC0B80D38F8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Finality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An order assessing a penalty or a cease-and-desist order issued under this subsection by the Secretary shall be final and conclusive unless the person against whom the order is issued files an appeal from the order with the appropriate district court of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9279F59D58AD4AEB802A0DBE8AC72149"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional remedies</header><text>The remedies provided in this Act shall be in addition to, and not exclusive of, other remedies that may be available.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HF1F96044FADB472C8CADF802AF50EB06"><enum>10.</enum><header>Investigation and power to subpoena</header>
 <subsection id="H7992E74210D34A3A9144BD26800E840A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Investigations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may conduct such investigations as the Secretary considers necessary for the effective administration of this Act, or to determine whether any person has engaged or is engaging in any act that constitutes a violation of this Act or any order or regulation issued under this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HFB3D172AA98148F1A09F53EC6136B73B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subpoenas, oaths, and affirmations</header>
 <paragraph id="H191BC2D5777B4637B8FA8372003F9E4F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Investigations</header><text>For the purpose of conducting an investigation under <internal-xref idref="H7992E74210D34A3A9144BD26800E840A" legis-path="10.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, the Secretary may administer oaths and affirmations, subpoena witnesses, compel the attendance of witnesses, take evidence, and require the production of any records that are relevant to the inquiry. The production of the records may be required from any place in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5867F57CDE25463EB8553A7C0E2D42E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative hearings</header><text>For the purpose of an administrative hearing held under <internal-xref idref="HE23420C4A965489A8099B06BF8D6B7B9" legis-path="8.(a)(2)">section 8(a)(2)</internal-xref> or <internal-xref idref="H4873C0CA05B44AB5B654EA2BA41AE274" legis-path="9.(c)(4)">section 9(c)(4)</internal-xref>, the presiding officer may administer oaths and affirmations, subpoena witnesses, compel the attendance of witnesses, take evidence, and require the production of any records that are relevant to the inquiry. The attendance of witnesses and the production of the records may be required from any place in the United States.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA7207A534F5B40ED801CF4DE6FF86C04"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Aid of courts</header>
 <paragraph id="H006F7DB8DA17446D99DE00CBD9C0399E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of contumacy by, or refusal to obey a subpoena issued under <internal-xref idref="HFB3D172AA98148F1A09F53EC6136B73B" legis-path="10.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref> to, any person, the Secretary may invoke the aid of any court of the United States within the jurisdiction of which the investigation or proceeding is conducted, or where the person resides or conducts business, in order to enforce a subpoena issued under <internal-xref idref="HFB3D172AA98148F1A09F53EC6136B73B" legis-path="10.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83A77B2CFACC4F2DB40C1FEC4B91354C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Order</header><text>The court may issue an order requiring the person referred to in <internal-xref idref="H006F7DB8DA17446D99DE00CBD9C0399E" legis-path="10.(c)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> to comply with a subpoena referred to in <internal-xref idref="H006F7DB8DA17446D99DE00CBD9C0399E" legis-path="10.(c)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C152A5CC7EF4A1F83669731F2247767"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Failure to obey</header><text>Any failure to obey the order of the court may be punished by the court as a contempt of court.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA9974DFBCA6745F289C3D6BCC74DFA76"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Process</header><text>Process in any proceeding under this subsection may be served in the United States judicial district in which the person being proceeded against resides or conducts business, or wherever the person may be found.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEED5D62BFB2B4D788E9953B9D07F8A4B"><enum>11.</enum><header>Suspension or termination</header>
 <subsection id="H790A212656154571A31F170C170D8E4F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mandatory suspension or termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall suspend or terminate an order or a provision of an order if the Secretary finds that an order or provision of an order obstructs or does not tend to effectuate the purpose of this Act, or if the Secretary determines that the order or a provision of an order is not favored by a majority of all votes cast in the referendum as provided in <internal-xref idref="HB8685325B1F74D62B84970055F3B691A" legis-path="7.">section 7(a)(2)</internal-xref>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3D0A6A6B89C14E18A051267B972E4E63"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation of suspension or termination</header><text>If, as a result of a referendum conducted under <internal-xref idref="HB8685325B1F74D62B84970055F3B691A" legis-path="7.">section 7</internal-xref>, the Secretary determines that the order is not approved, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H842FB7FDE33F49F4B42B1AFAC7260381"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 180 days after making the determination, suspend or terminate, as the case may be, collection of assessments under the order; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H329CB8D90814452696B313F05FC3FC48"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as soon as practicable, suspend or terminate, as the case may be, activities under the order in an orderly manner.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAA8B1B988B8F4CD2B42E12C19C2E2F9C"><enum>12.</enum><header>Amendments to orders</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The provisions of this Act applicable to the order shall be applicable to any amendment to the order, except that section 8 shall not apply to an amendment.</text>
 </section><section id="H8BC5202A27DA40D3911B92E387DFDFFC"><enum>13.</enum><header>Effect on other laws</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall not affect or preempt any other Federal or State law authorizing research, education, and promotion relating to concrete masonry products.</text>
 </section><section id="HED1130A8E560419CA75EEF33238AAA26"><enum>14.</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may issue such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this Act and the power vested in the Secretary under this Act.</text>
 </section><section id="H98A8B2AE1966414C9036F42E9DBF7BB1"><enum>15.</enum><header>Limitation on expenditures for administrative expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Funds appropriated to carry out this Act may not be used for the payment of the expenses or expenditures of the Board in administering the order.</text>
		</section><section id="H3BD6157A0DDD448687F1A89AABFABFBA"><enum>16.</enum><header>Limitations on obligation of funds</header>
 <subsection id="HC24DA6FCFAEA4B97A6E72C4F7B23492F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In each fiscal year of the covered period, the Board may not obligate an amount greater than the sum of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6F9F4507CBE844A7B3CDAD5CD384419A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>73 percent of the amount of assessments estimated to be collected under section 6 in such fiscal year;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H36D36A1640954297A0DF443C697F1AF3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>73 percent of the amount of assessments actually collected under section 6 in the most recent fiscal year for which an audit report has been submitted under section 5(f)(2)(B) as of the beginning of the fiscal year for which the amount that may be obligated is being determined, less the estimate made pursuant to paragraph (1) for such most recent fiscal year; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H754F189A2F6A49799B9F6F5E8567212C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>amounts permitted in preceding fiscal years to be obligated pursuant to this subsection that have not been obligated.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H494657A4182C411A8C6DECE85C4320F1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Excess amounts deposited in escrow account</header><text>Assessments collected under section 6 in excess of the amount permitted to be obligated under subsection (a) in a fiscal year shall be deposited in an escrow account for the duration of the covered period.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6055C4BB06834653B7FB2F650A597F7C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of amounts in escrow account</header><text>During the covered period, the Board may not obligate, expend, or borrow against amounts required under subsection (b) to be deposited in the escrow account. Any interest earned on such amounts shall be deposited in the escrow account and shall be unavailable for obligation for the duration of the covered period.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0DCC2E0A0AB8438DB88D6B958816C13F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Release of amounts in escrow account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the covered period, the Board may withdraw and obligate in any fiscal year an amount in the escrow account that does not exceed <fraction>1/5</fraction> of the amount in the escrow account on the last day of the covered period.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H03E5FDE015D643C1AC65B5938E20B9F4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Special rule for estimates for particular fiscal years</header>
 <paragraph id="HB92EF3E2D51B4DE38C548DA7AEDDA369"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a)(1), the amount of assessments estimated to be collected under section 6 in a fiscal year specified in paragraph (2) shall be equal to 62 percent of the amount of assessments actually collected under such section in the most recent fiscal year for which an audit report has been submitted under section 5(f)(2)(B) as of the beginning of the fiscal year for which the amount that may be obligated is being determined.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5BACEB56EADA4C73BF1BA73635E948A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fiscal years specified</header><text>The fiscal years specified in this paragraph are the 9th and 10th fiscal years that begin on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2298C194B89C429BAF26463E8BAA2416"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Covered period defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>covered period</quote> means the period that begins on the date of the enactment of this Act and ends on the last day of the 11th fiscal year that begins on or after such date of enactment.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HAD1C99A22657485FA7E21D7DB275E22A"><enum>17.</enum><header>Study and report by the Government Accountability Office</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 5 years and 8 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall prepare a study and submit to Congress and the Secretary a report examining—</text>
 <paragraph id="H04287A3610504BE5B9C402BA9B202472"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how the Board spends assessments collected;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B6EA6FC56E14A4085DB93A938626B63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the extent to which the Board’s reported activities help achieve its annual objectives;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7051316F9D546359CE4C04270BD19E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any changes in demand for concrete masonry products relative to other building materials;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2F0D32D00BA4F3DB052CC14194E78A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any impact of the Board’s activities on the market share of competing products;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H51BA19C805E5440091AFA6AD16DB73D8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any impact of the Board’s activities on the overall size of the market for building products;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF94730A7D3C04D4688CCC4DAA6272CFD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any impact of the Board’s activities on the total number of concrete-masonry-related jobs, including manufacturing, sales, and installation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C273D9FAD2B4AD5A8B437D305C4395A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any significant effects of the Board’s activities on downstream purchasers of concrete masonry products and real property into which concrete masonry products are incorporated;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35634CDCA7D841F8A8FF852CBF157A86"><enum>(8)</enum><text>effects on prices of concrete masonry products as a result of the Board’s activities;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H81E3CC00D1A146CF949FF53EE45306FB"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the cost to the Federal Government of an increase in concrete masonry product prices, if any, as a result of the program established by this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69199304B55A43CCA6DD27C5FDE293FD"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the extent to which key statutory requirements are met;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7EAB22AFFADC4AB78BB6E70CB8B5E46E"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the extent and strength of Federal oversight of the program established by this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF6D8DA4A0BC47FF8A561432E89BB5ED"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the appropriateness of administering the program from within the Office of the Secretary of Commerce and the appropriateness of administering the program from within any division of the Department of Commerce, including whether the Department has the expertise, knowledge, or other capabilities necessary to adequately administer the program; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H412A9A8BD94941B4AEFE15E784005785"><enum>(13)</enum><text>any other topic that the Comptroller General considers appropriate.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H1FBEDEC6DDAC4DC9B6AD96651E361BF8"><enum>18.</enum><header>Study and report by the Department of Commerce</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prepare a study and submit to Congress a report examining the appropriateness and effectiveness of applying the commodity check-off program model (such as those programs established under subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/7/101">chapter 101</external-xref> of title 7, United States Code) to a nonagricultural industry, taking into account the program established by this Act and any other check-off program involving a nonagricultural industry.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


