<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6F59906A5E184C37840A8D10183A142A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2834 IH: Partnership Grants to Strengthen Families Affected by Parental Substance Abuse Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2834</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170608">June 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="N000184">Mrs. Noem</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve the well-being of, and improve permanency outcomes for, children and families affected by heroin, opioids, and other substance abuse.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7F871354EE94437EA7EFBC2A7606888A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8430E74A1B914EC18EC1A1A73D319804" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Partnership Grants to Strengthen Families Affected by Parental Substance Abuse Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9D31A063FD34438C9A7E1975D3A84A3C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enhancements to grants to improve well-being of families affected by substance abuse</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 437(f) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/629g">42 U.S.C. 629g(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HED36765249F74B688B633EA478F8610A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">increase the well-being of, and to improve the permanency outcomes for, children affected by</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">implement IV–E prevention services, and improve the well-being of, and improve permanency outcomes for, children and families affected by heroin, opioids, and other</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCEE0476B4ADB4E8F95271FFA1DFAF41B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC14183CD48944B8088C9A71F55D8B4C4" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HB35CCD0648E647568FB1473DD445AB44"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regional partnership defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>regional partnership</term> means a collaborative agreement (which may be established on an interstate, State, or intrastate basis) entered into by the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H549B31A25E6B493E94F5A8DB6270B294"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Mandatory partners for all partnership grants</header> <clause id="H5089DF34525F41D3902E8C61D6137AC4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The State child welfare agency that is responsible for the administration of the State plan under this part and part E.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H15B002E3F8DF46E8A58C4A2920870F20"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The State agency responsible for administering the substance abuse prevention and treatment block grant provided under subpart II of part B of title XIX of the Public Health Service Act.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDB5AD64E201443AF93CAB2530BA53D1C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mandatory partners for partnership grants proposing to serve children in out-of-home placements</header><text>If the partnership proposes to serve children in out-of-home placements, the Juvenile Court or Administrative Office of the Court that is most appropriate to oversee the administration of court programs in the region to address the population of families who come to the attention of the court due to child abuse or neglect.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD9F50B2904EA4C3CA2997D01000BC33C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Optional partners</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the option of the partnership, any of the following:</text> <clause id="HDD7FD4154B024650B2B8016B55F55DC2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An Indian tribe or tribal consortium.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5DF1D66895FD4426BF20CB51DDFC3229"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Nonprofit child welfare service providers.</text></clause> <clause id="H43C216C20183489CA22C890433D00A9F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For-profit child welfare service providers.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H78B3E5AAD0D44BD391E32B32AEB57293"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Community health service providers, including substance abuse treatment providers.</text></clause> <clause id="H22CD06B16995471F8716FAFE091A6605"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Community mental health providers.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H46F4BF19907A4D5A8A2A76B57B51B9E6"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Local law enforcement agencies.</text></clause> <clause id="HDCB9FCB054BA477EB9610D2224B9125F"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>School personnel.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC147922EEFEE4A798D71BCD706677BE4"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Tribal child welfare agencies (or a consortia of the agencies).</text></clause> <clause id="H12AE20B9D78A4D4FA43DB2E4AA0CC90B"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Any other providers, agencies, personnel, officials, or entities that are related to the provision of child and family services under a State plan approved under this subpart.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9D81DC4A63184636AA21101ADB075BAA"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Exception for regional partnerships where the lead applicant is an Indian tribe or tribal consortia</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an Indian tribe or tribal consortium enters into a regional partnership for purposes of this subsection, the Indian tribe or tribal consortium—</text> <clause id="HA62424EF17AD46D680EDD3D7279F5E1E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may (but is not required to) include the State child welfare agency as a partner in the collaborative agreement;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAE826EAB6F094D789447E99A97E7CFA7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may not enter into a collaborative agreement only with tribal child welfare agencies (or a consortium of the agencies); and</text></clause> <clause id="H5DB6D645E90C48D09923499809565708"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if the condition described in paragraph (2)(B) applies, may include tribal court organizations in lieu of other judicial partners.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45C1B9FDECD34C1ABC2A0288F15092D2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <subparagraph id="HB0E223EC79544CEE80DF800D6B8A307C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<clause id="H27FF06F11842407DB43A395319BFE44F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2012 through 2016</quote> and inserting <quote>2017 through 2021</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H3281F2E9B2DD48609EE89F5EF6363214"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$500,000 and not more than $1,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$250,000 and not more than $1,000,000</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H56B0C1D95B5142C5A6F84F08DAAE13A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <clause id="H020F26E20CA1488FA6638E66306C7395"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subparagraph heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">; planning</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">approval</header-in-text></quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H51A088E1258646E88269F729BED6C7A1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>clause (ii)</quote> and inserting <quote>clauses (ii) and (iii)</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC8D921C8C6E34808BD4BF84AFDA3E8E6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B26AF956B8D46C1A376C796861B66F8" style="OLC"> 
<clause id="HC7FD269C5021433FA295551A41939222"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Sufficient planning</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded under this subsection shall be disbursed in two phases: a planning phase (not to exceed 2 years) and an implementation phase. The total disbursement to a grantee for the planning phase may not exceed $250,000, and may not exceed the total anticipated funding for the implementation phase.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB8910E14FAAE4F9C8AA3A1FA2381C3FF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA92063E8AE274D0EA672C905D6E4C358" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H2CAC059266F7447EBD3B1A2E8156C894"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limitation on payment for a fiscal year</header><text>No payment shall be made under subparagraph (A) or (C) for a fiscal year until the Secretary determines that the eligible partnership has made sufficient progress in meeting the goals of the grant and that the members of the eligible partnership are coordinating to a reasonable degree with the other members of the eligible partnership.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27A44C0D898C4108AFB34BB3B20844DF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEAE1B3D90354477E9153D19234C28C88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <clause id="HB73E2307E8144129AD497F216D3DBA5D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i), by inserting <quote>, parents, and families</quote> after <quote>children</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE14C5F89B1414757A19FBFA966FD2EEB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>safety and permanence for such children; and</quote> and inserting <quote>safe, permanent caregiving relationships for the children;</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="HA260960D4971493FA5201579C9DC2AD7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>or</quote> and inserting <quote>increase reunification rates for children who have been placed in out-of-home care, or decrease</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA150D27825CD4D9F8CE187CD22187986"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (iii) as clause (v) and inserting after clause (ii) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0220B3957C28481B97C1E8AE0FDFA40A" style="OLC"> <clause id="H96AF089B860743A18B18DD005870DED1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve the substance abuse treatment outcomes for parents including retention in treatment and successful completion of treatment;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDB5169FED9064B9BB9481A858DD1086D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate the implementation, delivery, and effectiveness of prevention services and programs under section 471(e); and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H97178EBCC738458D9CF14C37FDCF3B83"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>where appropriate,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB134CD667B094963BEBB0AECE9C289B6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subparagraphs (E) and (F) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H44688D272E6849F1A0994B5A390348A5" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H7448F40BDAB24C879FF3513E99F03EB8"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of a plan for sustaining the services provided by or activities funded under the grant after the conclusion of the grant period, including through the use of prevention services and programs under section 471(e) and other funds provided to the State for child welfare and substance abuse prevention and treatment services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H363355B0BD7041C4A6023149A54F7F89"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Additional information needed by the Secretary to determine that the proposed activities and implementation will be consistent with research or evaluations showing which practices and approaches are most effective.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC00C30B6D4124FA8BDE90E172EC600BB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(A), by striking <quote>abuse treatment</quote> and inserting <quote>use disorder treatment including medication assisted treatment and in-home substance abuse disorder treatment and recovery</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF295AA03F49545718696F8765AA89C30"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in paragraph (7)—</text> <subparagraph id="H3AD431B020864D768DBD2FC8EAF5E926"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (C); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBAEC92EA6F8A4B7BA5B85113B8D4A04B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (E) and inserting after subparagraph (C) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE91772E3000B47C98A8847E353C0D0DF" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H74921DCCA9474E189760FB5042CBB58F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrate a track record of successful collaboration among child welfare, substance abuse disorder treatment and mental health agencies; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F27528432FD42FCA0C22147DA9913C8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in paragraph (8)—</text> <subparagraph id="H8CE4703A56634C17A58F85513CA5A059"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<clause id="H8CC2E24E70154992BEB8CB626DFB557A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>establish indicators that will be</quote> and inserting <quote>review indicators that are</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC7979E1AD8A743D49FB6E44ABA3AB443"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>in using funds made available under such grants to achieve the purpose of this subsection</quote> and inserting <quote>and establish a set of core indicators related to child safety, parental recovery, parenting capacity, and family well-being. In developing the core indicators, to the extent possible, indicators shall be made consistent with the outcome measures described in section 471(e)(6)</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDB8382A9107C469AB7ABDD39871EF051"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <clause id="HA9A74A27F3264E8B8EFADAB961D6E725"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>base the performance measures on lessons learned from prior rounds of regional partnership grants under this subsection, and</quote> before <quote>consult</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H08196221A36F49AB95167F17EBB18496"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking clauses (iii) and (iv) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD009353F6AA347FFB44B138626D3A4AE" style="OLC"> <clause id="H41A40FDEBF224C11B519A4EDDD940B76"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other stakeholders or constituencies as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H386B7EFDCF1046EE886B403117485DF7"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in paragraph (9)(A), by striking clause (i) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC751CD6410894908B8EBA949ACBE2B62" style="OLC"> <clause id="H439F78BFD8B6407DBBE2720DE0C7D59E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Semiannual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30 of each fiscal year in which a recipient of a grant under this subsection is paid funds under the grant, and every 6 months thereafter, the grant recipient shall submit to the Secretary a report on the services provided and activities carried out during the reporting period, progress made in achieving the goals of the program, the number of children, adults, and families receiving services, and such additional information as the Secretary determines is necessary. The report due not later than September 30 of the last such fiscal year shall include, at a minimum, data on each of the performance indicators included in the evaluation of the regional partnership.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H88B1A744EE9F4CFB965CF88AB3F95879"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), by striking <quote>2012 through 2016</quote> and inserting <quote>2017 through 2021</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H9F5DE9EC380842D5A5FE9E9380480D9D" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header> <subsection id="H22DCD70BBF33424E90425FCAFD64469F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on October 1, 2017.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HECBB05C58AA146EA942359835C00525F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transition rule</header> 
<paragraph id="H6299C29A745A4D038322EA36B7F2BE3D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a State plan under part B of title IV of the Social Security Act which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) in order for the plan to meet the additional requirements imposed by the amendments made by this Act, the State plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such part solely on the basis of the failure of the plan to meet such additional requirements before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session shall be deemed to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC68D25BB7BE49709332682D42130C45" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application to programs operated by Indian tribal organizations</header><text>In the case of an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or tribal consortium which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires time to take action necessary to comply with the additional requirements imposed by the amendments made by this Act (whether the tribe, organization, or tribal consortium has a plan under section 479B of the Social Security Act or a cooperative agreement or contract entered into with a State), the Secretary shall provide the tribe, organization, or tribal consortium with such additional time as the Secretary determines is necessary for the tribe, organization, or tribal consortium to take the action to comply with the additional requirements before being regarded as failing to comply with the requirements.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

