<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H26E14BED916C4213986E2295B260FDA7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2400 IH: To amend title 5, United States Code, to allow individuals who are not Federal employees to enroll in the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2400</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170508">May 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to allow individuals who are not Federal employees to enroll
			 in the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1F767849DA774A51860A7C1E2FAA0081" style="OLC">
		<section id="H51C0FDF1B65D4939BE5037352BC4DC2A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Extension and modification of Federal employee health insurance</header>
			<subsection id="HAC7510D7F0AA4581B8DA2FDEFC5536A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>FEHBP</header>
 <paragraph id="H1FA403BF52574321A4AA793CEC360767"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">Chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H980EC7C3DD264B49AF2A2BBC527AF984" style="USC"> <section id="HB219B560FEB84C1E895BB6312E806B46"><enum>8915.</enum><header>Health insurance for individuals who are not Federal employees</header> <subsection id="H4AA6D82A650A41BDB988F5A40948D58F"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in this section, any individual may enroll in a health benefits plan provided under this chapter and receive health benefits, to the greatest extent practicable, in the same manner as an employee.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H455A543E2649486283AE9BD61DC2D3BC"><enum>(b)</enum><text>An individual may not enroll in a health benefits plan under this section if the individual—</text> <paragraph id="H40420EABAC574DECBCFF45676CC9EF7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is enrolled or eligible to enroll for coverage under a public health insurance program, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA9FD1F15CDB0436ABDEDAAE633CB07DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>title XVIII of the Social Security Act;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4688E22A65940D49BC2DF5BAD161633"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F8FEFC735554DA284817684F7857EE7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a State plan under title XXI of the Social Security Act; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83C66E3B2C1E4B25BBEA113401465E50"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other program determined by the Office;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FFE58D9D49C4AF592A18EA3FF838D9B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is a member of the uniformed services as defined under section 101(a)(5) of title 10; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3071AB9022194E2B9F7194D87CC9B6D2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is not a citizen or national of the United States or an alien lawfully present in the United States.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9D86B6BF316044DCA590014F28A199A9"><enum>(c)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD6FFF2F67DD04CF2930091F8BEC3B72A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Government contribution may be made for any individual enrolled in a health benefits plan pursuant to this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3DB2C86754B345889AC082A184A7B38A" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to regulations that the Office of Personnel Management may prescribe, an employer of an individual enrolled in such a plan may make a contribution on behalf of the individual.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC09778836F28483AA62CF305CF720EAA"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Office shall ensure that individuals enrolled in a health benefits plan under this section shall be in the same risk pool maintained for employees covered by this chapter.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7BE9BDDF3EC74FF08BA397B5348F9A79"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office shall issue regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H087AEBB326324B6589CCC6535DAAEB75"><enum>8916.</enum><header>No lifetime or annual limits</header> <subsection id="H5B7765D693184AAB9D4980641519A68E"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A carrier offering a health benefits plan under this chapter may not establish—</text>
 <paragraph id="H840EC15337DD41358FC561A4522B96C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">lifetime limits on the dollar value of benefits for any individual enrolled in such plan; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4ACC8FDDE188482A95F0FC14DEE6FEC3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">unreasonable annual limits (within the meaning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) on the dollar value of benefits for any such individual.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H268194159E3C4F7D82985E8006177C82"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall not be construed to prevent a health benefits plan under this chapter from placing annual or lifetime per beneficiary limits on specific covered benefits to the extent that such limits are otherwise permitted under Federal or State law.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H2BCB56D9B5D64CC193CA7EBD17DEAF42"><enum>8917.</enum><header>Non-discrimination in health care</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A carrier offering a health benefits plan under this chapter may not discriminate with respect to participation under the plan or coverage against any health care provider who is acting within the scope of that provider’s license or certification under applicable State law. This section shall not require that a health benefits plan or carrier contract with any health care provider willing to abide by the terms and conditions for participation established by the plan or issuer. Nothing in this section shall be construed as preventing a health benefits plan, a carrier, or the Director of the Office of Personnel Management from establishing varying reimbursement rates based on quality or performance measures.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H51E64D804B954818B6B266B3A8065705"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Child under the age of 26</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8901(5) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>22</quote> in each instance it appears and inserting <quote>26</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E82B604093E4C4CB42925C8849F45FF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Sections 8916 and 8917 of such title (as added by paragraph (1)) shall begin to apply to any contract for health benefits plans entered into by the Office of Personnel Management under chapter 89 of such title after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC88652B9AB6F4AF7A4798BE0CC008DC4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/8914">section 8914</external-xref> the following new items:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19D717817A05418C8452EEFD60C1F434" style="USC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">8915. Health insurance for individuals who are not Federal employees.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry level="section">8616. No lifetime or annual limits.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry level="section">8917. Non-discrimination in health care.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5B58820183A7468B96BB2A10021DF96C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Dental and vision benefits</header>
 <paragraph id="H8A6C226C5394478DB97A5F51FF2A99DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Dental</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8952 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC9B1900F6EF4A299006E2B69F0AD7C0" style="USC"> <subsection id="H4BCBFFF3EEBD4F8183D5E767277C8F88"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office shall issue regulations necessary to enroll individuals described in section 8915 in dental benefits plan offered under this chapter, consistent with the requirements of such section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB8FC9D8DE2104D88BE744132CCA42818"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vision</header><text>Section 8982 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91652C4E5AA84D12ABB158DB2D766A96" style="USC"> <subsection id="HA43C1D8F1DBD4B0E82CBB58B57D785A1"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office shall issue regulations necessary to enroll individuals described in section 8915 in vision benefits plan offered under this chapter, consistent with the requirements of such section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HAC6501B1CEE7441780224140B348ADE4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enrollment of insured individuals who are not Federal employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For plan years beginning in the year immediately following the year in which this subsection is enacted, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall issue regulations to provide for the enrollment of individuals (as described under section 8915 of title 5, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)) in health benefits plans under chapter 89, 89A, or 89B of such title.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF3545994579349C297AA9CEF79CB23EB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Plan for extension of Federal employee health benefits program</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act and after consultation with appropriate experts, representatives of affected individuals, and Federal officers, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall submit a comprehensive plan to Congress that—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H3EAE105F0CB942EA8C8E2C01E2B22EEB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provides for the orderly implementation of the amendments made by this section; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA0DB5B00ADEC482595226565864CAD31"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes a schedule of actions to be taken to provide for that implementation.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


