<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H39CA43E5E27A49D7A43A7C2DE8D6BE2C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3596 IH: Rightsizing Pension Premiums Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3596</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to adjust single-employer premiums,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9F85BEDB9D024A1492A7A88010E9417C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H99376F91ABA34E618DFDAAB3D8DCF566" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rightsizing Pension Premiums Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H359020D61ED442A9BBE511EAFA7C3BA4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rightsizing pension premiums</header> <subsection id="HB4464C8CF5CB480B86674366955290B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4006(a) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1306">29 U.S.C. 1306(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HBC9D2D9AE7FD4C79BF88321FDFE06385" style="OLC">
					<paragraph id="HDD662C4789624071B5D4E34FC093B6E5"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Premium adjustments for small employers and based on PBGC funded percentage</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA14A68ECF2F34FA89F2B9EB12F98E443"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (3)(A)(i) and subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), the annual premium rate payable to the corporation by a single-employer plan for basic benefits guaranteed under this title is—</text>
 <clause id="HBEEAD1BCD2224538909A330F80A94B4F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a single-employer plan for any plan year beginning in a fiscal year with respect to which the average of the single-employer pension insurance program funded percentages for the 2 fiscal years immediately preceding such fiscal year is 110 percent or greater, an amount for each individual who is a participant in such plan during the plan year equal to the sum of $19 and an additional premium equal to the quotient (not to exceed $500) obtained by dividing—</text>
 <subclause id="H6771246D7F1845989B20ED750C0F9CB7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an amount equal to $9 for each $1,000 (or fraction thereof) of unfunded vested benefits under the plan as of the close of the preceding plan year, by</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1204D3B4AA294553B9BB36ACCB6232CA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of participants in such plan as of the close of the preceding plan year;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H559979A3688349BC8889477CE94B4723"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a single-employer plan for any plan year beginning in a fiscal year with respect to which the average of the single-employer pension insurance program funded percentages for the 2 fiscal years immediately preceding such fiscal year is at least 100 percent but less than 110 percent, an amount for each individual who is a participant in such plan during the plan year equal to the sum of $30 and an additional premium equal to the quotient (not to exceed $500) obtained by dividing—</text>
 <subclause id="HD8E99CD51DDF4AD69BF61CDAE3444AC2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an amount equal to $9 for each $1,000 (or fraction thereof) of unfunded vested benefits under the plan as of the close of the preceding plan year, by</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9F9078A42B754C2E9D97807DFFBA0442"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of participants in such plan as of the close of the preceding plan year;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H35492A3A4CFD40CA9ED9F27F45C4060F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a single-employer plan for any plan year beginning in a fiscal year with respect to which the average of the single-employer pension insurance program funded percentages for the 2 fiscal years immediately preceding such fiscal year is at least 90 percent but less than 100 percent, an amount for each individual who is a participant in such plan during the plan year equal to the sum of $64 and an additional premium equal to the quotient (not to exceed $500) obtained by dividing—</text>
 <subclause id="H0D3F3F923BA84006B13A5CFFB2B88181"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an amount equal to $28 for each $1,000 (or fraction thereof) of unfunded vested benefits under the plan as of the close of the preceding plan year, by</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HFB6844C2592F43A5B8F36D54F84D8C3D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of participants in such plan as of the close of the preceding plan year;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H932BDA69CE56490FB99A85856C1CD119"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding clauses (i) through (iii), in the case of a CSEC plan (as defined in section 210(f)) or single-employer plan maintained by a small employer for any plan year, an amount for each individual who is a participant in such plan during the plan year equal to the sum of $19 and an additional premium equal to the quotient (not to exceed $500) obtained by dividing—</text>
 <subclause id="HF56BCD0E853F459889E8F621A01846AE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an amount equal to $9 for each $1,000 (or fraction thereof) of unfunded vested benefits under the plan as of the close of the preceding plan year, by</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H466DB0AEFAD84E798C0B347AF4C44175"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of participants in such plan as of the close of the preceding plan year; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H4A2E0C91498241628FA78966A4012CC5"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in any other case, the amount determined under paragraph (3)(A)(i).</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C1188BF302240C9A728C3CD6BE6DD4E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Small employer premium phase-out</header>
 <clause id="HD33E5202903C4049BC5654EBB7A2FE0F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a single-employer plan maintained by an employer who has more than 500 employees but not more than 600 employees on the first day of the plan year, the annual premium rate payable to the corporation by such plan for basic benefits guaranteed under this title is an amount for each individual who is a participant in such plan during the plan year equal to the sum of—</text>
 <subclause id="H672CC4B5D81D4377B9B3DCEAC9E5DE02"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the annual premium rate that would be so payable by such plan if such plan were maintained by a small employer for such plan year, plus—</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6FF80631C5C242C8B21D2B8F97376D06"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the applicable percentage of the excess of—</text> <item id="HC3E620E6D8C9415C98FD7701FB536991"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the annual premium rate so payable by such plan without regard to this subparagraph, over</text>
 </item><item id="HC84C94CAF2204E99BA93B14A0E47F45F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the annual premium rate that would be so payable by such plan as described under subclause (I).</text> </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H59CF28E66BCB48218EC765AA28529AB8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the <quote>applicable percentage</quote> is the ratio (expressed as a percentage) of—</text>
 <subclause id="HE18E7A8219664E38BCC4DBD847180C2F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of employees of the employer to the extent such number exceeds 500, over</text> </subclause><subclause id="H6E606C30411E4480AAC1CBE965FDE8E2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>100.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88627F2403964DCA991689264FF91343"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rule for multiple employer plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a multiple employer plan (other than a CSEC plan (as defined in section 210(f))), the annual premium rate payable to the corporation by such plan for basic benefits guaranteed under this title is the sum of the annual premiums that, if each employer maintaining such plan were treated as maintaining a separate plan in which—</text>
 <clause id="H8D2A8845B2C841568704CB6F95609877"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of participants equals the number of participants in the multiple employer plan who are employed (or formerly employed) by such employer, and</text>
 </clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF3823D20D0DC459CBEA1726C9E9514FB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of unfunded vested benefits equals the portion of the unfunded vested benefits under the multiple employer plan attributable to such employer,</text>
							</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">would be imposed on each separate plan in accordance with this section. In determining the annual
			 premiums that would be imposed on each of the separate plans described
			 under this subparagraph, the determination of whether an employer is a
			 small employer shall be made separately with respect to each employer
 maintaining the multiple employer plan.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8322981F37BB41CC9F3AA898FC7E9F81"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Special rule for small employers with 25 or fewer employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a single-employer plan maintained by a small employer who has 25 or fewer employees on the first day of the plan year (as determined under paragraph (3)(I)(ii)), the additional premium otherwise determined under subparagraph (A)(iv) shall not exceed $5 multiplied by the number of participants in the plan as of the close of the preceding plan year.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1FDC0D2144F9416A84DEC8BC235571AF">
							<enum>(E)</enum><header>Wage indexing of certain amounts</header>
 <text>For each plan year beginning in a calendar year after 2018, there shall be substituted for each of the first and second dollar amounts in clause (ii) of subparagraph (A) and the first, second, and third dollar amounts in clause (iii) of such subparagraph an amount equal to the greater of—</text>
							<clause id="HBECE7A138FC74F10BC7792ADFBE1AACC">
								<enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>the product derived by multiplying each such amount by the ratio of—</text> <subclause id="HFC9236487D8C40F59CF302A66E7DCE83"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>the national average wage index (as defined in section 209(k)(1) of the Social Security Act) for the first of the 2 calendar years preceding the calendar year in which such plan year begins, to</text>
								</subclause><subclause id="HE8C258C37E984CFA8695B887D3BA6211">
									<enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>the national average wage index (as so defined) for 2016; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HE0FEDBF29294441D9AA906F19C2C0171"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>each such amount as in effect for plan years beginning in the preceding calendar year.</text>
							</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">If any amount determined under this subparagraph is not a multiple of $1, such product shall be
 rounded to the nearest multiple of $1.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12984DD832FD4C6BA1855753A70D55B6"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph:</text> <clause id="H74CAC7B1D1264B42BF57E06CC01FBF82"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Small employer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>small employer</quote> means an employer who has 500 or fewer employees on the first day of the plan year.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H292B0AB18FF343AEAB3B1B990BD32DCF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Multiple employer plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>multiple employer plan</quote> means a single-employer plan maintained by more than one employer (as determined under section 210(a)).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE0BE534704224F45AB83B1D6486328B2"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Single-employer pension insurance program funded percentage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>single-employer pension insurance program funded percentage</quote> for a fiscal year means the ratio (expressed as a percentage) of—</text> <subclause id="HF610C6F4C8C84E4084164F7E1D3DC83B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the value of all assets held by the corporation in any trust or revolving fund on the last day of such fiscal year available for the payment of basic benefits guaranteed under section 4022, to</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7E08434CD63348F48681BFDBF9EE666A"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the present value (as determined in accordance with section 303(h) without regard to paragraph (2)(C)(iv)) of the liabilities of the corporation attributable to such guaranteed benefits on the last day of such fiscal year.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H6DC8EA54E18B4BB09ED25A4C1EC3B5AA"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Unfunded vested benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>unfunded vested benefits</quote> has the meaning given such term in paragraph (3)(E)(iii), except that with respect to a CSEC plan (as defined in section 210(f)), such term means the excess of—</text>
 <subclause id="H58E309305F7440D59A3CC79C4D3150C7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the plan’s funding liability (as defined in section 306(j)(5)(C)), determined by only taking into account vested benefits, over</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H21D7FDDFB7164E3487D39D90B49D62E1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the fair market value of plan assets for the plan year which are held by the plan on the valuation date.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC8DC7BF1F6694A24A5A2E25B03242E74"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Individuals participating in more than one plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4006(a)(3)(B) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1306">29 U.S.C. 1306(a)(3)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or paragraph (9)</quote> after <quote>subparagraph (A)(i)</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE2B1F32DC1C34C2F8D47D77F6E1D22B8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 4006(a)(3)(A) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1306">29 U.S.C. 1306</external-xref>) is amended in the matter preceding clause (i) by inserting <quote>and paragraph (9)</quote> after <quote>subparagraph (C)</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H98429A268C464865B7995C25438ACDBA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <text>The amendments made by this shall apply with respect to plan years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HD3101B4781A841C7934874A6769851C8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Correction of the budget effects of premium changes</header>
 <subsection id="H0C7BBEA38B0542E0B3E532981CD3B075"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the Senate and the House of Representatives, for purposes of determining points of order under the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/621">2 U.S.C. 621</external-xref> et seq.) or any concurrent resolution on the budget, any provision that increases or decreases, or extends the increase or decrease of, any premiums payable to the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation shall not be counted in estimating the level of budget authority, outlays, or revenues—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3251ED79C0974CF084E04DDC0A34DCFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the Senate, for any bill, joint resolution, amendment, amendment between the Houses, conference report, or motion; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9C1B321E0CE4EB7AAC5BA096DDC94BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the House of Representatives, for any bill or joint resolution, or amendment thereto or conference report thereon.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF951CEFBBEE84046B46BB1D749C5397A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules of senate and house of representatives</header><text>Congress adopts the provisions of this section—</text> <paragraph id="HEF3A850534654CC6936EF6853C9B08ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, and supersede other rules only to the extent that they are inconsistent with such rules; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCA9798E6574E4D909491D6B2474DCAB5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


