<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H09087DEF4B3541C2B84754B72BFE5A37" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 534 IH: U.S. Wants to Compete for a World Expo Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 534</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170113">January 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000594">Mr. Paulsen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000587">Mr. Lewis of Minnesota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of State to take such actions as may be necessary for the United States to
			 rejoin the Bureau of International Expositions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H27ED6AC8946C402D827B6329E9A26E5C" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB55530B4F8414F96B3EE68046CC74631" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>U.S. Wants to Compete for a World Expo Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE938B94496834C48A814CA7DF85A9D5C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HEEC57132649E4FA292D2AD66A249E093"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Bureau of International Expositions (BIE) is a treaty-based organization, with 169 member states, responsible for governing World Fairs and International Expositions since the signing of the Convention Concerning International Expositions on November 22, 1928. The United States is a party to the Convention.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H48241747988B423B8FA613E3BBC34A28"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The United States withdrew from membership in the BIE in 2001 in response to congressional limitations on the expenditure of funds for United States participation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45DFA1A78CDF46E898F8DFDBA19FA305"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States and other non-members of the BIE face significantly higher costs to host and to participate in international expositions because of their non-member status.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H93B16064BE814D60A81998B66501B82C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The bid of a United States city, region, or State to host an international exposition is unlikely to be successful if the United States is not a member of the BIE, because BIE rules require that members receive a preference over non-members for all such bids.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7212A54D50B84CC3BBF47C9B2643B247"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Since the United States was previously a member of the BIE, and has already acceded to the Convention, no formal congressional action is necessary for the United States to rejoin the BIE.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F78CF3FC79D47AE93502A23BE8DCCDE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Section 1(a) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/91/269">Public Law 91–269</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2801">22 U.S.C. 2801(a)</external-xref>) found that <quote>international expositions … have a significant impact on the economic growth of the region surrounding the exposition and … are important instruments of national policy</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HEF8DDC700BFD4408A74E61E8383F21DD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HB8E6EB7BB7AC419EBA0A900E92AD928C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>there are no statutory provisions that prohibit the United States from rejoining the BIE;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7FD7C75EFE1449DAAF51A65A311F045D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States should rejoin the BIE immediately to promote public diplomacy, global branding, and tourism to the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CBC3081B4A349A09BDC8D7B7CEE675A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary of State, in partnership with the Secretary of Commerce, State and local governments, and private and non-profit entities, should take all necessary steps to facilitate the timely submission of a request to rejoin the BIE.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HF4D3354C61254117A51ED3597F959B23"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization</header>
 <subsection id="H06BBDD66B5044E90A451FA0CB98FDA05"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall take such actions as may be necessary for the United States to rejoin the BIE, notwithstanding any prohibitions under section 204 of the Admiral James W. Nance and Meg Donovan Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 2000 and 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2452b">22 U.S.C. 2452b</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD2BDD0C021714547A6D8CE545DB402BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall inform the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate upon submitting a request to rejoin the BIE.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


