<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H54C1A1EDDD054C84AEE8D3E2ED93178D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1973 IH: Protecting Young Victims from Sexual Abuse Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1973</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001284">Mrs. Brooks of Indiana</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000289">Mr. Goodlatte</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prevent the sexual abuse of minors and amateur athletes by requiring the prompt reporting of
			 sexual abuse to law enforcement authorities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB4A71480C4E34AE78A94E655BE768819" style="OLC">
 <section id="H938937522C964EC5AC8A7EE049A0F040" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Young Victims from Sexual Abuse Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H904595C89FB1424587F7321253B12627"><enum>2.</enum><header>Required reporting of child and sexual abuse at facilities under the jurisdiction of amateur sports organizations recognized by the United States Olympic Committee</header> <subsection id="H7E1440C8CE434936B231A22BCA264351"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 226 of the Victims of Child Abuse Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/13031">42 U.S.C. 13031</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDC5CBF99D03F44FE96FC3EEF7131E34E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="HB3A88BCABB844DDBB31F798FD7B87C48"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A person who</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE7F48E8B19E484D9C1DA56053A4738A" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HAD38D49903864B45847F25A897A36BD2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered professionals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA58230EC75734FE68FBD0177C13D1D20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3614D7F8D61843D6A0B0D894A92BA309" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H211C9A58F67541FDA6D6EDDF9892172C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individuals at covered facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered individual who, while engaged in any activity sanctioned by a covered facility, learns of facts that give reason to suspect that a child has suffered an incident of child abuse, including sexual abuse, shall as soon as possible make a report of the suspected abuse to the agency designated by the Attorney General under subsection (d).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E79C5FCD0A9485F9F116D33DFC4E44C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)(1)</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1327365733CD4CB5BA181E7E3E12C452"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H212B15D7FCD74B9183F8E5DAED3AAAC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91402533270A41B9A770FCF8C9568F89"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4260196B8604911A6FBC33A45A4CE9E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA82309A09BAD4AEE8B2F0D0C827B3969" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H2F0CF81D06914CD8874B7F07716739D2"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>covered facility</quote> means a facility over which a national governing body has jurisdiction;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9DE9AA7DC8554D9B9BCD2671703ADFF3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the term <quote>covered individual</quote> means an adult who is authorized by a covered facility or by a national governing body to interact with a minor or amateur athlete at the covered facility or at any event sanctioned by the covered facility; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1008FDC26D584CE8B76739A242EA4175"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the term <quote>national governing body</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 220501(b) of title 36, United States Code.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE4FD4C5B9DA4D0BA29F55421E5F6440"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (d), in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>and for all covered facilities</quote> after <quote>reside</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2CE5661E83B04C6F962DD831ED72A6EA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (f), in the first sentence—</text> <subparagraph id="H9811DD58134B42CC840ACFE378B7B086"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and on all</quote> and inserting <quote>on all</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1077844DEACC4D968962CA0F2272931B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and for all covered facilities,</quote> after <quote>lands,</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4409AC79C2C9407BA6E118E53C2AAE65"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (h), by inserting <quote>and all covered individuals,</quote> after <quote>facilities,</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C7799CD1E9941078F2BF42B4B226931"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalty for failure To report</header><text>Section 2258 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>or while engaged in a professional capacity or activity at a covered facility as described in subsection (a)(2) of such section 226</quote> after <quote>facility</quote>.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H6BB0BBAC61B049BCA380D6A9B188E41C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Civil remedy for personal injuries</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2255 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE819972583434BE6A9A7EA8F819848D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1876227A2094428CA7691913518D1C53" style="USC">
 <subsection id="H697C4C7EEE63468F912BC4A67865475F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who, while a minor, was a victim of a violation of section 1589, 1590, 1591, 2241(c), 2242, 2243, 2251, 2251A, 2252, 2252A, 2260, 2421, 2422, or 2423 of this title and who suffers personal injury as a result of such violation, regardless of whether the injury occurred while such person was a minor, may sue in any appropriate United States District Court and shall recover the actual damages such person sustains or liquidated damages in the amount of $150,000, and the cost of the action, including reasonable attorney’s fees and other litigation costs reasonably incurred. The court may also award punitive damages and such other preliminary and equitable relief as the court determines to be appropriate.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCCB01AF70943417A94D8A2943A9ACE5B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>filed within</quote> and all that follows through the end and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H680700908D4C46AE8E7501A7419B35B8" style="USC"> <text>file—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HFA631B72541F4B6FBF7A880DCDF4A3CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 10 years after the date on which the plaintiff discovers the later of—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H30F2162B672A4455A394D65582A583A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the violation that forms the basis for the claim; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H97D7A0A0228E495482AC58EF7ABDF655"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the injury that forms the basis for the claim; or</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC0DB4C28403447F58A6BF117BA590C0E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of a person under a legal disability, not later than 10 years after the date on which the disability ends.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H92184D900B6B4C40822A6E82B76BA0B8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H17F9E037109B49B6AE3DE3DFEC5C6772" style="USC"> <subsection id="HB93998F8E5E3442AA008F468F78C965A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Venue; Service of process</header> <paragraph id="HB3A6F65FCC194FEB9F11E9DCEBD87227"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Venue</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any action brought under subsection (a) may be brought in the district court of the United States that meets applicable requirements relating to venue under section 1391 of title 28.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H212A3E2C4AE54253BBE838C4D3B23A12"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Service of process</header><text>In an action brought under subsection (a), process may be served in any district in which the defendant—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6561519F5D554573B7EB83F92FCDA7C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is an inhabitant; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72F473D632544289A474CDE19100A61A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be found.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H12CDE949E3A941EAAC2FE70064DE5804"><enum>4.</enum><header>Expansion of authorities and duties of amateur sports organizations recognized by the United States
			 Olympic Committee to prevent the abuse of minor and amateur athletes</header>
 <subsection id="H85691DAE844242E8AA67FFAD7EE66CA5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expansion of authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 220523(a) of title 36, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HCF7082BE41D44CB09A206F3FDF6D045E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H11339B37207146E7B83549F46AC1E17B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H97DCE4C5A37A4186AECBDA75371AFDFC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3DC5D0C61B57453BA3AEF76B2651C526" style="USC">
 <paragraph id="H9F854D61A72E4CF69564C6D6011B19E7"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop training, oversight practices, policies, and procedures to prevent the abuse, including physical abuse and sexual abuse, of any minor or amateur athlete by any adult.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4042BD55740E4B03A82FCB1CB4D48508"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional duties</header><text>Section 220524 of such title is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H58FB870F74BC47E9A6152B221FD05B53"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71F23EB33513433990D7127C802EFB22"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking the period and inserting a semicolon; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H74E0555B39AB46649E005177075C22BF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4717AD75BE00413EBAED7BDDC3D6DCE6" style="USC">
 <paragraph id="H4359D2ADD5064199A353575307E7D345"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and enforce policies, mechanisms, and procedures to prevent the abuse, including physical abuse and sexual abuse, of any minor or amateur athlete, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA85583F9A10E46F4AA9AC7A941570F4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>requiring all members of the national governing body or a facility under the jurisdiction of the national governing body and adults authorized by such members to interact with minor or amateur athletes, to immediately report all allegations of sexual abuse to law enforcement authorities and other appropriate authorities whenever such members or adults learn of facts leading them to reasonably suspect that a minor or amateur athlete has suffered an incident of sexual abuse;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E5FC5B11AE240F0A6292C1325D6AE80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing a mechanism, approved by a trained expert on child abuse, that allows a complainant to easily report an incident of sexual abuse committed by a member or adult described in subparagraph (A) to interact with a minor or amateur athlete, to the national governing body or another authority;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEF2FFDA128D4CE98D79D47E62185DDD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>procedures to ensure that each amateur athlete who is a minor is prevented from being in a one-on-one situation with an adult (who is not the minor’s legal guardian) at a facility under the jurisdiction of the national governing body without being in an observable and interruptible distance from another adult; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H247B9100554C4C7E8BD707238701D1CC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>oversight procedures, including regular and random audits conducted by subject matter experts unaffiliated with the national governing body, of all members and adults described in subparagraph (A) to ensure that policies and procedures developed under this paragraph are followed correctly and that consistent training is offered and given to all members regarding prevention of sexual abuse; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H07E9DAA5825D480CB9083108E7C3A7ED"><enum>(11)</enum><text>in the case of a national governing body with jurisdiction over more than one athletic facility, establish a mechanism by which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAE2F139A75BC4769B53B7597FD78BCF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the national governing body can—</text> <clause id="HC7D021C3BF3749798CAB2900F793B68E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>receive a report from one of such facilities regarding a case in which an adult authorized by the facility to interact with a minor or amateur athlete at such facility is expelled from or leaves such facility for sexual misconduct, including because of a mere allegation of sexual misconduct; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H92360AEBBF184B2C8186173C52D9E0BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>share a report received under subparagraph (A) with each of the other athletic facilities under the jurisdiction of the national governing body; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H425DF395015F49DA89E8A38E5D8A7CC6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an athletic facility under the jurisdiction of the national governing body can—</text> <clause id="H4AC7CC8F4C29487DAFD268933FEB3F38"><enum>(i)</enum><text>review the reports received by the national governing body under subparagraph (A)(i) to assess any allegations of sexual misconduct made in such reports; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF8BAF3D0D1A84AD283AB554EDCE4CA9E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>withhold providing to an adult who is the subject of an allegation of sexual misconduct in a report reviewed under clause (i) authority to interact with a minor or amateur athlete at such facility until such time as the facility determines that there is no risk to a minor or amateur athlete at such facility.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H373AB2E9A3E74DA8BCD6818E838E76EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Section 220522 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF645C3EDA02647E483EB130C49C0CF3C" style="USC"> <subsection id="H688A1C5428CF4147A5DBF79466BAE0DD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in paragraph (a) shall be construed to limit the ability of a national governing body to develop a policy or procedure to prevent an individual who is the subject of an allegation of sexual misconduct from interacting with a minor or amateur athlete until such time as the national governing body, or any person under the jurisdiction of the national governing body, determines that there is no risk to the minor or amateur athlete by allowing the individual to interact with the minor or amateur athlete.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


