<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4221E97AF721472C96F749C3716E138D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3254 IH: Heroin and Opioid Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3254</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170714">July 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code to impose an excise tax on opioid manufacturers, to make the funds collected through such tax available for opioid (including heroin) abuse prevention and treatment programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5B3192B8A4A9467281554A0FA58BCFBA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H07C9675316F24C85B2E12E8EAD621ED5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Heroin and Opioid Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1DCF91D720AF44AB965E9CE9983C1DF2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Excise tax on opioids</header> <subsection id="H74D1C03AC69F42A09E57F257FBC0222D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter E of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/32">chapter 32</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HDC362D3C5C6042938845D008104087F9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4CDE9CF902D24FEC98B327F93B32EEDA"><enum>4192.</enum><header>Opioids</header> 
<subsection id="HDBEB15A3710449D6A5B28B451C5241CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is hereby imposed on the manufacturer, producer, or importer of any taxable active opioid a tax equal to the amount determined under subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H99E70BB3C27241D7B7818B327826C166"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amount determined</header><text>The amount determined under this subsection with respect to a manufacturer, producer, or importer for a calendar year is 1 cent per milligram of taxable active opioid in the production or manufacturing quota determined for such manufacturer, producer, or importer for the calendar year under section 306 of the Controlled Substances Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H451164802F2E4550BF684774E82D9EBA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Taxable active opioid</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H4167A6DB53F741F2A390815F1CC63110"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>taxable active opioid</term> means any controlled substance (as defined in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act) manufactured in the United States which is opium, an opiate, or any derivative thereof. Such term excludes a narcotic drug for maintenance treatment or detoxification treatment if, to dispense the drug, a practitioner must obtain a separate registration under section 303(g) of the Controlled Substances Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA0AC83D5E2C3477D95FA24D60262EB30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other ingredients</header><text>In the case of a product that includes a taxable active opioid and another ingredient, subsection (a) shall apply only to the portion of such product that is a taxable active opioid.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H5CAE03CBD9874285B10B3694B53B4357"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header> <paragraph id="H684B630ECB424522A7B4499DCD4B3555"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The heading of subchapter E of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/32">chapter 32</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>Medical Devices</quote> and inserting <quote>Other Medical Products</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0A4A4DE88E734DA48375CB7541D25F45"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The table of subchapters for chapter 32 of such Code is amended by striking the item relating to subchapter E and inserting the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H30A3BB2BA70D4365A5697F109A54B18F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="subchapter">Subchapter E. Other Medical Products</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D13822C58444902AF71E968C52DAD54"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The table of sections for subchapter E of chapter 32 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HC5472AFFF7C94D8E98D00A87B3CA6706" style="OLC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 4192. Opioids.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H52D5C4DBA112452D9D6639C0B997255C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to calendar years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H0050ACF02E2B42479EE836586BF5A2E8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants to States for prevention and treatment of opioid (including heroin) abuse</header> <subsection id="H4FC549E6B2C94801A29DE9188D3886AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 399V–6 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g-17">42 U.S.C. 280g–17</external-xref>) the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H6FCB83C5D82E4205BEFFC32DDFAB3BD5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA5EC215CCB944C0D87A74D2F32BDDB7D"><enum>399V–7.</enum><header>Prevention and treatment of opioid (including heroin) abuse</header> 
<subsection id="H2D9F1DEE112B496DBBABE60D69E5FFEA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide—</text> <paragraph id="HF9746FF962C9488B985B8AFC283DB69C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">grants to States for research on opioids (including heroin); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8726A40CC383408392E9A33E2A4AE056"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">grants to States for opioid abuse prevention and treatment, which may include—</text> <subparagraph id="H73F925DEFD674C9587B52CD11AF071E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing new addiction treatment facilities for opioid addicts;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9852E008468A4769A0E2AD1B2A599D8B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing sober living facilities for recovering opioid addicts;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAA7EAC95B7D042678E3FE86EC3366CDF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recruiting and increasing reimbursement for certified mental health providers providing opioid abuse treatment in medically underserved communities or communities with high rates of opioid abuse;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H83C3C7CABEC74A9A95DAA2D3C297FD7E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expanding access to long-term, residential treatment programs for opioid addicts and recovering addicts;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C47D3A983C34F6FA2A230DAB7381EE8"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing or operating support programs that offer employment services, housing, and other support services for recovering opioid addicts;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAEF22654E7A1448E879FCC5E77386ADB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>establishing or operating housing for children whose parents are participating in opioid abuse treatment programs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H95B3821E1D1248FFBBB58F116C55DD73"><enum>(G)</enum><text>establishing or operating facilities to provide care for babies born with neonatal abstinence syndrome;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7AF3ECB74424451FB311E23375CDF09A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>establishing or operating controlled opioid take-back programs; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H98442C279772429FA7D344D73DD9C1E4"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other opioid abuse prevention and treatment programs, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4527666EC34D4F90912A4ABA8B71C58A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriation of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From time to time, beginning in the second calendar year that begins after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer from the general fund of the Treasury an amount equal to the total amount of taxes collected under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4192">section 4192</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out this section. Amounts transferred under this subsection shall remain available without further appropriation until expended.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H277F383E50C84AE4937918CB0EB1A278"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Emergency designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amounts made available by amendments made by this section are designated as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 4(g) of the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/933">2 U.S.C. 933(g)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

