<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3AD6A77B81F3468D9CCAEB146F6A115C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 742 IH: To prohibit any hiring freeze from affecting any Department of Defense position at, or in support of, a public shipyard.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 742</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170130">January 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit any hiring freeze from affecting any Department of Defense position at, or in support
			 of, a public shipyard.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE969323915844AF5AA6F2610334C6874" style="OLC">
 <section id="H83580186154B43C2B08A7CC7B079186E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition on hiring freeze from affecting Department of Defense public shipyard positions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The memorandum titled <quote>Presidential Memorandum Regarding the Hiring Freeze</quote> published on January 23, 2017, or any other substantially similar memorandum, Executive order, or other action by the President to prevent a department or agency of the Federal Government from filling vacant Federal civilian employee positions or creating new such positions, shall have no force or effect with respect to any Department of Defense civilian position under which an employee performs a Department of Defense function at a public shipyard or a Department of Defense function that directly supports a public shipyard.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


