<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF6E127FA3D344F87B683E27F0DB9DC75" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 262 IH: Buffalo Bayou National Heritage Area Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 262</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170104">January 4, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Buffalo Bayou National Heritage Area in the State of Texas, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9382D93ED00B48F88545BE9283A65385" style="OLC">
 <section id="H05CE2E989B3B42029420D521508AA988" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Buffalo Bayou National Heritage Area Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H883E968576A64520AA93AAE17F7EB2DF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="HDEC733780E834C8D9289DAE8AE5D930B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Heritage area</header><text>The term <term>Heritage Area</term> means the Buffalo Bayou National Heritage Area established in this Act.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3678B875E4844CCA01A423BAB0D41C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management entity</header><text>The term <term>management entity</term> means the management entity for the Heritage Area designated by this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BD92EC5987D4C98AFD091F70F41F549"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Management plan</header><text>The term <term>management plan</term> means the management plan for the Heritage Area required under this Act.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2AADC8C793954078B93C1BF5EF85A2A2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>map</term> means the map entitled <quote><short-title>Buffalo Bayou National Heritage Area Proposed Boundary</short-title></quote>, numbered T11/101,592, and dated March 2010.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H41B6733245BE4412A35A99CA19EE924D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H72B9889E5DEE4C23B232343AD753EC3A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Texas.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HF7B46C6F14714C67BF374783CCD7D186"><enum>3.</enum><header>Buffalo Bayou National Heritage Area</header>
 <subsection id="HA59D1731DAAB493ABFDBF320843E846F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the State the Buffalo Bayou National Heritage Area.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HC692627CAE64437E86AB037E2E615873"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Boundaries</header><text>The Heritage Area shall consist of areas included in the map in Harris County, Texas.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H307B61F913B840A2BDEDD6D16FA45C2F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Map</header><text>A map of the Heritage Area shall be—</text> <paragraph id="H9F7A2C80EB16426AA40B868173FA5EC8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>included in the management plan; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CCE3F035A5A4E0A8151101DEE3B93E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD924C205935D490B96B16D6250C7F342"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Management entity</header><text>The management entity for the Heritage Area shall be the Buffalo Bayou National Heritage Area Corporation.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H1E71CE99F22F42EC8A65555CA0DC6A6C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The management entity shall—</text> <paragraph id="H9B024DE2BCCE4CADBD2157BDAF13159F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in accordance with section 5, prepare and submit a management plan for the Heritage Area to the Secretary;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H291A2DAF991F4559BB894C87CEB231A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assist units of local government, regional planning organizations, and nonprofit organizations in carrying out the approved management plan by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H853A85F42DFE40F9915D090C75BE7DF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carrying out programs and projects that recognize, protect, and enhance important resource values in the Heritage Area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1110C791F7CB46D88415FEDF540781A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing and maintaining interpretive exhibits and programs in the Heritage Area;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C796372480D42F29278C53255070ABD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>developing recreational and educational opportunities in the Heritage Area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D2A7614EC454E5AA558EE5FDD796A55"><enum>(D)</enum><text>increasing public awareness of, and appreciation for, natural, historical, scenic, and cultural resources of the Heritage Area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A04F4184F7844B9ADDE4C04CB4348AF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>protecting and restoring historic sites and buildings in the Heritage Area that are consistent with Heritage Area themes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAAEBE068F9D44E49782E38A6988140B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>ensuring that clear, consistent, and appropriate signs identifying points of public access, and sites of interest are posted throughout the Heritage Area; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CFC0737D76F4B1B87FAB188194B9F27"><enum>(G)</enum><text>promoting a wide range of partnerships among governments, organizations, and individuals to further the Heritage Area;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87D23911DF1B4852911E0FB459AA2151"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consider the interests of diverse units of government, businesses, organizations, and individuals in the Heritage Area in the preparation and implementation of the management plan;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H393F06E07E95441190927D3498F07DCB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>conduct meetings open to the public at least semiannually regarding the development and implementation of the management plan; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9AD7F8F2006B40F9A6C06B00FBD79C78"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit an annual report to the Secretary that describes the activities, expenses, and income of the management entity (including grants to any other entities during the year that the report is made).</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HDA82902EA5144460896F8883908151E3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Management plan</header>
 <subsection id="HD5B74EC236B94174A9669CE75F5131EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the management entity shall submit to the Secretary for approval a proposed management plan for the Heritage Area.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFC760542A1D946D0B7EC1172E4D22221"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The management plan shall—</text> <paragraph id="H01D6ED93E54A41869104D237906DA5AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>incorporate an integrated and cooperative approach for the protection, enhancement, and interpretation of the natural, cultural, historic, scenic, and recreational resources of the Heritage Area;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCED5769BBFBD4CA4910B90299FD10DF0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>take into consideration State and local plans;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1E5DA25AC674593B2CFD1B4FB025F33"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4AE6A32343074B1AAA26C046B1070285"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an inventory of—</text> <clause id="H32647B3596D34272AA08FE4E322F2D65"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the resources located in the core area described in section 4(b); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4B457A8DE2B2417A8AA984C789C2A8A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other property in the core area that—</text> <subclause id="H8D7DF2837C7B4E5192ADB5AE624496DA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is related to the themes of the Heritage Area; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7D0886542C2B47D483D7EEB02C4ED9FE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>should be preserved, restored, managed, or maintained because of the significance of the property;</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2D039FBE7204D56A416D9D0C5B6B48B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>comprehensive policies, strategies, and recommendations for conservation, funding, management, and development of the Heritage Area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CF1577593E34ECB8D3F76AAE28DA5B0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of actions that governments, private organizations, and individuals have agreed to take to protect the natural, historical, and cultural resources of the Heritage Area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H430BBF96AA5D4F86B203CBDDE0B27904"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a program of implementation for the management plan by the management entity that includes a description of actions to facilitate ongoing collaboration among partners to—</text>
 <clause id="HCB260CF8DCF943F8B93CDA79037262F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>promote plans for resource protection, restoration, and construction; and</text> </clause><clause id="HE8B2B48585924B1CA5D2611B83FEEC19"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>specific commitments for implementation that have been made by the management entity or any government, organization, or individual for the first 5 years of operation;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBCE50FFE6F841C8919E8C1A5DBCBDF9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the identification of sources of funding for carrying out the management plan;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BFE785D43764086BDD5A637D1CB6A81"><enum>(F)</enum><text>analysis and recommendations for means by which local, State, and Federal programs, including the role of the National Park Service in the Heritage Area, may best be coordinated to carry out this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H641710691EB74748BCF4B4667D2E22D7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>an interpretive plan for the Heritage Area; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0273CDE18BC54D7EBEE22C9386F6E64C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommend policies and strategies for resource management that consider and detail the application of appropriate land and water management techniques, including the development of intergovernmental and interagency cooperative agreements to protect the natural, historical, cultural, educational, scenic, and recreational resources of the Heritage Area.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D483347CCC04C4AB379F5C649E53229"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>If a proposed management plan is not submitted to the Secretary by the date that is 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the management entity shall be ineligible to receive the designation of a National Heritage Area under this Act until the date that the Secretary receives and approves the management plan.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HC9E6E03BF0284220AE6FC604F7E49BE8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Approval or disapproval of management plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H7FB914EEB89C42D38069DA24B5005DA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of receipt of the management plan under subsection (a), the Secretary, in consultation with the State, shall approve or disapprove the management plan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H850C5A5FD9914FAC9A56307787206E9F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria for approval</header><text>In determining whether to approve the management plan, the Secretary shall consider whether—</text> <subparagraph id="HBD05064D5B514474877FA7DBAC0C330C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the management entity is representative of the diverse interests of the Heritage Area, including governments, natural and historic resource protection organizations, educational institutions, businesses, and recreational organizations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81CE23FAD01846AB91B567522621F281"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the management entity has afforded adequate opportunity, including public hearings, for public and governmental involvement in the preparation of the management plan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BFA1E498F0A47BCB554909E6F8723CD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the resource protection and interpretation strategies contained in the management plan, if implemented, would adequately protect the natural, historical, and cultural resources of the Heritage Area.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H05D7450F75514EA38381DD3751791C2E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Action following disapproval</header><text>If the Secretary disapproves the management plan under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H5E63D715F285481790FA857FBF3491C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advise the management entity in writing of the reasons for the disapproval;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0C0C5A25A254948A1AC13EB1F8D784B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make recommendations for revisions to the management plan; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CFCDEEE08464ECD80241E12F5EC85F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the receipt of any proposed revision of the management plan from the management entity, approve or disapprove the proposed revision.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B0E53A131864581865181EE8ECDDA6D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall approve or disapprove each amendment to the management plan that the Secretary determines makes a substantial change to the management plan.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H38FAE2F472C44B39B46B5ECED645A1FE"><enum>6.</enum><header>Relationship to other Federal agencies</header>
 <subsection id="HE077E59608684DFDB79329D9AC950FF6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects the authority of a Federal agency to provide technical or financial assistance under any other law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBE530901425B4C11B3416B7BA8E59584"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation and coordination</header><text>The head of any Federal agency planning to conduct activities that may have an impact on the Heritage Area is encouraged to consult and coordinate the activities with the Secretary and the management entity to the maximum extent practicable.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1CD2A2DFE74F42B7AEBB214F0F2288D7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other Federal agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H7B8806BCE7A647CFAE244C325C3F069D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>modifies, alters, or amends any law or regulation authorizing a Federal agency to manage Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Federal agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7BACCF0F73B54F93A791A9E72D70B785"><enum>(2)</enum><text>limits the discretion of a Federal land manager to implement an approved land use plan within the boundaries of the Heritage Area; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B388629D16049DBB4C7703A9D19B65E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>modifies, alters, or amends any authorized use of Federal land under the jurisdiction of a Federal agency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H969AB25D0BEF40C4B86169DB9CFE084F"><enum>7.</enum><header>Private property protection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act—</text> <paragraph id="HE26AC84AA79B4E168C9F452934CB4F74"><enum>(1)</enum><text>abridges the rights of any property owner (whether public or private), including the right to refrain from participating in any plan, project, program, or activity conducted within the Heritage Area;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H096432E05E4A45738CCF85E5FE98D514"><enum>(2)</enum><text>requires any property owner to permit public access (including access by Federal, State, or local agencies) to the property of the property owner, or to modify public access or use of property of the property owner under any other Federal, State, or local law;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DB6B47FEB4A482D8660AF52F68E33BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>alters any duly adopted land use regulation, approved land use plan, or other regulatory authority of any Federal, State or local agency, or conveys any land use or other regulatory authority to the management entity;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CDA482BCF1441EEB8B6CBA21F0D88E2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>authorizes or implies the reservation or appropriation of water or water rights;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7F69251585540738DF38BC5C67046D0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>diminishes the authority of the State to manage fish and wildlife, including the regulation of fishing and hunting within the Heritage Area; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADF7A30C7BBA4EE09065F85842E11130"><enum>(6)</enum><text>creates any liability, or affects any liability under any other law, of any private property owner with respect to any person injured on the private property.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HFC4CE6EF4A6141D19245A527212DB14E"><enum>8.</enum><header>Water rights</header>
 <subsection id="H88095A4DAA7F4760AB2A40C0FA553AE6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>Nothing in this Act is meant to modify the Rio Grande Natural Area Act.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H659DA2B4003B4E4586B0725040182C03"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Nothing in this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9C10505AAC7C45ACAD6E20FA9C762294"><enum>(1)</enum><text>amends, modifies, or is in conflict with the Act of May 31, 1939 (53 Stat. 785, chapter 155);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H87BCECE74A944085AB1830CF3423ECF9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>authorizes the regulation of private land in the Heritage Area;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7EA2CDA97B147D59C2A92C891BBDE39"><enum>(3)</enum><text>authorizes the imposition of any mandatory streamflow requirements;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC57EF6B11E9407CA260535A6D558BB0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>creates an express or implied Federal reserved water right;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7E8631348244444B5AA0D20A5716237"><enum>(5)</enum><text>imposes any Federal water quality standard within or upstream of the Heritage Area that is more restrictive than would be applicable had the Heritage Area not been established; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69625A0D23C846A5B5BEA435DF5A5D6A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>prevents the State of Texas from acquiring an instream flow through the Heritage Area under the terms, conditions, and limitations of State law to assist in protecting the natural environment to the extent and for the purposes authorized by State law.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H959719A78CA34B03A6290D92B0DD489A"><enum>9.</enum><header>Evaluation Report</header>
 <subsection id="H3F03B7C2D25E46B985B5630696E7CE16"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ten years after the establishment of the Heritage Area, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HDE9A463A4BE24690B0E6F213D78B214C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct an evaluation of the accomplishments of the Heritage Area; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H969671DCF9434890B41284699442A270"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prepare a report in accordance with subsection (c).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C437C1F3DF24625A416CFBC99C7DD90"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>An evaluation conducted under subsection (a)(1) shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H113BD73EFA2C4BA9A58188221E2EA141"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assess the progress of the management entity with respect to—</text> <subparagraph id="HBF122AE7C190451EB26578B847475FA9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accomplishing the purposes of this Act for the Heritage Area; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H868CC222939941DF881F9284070B5E1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>achieving the goals and objectives of the approved management plan for the Heritage Area;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H69E249E286F144A3961254872BAEDE52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>analyze the Federal, State, local, and private investments in the Heritage Area to determine the impact of the investments; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6CE2EC55A764AADB83902802736260C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>review the management structure, partnership relationships, and funding of the Heritage Area for purposes of identifying the critical components for sustainability of the Heritage Area.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H204472B062ED40FAB46DC187CA7B2847"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <paragraph id="H3429B2357ED441F9907F12CB25FE705D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Based on the evaluation conducted under subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall prepare a report that includes recommendations for the future role of the National Park Service, if any, with respect to the Heritage Area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4251B0363C2D48B7894290153F365C1C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission to congress</header><text>On completion of the report, the Secretary shall submit the report to—</text> <subparagraph id="HA3861A82B7F5416096EF25B58DC3E679"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF92ED7D853042F8BC25A0DFFFB415AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

