<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H39C52A4D770748589D5C0865D543ECEC" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2500 IH: Executive Appointee Ethics Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2500</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170517">May 17, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit high-level Federal employees from participating
			 in any matter substantially related to the appointee’s former employment,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE4802D1327FB4365A9642BC2E3F8E9D2" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1CFD6A4AE364486A8983ABE6069461FF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Executive Appointee Ethics Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6F5D69FF0D08492B8DB875FE9340822C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments to section 207 of title 18</header> <subsection id="H7666D845E3604C6CB4065BE1A60F96E1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension of post-Employment ban on lobbying for certain former government employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 207 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF5A29211C32C43829D9D6232D567825F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="H7FF65D9290884E649E264F75A491A4B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">one-year</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">two-Year</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58096CA71D364A72825086F9D7A14FC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="HF70E5441280D403A90443A4B191D159F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>within 1 year after</quote> and inserting <quote>within 2 years after</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H28C997055DB947C6ADCB1872B7CA4A2E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>within 1 year before such termination</quote>; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1492B2FA12394BCA96DF5AFF313AC298"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF6E8A6D4A8394F399395454DCD171C56" style="USC">
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H345A82938D63464399B8EA25C628F4F0" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after a waiver is granted under subparagraph (C), the waiver shall be published in the Federal Register and accompanied by a signed statement by the Director of the Office of Government Ethics describing in detail the reasons for providing such waiver unless such a description would compromise national security.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H66608FBAB31E4171823C7A5523C31B8A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1), in the matter following subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>within 2 years</quote> and inserting <quote>within 5 years</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H03587BFA9F884D8A903478A82E9BB723"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(2)(A), by striking <quote>in such position</quote> and all that follows through <quote>terminated</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC635310DBE347D4B73602BC1D4FA917"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Lifetime ban on representation of foreign entities for certain high-Level former employees</header><text>Section 207(f) of such title is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H99246599C17E4AB78AAFE8CAA91919CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>(or, in the case of an individual described in paragraph (2), at any time)</quote> after <quote>within 1 year</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C22FA62AD444AC593D262F8EFAF3CF0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>paragraph (1)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (1) and (2)</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H005E3519EB5E46029100C076ABBFAC86"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) and (3) as paragraphs (3) and (4); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H75FC2AAD7CEF47109A0224AAF10EA21E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4ADFFBE170F54ACD922C35C161556B61" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H170900DE355043DF8C30673F6F9303EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Description of individuals subject to lifetime ban</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual described in this paragraph is any individual who was—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H433799FBE1854875B5A12C3DBD1180E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employed in a position described under sections 5312 through 5316 of title 5, United States Code (relating to the Executive Schedule);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52D7163ED74644D488A5B8ADF0302A4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a limited term appointee, limited emergency appointee, or noncareer appointee in the Senior Executive Service, as defined under paragraphs (5), (6), and (7), respectively, of section 3132(a) of title 5, United States Code; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68B3429EC5404FE5B8D166BB183FEA06"><enum>(C)</enum><text>employed in a position of a confidential or policy-determining character under schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5 of the Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H03461308288149ED91F011CE557D7AB3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on participation in matter relating to previous employment</header>
 <subsection id="H14D4345D78FC4CACBA03595C62D41776"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/11">Chapter 11</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/219">section 219</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA88759406E1848E6B929EE51E3577FA5" style="USC">
					<section id="HC2D83503872C47FCB38931402328EA20"><enum>220.</enum><header>Prohibition on participation in matter relating to previous employment</header>
 <subsection id="H3F3E71EAA03F40D9862BE8E5BB7F9E1F"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 2-year period beginning on the date an individual is appointed to a covered position at an agency, any such individual who has not received a waiver under subsection (b)—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE1619C0C53EA4EDC8E3D297E967C84F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>who participates in any particular matter involving specific parties that is directly and substantially related to the individual’s former employer or former clients, or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3317ECDBFAF74752B66871C7894F7A5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to any such individual who was a registered lobbyist under the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995, or who was not a registered lobbyist under such Act but who engaged in lobbying activity as defined in subsection (c), during the 2-year period preceding the date of such appointment, who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H84AD3B7607D74C26A46653136867445C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>participates in any particular matter on which the individual made a lobbying contact (in the case of a registered lobbyist under such Act), or engaged in such activity, during such 2-year period,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAADF101C1B64680AF319BCFD6B4742F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">participates in the specific issue area in which such particular matter falls, or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H787449A1DBFF43D9B72F25EE9C8F28F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seeks or accepts employment with any agency with respect to which the individual made a lobbying contact (in the case of a registered lobbyist under such Act), or engaged in such activity, during such 2-year period,</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall be punished as provided in section 216 of this title.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="HCD78A3BDD5EC4EF9BBD3C2A70041F9F6"><enum>(b)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBC16B322512240B2863F7AA95EB6A02C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Counsel to the President, may waive the requirements of subsection (a) with respect to any individual covered by such subsection if the Director certifies, in writing, to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and the appropriate congressional committees of jurisdiction, that it is in the public interest to grant the waiver.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H924CC10D43444D6AA722045A12051A02" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of carrying out paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H22F767706EBF45D29667AB3E43D62DB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the public interest includes exigent circumstances relating to public health, public safety, or national security;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43FA632C1C8E4CD9A443B3B519E8D03D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>de minimis contact with an agency shall be cause for a waiver of subsection (a)(2); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD86502D34AB048A891D0175B3FDB561A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any waiver shall take effect when the certification is published in the Federal Register, accompanied by a signed statement by the Director describing in detail the reasons for providing the waiver unless such a description would compromise national security.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H60E6BABB7F2540DF8EFD87C349BBDD44"><enum>(c)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HECFD8BB583B746C98783C2A88F1AC17D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>lobbying activity</quote> means, with respect to an individual, knowingly making, with the intent to influence, any communication to or appearance before any officer or employee of the Federal Government on behalf of another person as an employee of a lobbying firm or lobbying organization, in connection with any matter on which such person seeks official action by such officer or employee of the Federal Government. The previous sentence applies only with respect to an individual who spends greater than 20% of the individual’s time as an employee of a lobbying firm or lobbying organization engaged in such lobbying activity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4C33B3B86EF4C76A3F69FC5D06F5721" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In paragraph (1), the term <quote>lobbying firm</quote> means any firm, corporation, or limited liability company in which—</text> <subparagraph id="HACC4E780B9184FA884A3D98993D9E635"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employees of the firm in the aggregate make 2 or more lobbying contacts at any time on behalf of a particular client; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD91CB02633A94BF5877F3BAFFC1D158E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the firm receives or expects to receive from a particular client for matters related to lobbying activities at least the amount specified in section 4(a)(3)(A) of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1603">2 U.S.C. 1603(a)(3)(A)</external-xref>) in the quarterly period during which registration would be made under such Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB52BBB395F3F43009B0C3E50502C5608" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In paragraph (1), the term <quote>lobbying organization</quote> includes any organization in which—</text> <subparagraph id="H2EE8BE155C7540C384C6C7C8B0B62DF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employees of the firm in the aggregate make 2 or more lobbying contacts at any time on its behalf; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3EB7EDE2C2247CE960304B843A34600"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the organization expends in connection with lobbying activities at least the amount specified in section 4(a)(3)(B) of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1603">2 U.S.C. 1603(a)(3)(A)</external-xref>) in the quarterly period during which registration would be made under such Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C51A909D72F4A888350F98F19BED707" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>employee</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3(5) of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1602">2 U.S.C. 1602(5)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBCA100E921C9416B8389227BEBECEAFA"><enum>(d)</enum><text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="HFA06CCCADB66493EB2D03249DA25D1DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>agency</quote> means an <quote>Executive agency</quote> (as that term is defined in section 105 of title 5), the Executive Office of the President, the United States Postal Service, and the Postal Regulatory Commission, but does not include the Government Accountability Office.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE1F616CFD0642B883439780B2EC0C23"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered position</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="H169459EABE35496686474B58FDE166D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H7038A8FB00904ED986EDC5491B336C2E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>full-time, non-career position which requires appointment by the President or Vice-President;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H7CE399ED7A304159BF9B9435DC5EB271"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>non-career position within the Senior Executive Service or other SES-type system; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7FCE4A8EEF94415986EAE5EA060523C9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">position that has been excepted from the competitive service by reason of being of a confidential or policymaking character, including positions under schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5 of the Code of Federal Regulations; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H916EB6951DCE43ABBB8DC9D106F9717D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include any individual appointed as a member of the Senior Foreign Service or solely as a uniformed service commissioned officer.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C7F9D644280498B93FBDEDC1F7FEC1F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>directly and substantially related to former employer or former clients</quote> means matters in which the individual’s former employer or a former client is a party or represents a party.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2928A77244CC4DAC81CA85ABB8A20148"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>former client</quote> means any person for whom the individual served personally as agent, attorney, or consultant, but does include instances where the service provided was limited to a speech or similar appearance or clients of the individual’s former employer to whom the individual did not personally provide services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B5EDB5BCB064B7FA3A3ED9A46CD53B6"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>former employer</quote> means any person for whom the individual has within the 2 years prior to the date of appointment served as an employee, officer, director, trustee, or general partner, but does not include any agency or other entity of the Federal Government, Native American tribe, or any United States territory or possession.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4110C6D706146E4B0C3ED98FF5A218D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <quote>lobbying contact</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3(8) of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1602">2 U.S.C. 1602(8)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE806546097A4910B08C49937A51BCF0"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>particular matter</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 207 and section 2635.402(b)(3) of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5DEB32B4AA75478F9FA9122674BCFA5E"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>participate</quote> means to participate personally and substantially.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H99418A01B1334020AB1D8DD3C9A1E874"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>particular matter involving specific parties</quote> has the meaning as set forth in section 2641.201(h) of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation, except that it shall also include any meeting or other communication relating to the performance of an individual’s official duties with a former employer or former client, unless the communication applies to a particular matter of general applicability and participation in the meeting or other event is open to all interested parties.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H293FB6FCE2AF413DAC776B93A5F97164"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/219">section 219</external-xref> the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H53AF89E6F7FC4305B2CB0A0826425510" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">220. Prohibition on participation in matter relating to previous employment.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H64CF077EF7294DAD8653011202E6CA52"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The amendments made after subsection (a) shall apply to any individual appointed to a covered position (as that term is defined in section 220(d)(2) of title 18, United States Code, as added by such subsection) after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


