<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H511CD279CAE343F4BC369A56606BD6CE" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1308 IH: Frank and Jeanne Moore Wild Steelhead Special Management Area Designation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1308</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170302">March 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate the Frank and Jeanne Moore Wild Steelhead Special Management Area in the State of
			 Oregon.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA84C865DE80940A6ABFD4F3189901368" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4CA0F06AE74E4EF7B539E8BB327B9C03" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Frank and Jeanne Moore Wild Steelhead Special Management Area Designation Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7978464AA81E43239CEEAA471B421FBE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAD01671FD223491A834C169297BDA413"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Frank Moore has committed his life to family, friends, his country, and fly fishing;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E01897F11794AEBB27565781A5CA5D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Frank Moore is a World War II veteran who stormed the beaches of Normandy along with 150,000 troops during the D-Day Allied invasion and was awarded the Chevalier of the French Legion of Honor for his bravery;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H10BE51FC74254A569CDC8B1598161480"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Frank Moore returned home after the war, started a family, and pursued his passion of fishing on the winding rivers in Oregon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DE1428475454C2DB471031BA3629156"><enum>(4)</enum><text>as the proprietor of the Steamboat Inn along the North Umpqua River in Oregon for nearly 20 years, Frank Moore, along with his wife Jeanne, shared his love of fishing, the flowing river, and the great outdoors, with visitors from all over the United States and the world;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69AC4850A3F6472EB6539A4386B1BD0C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Frank Moore has spent most of his life fishing the vast rivers of Oregon, during which time he has contributed significantly to efforts to conserve fish habitats and protect river health, including serving on the State of Oregon Fish and Wildlife Commission;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE72A328769724451AEED9040B8B1C651"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Frank Moore has been recognized for his conservation work with the National Wildlife Federation Conservationist of the Year award, the Wild Steelhead Coalition Conservation Award, and his 2010 induction into the Fresh Water Fishing Hall of Fame; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C0602F1179641A39028E5CC59A5AF53"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in honor of the many accomplishments of Frank Moore, both on and off the river, approximately 99,653 acres of Forest Service land in the State of Oregon should be designated as the <quote>Frank and Jeanne Moore Wild Steelhead Special Management Area</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HDB7BE249FAF744B1A29A0445FB16683A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HB770B13F87E241CC8F4AAC4B75B94867"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>Map</term> means the map entitled <quote>Frank Moore Wild Steelhead Special Management Area Designation Act</quote> and dated June 23, 2016.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H73F0D0AF89794202B105B8BD72BF2889"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51B03C357C144D21B961B12D505EC607"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Special management area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Special Management Area</quote> means the Frank and Jeanne Moore Wild Steelhead Special Management Area designated by section 4(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33E750E42FFD4609A68B2ECC5CEDBA5B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Oregon.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H35A8AA92BD4C4B4DA31479C365C28D49"><enum>4.</enum><header>Frank and Jeanne Moore Wild Steelhead Special Management Area, Oregon</header> <subsection id="H1A8655EB8CFC404BA74A08D7D843CFBF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The approximately 99,653 acres of Forest Service land in the State, as generally depicted on the Map, is designated as the <quote>Frank and Jeanne Moore Wild Steelhead Special Management Area</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H0587DFC126BD490C830D51180CC0DF3A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Map; legal description</header>
 <paragraph id="H9C12EE7D8E3E452F94332C2246D73B97"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prepare a map and legal description of the Special Management Area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF59794324A95403D902B131F9ACC3AF6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The map and legal description prepared under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct clerical and typographical errors in the map and legal description.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA773829F522F4CCDAF4C9B4B20CA1EC2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The map and legal description prepared under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Forest Service.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H40F43E84ACA046AFB92FBF390C8D7AE9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Special Management Area shall be administered by the Secretary—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB76CF37773FD450CA730E72D11A53699"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in accordance with all laws (including regulations) applicable to the National Forest System; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF9428213C1E48DDB03EC70595B5192B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in a manner that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE50393CB781D4D419D4F3307DA843B71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conserves and enhances the natural character, scientific use, and the botanical, recreational, ecological, fish and wildlife, scenic, drinking water, and cultural values of the Special Management Area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EF1D1069F4140F09860234013D5F138"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintains and seeks to enhance the wild salmonid habitat of the Special Management Area;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DE935D6B3064EF8B01EADE3AB871784"><enum>(C)</enum><text>maintains or enhances the watershed as a thermal refuge for wild salmonids; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED46DF93D1C042CC8C78300802C3B27C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>preserves opportunities for recreation, including primitive recreation.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCAD0EA29C25B4A0FB31FA70DC46077E1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header><text>Nothing in this section affects the jurisdiction or responsibilities of the State with respect to fish and wildlife in the State.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE7BCF0A96142466682BCB1AA181204C5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Adjacent management</header><text>Nothing in this section—</text> <paragraph id="H93411CE21E374354A9E3E60933A419FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>creates any protective perimeter or buffer zone around the Special Management Area; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADF734ECDBCB49EDA53AEBD188B81D50"><enum>(2)</enum><text>modifies the applicable travel management plan for the Special Management Area.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H24B33755BAD246BB90303CF3CE8712EE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Wildfire management</header><text>Nothing in this section prohibits the Secretary, in cooperation with other Federal, State, and local agencies, as appropriate, from conducting wildland fire operations in the Special Management Area, consistent with the purposes of this Act, including the use of aircraft, machinery, mechanized equipment, fire breaks, backfires, and retardant.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB20EAE00103745CD89A7655280000AE5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Vegetation management</header><text>Nothing in this section prohibits the Secretary from conducting vegetation management projects within the Special Management Area in a manner consistent with—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC2F30269727B4536A79D459ED5A02D6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the purposes described in subsection (c); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B141A9F1A2D49658F2CF9DF13355D57"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the applicable forest plan.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEDD5FD4B3F2A45768FB32AFD958C6E18"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Protection of tribal rights</header><text>Nothing in this section diminishes any treaty rights of an Indian tribe.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H14B0EFE282B74406A92B37403D65E425"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land within the boundaries of the Special Management Area river segments designated by subsection (a) is withdrawn from all forms of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF0009B668A3249EF8E602B44F6DC755C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H18E19A8F197D4FF08283A1D3CDF76AC7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H53B388BF0447421F8F99AF6AE4E0BFA0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>disposition under all laws relating to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

