<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8527B36615FF497CAFAE21EEBB3FC9FE" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2777 IH: Give Veterans Home Loan Choices Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2777</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170606">June 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To include information regarding VA home loans in the Informed Consumer Choice Disclosure required
			 to be provided to a prospective FHA borrower who is a veteran, to amend
			 title 10, United States Code, to authorize the provision of a certificate
			 of eligibility for VA home loans during the preseparation counseling for
			 members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H403F9CED046948EB9D50F5125E940524" style="OLC">
 <section id="H10859B8A7548430E88D89B76A3578365" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Give Veterans Home Loan Choices Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5DE17EDF2D5D41A0BDC3966DCADD6EF9"><enum>2.</enum><header>FHA Informed Consumer Choice Disclosure</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) of section 203(f)(2) of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1709">12 U.S.C. 1709(f)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H760176A5428F489F9F999CC07715B1EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(i)</quote> after <quote>loan-to-value ratio</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H96A3C9DE1ACD49D199AE7A9CFEAA6536"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting before the semicolon the following: <quote>, and (ii) in the case of a prospective borrower who is a veteran (as such term is defined in section 101 of title 38, United States Code), in connection with a loan guaranteed or insured under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/37">chapter 37</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, assuming prevailing interest rates</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H5F26E6AFFF7449CA958D678FCD8F2546"><enum>3.</enum><header>Uniform residential loan application</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency shall direct the Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation to revise the Uniform Residential Loan Application developed by such enterprises, not later than December 31, 2018, by—</text>
 <paragraph id="H36238916C411421B845CD50235BE794A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>including in an appropriate place a check box for the applicant to check to indicate that the applicant is a veteran;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1541A76B01EC44F6A9E24AE6FE0C2F9B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>adjacent to the matter required by paragraph (1) and in boldface type, the following statement: <quote>If you are a veteran, you may be eligible for a VA mortgage.</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7BA2985CF8684AC49120258CB56BB711"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adjacent to the matter required by paragraph (2), a blank line for the borrower to initial, and a statement that all applicants must initial such blank line to confirm that they have read the statement required by paragraph (2).</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HBC344B4EF97E448F80DF38F73C65A732"><enum>4.</enum><header>Preseparation counseling for members of the Armed Forces regarding Department of Veterans Affairs
 home loan services and housing assistance benefits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1142(b) of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HFDF099AFF86243ADB06EC12DF7D40DEA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (17) as paragraph (18); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBAF70F285F1346A6BFF9C391D95ADB63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (16) and inserting the following new paragraphs:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2EAC3373553948A18165045034B50862" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H5287C4509A704589ADDC7A94BA626BCA"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on the availability of home loan services by and housing assistance benefits of the Department of Veterans Affairs, including the authority of the member—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H144BDC2BF4BE4A97A262A33DB55E2926"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to use an honorable discharge certificate as a certificate of eligibility to apply for a guaranteed housing loan from the Department of Veterans Affairs; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6759634CE6DE4962A2107FDD4524FEB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to request, during the preseparation process or after separation, a specific certificate of eligibility for such a loan under section 3702(c) of title 38.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F9F257E760B4D4897677CA0DAC4BC19"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Counseling on responsible borrowing practices.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

