<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5A99F906F76B4AB095C6FC425EA6D130" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2734 IH: Trade Enforcement and Trade Deficit Reduction Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2734</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170217">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Department of Commerce to address the trade deficits between the United States and
			 other countries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7F67B8575B434773BF8AA49C92451BEA" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4EB6E6B879F04DC4BCE4793EE979BECC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Trade Enforcement and Trade Deficit Reduction Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="id637AC96A5DCB4AA8883D734C1384C497" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="idDCD7B5BB91614AC4A92BA540323D7DBB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States market is widely recognized as one of the most open markets in the world. Average United States tariff rates are very low and the United States has limited, if any, nontariff barriers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idCE6DFCF371C5412BA518FBB00A5145BF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With each subsequent round of bilateral, regional, and multilateral trade negotiations, tariffs have been significantly reduced or eliminated for many manufactured goods, leaving nontariff barriers as the most pervasive, significant, and challenging barriers to United States exports and market opportunities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id9F4EA6C82EAD4992A91A8D4E964A5726"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Often the only leverage the United States has to obtain the reduction or elimination of nontariff barriers imposed by foreign countries is to negotiate the amount of tariffs the United States imposes on imports from those foreign countries.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id4B2A07482EA04EC2927B35C59F31C23A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The United States has become the world’s largest net debtor nation, having run up massive trade deficits since the mid-1970s.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id28157ED4DEBC4FF7A8F63E98DE7DE349"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Every year since 1976, whether in expansion or recession, the United States has run a deficit in goods and services trade, which weakens and detracts from America’s global leadership position.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id5B9CFEBACD9042B38574F34197DB84D2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The United States trade deficit in 1993, the year before the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) went into force, was $135.6 billion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id599DA41B8BEA4623A9497EBE059A4980"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In 2015, the United States had a deficit in the balance of trade in goods and services of $939.8 billion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD82AD58D8BF34A1C8BDAE5A5DC41D723"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In 2015, the United States had a trade deficit of $179 billion with countries with which it has free trade agreements.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id151D3CAC8CFE4133923B018F33D0AC5F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Persistent deficits weaken the United States economy, defense industrial base, and innovation system and increase the likelihood of ownership of large segments of the United States economy by foreign interests.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idE28D12294E1A4BE4B9C42F1D3DDECA17"><enum>3.</enum><header>Withdrawal of tariff concessions</header><subsection id="id5CB45457E4564AC08F9BD1E18B905787"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Department of Commerce determines pursuant to subsection (c) that—</text><paragraph id="id178976D4320642D882213FD8734B65C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a tariff or nontariff barrier or policy or practice of the government of a foreign country with respect to United States exports of any product has not been reduced or eliminated in accordance with the terms of a trade agreement entered into between the United States and the foreign country; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id58E0841909394FB0987B5B1AA9AE756A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a tariff or nontariff barrier or policy or practice of such government with respect to United States exports of any product has been imposed or discovered,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">the United States Trade Representative shall withdraw any modification of any duty that reduced or
			 eliminated the bound or applied rate of duty on any product that has the
			 same physical characteristics and uses as a product described in paragraph
			 (1) or (2) until such time as the Department of Commerce submits to
			 Congress a certification that the foreign government has reduced or
 eliminated the tariff or nontariff barrier or policy or practice.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="id8861D1CAD0E04737A77A80701DF78B24"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Investigation</header><paragraph id="idAFEDDE4871AB4F268876B097F48433A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Department of Commerce shall initiate an investigation if an interested party files a petition with the Department of Commerce which alleges the elements necessary for the withdrawal of the modification of an existing duty under subsection (a), and which is accompanied by information reasonably available to the petitioner supporting such allegations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id78853EE12ED64B2CB9AC30AF710B2C9B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interested party defined</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <term>interested party</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id026A98ABB2CE4CDC8C06DE8CD91424B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a manufacturer, producer, or wholesaler in the United States of a domestic product that has the same physical characteristics and uses as the product for which a modification of an existing duty is sought;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD6F7754BC7F74EAAA53E03EF14089E03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a certified union or recognized union or group of workers engaged in the manufacture, production, or wholesale in the United States of a domestic product that has the same physical characteristics and uses as the product for which a modification of an existing duty is sought;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id486FE0E0F6F641A48F9EF59426205213"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a trade or business association a majority of whose members manufacture, produce, or wholesale in the United States a domestic product that has the same physical characteristics and uses as the product for which a modification of an existing duty is sought; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7F470BDA324C4F5F8B9C91F2D63BCA3A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a member of the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives or a member of the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id52AADF3649714789922E4C99216D6F2F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determination by the Department of Commerce</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the date on which a petition is filed under subsection (b), the Department of Commerce shall—</text><paragraph id="idB4C82BA1DE8A4B94AFC861914AB6467A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine whether the petition alleges the elements necessary for the withdrawal of the modification of an existing duty under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD7270029C9594FA4A596A01C2D083194"><enum>(2)</enum><text>notify the petitioner of the determination under paragraph (1) and the reasons for the determination.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id4C5FBC8DAA164ADABD3970E97492FE27"><enum>4.</enum><header>Trade deficit reduction</header><subsection id="idF4F3479BA2A04FB8A136146E1BD14112"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification</header><paragraph id="id4DCA9C4444144C97B0C772CD60A91852"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and monthly thereafter, the Department of Commerce shall identify each country from which the value of goods and services imported into the United States exceeds twice the value of goods and services that are products of the United States that are exported from the United States to that country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC1C5CEE4E702467F8A240D61F2310852"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Statistical sources</header><text>For purposes of the calculations described in this section, the Department of Commerce shall use the goods and services trade deficit data compiled by the United States International Trade Commission, specifically—</text><subparagraph id="idA456D9AD32D444218CAE0C80490949D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>U.S. Imports for Consumption data, in the case of imports; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id23838DE54D474942803D325E6B700BEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>U.S. Domestic Exports data, in the case of exports.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id42EA3B6DB0E84B1C83EA1561EA2C4405"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exclusion of least developed countries</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>country</term> does not include a country that is identified on the most recent List of Least Developed Countries published by the United Nations Committee for Development Policy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF2A4C1FFFE624C50834A9223E505A02C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Action by U.S. Customs and Border Protection</header><text>In the case of a country which is identified under subsection (a) for six consecutive months, U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall bar the importation of products from a country identified under subsection (a), other than those granted a waiver under subsection (c), beginning 180 days after the date on which a determination is made under subsection (a) until such time that—</text><paragraph id="id82F21D08D40F43A0A578D584F0A1514D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such country is no longer identified under subsection (a); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2352FD4332D845A9A872F6278CFC0F74"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the President has provided written notice to Congress of the President’s intention to enter into negotiations with such country to enter into a trade agreement, or changes to an existing trade agreement, with such country pursuant to section 105(a)(1)(A) of the Bipartisan Congressional Trade Priorities and Accountability Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4204">19 U.S.C. 4204(a)(1)(A)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idFB85B6C77EEC4A5D89E9C1C0680A6837"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>A manufacturer, producer, or wholesaler in the United States may apply to the Department of Commerce to allow the importation of a product from a country identified under subsection (a), which the Department of Commerce shall grant—</text><paragraph id="id736FD21362954E1E9E39A4F40B204ECF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>if it is shown that such product is not available in sufficient quantities from other sources; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB4E7619ED26A4233AF5FF2FE666CABBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for a period not to exceed one year.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

