<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8B721D1AA7B94FBDAC82A6047D2E9FCD" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 918 IH: Veteran Urgent Access to Mental Healthcare Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 918</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170207">February 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001077">Mr. Coffman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster of New Hampshire</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to furnish
			 mental health care to certain former members of the Armed Forces who are
			 not otherwise eligible to receive such care, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2C3E8892CDCF47908DD7F6CAD7A09657" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD1BAA249C7A94438B7AA37CC3CCCD893" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veteran Urgent Access to Mental Healthcare Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HEFC4283D861840878F6C4EF59720EA73" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expansion of initial and urgent mental health care for certain former members of the Armed Forces</header> <subsection id="H476BA8AFD0E043F4A9766E9011013373"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">Chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1720H">section 1720H</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8EDCFF7D7E04994BCEA6DEB6A4CCFAB" style="USC">
					<section id="H949D19E0F1AF49EA8BD3C07EA1754F94"><enum>1720I.</enum><header>Provision of initial and urgent mental health care for certain former members not otherwise
			 eligible for care</header>
 <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC708A3F3E17845EB93B0325744A272A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall furnish to former members of the Armed Forces described in subsection (b)—</text> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E6E5CAC92F34C6DA91767E44618124C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an initial mental health assessment; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB1927502D0B448119ADF389894F31BE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the mental health care services authorized under this chapter that the Secretary determines are required to treat the urgent mental health care needs of the former member, including risk of suicide or harming others.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFBE6D21C3B6940CDA9FB92B4706708B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Former members of the Armed Forces described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A former member of the Armed Forces described in this subsection is an individual who meets the following criteria:</text>
 <paragraph id="H33FC431BED1142BB9EB192FF033D85D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The individual is a former member of the Armed Forces, including the reserve components, who—</text> <subparagraph id="HF8961FC4730047E5BB8708853C264B7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>served in the active military, naval, or air service, and was discharged or released therefrom under a condition that is not honorable except—</text>
 <clause id="HFF5832A1ADBA499E816FE0852ABBB73F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>dishonorable; or</text> </clause><clause id="H48D3D8F4D2F24E0FB855F5E076E12534"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>bad conduct discharge;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H45D01195E49E46BC9D25EED9C7D6BC5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has applied for a character of service determination and such determination has not been made; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4ED848DA8BA4613BE18839CB0D1B32E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not otherwise eligible to enroll in the health care system established by section 1705 of this title by reason of such discharge or release not meeting the requirements of section 101(2) of this title.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF57E40B1E1A4A2FB87DD7D253652819"><enum>(2)</enum><text>While serving in the Armed Forces—</text> <subparagraph id="H84D257D41CF54A8D92760DBD5F63B7C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the former member was deployed in a theater of combat operations or an area at a time during which hostilities occurred in that area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H496CB86089034C279BD742093E248128"><enum>(B)</enum><text>participated in or experienced such combat operations or hostilities, including by controlling an unmanned aerial vehicle from a location other than such theater or area; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E34B1F4DE4E4D1AA8111EA32DAC19DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was the victim of a physical assault of a sexual nature, battery of a sexual nature, or sexual harassment (as defined in section 1720D(f) of this title).</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF629C06DF34A42D9B6A9642CC67B225E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Non-Department care</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H127ADEBBE3DA43E8B824AAC78ECB7EFC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In furnishing mental health care services to an individual under this section, the Secretary may provide such mental health care services at a non-Department facility if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1465AD5577B5474DB6AA6174FF112E82" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the judgment of a mental health professional employed by the Department, the receipt of mental health care services by that individual in facilities of the Department would be clinically inadvisable; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98790E7F56F34AA4A6482EA1261EDC46" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilities of the Department are not capable of furnishing such mental health care services to that individual economically because of geographical inaccessibility.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H668B9D86AAAD439B8F0E6AD3B4451929" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall carry out paragraph (1) pursuant to section 1703 of this title or any other provision of law authorizing the Secretary to enter into contracts or agreements to furnish hospital care and medical services to veterans at non-Department facilities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB4D4DDA9B68E4C668DB0EA7DC8DF0B3C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Setting and referrals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In furnishing mental health care services to an individual under this section, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HCA832F21CB7149A6BEC2B5535871DE23"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seek to ensure that such mental health care services are furnished in a setting that is therapeutically appropriate, taking into account the circumstances that resulted in the need for such mental health care services; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H61AAFC5A1B70454AA4C19E49F1CC43AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide referral services to assist former members who are not eligible for services under this chapter to obtain services from sources outside the Department.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H47AED0BBFA984208A9D5AD7DCA47668A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide information on the mental health care services available under this section. Efforts by the Secretary to provide such information—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCAD4DE57EF69402CB45A51401C83A6AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall include availability of a toll-free telephone number (commonly referred to as an 800 number);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H55D5788AF0AE4A02934469EF364CD2D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall ensure that information about the mental health care services available under this section—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H258BE4722A78437B95915BC3AFE7807D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is revised and updated as appropriate;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4926D7983A654B14868C367343A384EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is made available and visibly posted at appropriate facilities of the Department; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF298992EB009471C9D7678906E7D4975"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is made available through appropriate public information services; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7D06005DBB34E13A6733CA779A1CD86"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include coordination with the Secretary of Defense seeking to ensure that members of the Armed Forces and individuals who are being separated from active military, naval, or air service are provided appropriate information about programs, requirements, and procedures for applying for mental health care services under this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E5C09FC55A34475897FBD7111E518ED"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress an annual report on the mental health care services provided pursuant to this section. Each report shall include data for the year covered by the report with respect to each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HCBA461A42A764E5AACA7B2F12C3F594C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of individuals who received mental health care services under subsection (a), disaggregated by the number of men who received such services and the number of women who received such services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA15D380D39DD41A2B2D18E197E607387"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Such other information as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H7480DE84B1FD43DCB32224B3749736E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1720H">section 1720H</external-xref> the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2299F56895B3415CA6F71617A19C2174" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">1720I. Provision of initial and urgent mental health care not otherwise eligible for care.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HEFE4E14A96F94AD59BB9CFE854691FAB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Study on effect of combat service on suicide rates</header>
 <paragraph id="HD5FE112C8F5D480B858C4BFECDE740DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall seek to enter into a contract with an independent nongovernmental entity to carry out a study on the effect combat service has had on suicide rates and serious mental health issues among veterans. To the extent practicable, such study shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1DF7817C183E4601AD1EB28911F17E41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>compare the rate and method of suicides among veterans who have received mental health care services from the Veterans Health Administration and veterans who have not received such services from the Veterans Health Administration; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F5F3E078FED4AB3897D0BB17AF17AE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compare the rate and method of suicides and the incidence of serious mental health issues among veterans who have served in combat and veterans who have not served in combat.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H38CBD5F82BC949798121A005302F9C4E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress a report containing the study conducted under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


