<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA81AA44D4C87445CB92935EFD2B9D72A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2330 IH: Yurok Tribe Klamath River Chinook Salmon Emergency Disaster Assistance Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2330</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170503">May 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To make funds available for fisheries resource disaster assistance for the 2016 Yurok Tribe Klamath
			 River Chinook salmon fishery disaster, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H6B3A6041BC7B4283BD707D1A57E925D0" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD172D1FD583F4E2B9386C9D8C3F7E555" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Yurok Tribe Klamath River Chinook Salmon Emergency Disaster Assistance Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD5E23F56980A4988A0F86B1082319888"><enum>2.</enum><header>Fishery Resource Disaster Assistance for the 2016 Yurok Tribe Klamath River Chinook salmon fishery disaster</header> <subsection id="HD050144224E546BB93216B6A226ACA7F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appropriation of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to any other funds available for such purpose, there is appropriated to the Secretary of Commerce $22,450,000 to provide assistance to the Yurok Tribe of California in accordance with this section for assistance for the economic and social effects of the 2016 Yurok Tribe Klamath River Chinook salmon fishery disaster as determined by the Secretary of Commerce on January 18, 2017, and to mitigate the economic losses to such Tribe, businesses, individuals, or other entities caused by fishing closures or other restrictions on the harvesting of Chinook salmon.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H669CCDC68C904C00A3B6AAA475A22FF4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>Of the amount appropriated under subsection (a), the Secretary shall make available to the Yurok Tribe—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB78C1C65AE7E4C1CA178A7028260D180"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$2,000,000 for use by the Tribe under section 312(a)(2) of the Magnuson Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1861a">16 U.S.C. 1861a(a)(2)</external-xref>) for the assessment of social and economic effects of the fisheries failure, including an assessment of Tribal needs related to the loss of sufficient fishing opportunities and an assessment of impacts to Tribal children;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H544EF94AC2F2495CA8ED8252619F436D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$14,450,000 for use by the Tribe under such section to provide assistance for the support of fishermen and the local community affected by the fisheries failure, including for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF37ACDEA3DD845EB8CFBDCCC3171AA0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the loss of revenue by fishermen and the community;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD55529068FB405BA864975C57EEFCF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the loss of Tribal revenue;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16D7B35856BB4B158D1C861113CEC6F5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>supplementation of traditional food sources;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F9AE322F57F46F69A10D458F8CE32C3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>economic assistance for Tribal families;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49FAE87CA10A4DFA89509CA176D733C7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>infrastructure to process fish;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43FF3634CA3B46F6AB5741A51F3EFD09"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Tribal enterprises that lost revenue from a reduction in fishing related business;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71DBABCA891F41808112D150013D15D2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Tribal members who own businesses dependent on fishing activities; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47FDE9E80E4D408D9E8E71A0269088F5"><enum>(H)</enum><text>support of Tribal law enforcement activities; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C41C994C9F743E9826D55081C18903E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$6,000,000 for use by the Tribe under such section to provide assistance for the restoration of and monitoring activities regarding fishery habitat and to address factors that impact the health of the fishery, in order to minimize the chance of a reoccurrence of a similar fishery failure in future years.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H499CC63D6DB14D249210A231CAB80864"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts appropriated by this section shall remain available for the period with respect to which the determination referred to in subsection (a) is made.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC913E49968664452B2C1AF4138E52C63"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Unused funds</header><text>Any amount appropriated by this section that is not expended or otherwise obligated for the purpose described in subsection (a) shall be returned to the Treasury of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H51EC1E70DF0D4B2693768B4D632FC50B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Treatment of Tribe as State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the application of section 312 of the Magnuson Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1861a">16 U.S.C. 1861a</external-xref>) with respect to amounts appropriated by this section, the Yurok Tribe shall be treated as a State.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


