<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H232CF2E14B934A76B9752BEDC65BFDF1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 843</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170203">February 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000289">Mr. Goodlatte</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000580">Mr. Garrett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a safe harbor for reports to potential employers by current or former employers of violent behavior or threats thereof by employees.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4BE37E23598545B48C3ACCCC3AF81565" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE4CB7213090740CF9D5B51AC1E6A27DA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>See Something, Say Something About Violent Behavior Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE840B38E12AF4D58BCA93220ABCDCA47"><enum>2.</enum><header>Safe harbor from liability for reports of violent behavior</header> <subsection id="H2EA8BF1B3FF442FA9EC6EDB2FC3E91CF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Safe harbor for employer reports of violent behavior or threatened violent behavior</header> <paragraph id="HE264A14295BE4874B1CCC8B4DE9A4293"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any employer who, in good faith and based on objectively reasonable suspicion, makes, or causes to be made, a voluntary report about violent behavior, or threatened violent behavior, by an employee or former employee to a potential employer of that employee, or to any authorized official, shall be immune from civil liability under Federal, State, and local law for such report.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HABA68D77D9F846F2945F7D0A6425C997"><enum>(2)</enum><header>False reports</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any report if it is shown by clear and convincing evidence that the employer knew such report to be false or that such report was made with reckless disregard for the truth at the time that employer made such report.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H62621B8752B94A16B9C54E404385D407"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Safe harbor for response</header><text>Any potential employer who observes or receives a report from an employer acting pursuant to subsection (a) about violent behavior, or threatened violent behavior, of an employee or potential employee and takes reasonable action in good faith to respond to such activity shall be immune from civil liability under Federal, State, and local law for such action.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE52616DD7EEB404B9A3F74CDC3AEBD03"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Immunity for response</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any authorized official who observes or receives a report of violent behavior, or threatened violent behavior, and takes reasonable action in good faith to respond to such activity shall have qualified immunity from civil liability for such action, consistent with applicable law in the relevant jurisdiction. An authorized official who is not entitled to assert the defense of qualified immunity shall nevertheless be immune from civil liability under Federal, State, and local law if such authorized official takes reasonable action, in good faith, to respond to the reported activity.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H75E0C13D7DEA4A899164F939CA7EF4DA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall affect the ability of any employer or authorized official to assert any defense, privilege, or immunity that would otherwise be available under Federal, State, or local law or regulations, or common law, and this Act shall not be construed as affecting any such defense, privilege, or immunity.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD81DA13FB5ED48E78F3B3436BED07523"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to create any duty of any employer to disclose violent behavior, or threatened violent behavior, or to preclude an employer from disclosing any such behavior, or other behavior.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC13C17C2713743CFBB86C9EAC67BE8E2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Attorney fees and costs</header><text>Any employer or authorized official who is found to be immune from civil liability under this section shall be entitled to recover from the plaintiff all reasonable costs and attorney fees.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD3728D747E474933A78928CC5A178394"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H76070BAA90334CDF9B38F3510FA39D1F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>authorized official</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7EF745A806CC4852A2A37939C40D7D5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any officer, employee, or agent of the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Transportation, or the Department of Justice; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H69A8A6EE8B98431E9A60FE2EFBC5A4BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any Federal, State, or local law enforcement officer; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0503A54E4A3C4488A29F81AE58244DF4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>employer</term> includes any individual agent or representative of that employer; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4A76D206F144BF49B163C6B71F6D9AA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>violent behavior, or threatened violent behavior</term> means battery, assault, threats of violence, physical fighting, physical intimidation, and other violent conduct, or a threat of such conduct, that a reasonable person would consider to pose a threat of physical injury to any person.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

