<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAD86CBF0028245AEB3677EBF5676B7CE" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3157 IH: Merchant Marine Academy Improvement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3157</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170629">June 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve the handling of instances of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence,
			 sexual assault, and stalking at the United States Merchant Marine Academy,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H28A1C15238B944CAA40C06902069BC90" style="OLC">
 <section id="H60F311A271A44F03A4D3BF7E73453A64" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Merchant Marine Academy Improvement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section commented="no" id="HAA5CBFB454B9499A98B25A38579B3E85"><enum>2.</enum><header>Application of title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 to the United States Merchant Marine Academy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 901(a)(4) of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681(a)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>States, or the merchant marine;</quote> and inserting <quote>States;</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="HBB02119CD79B42B2A6B90A87F9DCB661"><enum>3.</enum><header>Actions to address sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and
			 stalking at the United States Merchant Marine Academy</header>
 <subsection id="H632548D1DDF04EFFB0C8F7DF58757AB0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Required policy</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 51318 of title 46, United States Code, as added by section 3510 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; 130 Stat. 2782), is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1A52DE1C6E7E48B389A35FECE0895849"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>harassment and sexual assault</quote> and inserting <quote>harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H16CE842B9FB74A59B57FFC9238859912"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8FE5F17F31314873BA391BE30D539528"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>harassment and sexual assault</quote> and inserting <quote>harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF65BA481F2914667901B2831EA044FF3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>domestic violence, dating violence, stalking,</quote> after <quote>acquaintance rape,</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H176E9E49A73C40FE94F265E082FC62C3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <clause id="HEEEA4302AFCC48CC9F7D121D93164034"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>harassment or sexual assault,</quote> and inserting <quote>harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking,</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB13259A8E0D04308ACC4DB7EAF48506B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>harassment or sexual assault</quote> and inserting <quote>harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H0CA38FE4465A4340AE0FB73D4BEDE55A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>criminal sexual assault</quote> and inserting <quote>a criminal sexual offense</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD349C63410D0494795BAA4240556D848"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>harassment or sexual assault</quote> and inserting <quote>harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DF8585FCA654EAEB888B3609274B949"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E)—</text>
 <clause id="H4A0DC7FC5311454EB969339881BF106D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>harassment or sexual assault</quote> and inserting <quote>harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="H467264EB5EA54FA7B808B44A4A45F477"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>sexual assault</quote> and inserting <quote>sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9B2E073CBDAC47EB844FDB190496BFD0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>harassment and sexual assault</quote> and inserting <quote>harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking</quote>; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5174A9504B814F08AB499E37B93EE784"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by striking <quote>harassment or sexual assault</quote> and inserting <quote>harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H35C4556DEEE84977A16BFC46C80431B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) and (4) as paragraphs (4) and (5), respectively;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H621974CDD9724473ADE185EA292FFFE4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0799C8CC8D14B1F8804384C70E49395" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="H2540B8D9FA8E465A975242EA69DC7E86"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minimum training requirements for certain individuals regarding sexual harassment, dating violence,
			 domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA81E16D721564836A66537DF94258DC9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The Maritime Administrator shall develop a mandatory training program at the United States Merchant Marine Academy for each individual who is involved in implementing the Academy’s student grievance procedures, including each individual who is responsible for—</text>
 <clause id="HC4F55CB0C5394ADA98328FA171EA616E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>resolving complaints of reported sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC4135D9F639A43A8823D8AA583ED4FBA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>resolving complaints of reported violations of the sexual misconduct policy of the Academy; or</text> </clause><clause id="HEA5556DA1FBB43D4A01FFED7E3CB95B7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>conducting an interview with a victim of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20F302E081334718B7E08845C13099C5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Maritime Administrator shall develop the training program described in subparagraph (A) in consultation with national, State, or local sexual assault, dating violence, domestic violence, or stalking victim advocacy, victim services, or prevention organizations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F1844AED2124159BCA9141DD0549D38"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The training required by subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</text> <clause id="HD3C8507A03F64CF7A46C0DCB6D4E9A46"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Information on working with and interviewing persons subjected to sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3E4103D5164E440FA3A7560151DBC3EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Information on particular types of conduct that would constitute sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking, regardless of gender, including same-sex sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCD3C3D3C8C3A4C35946FFC9AACDB7726"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Information on consent and the effect that drugs or alcohol may have on an individual’s ability to consent.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8309BA0C0001419B8AA7B3B1742E5B90"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Information on the effects of trauma, including the neurobiology of trauma.</text> </clause><clause id="H8496382E91334F39815078F5E9B334DA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Training regarding the use of trauma-informed interview techniques, which means asking questions of an individual who has been a victim of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking in a manner that is focused on the experience of the victim, does not judge or blame the victim, and is informed by evidence-based research on the neurobiology of trauma.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9FA34BDE3B48403E85A238454AF1EF63"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Training on cultural awareness regarding how dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking may impact midshipmen differently depending on their cultural background.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF399F40DB9D646BFAC770B4C250DDFC1"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Information on sexual assault dynamics, sexual assault perpetrator behavior, and barriers to reporting.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF09DA9956F9B4E29A01C214997457D37"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>The training program described in subparagraph (A) shall be approved by the Director of the Departmental Office of Civil Rights of the Department of Transportation.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE82F00FB211B4C0185CBE65A9D1BD6AC"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Implementation</header>
 <clause id="HB6DDEC4DA56B4C44844D58D3FD02086A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Development and approval schedule</header><text>The training program required by subparagraph (A) shall be developed and approved as required by subparagraph (D) not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Merchant Marine Academy Improvement Act of 2017</short-title>.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF35CEC0121D24AE18079793B555A8E25"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Completion of training</header><text>Each individual who is required to complete the training described in subparagraph (A) shall complete such training not later than—</text>
 <subclause id="HC94996F654D64D2BA0AB6AB8983E766E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>270 days after enactment of the <short-title>Merchant Marine Academy Improvement Act of 2017</short-title>; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H264742802AE140D5A301448AD271C540"><enum>(II)</enum><text>180 days after starting a position with responsibilities that include the activities described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of subparagraph (A).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86DC52D8F58B48DFB6023C7A2CCEC552"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (5), as so redesignated, the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H063F1B7B1A3D40C5BB6C6A02B948C27D" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H613D1EAB1BF94067A685165687872DF2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Consistency with the Higher Education Act of 1965</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the policy developed under this subsection meets the requirements set out in paragraph (8) of section 485(f) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092">20 U.S.C. 1092(f)(8)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H12A2EC94D39D4009A20F5D2E0723AF32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum procedures for handling reports of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence,
 sexual assault, or stalking</header><text>Subsection (b) of section 51318 of title 46, United States Code, as added by section 3510 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; 130 Stat. 2782), is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H274FB7920E8F406B8B10FE4C689748A7" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H448FECB89C634022A95FEC9DD907C21D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development program</header>
 <paragraph id="H8F96C8BC1AFD49F4813AF9A8B7E7A58E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the development program of the Academy includes a section that—</text> <subparagraph id="H43646445BF594D4D85B30C2753F8D9B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describes the relationship between honor, respect, and character development and the prevention of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking at the Academy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FB485FB84224DF7AD1C302A8DF68241"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a brief history of the problem of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking in the merchant marine, in the Armed Forces, and at the Academy; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H205585A7E0084E29BE4351B61EBCED4A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes information relating to reporting sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking, victims’ rights, and dismissal for offenders.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H54EC198DD5844C4BB0A2857EF1E8584D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum requirements to combat retaliation</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9B67C8FD4E6B4D8B87A188F3FE3B0064"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement for plan</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Merchant Marine Academy Improvement Act of 2017</short-title>, the Maritime Administrator shall create and implement a plan to combat retaliation against midshipmen at the United States Merchant Marine Academy who report sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BD35BF9E35F41E987F64CA373E6DB7C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Violation of code of conduct</header><text>The Maritime Administrator shall consider an act of retaliation against a midshipman at the Academy who reports sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking as a Class I violation of the Academy’s Midshipman Regulations and Sea Year Regulations and Instructions or equivalent code of conduct.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26192D73C947443CB723E0C22FF950FD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Retaliation definition</header><text>The Maritime Administrator shall work with the sexual assault prevention and response staff of the Academy to define <quote>retaliation</quote> for purposes of this subsection.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3E7A828B9B640A49FC77CC9C25EF076"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minimum resource requirements</header>
 <subparagraph id="HDB143F2DE7E34526A96E5301B62F26E2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation shall provide the staff at the United States Merchant Marine Academy with adequate and appropriate sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking prevention and response training materials and resources. Such resources shall include staff as follows:</text>
 <clause id="H2C4AE3F884794E789B2A33A9516DB7F4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Sexual assault response coordinator.</text> </clause><clause id="HC0E4DA1467E6494F9138D972BB99746D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Prevention educator.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEE254B52B7E044B8B80899D9F8BF6A87"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Administrative staff member.</text> </clause><clause id="HDF27448B7DCA4343BA6D850725E44B99"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Strategic Sealift Officer.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC1D767C897A4257AD17DD1B31307315"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Communication</header><text>The Director of the Office of Civil Rights of the Department of Transportation shall create and maintain a direct line of communication to the sexual assault response staff of the Academy that is outside of the chain of command of the Academy.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F9D27F100894BFB9A9B9D368C198E71"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Minimum training requirements</header><text>The Superintendent shall ensure that all cadets receive training on the sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking prevention and response sections of the development program of the Academy, as described in paragraph (1), as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE4F20C5B4CAA40D9AD6201A1B6FF89B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An initial training session, which shall occur not later than 7 days after a cadet’s initial arrival at the Academy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A0FBE9AD6AB45DAB56AACBD6A634976"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Additional training sessions, which shall occur biannually following the cadet’s initial training session until the cadet graduates or leaves the Academy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3D5538ADFF5649C1AA7725437FD82252"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Aggregate reporting</header><text>Section 51318 of title 46, United States Code, as added by section 3510 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; 130 Stat. 2782), is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1EF2A44F08841DB837841D085E26979" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H05D3DB9CF159400C971589B973B0728A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Data for aggregate reporting</header>
 <paragraph id="HE84F829E8D9245409B5FF90A690A8C09"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No requirement related to confidentiality in this section or section 51319 may be construed to prevent a sexual assault response coordinator from providing information for any report required by law regrading sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H21D7FA3ED0DF4B208E861E4AED4A6A13"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Identity protection</header><text>Any information provided for a report referred to in paragraph (1) shall be provided in a manner that protects the identity of the victim or witness.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2B4F76E106F44FC9A290DA7E0B03FD35"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 51318 of title 46, United States Code, as added by section 3510 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; 130 Stat. 2782), as amended by subsection (c), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D98BBC975C64263A8EE33B2850745D4" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H092F97EA695E49B78E3042205461CB10"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section and section 51319:</text> <paragraph id="H8129F77C37B74E77BE97D6471CAA4816"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Dating violence; domestic violence; stalking</header><text>The terms <term>dating violence</term>, <term>domestic violence</term>, and <term>stalking</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 40002(a) of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/13925">42 U.S.C. 13925(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H437C8E7B10FF42E394CB89CFEF62CBAE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sexual assault</header><text>The term <term>sexual assault</term> means an offense classified as a forcible or nonforcible sex offense under the uniform crime reporting system of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H530A2EAFE23A4DC9966B41A3A204F223"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H1E350E49130A4A21BAEC9BDE95B3871D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Heading</header><text>Section 51318 of title 46, United States Code, as added by section 3510 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; 130 Stat. 2782), is amended by striking the section heading and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0248520148514A4892CF603FD2C0C960" style="USC">
						<section id="HAB5C5947F1BA4703A822261F048AF70E"><enum>51318.</enum><header>Policy on sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking</header></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE853A8D48234985957B49972209CA08"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Table of sections amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/513">chapter 513</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, as amended by subtitle A of title XXXV of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; 130 Stat. 2774), is amended by striking the item relating to section 51318 and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H67357E1C13594A04B9666B1542A041E3" style="USC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry idref="HAB5C5947F1BA4703A822261F048AF70E" level="section">Sec. 51318. Policy on sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and
			 stalking.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC360C8E38CCE4C8199FECF9BF6206180"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sexual assault response coordinators and sexual assault victim advocate</header>
 <subsection id="H0FB16C0DAC7747D0B8AF43318937A0D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 51319 of title 46, United States Code, as added by section 3511 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; 130 Stat. 2785), is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5FCC96707E2441A094C92D1048362D07"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (b) as subsection (g); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBA3A91743A214F3687354813BC81196D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57E5769353FB4B7D8950AB32E5DF0712" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="H14E26AD6453242BAAFE5F290DAFBF852"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sexual assault response coordinators</header>
 <paragraph id="HEE1385204CB94E2F9B17886B032D748B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement for coordinators</header><text>The United States Merchant Marine Academy shall employ or contract with at least 1 full-time sexual assault response coordinator who shall reside at or near the Academy. The Secretary of Transportation may assign additional full-time or part-time sexual assault response coordinators at the Academy as necessary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE430CF39383F4B83A603D42DD5C8170C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>Each sexual assault response coordinator shall be selected based on—</text> <subparagraph id="H7C4600FCDCBA4E938060E60DB7A4E692"><enum>(A)</enum><text>experience and a demonstrated ability to effectively provide victim services related to sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E20327BD8A8448BB8A1E5702ADE9E2B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protection of the individual under State law to provide privileged communication.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7916B58C9896434CB9EDA4FD8BC91903"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text>A sexual assault response coordinator shall, to the extent authorized under State law, provide confidential services to a midshipman who reports being a victim of, or witness to, sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H7B4B30FFAA994C089D882A54A50C300F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Training</header>
 <subparagraph id="HBF4118F34DF8485596D8B48537B84CF6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Merchant Marine Academy Improvement Act of 2017</short-title>, the Maritime Administrator shall develop a specialized training program for each sexual assault response coordinator and receive approval for such program from the Director of the Departmental Office of Civil Rights of the Department of Transportation within 90 days of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73D6EF7EDA5747BABFF4CBDDE923F9BC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Training program requirements</header><text>The specialized training program required by subparagraph (A) shall include training in—</text> <clause id="H23A136B10D8347B88C25FADD28C79794"><enum>(i)</enum><text>working with victims of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD93E5C40E2AC4EB182EDA7C0958F9DAE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the policies, procedures, and resources of the Academy related to responding to sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1FBB3303235A487C89EABC5268EA9BC4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>national, State, and local victim services and resources available to victims of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF12C5FA3030D4EE8BA3D6E2968D1CE34"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>The specialized training program developed under subparagraph (A) shall be approved by the Director of the Departmental Office of Civil Rights of the Department of Transportation.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24ABB0CBB97642E99D269FE70EA9BC8D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Implementation</header>
 <clause id="H8B3BD4E59FBC4B11A7B4648739B1E804"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Development and approval schedule</header><text>The specialized training program required by subparagraph (A) shall be developed and approved as required by subparagraph (C) not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Merchant Marine Academy Improvement Act of 2017</short-title>.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1655CCF74FC04E6084B6FD7F1DE9E7AA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Completion of training</header><text>A sexual assault response coordinator shall complete the specialized training program required by subparagraph (A) not later than—</text>
 <subclause id="H67219D9BD11E43EBA26D452906BE70CF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>270 days after enactment of the <short-title>Merchant Marine Academy Improvement Act of 2017</short-title>; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="H3D6A2648CCFE4BE69D4C3A55685CBBB2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>180 days after starting in the role of sexual assault response coordinator.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0D24E3EBFED4FC0BFEDF87F4E7A90A5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>A sexual assault response coordinator shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H82813BC95F9245CC92853703DAE898AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>confidentially receive reports from victims of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H528745FDB58D4A66B0FBC6080557F197"><enum>(B)</enum><text>inform such victims of—</text> <clause id="HB91283E67EDB44D1AB65216DD86FD954"><enum>(i)</enum><text>their rights under Federal and State law;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H46347F4832C641B6ABE6F4C526645BBD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>options for reporting an incident of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking to the Academy and law enforcement;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA638DD62D9CA4624BDBC61C023971B13"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>how to access available services, including emergency medical care, medical forensic or evidentiary examinations, legal services, services provided by rape crisis centers and other victim service providers, services provided by the volunteer sexual assault victim advocates at the Academy, and crisis intervention counseling and ongoing counseling;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H211DC050EE794DCFB16DE043582B633D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>such coordinator’s ability to assist in arranging access to such services, with the consent of the victim;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6DD235FEE54F47E399EF0FA6B4DAECAC"><enum>(v)</enum><text>available accommodations, such as allowing a victim to change living arrangements and obtain accessibility services;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5863CD55BEED44349D06304587160B39"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>such coordinator’s ability to assist in arranging such accommodations, with the consent of the victim;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC8312FF28BF14F4B88ADC9E9754C59F1"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the victim’s rights and the Academy’s responsibilities regarding orders of protection, no contact orders, restraining orders, or similar lawful orders issued by the Academy or a criminal, civil, or tribal court; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7F889E42DF694ED4B8B3C0327795704B"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>privacy limitations based on Federal and State law;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B67E299DB2F4F0FA0A183D3F4A11F66"><enum>(C)</enum><text>represent the interests of any midshipmen who reports being a victim of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking, even if such interests are in conflict with the interests of the Academy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29A19830493D4B4D88D77B051D5FD7DD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>advise such victims of, and provide written materials regarding, the information described in subparagraph (B);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FA2BD84700D4B2CB92565933EE338B3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>liaise with appropriate staff at the Academy, with the victim’s consent, to arrange reasonable accommodations through the Academy to allow a victim to change living arrangements, obtain accessibility services, or access other accommodations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADA0208E5AB54747B388964787372AA2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>maintain the privacy and confidentiality of the victim, and shall not notify the Academy or any other authority of the identity of the victim or the alleged circumstances surrounding the reported incident unless—</text>
 <clause id="HDDBE27A95A004D3E8C6639D5FA5BFCD7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>otherwise required by the applicable State law; or</text> </clause><clause id="H7B69F19529534E77B1DEA18ECE9D00E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>requested to do so by the victim who has been fully and accurately informed about what procedures shall occur if the information is shared;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0866F2E1035C483DBD6FE685627761B3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>assist the victim in contacting and reporting an incident of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking to the Academy or law enforcement, if requested to do so by the victim who has been fully and accurately informed about what procedures shall occur if information is shared; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H274B3FC1071948BFB47946D69BE1D870"><enum>(H)</enum><text>submit to the Director of the Office of Civil Rights of the Department of Transportation an annual report summarizing how the resources supplied to the coordinator were used during the prior year, including the number of victims assisted by the coordinator.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H11BAB88A46654457B511CD9B5ECBB9B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Oversight</header>
							<paragraph id="H48C0381F6691442A8ABF89BAD502DEEE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <subparagraph id="H606BEABCE0714F37AD9AF56B11DA7F52"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Each sexual assault response coordinator shall—</text> <clause id="HC1A33BE60D2D43CCB6347A3B0C2F0B9A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>report directly to the Superintendent; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA04C790405F34DEB90D4BDBB88094DB6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have concurrent reporting responsibility to the Executive Director of the Maritime Administration on matters related to the Maritime Administration and the Department of Transportation and upon belief that the Academy leadership is acting inappropriately regarding sexual assault prevention and response matters.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD43A9329B734D748B946BD0B172ACC7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Support</header><text>The Maritime Administration Office of Civil Rights shall provide support to the sexual assault response staff at the Academy on all sexual assault and sexual harassment prevention matters.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF5DE8E2ABEB4A889A570FC8AF4C09C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on investigation by the Academy</header><text>Any request by a victim for an accommodation, as described in subsection (a)(5)(F), made by a sexual assault response coordinator shall not trigger an investigation by the Academy, even if such coordinator deals only with matters relating to sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD11632528CFE41138AE2FB1C4A2BD81F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition on retaliation</header><text>A sexual assault response coordinator, victim advocate, or companion may not be disciplined, penalized, or otherwise retaliated against by the Academy for representing the interests of the victim, even if such interests are in conflict with the interests of the Academy.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA72434925A44D6A892D8ADAE009931B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Support for reporting</header><text>The Maritime Administrator shall contract with a third party to make support services available 24 hours a day to midshipmen at the United States Merchant Marine Academy who are victims of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking. Such support shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE6C4B169078140338209BF01CB63723C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be greater than or equal to the support services offered by the Department of Defense SAFE Helpline; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H710584433311404DA4897C3D8A32F495"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be provided by individuals who are trained regarding the resources that are available to midshipmen that might not be available to the general public.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H11558558FF624279A4F2196ECE9138BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal of duplicate requirement</header><text>Subsection (g) of section 51319 of title 46, United States Code, as redesignated by subsection (a)(1), is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2951095DC6D74F8C9130D489AF3C5A24"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (5);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFCFF4668BDE341BD9FEBF97F0F264ADD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (6) as paragraph (5); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F4BAD37F7294783B9657DCB43AF316F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>(3), (4), and (5)</quote> and inserting <quote>(3) and (4)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB7A3CD2266854CD48E88102A71717DDE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Protection of students from sexual assault onboard vessels</header> <subsection id="HEE58F2CE6B944067B05664B61BB8113C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/513">Chapter 513</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, as amended by subtitle A of title XXXV of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>), is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA965A039B0D241728AA3680B237433B1" style="USC">
					<section id="H29AACE487B97469FBA53072326665654"><enum>51320.</enum><header>Protection of students from sexual assault onboard vessels</header>
						<subsection id="HA0220E65087E4E0D93F36B1161B3C27C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Provision of individual satellite communication devices during sea year</header>
 <paragraph id="H8A1617510E2C468188F0B299F76D91D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Maritime Administrator shall ensure that each midshipman at the United States Merchant Marine Academy is provided a functional satellite communication device during the midshipman’s Sea Year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8389A679F7114210B47BC84D0D64A331"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Check-in</header><text>Not less often than once each week, each such midshipman shall check-in with designated personnel at the Academy via the midshipman’s personal satellite communication device.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF364CA10577476BA29B6FC366730C15"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Maritime Administrator such funds as may be necessary to carry out paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H199AF04CAEDE4F56B8D06FD18F00DBA7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Riding gangs</header><text>The Maritime Administrator shall—</text> <paragraph id="H74228840CC9B4B69803BD2AE4FDC6502"><enum>(1)</enum><text>require the owner or operator of any commercial vessel carrying a midshipman of the Academy to certify their compliance with the International Convention for Safety of Life at Sea, 1974, with annex, done at London November 1, 1974 (32 UST 47), and section 8106; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HACB882CEEDE04A0896590A2FC2F1E34D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure the Academy informs midshipmen preparing for Sea Year of the obligations that vessel owners and operators have to provide for the security of individuals aboard a vessel under United States law, including chapter 81 and section 70103(c).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF815F4516B1C41F3BDD8F53CD4C60791"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Checks of commercial vessels</header>
 <paragraph id="H0518BD928A6544F7BD8D9882EE4982E0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Not less frequently than once every two years, the sexual assault prevention and response staff of the United States Merchant Marine Academy or the Maritime Administration shall conduct both random and targeted unannounced checks of not less than 10 percent of the commercial vessels that host a midshipman from the Academy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H15FBD1C2F8064774AC49B21B200B9580"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Removal of students</header><text>If such staff determine that such a commercial vessel is in violation of the sexual assault policy developed by the Academy through such a check, such staff are authorized to remove any midshipman of the Academy from the vessel and report any such violation to the company that owns the vessel.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA4E6FE4DCE6248B884006C9C54E20C01"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Maintenance of sexual assault training records</header><text>The Maritime Administrator shall require each company or seafarer union for a commercial vessel to maintain records of sexual assault training for the crew and passengers of any vessel hosting a midshipman from the Academy.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="HAB7CD769C5CB492D9DB4BE9831147C91"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sea Year survey</header>
 <paragraph id="H46C90733643E48719E8F6568BB01802E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The Maritime Administrator shall require each midshipman from the Academy upon completion of the midshipman's Sea Year to complete a survey regarding the environment and conditions on each commercial vessel that hosted the midshipman during the Sea Year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD0B66F4B677441199F9F7BF592E4E6DA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The Maritime Administrator shall make available to the public for each year—</text> <subparagraph id="H07225A26299F45FBABF8D527979FA144"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the questions used in the survey required by paragraph (1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2F768A3C0FB4A478273D3302963D234"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the aggregated data received from such surveys.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HD02E8BE3E6534C4695CB33A617FAAA46"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of sections amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/513">chapter 513</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, as amended by subtitle A of title XXXV of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>), is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HAF3671FCE7D24617BD3AC72FA6114611" style="USC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry idref="H29AACE487B97469FBA53072326665654" level="section">Sec. 51320. Protection of students from sexual assault onboard vessels.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="HEC66E71FA4DF43D1BB3F85483AF653C8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Training requirement for sexual assault investigators</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation shall require each employee of the Office of Inspector General of the Department of Transportation who conducts investigations and who is assigned to the Regional Investigations Office in New York, New York—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0E3991D7AB0F48009C9D4CD3A2646426"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to participate in specialized training in conducting sexual assault investigations; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE6FC057AC0D04A3DBC868120E9FE973D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to attend at least one Federal Law Enforcement Training Center (FLETC) sexual assault investigation course each year.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


