<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE790B0A679264CC8883A17F96A9E237A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4476 IH: PURPA Modernization Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4476</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171129">November 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001294">Mr. Blum</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To modernize the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF0D6F344057240C0B4A647D6CE00896D" style="OLC">
 <section commented="no" id="HBE9D9B12C6C142A196496E7A845E9C4F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>PURPA Modernization Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H15DC5A12B45D4D6DAEFCFA8FB41B0582"><enum>2.</enum><header>Location of small power production facilities</header> <subsection id="H3F4B5C72F48D4882952978FAED96E71F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rebuttable presumption</header><text>The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission shall, not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, publish in the Federal Register a final rule amending its regulations implementing section 3(17)(A)(ii) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/796">16 U.S.C. 796(17)(A)(ii)</external-xref>), regarding the method for determining whether facilities are considered to be located at the same site as the facility for which qualification is sought for the purpose of calculating power production capacity, to provide a rebuttable presumption that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9857EE12061542E6919F480C131FA5EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>facilities located one mile or more away from each other are not located at the same site; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4CA57635235485C94AA55B0271D0095"><enum>(2)</enum><text>facilities located within one mile of each other are located at the same site.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C5D16034CF64F6F8E72E2F755BCBAF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Overcoming the presumption</header>
 <paragraph id="HB8AC9CBE6EB84075857B603CB49E5F4F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Persons who may rebut the presumption</header><text>The Commission shall allow any person (as defined in section 385.102 of title 18, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act) to rebut the presumption described in subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE15DFB80B92242E4ADCFDAA38DE0760B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Factors to be considered</header><text>In determining whether a facility is considered to be located at the same site as the facility for which qualification is sought, the Commission shall take into account, to the extent practicable, the following factors:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H844196CB2D524A56B42184BFB8CE06EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which the owners or operators of the facilities are affiliated or associated with each other, or are under the control of the same company or person.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44A5B244088243018EAC466409001891"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which the owners or operators of the facilities have treated the facilities as a single project for purposes of other regulatory filings or applications.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H709A71E279CB4F088550FFF63A159F11"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Whether the facilities use the same energy resource.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1A08226FD0543049CBA3CC35095AE34"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Whether the facilities have a common generator lead line or connect at the same or nearby interconnection points or substations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9A69C00854D4E87AFB4285A0820346B"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which the owners or operators of the facilities have a common land lease or land rights with respect to land on which the facilities are located.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD752FF48F534423EAA85B3550BC5CCFD"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which the owners or operators of the facilities have common financing with respect to the facilities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H950B6A874BDB4AE9A39F6A8E05E0F34B"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which the facilities are part of a common development plan or permitting effort, even if the interconnection of the facilities occurs at separate points.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H56B5C8F3EC9D4B0F86C705FA9DD57EF6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Affiliation and association</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall consider the owners or operators of facilities to be affiliated or associated for purposes of this section if they are affiliates or associate companies within the meaning of those terms as defined in section 1262 of the Public Utility Holding Company Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16451">42 U.S.C. 16451</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H19A8722549034315BA73D03FB9053462"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Control</header><text>The Commission shall consider the owner or operator of a facility to be under the control of a company or person for purposes of this section if—</text>
 <paragraph id="H81BA464B5B1D4294A21E0B58CC9C64B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the company or person directly or indirectly owns, controls, or holds, with power to vote, 10 percent or more of the outstanding voting securities of the owner or operator; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H661DE61DDF1540B8B14FEEAA224F1FBA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Commission determines, after notice and opportunity for hearing, that the company or person exercises, directly or indirectly (either alone or pursuant to an arrangement or understanding with one or more companies or persons), a controlling influence over the management of the owner or operator.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDF7AC4FFAA4C40C2A16546B6D036CBD1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Nondiscriminatory access</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 210(m) of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824a-3">16 U.S.C. 824a–3(m)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H610382A683E247059514A13A3F0B5064" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H0E5ABBFDDF454549957D67FDBB397E99"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Nondiscriminatory access</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, a qualifying small power production facility with an installed generation capacity of 2.5 megawatts or greater is presumed to have nondiscriminatory access to transmission and interconnection services and wholesale markets described in subparagraphs (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H561C2FAADF4D4D928F337E39349F23E2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Recognition of State or local determinations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 210(m) of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824a-3">16 U.S.C. 824a–3(m)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H6439A79B13824D94A392B4FF584DB7C5" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H3AFF0F5AFDA34D9A8E609320466C8E68"><enum>(9)</enum><header>State or local determination</header><text>After the date of enactment of this paragraph, no electric utility shall be required to enter into a new contract or obligation to purchase electric energy from a qualifying small power production facility under this section if the appropriate State regulatory agency or non-regulated electric utility finds, and submits to the Commission a written determination, that—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC2B027A6F50C4468A943135FC4581BF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the electric utility has no need to purchase electric energy from such qualifying small power production facility in the amounts to be offered within the timeframe proposed by the qualifying small power production facility, consistent with the needs for electric energy and the timeframe for those needs as specified in an electric utility’s integrated resource plan, in order to meet its obligation to serve customers; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE025641FA19E4C4C9850C32DBF12918C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the electric utility employs integrated resource planning and conducts a competitive resource procurement process for long-term energy resources that provides an opportunity for qualifying small power production facilities to supply electric energy to the electric utility in accordance with the integrated resource plan of the electric utility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


