<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3A36545793ED4947AE7B597CE4903F64" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 998 : Searching for and Cutting Regulations that are Unnecessarily Burdensome Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 998</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20170302">March 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To provide for the establishment of a process for the review of rules and sets of rules, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HBDE9ED4B060542B3821B83FA130855FC" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB4F9EDE710774FA7838E346F89970861" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Searching for and Cutting Regulations that are Unnecessarily Burdensome Act</short-title></quote> or as the <quote><short-title>SCRUB Act</short-title></quote> .</text> </section><section id="H914C409AE22046FAB592E18CAEC4CCE3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header> <toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> <toc-entry idref="HB4F9EDE710774FA7838E346F89970861" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H914C409AE22046FAB592E18CAEC4CCE3" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H85E8EBABC28945E5B0985A248AC05024" level="title">Title I—Retrospective Regulatory Review Commission</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H23B1505EEA7C4599AE47EDC9334E26AC" level="section">Sec. 101. In general.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HD80E87C30696429D895804B97BE82145" level="title">Title II—Regulatory Cut-Go</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HA7480D14C01A41CCB01461BDFC3484E0" level="section">Sec. 201. Cut-go procedures.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HEE8C4C32F7874860A873D9F5E9846FB7" level="section">Sec. 202. Applicability.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HD1122B7F0AA044A9B175EE2631BD85D9" level="section">Sec. 203. OIRA certification of cost calculations.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HA6AC580B54804DB9B6D0F4687FDCA616" level="title">Title III—Retrospective Review of New Rules</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H476F6CBE405B48F69EED3CAE61E9A4D8" level="section">Sec. 301. Plan for future review.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H886863C142F54B7B88FC117C886D11C5" level="title">Title IV—Judicial Review</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HB788F39A348148CCBA4AD61339704FFD" level="section">Sec. 401. Judicial review.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H7E89AD48C7A748B4A8DA5F99317E1846" level="title">Title V—Miscellaneous Provisions</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HD866F0F10BBB4EE4A48E05AD9787BE6B" level="section">Sec. 501. Definitions.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H4DD22A8A978C48C294446A5B25169E9E" level="section">Sec. 502. Effective date.</toc-entry></toc> </section><title id="H85E8EBABC28945E5B0985A248AC05024"><enum>I</enum><header>Retrospective Regulatory Review Commission</header> <section id="H23B1505EEA7C4599AE47EDC9334E26AC"><enum>101.</enum><header>In general</header> <subsection id="HB0084E3132C947E3B9168C73D9250EF3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established a commission, to be known as the <quote>Retrospective Regulatory Review Commission</quote>, that shall review rules and sets of rules in accordance with specified criteria to determine if a rule or set of rules should be repealed to eliminate or reduce the costs of regulation to the economy. The Commission shall terminate on the date that is 5 years and 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act or 5 years after the date by which all Commission members’ terms have commenced, whichever is later.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="HA2ABEA775054461EAB2FC999E344F8A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H44B0DDE49E9641DC9F869568DBE63D0F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Number</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall be composed of 9 members who shall be appointed by the President and confirmed by the Senate. Each member shall be appointed not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB5A31F3D26244EB863C6898E0AF8691"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term of each member shall commence upon the member’s confirmation by the Senate and shall extend to the date that is 5 years and 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act or that is 5 years after the date by which all members have been confirmed by the Senate, whichever is later.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6751BB9868E34199809B924BD5FDA806"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The members of the Commission shall be appointed as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="H1F6E58BE0860457A85411AF430BC0BE6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Chair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall appoint as the Chair of the Commission an individual with expertise and experience in rulemaking, such as past Administrators of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, past chairmen of the Administrative Conference of the United States, and other individuals with similar expertise and experience in rulemaking affairs and the administration of regulatory reviews.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2342E1BDAAC84C4FA3149719220D527C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Candidate list of members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, the Majority Leader of the Senate, and the Minority Leader of the Senate shall each present to the President a list of candidates to be members of the Commission. Such candidates shall be individuals learned in rulemaking affairs and, preferably, administration of regulatory reviews. During the two-year period prior to the inclusion of an individual on a list of candidates under this subparagraph, the individual may not have been a registered lobbyist under the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1601">2 U.S.C. 1601</external-xref> et seq.). The President shall appoint 2 members of the Commission from each list provided under this subparagraph, subject to the provisions of subparagraph (C).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H407922DFAD914C5E94E7722C7446895A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Resubmission of candidate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may request from the presenter of the list under subparagraph (B) a new list of one or more candidates if the President—</text>
 <clause id="H7110DC2030F4420ABDB7589D552737AF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determines that any candidate on the list presented pursuant to subparagraph (B) does not meet the qualifications specified in such subparagraph to be a member of the Commission; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H50240676533B43C7B1B0EC3A91B6ABEA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certifies that determination to the congressional officials specified in subparagraph (B).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE458DFC3DFF644CDB0AFDD51277A98CC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Financial disclosure reports of members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member of the Commission shall file the financial disclosure reports required under title I of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.) in accordance with the requirements of such title.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF59953AB43F4A6192C361E5E1029760"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Powers and authorities of the Commission</header>
 <paragraph id="HB7AB975711574A2DB9B4F20DE0A06C58"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Commission may meet when, where, and as often as the Commission determines appropriate, except that the Commission shall hold public meetings not less than twice each year. All meetings of the Commission shall be open to the public.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H904A3E1651794A3FBEB7E85861DBC71C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to meetings held under paragraph (1), the Commission may hold hearings to consider issues of fact or law relevant to the Commission’s work. Any hearing held by the Commission shall be open to the public.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA2FE17B9F60435EB3EF482D80107888"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Access to Information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may secure directly from any agency information and documents necessary to enable the Commission to carry out this Act. Upon request of the Chair of the Commission, the head of that agency shall furnish that information or document to the Commission as soon as possible, but not later than two weeks after the date on which the request was made.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HDC2AE7F933D14FF89AF93D4E4B51906C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Subpoenas</header>
 <subparagraph id="H370A8C654763420F93BA835F6D2A1265"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission may issue subpoenas requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of any evidence relating to the duties of the Commission. The attendance of witnesses and the production of evidence may be required from any place within the United States at any designated place of hearing within the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C814055217A471B974BEA6D24C21A26"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure to obey a Subpoena</header><text>If a person refuses to obey a subpoena issued under subparagraph (A), the Commission may apply to a United States district court for an order requiring that person to appear before the Commission to give testimony, produce evidence, or both, relating to the matter under investigation. The application may be made within the judicial district where the hearing is conducted or where that person is found, resides, or transacts business. Any failure to obey the order of the court may be punished by the court as civil contempt.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74AFCEE5D0554C938FA87C44E8F2F625"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Service of subpoenas</header><text>The subpoenas of the Commission shall be served in the manner provided for subpoenas issued by a United States district court under the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure for the United States district courts.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87C1E4F8DD764187ABC47A17C3F03DD7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Service of process</header><text>All process of any court to which application is made under subparagraph (B) may be served in the judicial district in which the person required to be served resides or may be found.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE85CCC867BCF498CA8D757166233180F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Pay and Travel Expenses</header>
					<paragraph id="H3800BA3B82AB4A40982846C34B993D52"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pay</header>
 <subparagraph id="H420FAAE48EA14B51A9D4671DB1AF1B1B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member, other than the Chair of the Commission, shall be paid at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the minimum annual rate of basic pay payable for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code, for each day (including travel time) during which the member is engaged in the actual performance of duties vested in the Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0137BDBEF0E24E15824183DA305C9794"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Chair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chair shall be paid for each day referred to in subparagraph (A) at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the minimum annual rate of basic pay payable for level III of the Executive Schedule under section 5314 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3ABE8B1C981A43AB96D516D61DB7A680"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>Members shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with sections 5702 and 5703 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB6A5C15309984A61A5B90758B0A52581"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Director of Staff</header>
 <paragraph id="H2EB12ACBC16741DFAD3D073BC743C84C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall appoint a Director.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H033A564E9CAD406684F585EF6618BBA5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pay</header><text>The Director shall be paid at the rate of basic pay payable for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7FFBB09CD6104820AB714C7669B195F5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Staff</header>
 <paragraph id="HBE40C056B89F4C9DA77124737CDE47DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), the Director, with the approval of the Commission, may appoint, fix the pay of, and terminate additional personnel.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC286946C896490CACE35A4DF298080C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations on appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director may make such appointments without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, and any personnel so appointed may be paid without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of that title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates, except that an individual so appointed may not receive pay in excess of the annual rate of basic pay payable for GS–15 of the General Schedule.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFAA9C21F3F2C4C4DAABCD29EA6F0170D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Agency assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following consultation with and upon request of the Chair of the Commission, the head of any agency may detail any of the personnel of that agency to the Commission to assist the Commission in carrying out the duties of the Commission under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDBB54D8EBB9D4701BF65B849EC0D3604"><enum>(4)</enum><header>GAO and OIRA assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States and the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs shall provide assistance, including the detailing of employees, to the Commission in accordance with an agreement entered into with the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD129D8D2324D4B85984366BCA83D0489"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Assistance from other parties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress, the States, municipalities, federally recognized Indian tribes, and local governments may provide assistance, including the detailing of employees, to the Commission in accordance with an agreement entered into with the Commission.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2F833AE2C4F4404A86D244393201F118"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Other Authority</header>
 <paragraph id="H520BD5D3CBE94163A70C5F3D95AAC097"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Experts and consultants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may procure by contract, to the extent funds are available, the temporary or intermittent services of experts or consultants pursuant to section 3109 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB13D6C708F4245E98D969FCF8789CAFA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may lease space and acquire personal property to the extent funds are available.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H60E9C016C61F4755B81B34CF87840853"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Duties of the Commission</header> <paragraph id="H4ABE7816EA974D979B4C383C42F760DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall conduct a review of the Code of Federal Regulations to identify rules and sets of rules that collectively implement a regulatory program that should be repealed to lower the cost of regulation to the economy. The Commission shall give priority in the review to rules or sets of rules that are major rules or include major rules, have been in effect more than 15 years, impose paperwork burdens or unfunded mandates that could be reduced substantially without significantly diminishing regulatory effectiveness, impose disproportionately high costs on entities that qualify as small entities within the meaning of section 601(6) of title 5, United States Code, or could be strengthened in their effectiveness while reducing regulatory costs. The Commission shall have as a goal of the Commission to achieve a reduction of at least 15 percent in the cumulative costs of Federal regulation with a minimal reduction in the overall effectiveness of such regulation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3610C64A85248EEB8E0538830C629E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nature of review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To identify which rules and sets of rules should be repealed to lower the cost of regulation to the economy, the Commission shall apply the following criteria:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H228428DE53864A3EA4A9B6D108FFD74C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the original purpose of the rule or set of rules was achieved, and the rule or set of rules could be repealed without significant recurrence of adverse effects or conduct that the rule or set of rules was intended to prevent or reduce.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB756EDC4517641B0B8A0C7D140718A67"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the implementation, compliance, administration, enforcement, imposition of unfunded mandates, or other costs of the rule or set of rules to the economy are not justified by the benefits to society within the United States produced by the expenditure of those costs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2053CC3863E54B0883DD241BA5550D6D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the rule or set of rules has been rendered unnecessary or obsolete, taking into consideration the length of time since the rule was made and the degree to which technology, economic conditions, market practices, or other relevant factors have changed in the subject area affected by the rule or set of rules.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54293451527E4170900D4C933DA784BE"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the rule or set of rules is ineffective at achieving the purposes of the rule or set of rules.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB5A6448E4F9426E8680F159CDFCDA1A"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the rule or set of rules overlaps, duplicates, or conflicts with other Federal rules, and to the extent feasible, with State and local governmental rules.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD28663AD7C4F4EC5B39295BB866614C9"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the rule or set of rules has excessive compliance costs, imposes unfunded mandates, or is otherwise excessively burdensome, as compared to alternatives that—</text>
 <clause id="H69B3C1D4E91344D99466C58D93EAD5FF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>specify performance objectives rather than conduct or manners of compliance;</text> </clause><clause id="H31890569A4B149C9B711FE4FFA2CD32C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish economic incentives to encourage desired behavior;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB9CED59AFE3B4D45B698ADF176C05F7F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide information upon which choices can be made by the public;</text> </clause><clause id="H64ABBF43C92B4395906CF292BC6E65FA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>incorporate other innovative alternatives rather than agency actions that specify conduct or manners of compliance; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6A9E8D8745F5436D8499DBF574FAE5AC"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">could in other ways substantially lower costs without significantly undermining effectiveness.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F0B97423ADF4AEBBE2F8E88BDABB217"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the rule or set of rules inhibits innovation in or growth of the United States economy, such as by impeding the introduction or use of safer or equally safe technology that is newer or more efficient than technology required by or permissible under the rule or set of rules.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE893277C1F3C47D6B0076C993192377C"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether or not the rule or set of rules harms competition within the United States economy or the international economic competitiveness of enterprises or entities based in the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA22B0194018B4687AF4CC872896E8FB6"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether or not the rule or set of rules limits or prevents an agency from applying new or emerging technologies to improve efficiency and effectiveness of government.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E548B9963C44517AEB2AF611E867A4B"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the rule or set of rules harms wage growth, including wage growth for minimum wage and part-time workers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDAC19FFE1FFD41EE8396888E89600970"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the rule or set of rules is in full compliance with the requirements of section 801(a)(1)(A) of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAC9B79333254976BDA952B9A6718E20"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether, and the extent to which, the repeal of the rule or set of rules would impact public health.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE358BC44275B4111BBF137EEDA3E8818"><enum>(M)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such other criteria as the Commission devises to identify rules and sets of rules that can be repealed to eliminate or reduce unnecessarily burdensome costs to the United States economy.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD21630B1405C49E3B17B82542FEE8366"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Methodology for review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall establish a methodology for conducting the review (including an overall review and discrete reviews of portions of the Code of Federal Regulations), identifying rules and sets of rules, and classifying rules under this subsection and publish the terms of the methodology in the Federal Register and on the website of the Commission. The Commission may propose and seek public comment on the methodology before the methodology is established.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H7708CA2564064BB095885C513DFA2342"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Classification of rules and sets of rules</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9F9EB8C07AD548A5B2FBCA9E24ED402F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>After completion of any review of rules or sets of rules under paragraph (2), the Commission shall classify each rule or set of rules identified in the review to qualify for recommended repeal as either a rule or set of rules—</text>
 <clause id="HB503AA5695244B72AA8911F6B21E7D8D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on which immediate action to repeal is recommended; or</text> </clause><clause id="H964B6D23D0504882ADC15AEDE2B7D286"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that should be eligible for repeal under regulatory cut-go procedures under title II.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54AEE1D8C37F4858BC4FA3A388DAC552"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Decisions by majority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each decision by the Commission to identify a rule or set of rules for classification under this paragraph, and each decision whether to classify the rule or set of rules under clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A), shall be made by a simple majority vote of the Commission. No such vote shall take place until after all members of the Commission have been confirmed by the Senate.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB198860877842CBA1D5D1F3F952DD18"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Initiation of review by other persons</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB47E551F516D4FE690DE58EF6A6A8416"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may also conduct a review under paragraph (2) of, and, if appropriate, classify under paragraph (4), any rule or set of rules that is submitted for review to the Commission by—</text>
 <clause id="H9104E2E4C79D48FDBB7E3AA28AEBDC43"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the President;</text> </clause><clause id="H30006F45EDF54F1A9EB181EA180028EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a Member of Congress;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2FBA03870E5049B4968FCEC2A63F2743"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any officer or employee of a Federal, State, local or tribal government, or regional governmental body; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCA6763BEB5474029BD5345B7B09D9596"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any member of the public.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB97067E75E2B420FBA9EA8A740149B2A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Form of submission</header><text>A submission to the Commission under this paragraph shall—</text>
 <clause id="H6D055E9FF23B4A85B04D1A2176E5DCFD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify the specific rule or set of rules submitted for review;</text> </clause><clause id="H29C74C31F2C94FE1B981DDCEEA07C0BF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide a statement of evidence to demonstrate that the rule or set of rules qualifies to be identified for repeal under the criteria listed in paragraph (2); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBB0EC2E9856A43858E72DAF695B257B9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other information as the submitter believes may be helpful to the Commission’s review, including a statement of the submitter’s interest in the matter.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB532D59F8FEB4041B3A61667F80809BB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Commission shall make each submission received under this paragraph available on the website of the Commission as soon as possible, but not later than 1 week after the date on which the submission was received.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H443CCC928D5B46B9919C9FB7AD8B6543"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Notices and reports of the Commission</header>
 <paragraph id="H6D021298382F46C68B9188F65E9E49DE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notices Of And Reports On Activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall publish, in the Federal Register and on the website of the Commission—</text> <subparagraph id="HCDEC970F27A94BB6BBFD1F4965A4EC59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notices in advance of all public meetings, hearings, and classifications under subsection (h) informing the public of the basis, purpose, and procedures for the meeting, hearing, or classification; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E370BF8F8954CA5B539697A08E0D84C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reports after the conclusion of any public meeting, hearing, or classification under subsection (h) summarizing in detail the basis, purpose, and substance of the meeting, hearing, or classification.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DEE7A68FBD247859607D4711B01F730"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each year, beginning on the date that is one year after the date on which all Commission members have been confirmed by the Senate, the Commission shall submit a report simultaneously to each House of Congress detailing the activities of the Commission for the previous year, and listing all rules and sets of rules classified under subsection (h) during that year. For each rule or set of rules so listed, the Commission shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBF05124150D946728A8863CF41F4D525"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify the agency that made the rule or set of rules;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04AFDF1117C64DB385C8340CD2EF008D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify the annual cost of the rule or set of rules to the United States economy and the basis upon which the Commission identified that cost;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35D86E730F1E47FBA49C3E913DC0695C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify whether the rule or set of rules was classified under clause (i) or clause (ii) of subsection (h)(4)(A);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1357E33E22E42078751E90A668C3C14"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify the criteria under subsection (h)(2) that caused the classification of the rule or set of rules and the basis upon which the Commission determined that those criteria were met;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AD5E81A61BF4995B1109D7030C522C1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each rule or set of rules listed under the criteria set forth in subparagraph (B), (D), (F), (G), (H), or (I) of subsection (h)(2), or other criteria established by the Commission under subparagraph (I) of such subsection under which the Commission evaluated alternatives to the rule or set of rules that could lead to lower regulatory costs, identify alternatives to the rule or set of rules that the Commission recommends the agency consider as replacements for the rule or set of rules and the basis on which the Commission rests the recommendations, and, in identifying such alternatives, emphasize alternatives that will achieve regulatory effectiveness at the lowest cost and with the lowest adverse impacts on jobs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF326106C892F4F1AB248D690B01C6522"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each rule or set of rules listed under the criteria set forth in subsection (h)(2)(E), the other Federal, State, or local governmental rules that the Commission found the rule or set of rules to overlap, duplicate, or conflict with, and the basis for the findings of the Commission; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AE65332EAC245C38A92D7834EB48D78"><enum>(G)</enum><text>in the case of each set of rules so listed, analyze whether Congress should also consider repeal of the statutory authority implemented by the set of rules.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3187FD8043E34FA8BDA35CE402E12224"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the date on which the Commission members’ appointments expire, the Commission shall submit a final report simultaneously to each House of Congress summarizing all activities and recommendations of the Commission, including a list of all rules or sets of rules the Commission classified under clause (i) of subsection (h)(4)(A) for immediate action to repeal, a separate list of all rules or sets of rules the Commission classified under clause (ii) of subsection (h)(4)(A) for repeal, and with regard to each rule or set of rules listed on either list, the information described in subparagraphs (A) through (F) of subsection (h)(2). This report may be included in the final annual report of the Commission under paragraph (2) and may include the Commission’s recommendation whether the Commission should be reauthorized by Congress.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCEFAC93BC9F2467D8FC2D9DC33C7C9FA"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Repeal of regulations; Congressional consideration of commission reports</header>
 <paragraph id="H46C00C2CD0784B689E10ACE046147312"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HCEA1F5821BE84FC4AE7DA7A53095F223"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the head of each agency with authority to repeal a rule or set of rules classified by the Commission under subsection (h)(4)(A)(i) for immediate action to repeal and newly listed as such in an annual or final report of the Commission under paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (i) shall repeal the rule or set of rules as recommended by the Commission within 60 days after the enactment of a joint resolution under paragraph (2) for approval of the recommendations of the Commission in the report; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FB5391388AC48039F9BD618C4CF0F3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the head of each agency with authority to repeal a rule or set of rules classified by the Commission under subsection (h)(4)(A)(ii) for repeal and newly listed as such in an annual or final report of the Commission under paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (i) shall repeal the rule or set of rules as recommended by the Commission pursuant to section 201, following the enactment of a joint resolution under paragraph (2) for approval of the recommendations of the Commission in the report.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3CE6341E63145BC80E4E7824958A8D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional approval</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3D46728F6CAB48D39F0F9661BB74C3D0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No head of an agency described in paragraph (1) shall be required by this Act to carry out a repeal listed by the Commission in a report transmitted to Congress under paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (i) until a joint resolution is enacted, in accordance with the provisions of subparagraph (B), approving such recommendations of the Commission for repeal.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FBBD9A533D64A2E87A537A3F50018FC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Terms of the resolution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (A), the term <term>joint resolution</term> means only a joint resolution which is introduced after the date on which the Commission transmits to the Congress under paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (i) the report containing the recommendations to which the resolution pertains, and—</text>
 <clause id="HB196E71E2BA24B05920BE1EC0FA4D1E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which does not have a preamble;</text> </clause><clause id="H154BC69354614E1B96C0020F2966FEE3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the matter after the resolving clause of which is only as follows: <quote>That Congress approves the recommendations for repeal of the Retrospective Regulatory Review Commission as submitted by the Commission on ____</quote>, the blank space being filled in with the appropriate date; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H71B8D55311CB4102B395C8ADD30EBFCF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the title of which is as follows: <quote>Approving recommendations for repeal of the Retrospective Regulatory Review Commission.</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3890470C488146A0925C6734415E9E63"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reissuance of rules</header> <subparagraph id="HA6BFB15B42AE40DF812ED4F7AD3C3344"><enum>(A)</enum><header>No substantially similar rule to be reissued</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A rule that is repealed under paragraph (1) or section 201 may not be reissued in substantially the same form, and a new rule that is substantially the same as such a rule may not be issued, unless the reissued or new rule is specifically authorized by a law enacted after the date of the joint resolution approving the Commission’s recommendation to repeal the original rule.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC5B042892DA4B17927FA337A7CF3290"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Agency to ensure avoidance of similar defects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agency, in making any new rule to implement statutory authority previously implemented by a rule repealed under paragraph (1) or section 201, shall ensure that the new rule does not result in the same adverse effects of the repealed rule that caused the Commission to recommend to Congress the latter’s repeal and will not result in new adverse effects of the kind described in the criteria specified in or under subsection (h).</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD3B6FC075BE24A0BB00449ADF9A7BB48"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="H1341B2467A794F1B9AF4A2500D15DC42"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to the Commission to carry out this Act, not to exceed $30,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H13B37A1BC8404574BD4D3613DC117DFE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any sums appropriated under the authorization contained in this section shall remain available, without fiscal year limitation, until the earlier of the date that such sums are expended or the date of the termination of the Commission.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H18F6CEB8D0DF42598BBF7245D2424F64"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Website</header>
 <paragraph id="H616EE316C03D46F4A7034A71DF4CE8B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall establish a public website that—</text> <subparagraph id="H12A45F8EE19444AEB465BB46AF5ED654"><enum>(A)</enum><text>uses current information technology to make records available on the website;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H221EF97819A8470FA787DFBB00B6DE41"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides information in a standard data format; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC81C42466B14EFD9348B4F05B8CD5D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>receives and publishes public comments.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8AD7E65D7B04640B9FCF4D431DBDE97"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publishing of information</header><text>Any information required to be made available on the website established pursuant to this Act shall be published in a timely manner and shall be accessible by the public on the website at no cost.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H46776F3BABFB41C2910F9A25A44AB102"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Record of public meetings and hearings</header><text>All records of public meetings and hearings shall be published on the website as soon as possible, but not later than 1 week after the date on which such public meeting or hearing occurred.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70116AF4C6F24C2B94793C5F4D710E57"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public comments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall publish on the website all public comments and submissions.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H19540C0F4BF94B4FAD5F12C005048201"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Notices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall publish on the website notices of all public meetings and hearings at least one week before the date on which such public meeting or hearing occurs.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD89DDFFF391C4E4982F398A3C8B837CD"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Applicability of the Federal Advisory Committee Act</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H3AD29D408F6A48E5ACD39C4187921FA4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this Act, the Commission shall be subject to the provisions of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2FBD7C075A5C4C08B266125A206534D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advisory committee management officer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall not be subject to the control of any Advisory Committee Management Officer designated under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Federal Advisory Committee Act /8">section 8(b)(1)</external-xref> of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H59123F62E6E147AEB1B328365BB8C147"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subcommittee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any subcommittee of the Commission shall be treated as the Commission for purposes of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC2F918BEE2A14B9CA45F9BD0B4E0AB0F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Charter</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The enactment of the <short-title>SCRUB Act</short-title> shall be considered to meet the requirements of the Commission under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Federal Advisory Committee Act /9">section 9(c)</external-xref> of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H32D81B3E75804D4697E0F4987097DCA3"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>unfunded mandate</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>Federal mandate</quote> in section 421(6) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/658">2 U.S.C. 658(6)</external-xref>).</text> </subsection></section></title><title id="HD80E87C30696429D895804B97BE82145"><enum>II</enum><header>Regulatory Cut-Go</header> <section id="HA7480D14C01A41CCB01461BDFC3484E0"><enum>201.</enum><header>Cut-go procedures</header> <subsection id="H624BF996E63A4B21886640A496B8EE0C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in section 101(j)(2)(A) or section 202, an agency, when the agency makes a new rule, shall repeal rules or sets of rules of that agency classified by the Commission under section 101(h)(4)(A)(ii), such that the annual costs of the new rule to the United States economy is offset by such repeals, in an amount equal to or greater than the cost of the new rule, based on the regulatory cost reductions of repeal identified by the Commission.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC2D441B37AEE41F3BAB1C2B15A3D0ED6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Alternative procedure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agency may, alternatively, repeal rules or sets of rules of that agency classified by the Commission under section 101(h)(4)(A)(ii) prior to the time specified in subsection (a). If the agency so repeals such a rule or set of rules and thereby reduces the annual, inflation-adjusted cost of the rule or set of rules to the United States economy, the agency may thereafter apply the reduction in regulatory costs, based on the regulatory cost reductions of repeal identified by the Commission, to meet, in whole or in part, the regulatory cost reduction required under subsection (a) of this section to be made at the time the agency promulgates a new rule.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="HA90C660BDFFE4AC18F3A2EDC1D3FBD1D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Achievement of full net cost reductions</header>
 <paragraph id="HF09A3E9CDDC34AF7BB66D0ACC2E386F0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2), an agency may offset the costs of a new rule or set of rules by repealing a rule or set of rules listed by the Commission under section 101(h)(4)(A)(ii) that implement the same statutory authority as the new rule or set of rules.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H460E1624D8BA45939FE231E33B5C7E6E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When using the authority provided in paragraph (1), the agency must achieve a net reduction in costs imposed by the agency’s body of rules (including the new rule or set of rules) that is equal to or greater than the cost of the new rule or set of rules to be promulgated, including, whenever necessary, by repealing additional rules of the agency listed by the Commission under section 101(h)(4)(A)(ii).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEE8C4C32F7874860A873D9F5E9846FB7"><enum>202.</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An agency shall no longer be subject to the requirements of sections 201 and 203 beginning on the date that there is no rule or set of rules of the agency classified by the Commission under section 101(h)(4)(A)(ii) that has not been repealed such that all regulatory cost reductions identified by the Commission to be achievable through repeal have been achieved.</text>
 </section><section id="HD1122B7F0AA044A9B175EE2631BD85D9"><enum>203.</enum><header>OIRA certification of cost calculations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget shall review and certify the accuracy of agency determinations of the costs of new rules under section 201. The certification shall be included in the administrative record of the relevant rulemaking by the agency promulgating the rule, and the Administrator shall transmit a copy of the certification to Congress when it transmits the certification to the agency.</text>
			</section></title><title id="HA6AC580B54804DB9B6D0F4687FDCA616"><enum>III</enum><header>Retrospective Review of New Rules</header>
 <section id="H476F6CBE405B48F69EED3CAE61E9A4D8"><enum>301.</enum><header>Plan for future review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">When an agency makes a rule, the agency shall include in the final issuance of such rule a plan for the review of such rule by not later than 10 years after the date such rule is made. Such a review, in the case of a major rule, shall be substantially similar to the review by the Commission under section 101(h). In the case of a rule other than a major rule, the agency’s plan for review shall include other procedures and standards to enable the agency to determine whether to repeal or amend the rule to eliminate unnecessary regulatory costs to the economy. Whenever feasible, the agency shall include a proposed plan for review of a proposed rule in its notice of proposed rulemaking and shall receive public comment on the plan.</text>
			</section></title><title id="H886863C142F54B7B88FC117C886D11C5"><enum>IV</enum><header>Judicial Review</header>
			<section id="HB788F39A348148CCBA4AD61339704FFD"><enum>401.</enum><header>Judicial review</header>
 <subsection id="H917DE33575C74451A632CB0D98F3EC2F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Immediate repeals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Agency compliance with section 101(j) of this Act shall be subject to judicial review under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1D682B5B06264DB9A56E49CC0E7571F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cut-Go procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Agency compliance with title II of this Act shall be subject to judicial review under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H73C2547F9C1748BE927C2EDE0F50BDDB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Plans for future review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Agency compliance with section 301 shall be subject to judicial review under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="H7E89AD48C7A748B4A8DA5F99317E1846"><enum>V</enum><header>Miscellaneous Provisions</header>
 <section id="HD866F0F10BBB4EE4A48E05AD9787BE6B"><enum>501.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HC6E826BA5EA244BFBF1075750E4BB048"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA70D7BD2869478190DBC7233926C828"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Retrospective Regulatory Review Commission established under section 101.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3CF2FFE3CF46433DA3DA00B6B64451E6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Major rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>major rule</term> means any rule that the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs determines is likely to impose—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE6E2E9678F334F7198A4C35A729CCBCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an annual cost on the economy of $100,000,000 or more, adjusted annually for inflation;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67A6C95DD5184138BB903116405D1567"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a major increase in costs or prices for consumers, individual industries, Federal, State, local, or tribal government agencies, or geographic regions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78F2D83420D84DB291E7BDBD9335FC23"><enum>(C)</enum><text>significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, or on the ability of United States-based enterprises to compete with foreign-based enterprises in domestic and export markets; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA547BCA343F42B89ED9F09AAC3FC8CC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>significant impacts on multiple sectors of the economy.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE868E4B4F3D44C28B1BD0D9ACB5D77D1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule</header><text>The term <term>rule</term> has the meaning given that term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5E7ACB3C769A4853A3C685F7234FB34A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Set of rules</header><text>The term <term>set of rules</term> means a set of rules that collectively implements a regulatory authority of an agency.</text> </paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="H4DD22A8A978C48C294446A5B25169E9E"><enum>502.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</section></title></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170301">Passed the House of Representatives March 1, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


