<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3A1887C9570F416585CF53074D945E24" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2317 IH: United States Coast Guard Commemorative Coin Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2317</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170503">May 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001048">Mr. Hunter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001077">Mr. Coffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000625">Mr. Donovan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001200">Mr. McEachin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000576">Mr. Ruppersberger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001227">Mr. Brady of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint coins in commemoration of the United States Coast
			 Guard.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H50EF449D30794120B0DE6564F96C2A5F" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3DDB7C8C74C64017A1A29746B1677DEB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States Coast Guard Commemorative Coin Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5263413AF80E4F9F91EF4315E4586E20"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H4E63E3E5473A4092A74F9F156F62E627"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States Coast Guard was founded on August 4, 1790, as the Revenue Cutter Service under the United States Department of the Treasury.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H67BA83C1026B4D69853EB10B05DD6AC0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Congress created the Coast Guard on January 28, 1915, by merging the Revenue Cutter Service and the United States Lifesaving Service, was moved to the Department of Transportation in 1967, and on February 25, 2003, became part of the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8ADC3B74BFD24A27B806920063CCE334"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Although the smallest of the uniformed services, today the United States Coast Guard conducts a wide variety of missions to protect the public, the environment, and the United States economic and security interests in any maritime region, including international waters and America’s coasts, ports, and inland waterways.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF14A9196DBCA4987AA5C18AE2754EFD2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Every day, the United States Coast Guard plays a broad and important role in homeland security, law enforcement, search and rescue, marine environmental pollution response, and the maintenance of river, intra-coastal and offshore aids to navigation (ATON).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C7F1B6F113B4C978E1210DC831CC7D7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The United States Coast Guard is our Nation’s oldest seagoing military service, staying true to their motto, Semper Paratus or <quote>Always Ready</quote>, for 227 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7656252437E0491E8758DAFD744460D3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The United States Coast Guard is supported by over 55,000 Active Duty, Reserve, and Civilian personnel, who in 2016 responded to 16,304 search and rescue cases saving 5,221 lives, conducted 47,418 waterborne patrols of critical maritime infrastructure, escorted over 2671 high-capacity passenger vessels, conducted 7022 security boardings in and around United States ports, removed $5.7 billion worth of illegal drugs, interdicted 6,346 undocumented migrants attempting to illegally enter the United States, and maintained 45,114 navigation aids that support $3.2 trillion in economic activity on our Nation’s waterways.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H12DDDE71328143E4B37EE9B58ABAD1C4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Section 213 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/293">Public Law 108–293</external-xref> states that <quote>The Commandant may establish a National Coast Guard Museum, on lands which will be federally owned and administered by the Coast Guard, and are located in New London, Connecticut, at, or in close proximity to, the Coast Guard Academy</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H47E5935DE67341B5A52035F081DC1C85"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The National Coast Guard Museum Association, a nonprofit association dedicated to improve public understanding of the history, service and missions of the Coast Guard, is working with the United States Coast Guard, the City of New London, the State of Connecticut, and a range of local, regional, and national stakeholders to develop, plan and raise capital for the National Coast Guard Museum, to be located in New London, Connecticut.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A51360E51DD4069B9B86E4E492C65E4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The United States Coast Guard is the only military service without a national museum through which to share its history and legacy with the American public.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HF5FAE0835D494AE087E3DA49F806EB89"><enum>3.</enum><header>Coin specifications</header>
 <subsection id="H701FC77A45804D14A6849AB47E184CD0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Denominations</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall mint and issue the following coins:</text> <paragraph id="HBF8F2F00F81B43BF9256283D2176E696"><enum>(1)</enum><header>$5 gold coins</header><text>Not more than 100,000 $5 coins, which shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1D9E78B3236F4D8C80AE29A1E1382983"><enum>(A)</enum><text>weigh 8.359 grams;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC69EEA458D74A01BDEC61A3AED04EDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have a diameter of 0.850 inches; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7A465AE2C5848D9815DA777C61FEEAC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contain 90 percent gold and 10 percent alloy.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H13850713189A4105B3F4BA01B57FB757"><enum>(2)</enum><header>$1 silver coins</header><text>Not more than 500,000 $1 coins, which shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDCBDE47DB8A54E11A3A4032C71017B8F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>weigh 26.73 grams;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F1555028B5A4E809D382BCA647EC7E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have a diameter of 1.500 inches; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE8A198D5E7A4ECF94F28125229F0C1A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contain at least 90 percent silver.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE3831A0E9384D7FAC4E39850F1ABDEC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Half dollar clad coins</header><text>Not more than 750,000 half dollar coins, which shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD451A319DD944444B18B4307CB52338C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>weigh 11.34 grams;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F0C9E85CA2A455DB8E20B0E51F2C866"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have a diameter of 1.205 inches; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23DD16D43508469DBAEBA7A70C79D536"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be minted to the specifications for half dollar coins, contained in section 5112(b) of title 31, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7069AD0CD18C44F3B5ED1342129643E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Legal tender</header><text>The coins minted under this Act shall be legal tender, as provided in section 5103 of title 31, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF122433A89D04549919E3885E8D4D764"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all coins minted under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H6212811B15D24A689A11391DD3C28D7D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Design of coin</header>
			<subsection id="H03F1168B50EE487489E9CA0869E6E84D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Design requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="H39D5B65EE370446CAA223F9794A90E2E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The design of the coins minted under this Act shall be emblematic of the traditions, history, and heritage of the United States Coast Guard, and its role in securing our Nation since 1790.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA2EC808C964B42EF88CEE0BCA42135EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designations and inscriptions</header><text>On each coin minted under this Act, there shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="H868D81E331B64E2D8FD3E1FC1746E777"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a designation of the value of the coin;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98EBBCF8E9F04D4998138F2D503C3EBB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an inscription of the year <quote>2020</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE83ADA9E8044479BE39C33C919BAF6C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>inscriptions of the words <quote>Liberty</quote>, <quote>In God We Trust</quote>, <quote>United States of America</quote>, <quote>E Pluribus Unum</quote>, and <quote>Semper Paratus</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF34E062BE594FD595F86A8CCD538A44"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The design for the coins minted under this Act shall—</text> <paragraph id="H5EBDF5B0D8F248C08C02CAEBC6A76356"><enum>(1)</enum><text>contain motifs that specifically honor the United States Coastguardsman of both today and yesterday, in wartime and in peace, such designs to be consistent with the traditions and heritage of the United States Coast Guard, the mission and goals of the National Coast Guard Museum, and the missions and goals of the National Coast Guard Museum Association;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H710A05381BF847F79411C275EEB97DBB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be selected by the Secretary, after consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, the National Coast Guard Museum Association, and the Commission of Fine Arts; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B87355B3D4A4BE6B683039959B349E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be reviewed by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1611D74EF381476588F3F53CC66A5C4B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Issuance of coins</header> <subsection id="H47A86DA06D7B4DE88053FBABED429E55"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Quality of coins</header><text>Coins minted under this Act shall be issued in uncirculated and proof qualities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDD01625D22594C2A951E084EB7413B38"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mint facilities</header><text>For each of the 3 coins minted under this Act, at least one facility of the United States Mint shall be used to strike proof quality coins, while at least one other such facility shall be used to strike the uncirculated quality coins.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0871E9C5B60D46CEBFB9AF784E4ACB2A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Period for issuance</header><text>The Secretary may issue coins minted under this Act only during the 1-year period beginning on January 1, 2020.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H53BBCEB2F52A41F19DD485482D356A53"><enum>6.</enum><header>Sale of coins</header>
 <subsection id="HA40EAA89C7EB4753902B9C5D9EE9BFAC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sale price</header><text>The coins issued under this Act shall be sold by the Secretary at a price equal to the sum of—</text> <paragraph id="H4D8528A5E35F44DEB3060E6CCD554680"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the face value of the coins;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82121FA437904E5C898C210D12BFC676"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the surcharge provided in section 7(a) with respect to such coins; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H023441650C9D40DEB2D0827EFCB32A73"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the cost of designing and issuing the coins (including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, overhead expenses, marketing, and shipping).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC699A15C051B4B1FACA0111F040D78E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bulk sales</header><text>The Secretary shall make bulk sales of the coins issued under this Act at a reasonable discount.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HAD93F73DA73649C8BA86566EAA9E229F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prepaid orders</header> <paragraph id="H3C7A3B6C66944AE8B7D9FDC0DB754546"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall accept prepaid orders for the coins minted under this Act before the issuance of such coins.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB82C6B99B8614C56B76B673C46DC5CBA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Discount</header><text>Sale prices with respect to prepaid orders under paragraph (1) shall be at a reasonable discount.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H43C8CC1A3B134327A9F6981FF39AE882"><enum>7.</enum><header>Surcharges</header> <subsection id="H4168706520B54AD686BF90AB8B95F72D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All sales of coins minted under this Act shall include a surcharge as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H037DEDB313054BF98EDD6B896DC1C9F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A surcharge of $35 per coin for the $5 coin.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCEEC932188F74CBA9659DA9EB0A1931B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A surcharge of $10 per coin for the $1 coin.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A39AD0BE5AD4D2682849E404B6E776F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A surcharge of $5 per coin for the half dollar coin.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4CA0C10FEE84310924FBA1BCA188AF8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>Subject to section 5134(f) of title 31, United States Code, all surcharges received by the Secretary from the sale of coins issued under this Act shall be promptly paid by the Secretary to the National Coast Guard Museum Association to help finance the design, construction, operations, and maintenance of the National Coast Guard Museum.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H83CBEB2B189A42CE92B4AE6C9C8CDF40"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Audits</header><text>The National Coast Guard Museum Association shall be subject to the audit requirements of section 5134(f)(2) of title 31, United States Code, with regard to the amounts received under subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB8E89C07E8F342FA898CA69B82019F43"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), no surcharge may be included with respect to the issuance under this Act of any coin during a calendar year if, as of the time of such issuance, the issuance of such coin would result in the number of commemorative coin programs issued during such year to exceed the annual 2 commemorative coin program issuance limitation under section 5112(m)(1) of title 31, United States Code. The Secretary may issue guidance to carry out this subsection.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H84DB202A0DB24F79B297ED6635735B42"><enum>8.</enum><header>Financial assurances</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall take such actions as may be necessary to ensure that—</text> <paragraph id="HD44532449FA54E3A91F4AE298939848B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>minting and issuing coins under this Act will not result in any net cost to the United States Government; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F420407DC1849BAA8378EEDCE4E8A39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no funds, including applicable surcharges, shall be disbursed to any recipient designated in section 7 until the total cost of designing and issuing all of the coins authorized by this Act (including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, overhead expenses, marketing, and shipping) is recovered by the United States Treasury, consistent with sections 5112(m) and 5134(f) of title 31, United States Code.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


