<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H06CBDA9075DF40AF96A9F3AAB3BEC6D4" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1047 IH: Fairness in Firearm Testing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1047</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170214">February 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000598">Mr. Rothfus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000560">Mr. Graves of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000621">Mr. DeSantis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives to make video recordings of the
			 examination and testing of firearms and ammunition, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1F218BCA4B6A47A39E52BB1C4DD33253" style="OLC">
 <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C8B00ED7C0F46AEB19EFCCC0C5CEB0C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fairness in Firearm Testing Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB54A85E634914C469B62C0CF3BD35CF5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Video recording of examination and testing of firearms and ammunition by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1111 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/531">6 U.S.C. 531</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD603B1A3C4004407A3F635ED0B983B60" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H31D7D04C92D4464CBE9DF0D9D62C668F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional responsibilities regarding examination and testing of firearms and ammunition</header>
 <paragraph id="H17E12A0B976B445DA385746753325758"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Video recording required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau shall make a video recording of the entire process of the examination and testing by the Bureau of an item for the purpose of determining, pursuant to section 921(a)(3), 922(o), 922(p), or subsection (a)(3), (a)(4), (d), or (e) of section 925 of title 18, United States Code, or <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5845">section 5845(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, whether the item is a firearm and if so, the type of firearm, or of determining pursuant to section 921(a)(17) of title 18, United States Code, whether the item is ammunition, and shall not edit or erase any recording made pursuant to this paragraph.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HBC0784EA57F34CB9A2435EC22E186340"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header>
 <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A870D163FBF4594A04C0B6F086FDACB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>To owners</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On request of a person who claims an ownership interest in an item with respect to which a recording is made under paragraph (1), the Bureau shall make available to the person, without charge, a digital video disc that contains a copy of the recording.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53210C5410584B7A99DED2785AA167B9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>To defendants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau shall make available to a defendant in a criminal proceeding involving an item with respect to which a recording is made under paragraph (1) a digital video disc that contains a copy of the recording.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F0E3F47948A47E081C0621F91DB7851"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Admissibility as evidence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An item which the Bureau has determined is a firearm or a type of firearm or ammunition pursuant to any provision of law specified in paragraph (1) shall not be admissible as evidence in any judicial or administrative proceeding unless—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H121F0AB13B234C0F9A5AC021E118974B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Bureau has complied with paragraph (2) with respect to the item; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C916C81875248899F3B3F4492C9308E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such compliance has been waived, in writing, by the person against whom the item is offered as evidence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


