<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB8F57B87A048402CA3D66725E6DD38EE" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4466 IH: WMATA Flexible Funding and Safety Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4466</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171128">November 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide funding flexibility to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority, to grant
			 authority to amend the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority
			 Compact, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HBC7FC062DCE9416C843CD8327D9C0EC4" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCCD0C4E8BF8D47629A544732B4D81012" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>WMATA Flexible Funding and Safety Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><title id="H2900167ADAC144A68A45BDEF0EDE1F31"><enum>I</enum><header>Operating Assistance</header> <section id="H03D783F0239F4039A0AFE5E0C7591E47"><enum>101.</enum><header>Federal operating assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5307 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7170DBE09F504A71A28CAFA566091636" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H721E744E8CD948218C2288AC4356326A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>The Secretary may make grants under this section to finance the operating cost of equipment and facilities for use in an urbanized area with a population of not fewer than 200,000 individuals, as determined by the Bureau of the Census, for a public transportation system that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0679B571DCB24693A6547F1CBC1FF227"><enum>(1)</enum><text>operates as an interstate compact agency by the terms of its enabling legislation; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H09B37FC9D45D4F53A2FF41DD7277F004"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is an agency and instrumentality of 3 signatories, which have enacted legislation—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFFD6B78B898E46DAB2DB8CF93896FF0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to provide a dedicated source of revenue to finance the operating costs of equipment and facilities for use in public transportation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF6A4E50D9C9403CA74BFB8C5FBBD909"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that results in the collection of local and State funds that cover at least 50 percent of such operating costs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="H1373E91BB2E34E1B98C57B8B01624A00"><enum>II</enum><header>Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Compact</header>
 <section id="H89A162EC3C4A4070B58302517B12465D"><enum>201.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="HAB670F1A7BD84A8A9C9B75D053318831"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compact</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Compact</term> means title III of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Regulation Compact, known as the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Compact, consented to by Congress under <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/89/774">Public Law 89–774</external-xref> (80 Stat. 1324 et seq.).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E39E72B947B40B99AC5220D5FFC902F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadhead miles</header><text>The term <term>deadhead miles</term> means the movement of a transit vehicle without passengers aboard, which often occurs to and from a garage or to and from 1 route to another.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4D9DFCE4C4744B74B1B3234A451C7369"><enum>(3)</enum><header>MetroAccess</header><text>The term <term>MetroAccess</term> means the paratransit service of the Transit Authority for individuals whose disability prevents them from using a bus or rail facility.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5B84174BEB64FB6ACF73A06ED87D012"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Super-late trips</header><text>The term <term>super-late trips</term> means MetroAccess trips extending at least 20 minutes past the delivery window.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE970C10943AC4687A1D2BC23F6652EB6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Transit Authority</header><text>The term <term>Transit Authority</term> means the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="H3A99A47C210C48F78DAA523C7153ACF8"><enum>202.</enum><header>Authority for Compact amendments</header>
 <subsection id="H87B1308AFDF24721B9BC687AD6F7B35B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The consent of Congress is hereby granted for the State of Maryland, the Commonwealth of Virginia, and the District of Columbia to amend the Compact for the purposes described in this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H52B09E2EDCB04EA58DC65E4F795F1376"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Safety task forces</header><text>The Compact may be amended to authorize the Transit Authority to establish and maintain—</text> <paragraph id="H3B11AF59413D4804BD97FB678D36FB64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Jeanice McMillan Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Track Safety Task Force for the development of on-track safety standards for the Transit Authority, as provided by section 203; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D3DA44C02F4408CB8C8FB79D3867AB5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Thomasine Maria Smith Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Bus Safety Task Force for the development of bus safety standards for the Transit Authority, as provided by section 204.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF30AA4885083494DA3BE84FB116B7618"><enum>(c)</enum><header>MetroAccess review</header>
 <paragraph id="H03781050933849FB8CC6FFC7FAE6C1AB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Compact may be amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HFA9413D3F8DD44BEBBA24270653A86E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to direct the Inspector General for the Transit Authority, prior to the renewal of any private MetroAccess contract by the Transit Authority for the provision of demand response services, to conduct a review of the MetroAccess program and submit a report on the results of the review in accordance with this subsection; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEE7E827C6494E70A27CD7A8D602F140"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to include the prohibition set forth in paragraph (5).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2868845E8CD648D295CA176349753033"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In conducting the review, the Inspector General shall compare paratransit services provided under the MetroAccess program to similar programs carried out by at least 30 peer transit agencies across the United States, including systems that directly operate such services and systems that purchase transportation for such services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H37DFEDE044B4449A8649B77B29DF31D8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Scope</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General shall ensure that the scope of the review includes an examination of—</text> <subparagraph id="H9C9597BE24AA40FC928FA8AEB6BCF33A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>percentage of deadhead miles;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1A23759A11C4D28B70400EBE40CE006"><enum>(B)</enum><text>percentage of deadhead hours;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H039BA009286A411B8B0B1B5EB734E37E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>passengers per revenue mile;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84B469E279A44649929FB6833DB0F092"><enum>(D)</enum><text>average trip length;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C4A9DDFC2284E5F89A477CFC6125699"><enum>(E)</enum><text>cost per revenue mile;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CEF995A945E40429E68DDD001CE12A9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>cost per revenue hour;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC416F183F2E9472DA8D394A1BF165C5D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>cost per unlinked trip;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04B1D967EB99400088441A23AF1667AF"><enum>(H)</enum><text>unlinked passenger trips per vehicle revenue hour;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68074ED0D5DD4B459A9DDEEB2C18E428"><enum>(I)</enum><text>unlinked passenger trips per vehicle revenue mile;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5216239EFD32439C97092366EB059210"><enum>(J)</enum><text>late trips;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13B508E06A8646F18EE176039EE4E554"><enum>(K)</enum><text>super-late trips; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADC5D306CFB74CF0A4977EF320F0B006"><enum>(L)</enum><text>additional related matters.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC55CF63DD83A480D9C75464E1C8D1AFB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Submission of report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon completion of the review, the Inspector General shall submit a report on the results of the review to the Governor of Maryland, the Governor of Virginia, the Mayor of the District of Columbia, the President of the Maryland Senate, the President of the Virginia Senate, the Speaker of the Maryland House of Delegates, the Speaker of the Virginia House of Delegates, and the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC19B0569A1904641A3DAF6717530DD6E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the results of the review indicate that the Transit Authority ranks in the bottom half of transit systems with respect to a majority of categories within the scope of the review, the Transit Authority—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H177395D8E8A6400AB889FC767DE6921E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not renew the MetroAccess contract that triggered the review; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB603A73ABAAC4D25B52B10015C1E8A53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall arrange to perform such services directly.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75DCC18E886041888E813C059E9BD87F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Flat fare, free transfer pilot program; ability-Based fares program</header>
 <paragraph id="H3AC88C6C916948048E4ACC7E6D82A9FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Compact may be amended to provide for, in accordance with the requirements of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H15719A850A764C44BC7CB8F9DBCC80EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a flat fare, free transfer pilot program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H295ABEDE209E42DC88698A7B72A42A69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an ability-based fares program.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H88E47B01D803453D8A3C81584876E0A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Flat fare, free transfer pilot program</header> <subparagraph id="H9DEDC3783A604562ADA965EDC03EE10B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under the flat fare, free transfer pilot program authorized by paragraph (1), not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Transit Authority shall institute at each participating Metrorail station, and widely publicize, a 1-year flat fare consisting of—</text>
 <clause id="HC68E9CFBB49B4C2D8A76E27D96568DF8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a flat fare of $2.50 for all Metrorail trips originating from the participating Metrorail station; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7ACB4B90F7C84C828B8008F978E57EC3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>free transfers at the participating Metrorail station between Metrorail and Metrobus.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EDA4C79EAD342969B7FC9DA5FD51AE6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Selection of participating Metrorail stations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Transit Authority shall select 3 Metrorail stations for participation in the pilot program, one of which shall be located in Maryland, one of which shall be located in Virginia, and one of which shall be located in the District of Columbia.</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB38E8A4D583841D1A875169600EA1FCE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <clause id="H2FDBCD38FC684BF7A777230E9B6C0372"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Transit Authority shall develop a report on the results of the pilot program.</text> </clause><clause id="H5725FF47C7F941BABC44839597FCBD3C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In developing the report, the Transit Authority shall examine—</text>
 <subclause id="H13335EF111EE409A812A9D1AD26244A7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>bus and rail ridership at Metrorail stations participating in the pilot program, comparing data from the period of the pilot program to the 2 previous years; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5AE5B0E11B0D4DD79C040F54372512AF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ridership patterns at other nearby Metrorail stations compared to the 2 previous years.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H6663C9B1B6BC41E4820757D0BD17606D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later that 90 days after the termination of the pilot program, the Transit Authority shall submit the report to the Governor of Maryland, the Governor of Virginia, the Mayor of the District of Columbia, the President of the Maryland Senate, the President of the Virginia Senate, the Speaker of the Maryland House of Delegates, the Speaker of the Virginia House of Delegates, and the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0D69C96379E84154B9BD355011AE3682"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Consideration of report results</header><text>If the report indicates that there was significant ridership growth at participating Metrorail stations as a result of the pilot program, the Transit Authority shall consider system-wide implementation of a successor program that is based on the pilot program.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8C61A9B20C74246B493D592959CC8C0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ability-based fares program</header>
 <subparagraph id="H04146724AFBF4D629B13BF03FBD346AB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under the ability-based fares program authorized by paragraph (1), not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Transit Authority shall implement a fare system, to be known as the lifeline fare system, that takes into account the ability of a passenger to pay.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3ED997BAF844C7C99679000B8763465"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>The lifeline fare system shall provide a 50-percent discount for residents whose incomes are at least 200 percent below the Federal poverty level.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF9A00A54805841B7894D464A79FFCCEC"><enum>203.</enum><header>Jeanice McMillan Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Track Safety Task Force</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments to the Compact referred to in section 202(b)(1) are substantially as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B0E3907FB6F4F9797101E935656ED6D" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HDCF11AACFA5B4562B5896E52E6FBA58E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of track safety task force</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established the Jeanice McMillan Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Track Safety Task Force.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8437631F790846EC950D9996DA41863F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Task force shall be responsible for reviewing the on-track safety program of the Transit Authority, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0F0E642D80964EB281C5380CF5E999D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">training and qualifications of employees of the Transit Authority affected by the program;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H983918BCAB414C8D92F556E57DA615A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>appropriate procedures for protecting employees of the Transit Authority engaged in work along the track right-of-way, including good faith challenge procedures;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01320C9EA91A477B9B717604249878BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>instructions to train operators;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD17EF5A5351A4F1B82C9A09948BD09E3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>relevant rules of the Transit Authority;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H550B69ECA98D4612B99E0FFBF25C8353"><enum>(5)</enum><text>third rail safety;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDDA01CC0276F48C8B346562D8B158AB0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>illuminations; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCFFA3A9D78D042CBBB4D6AF55B4E6517"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any additional related safety matters.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCAEE5C2E1E4A45799BC9CCE89B6A200A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Standards</header><text>The Task Fore shall conduct the review in accordance with—</text>
 <paragraph id="H583C0AFBEDEA4CF3B189C02DDC192224"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the best principles and practices found in Safety Management Systems and High Reliability Organizations identified in the report of the Transit Rail Advisory Committee entitled <quote>Implementing Safety Management System Principles in Rail Transit Agencies</quote>, dated May 20, 2011; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HECF998A90BCE42B6884244E41169B7A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations detailing how processes, practices, tasks, and individual employee responsibilities can support a strong safety culture, as reported in the report of the Transit Rail Advisory Committee entitled <quote>Building Toward a Strong Safety Culture Within the Bus and Rail Transit Industry</quote>, dated February 27, 2017.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H43CC5AEB2A074151BD5F71DC390766CB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <paragraph id="H0273575AE14E4CD78E0D0B85458FCC8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Task Force shall be composed of 4 members as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="H45F8C19F0BC14D89A542EF5C8214A912"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Chairman of the Washington Metrorail Safety Commission (or the Chairman’s designee).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87D3D2E1D5544F808564C1E4ED256B1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Chief Safety Officer of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (or the Chief Safety Officer’s designee).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E2103AA05C54E448300CCBED93FD1D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Deputy Chief of Rail Safety and Facilities of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (or the Deputy Chief’s designee).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE4C4707AD6E410191D150913AFFC4D4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The President of Amalgamated Transit Union, Local 689 (or the President’s designee).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H10CB4EB686144C4CA341F2F6B29FD6AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairman of the Washington Metrorail Safety Commission (or the Chairman’s designee) shall be the Chair of the Task Force.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB233B606881437A877B5FFFED6DA62E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Task Force shall meet at the call of the Chair, but in no event less than 4 times per year. Any member of the Task Force may call a meeting of the Task Force if the member provides not fewer than 10 days written notice of the meeting to the other members.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4747B99996DC498EA996408F0767A49C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compensation; expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members of the Task Force shall receive no salary or other compensation for their services, but the members shall be entitled to reimbursement for actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H923B99FF22714DC392D3D686DF550CC2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>On-Track safety program</header>
 <paragraph id="H03768DDB905140A8A8687B78CFB5D594"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the WMATA Flexible Funding and Safety Improvement Act, the Task Force shall issue one or more reports setting forth the rec­om­men­da­tions of the Task Force with respect to the on-track safety program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD365AF5A822B4553BC04F4D460F1532F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Task Force shall submit each report issued under this subsection to the Governor of Maryland, the Governor of Virginia, the Mayor of the District of Columbia, the President of the Maryland Senate, the President of the Virginia Senate, the Speaker of the Maryland House of Delegates, the Speaker of the Virginia House of Delegates, and the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H122FAF3FA0724C3D9DDD9A00FF691252"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Implementation of material modifications</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3C28A4525AC8476B8388282F60552DF8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Prior to the implementation of any material modification to the on-track safety program, the Transit Authority shall provide written notice of the material modification to the Task Force.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98C3D38881C04CF7A86AB144146220CC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Upon receipt of written notice of a material modification under subparagraph (A), the Task Force shall review the modification at the next meeting of the Task Force.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H392AD1D2266E4B348C9C4E41A2D172AA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation on statutory construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to preclude or limit the right of the Transit Authority to implement a modification to the on-track safety program that the Transit Authority determines is appropriate to enhance the safety of its employees, customers, or third parties.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H22899ABE28864F75A5C773DD59AE282A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual inspection</header>
 <paragraph id="H57F621846F7A4B739FEA42DAD1721BA4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Task Force shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HCE95DD18CA774D2D919774932E83D9CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct an annual inspection of the compliance by the Transit Authority with the on-track safety program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H446917F17EA04B899D715B3E79AEE1CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on or before July 1, 2019, and each year thereafter, issue to the Transit Authority a report detailing its findings.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF89CCBC2D4A4C5EB7882B3B01077DDB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Response</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of receipt of a report under paragraph (1), the Transit Authority shall provide written notice to the Task Force of the actions of the Task Force, if any, implemented or to be implemented in response to the report.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E79B3B8A1CB419996DDD3E58473975E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="H86AEFF392CA64D2A9C696F4CC6DC0E50"><enum>(1)</enum><header>On-track safety program</header><text>The term <term>on-track safety program</term> means the on-track safety program of the Transit Authority.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H12CD75984DFA4C838F3EF9FFF5A6CE20"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Task Force</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Task Force</term> means the Jeanice McMillan Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Track Safety Task Force established under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FE149B9B77542DF9638ACECF4BC3B98"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transit Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Transit Authority</term> means the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section id="H5A48071D345B4016A16FD993348A6466"><enum>204.</enum><header>Thomasine Maria Smith Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Bus Safety Task Force</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments to the Compact referred to in section 202(b)(2) are substantially as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0BECF0E48EFD4C1A9C1A18D2C15C0093" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HA95532DF8C2041BEAB79671EC96C47CE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of bus safety task force</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established the Thomasine Maria Smith Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Bus Safety Task Force.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2233F56A15764F819E53AB5AD37861A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Task Force shall be responsible for reviewing the bus safety program of the Transit Authority, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB1C5F0D0220642C9B9A74B1F4506C604"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">training and qualifications of employees of the Transit Authority affected by the program;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D447DA9BD4A4AE09B637CF082AB86A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>appropriate procedures for protecting employees of the Transit Authority engaged in bus operations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD51FC3D5F84479F82E5897CC21802C1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>instructions to bus operators;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CDEA6752ACE47B7965C7448B68E86A4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>relevant rules of the Transit Authority; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE85933E38B5D4A78A23CB64CA7D8E671"><enum>(5)</enum><text>strategies to eliminate or minimize the exposure of the public, personnel, and property to hazards and unsafe conditions by, among other measures—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6FCB558FE9694C74A13CA31211CCB45B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>scheduling fixed route bus service with adequate time and access for operators to use restroom facilities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A9A9324B66244B9B21FA4F126074902"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protecting bus operators from the risk of assault;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC21F77271FC34A3B8C67795A485A4B1F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>eliminating blind spots; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CD20C747B804998AA497FA199A71C3B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any additional related safety matters.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4FD2B106013C4516B95652C306FE76C5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header> <paragraph id="H54CFFFDCAB9244F09AA67AD1150A8B5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Task Force shall be composed of 3 members as follows:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H757CC483A4D94B50BA25A8155295EE93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Chief Safety Officer of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (or the Chief Safety Officer’s designee).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2D10000DB8745D985E18DDE0E6CF287"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Deputy Chief of Bus and MetroAccess of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (or the Deputy Chief’s designee).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EFE1E197F2D4874860CC88499E0873E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The President of Amalgamated Transit Union, Local 689 (or the President’s designee).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC1FD97B6A2B47DDA5877B4A92BB1F39"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief Safety Officer of the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (or the Chief Safety Officer’s designee) shall be the Chair of the Task Force.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E2D838EF7F74AAB9DC97787D495E221"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Task Force shall meet at the call of the Chair, but in no event less than 4 times per year. Any member of the Task Force may call a meeting of the Task Force if the member provides not fewer than 10 days written notice of the meeting to the other members.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC27CFC94E7C14E94A6245B232C66E007"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compensation; expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members of the Task Force shall receive no salary or other compensation for their services, but the members shall be entitled to reimbursement for actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H33FE18E6A815414D839111ABEE94D0F9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Bus safety program</header>
 <paragraph id="HA3FCAF0913F94598927F18BDA8353A95"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the WMATA Flexible Funding and Safety Improvement Act, the Task Force shall issue one or more reports setting forth the rec­om­men­da­tions of the Task Force with respect to the bus safety program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C7864BEBECC431EAF38C5CBEF13D4EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Task Force shall submit each report issued under this subsection to the Governor of Maryland, the Governor of Virginia, the Mayor of the District of Columbia, the President of the Maryland Senate, the President of the Virginia Senate, the Speaker of the Maryland House of Delegates, the Speaker of the Virginia House of Delegates, and the Chairman of the Council of the District of Columbia.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H22858F45CE2646489E6399942214C584"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Implementation of material modifications</header>
 <subparagraph id="H68B6FD07D7D84B3B8DAE18DF69B7DC03"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Prior to the implementation of any material modification to the bus safety program, the Transit Authority shall provide written notice of the material modification to the Task Force.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA5661915FC2414BA9FD9831AC059B46"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Upon receipt of written notice of a material modification under subparagraph (A), the Task Force shall review the modification at the next meeting of the Task Force.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6344FCDCE54F44F8BB19B8AD37E71C0B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation on statutory construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to preclude or limit the right of the Transit Authority to implement a modification to the bus safety program that the Transit Authority determines is appropriate to enhance the safety of its employees, customers, or third parties.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H623F34B7835D4173B199DC42607044EA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual inspection</header>
 <paragraph id="H32A01AA827C243FBBD54EE7BF74FE488"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Task Force shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H4B6D0BA798F44EB1BB790AE03119CB47"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct an annual inspection of the compliance by the Transit Authority with the bus safety program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H796A11B17269415485AEF31281A9E1A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on or before July 1, 2019, and each year thereafter, issue to the Transit Authority a report detailing its findings.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE750466E8F4A4FB0893E985E05DC1B92"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Response</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of receipt of a report under paragraph (1), the Transit Authority shall provide written notice to the Task Force of the actions of the Task Force, if any, implemented or to be implemented in response to the report.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D1CC379FD8B49738C93532FC52B2B6A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the following definitions apply:</text> <paragraph id="HBDED8FBA0B244AE99ED5E1B238059B61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bus safety program</header><text>The term <term>bus safety program</term> means the bus safety program of the Transit Authority.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B139DEEA2FB4C19BB34240630930B80"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Task Force</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Task Force</term> means the Thomasine Maria Smith Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Bus Safety Task Force established under subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2068693FB40427E94C7321C708C94A9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transit Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Transit Authority</term> means the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section></title></legis-body></bill> 

