<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H59D5ECDA69F84E46956F448B27F8A25B" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 971 IH: Surviving Spouse Contracting Preference Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
		<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 971</legis-num>
		<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date date="20170203">February 7, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to treat small businesses, owned by surviving spouses of 
members of the Armed Forces killed in the line of duty, as small business concerns owned and
			 controlled by veterans for purposes of contracting goals and preferences
			 of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H6ADFEF7A1A9845FFBB0DC53975B443AE" style="OLC">
		<section id="H70CA8620FAA340AA8B426DE9518AAC95" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Surviving Spouse Contracting Preference Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id961DA59C75134BFA853DA3B589CC77AC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of businesses owned by surviving spouses of members of the Armed Forces for purposes of Department of Veterans Affairs contracting goals and preferences</header> <subsection id="idFB17D8B8A25343E1B3EEA3137E891F5E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 8127 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="idCFB1EE99FA894E8580B69A77AD7E4ACC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (h) through (k) as subsections (i) through (l), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5956074321C14AC3890E9346B6B5B7BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (g) the following new subsection (h):</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id465BE572147F49958DD3A4D7B62ADC4A" style="OLC"><subsection id="id0C7F015F986D46BBA2547F3A8F4FE1A9"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Treatment of businesses after death of member</header><paragraph display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id1E6166A71068406CBFC46EA20D428EBB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If a member of the Armed Forces is killed in the line of duty in the active military, naval, or air service, the surviving spouse of such member who acquires ownership rights in a small business concern shall, for the period described in paragraph (2), be treated as the surviving spouse of a service-disabled veteran described in section 3(q)(2)(C)(i) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632(q)(2)(C)(i)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDEECCF3BAF89425D83E6D66CB33C2B75" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The period referred to in paragraph (1) is the period beginning on the date on which the member of the Armed Forces dies and ending on the earliest of the following dates:</text><subparagraph id="idD6F6FD2724EC46A784401C0EAF0285B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The date on which the surviving spouse of the member remarries.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id18122EC77DE5466394033289A10E3D7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The date on which the surviving spouse relinquishes such ownership interest in the small business concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC0DE47CAB29D4B4BB4F743A620F8BF8C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Subsection (h) of section 8127 of such title, as added by subsection (a), shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply with respect to the deaths of members of the Armed Forces occurring on or after such date.</text></subsection></section></legis-body>
</bill>


