<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H294A08D0F6F5414384AE12BC971DCBBF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2484 IH: Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2484</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170517">May 17, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000184">Mrs. Noem</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure that the United States promotes the meaningful participation of women in mediation and
			 negotiation processes seeking to prevent, mitigate, or resolve violent
			 conflict.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H79343CD3F7A54EE1A49DD803D2701B53" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6F63AAF760ED4E14AF84AFD8EFB8BC02" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H19259A712F5E4551AADAD8488A19E0EE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA98CD6714E7B40FE8A8D52F86D3C5A5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Around the world, women remain underrepresented in conflict prevention, conflict resolution, and post-conflict peace building efforts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H81AB8967B8944F1C958D27E329776F0F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Women in conflict-affected regions have achieved significant success in—</text> <subparagraph id="H815DBAA9302E40EEAFF4724280E87B97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>moderating violent extremism;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H085D5B07E94D4611A1710AFB6430518C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>countering terrorism;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37D797A9E3654D5EACD2FD2B4C8C6E7A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>resolving disputes through nonviolent mediation and negotiation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90B9983AABD746E1BCBF8D7A0F3657EB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>stabilizing societies by enhancing the effectiveness of security services, peacekeeping efforts, institutions, and decision-making processes.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H478CD1818C0E44058ACE0E19E4C69A76"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Research suggests that peace negotiations are more likely to succeed and to result in durable peace agreements when women participate in the peace process.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HDE2369772DB447BCAD5CD979BD5610E6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H8F8BC8B602464D949E6FFF1E85956B74"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the meaningful participation of women in conflict prevention and conflict resolution processes helps to promote more inclusive and democratic societies and is critical to the long-term stability of countries and regions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H576078AFC1FE4F5EAB75BDF94A59FF68"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the political participation, and leadership of women in fragile environments, particularly during democratic transitions, is critical to sustaining lasting democratic institutions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA435DA135174208BF6EDB2FF7E5DF17"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States should be a global leader in promoting the meaningful participation of women in conflict prevention, management, and resolution, and post-conflict relief and recovery efforts.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H7510426CC52C4AD8AE9E1E6B7D6653BC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It shall be the policy of the United States to promote the meaningful participation of women in all aspects of overseas conflict prevention, management, and resolution, and post-conflict relief and recovery efforts, reinforced through diplomatic efforts and programs that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC886A5DC002641BCA8CD967241676B85"><enum>(1)</enum><text>integrate the perspectives and interests of affected women into conflict-prevention activities and strategies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H42C13D31AB26482CA311DF92B79B2368"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourage partner governments to adopt plans to improve the meaningful participation of women in peace and security processes and decision-making institutions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6CFD6CDE661F475D9924817BC7933EA2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promote the physical safety, economic security, and dignity of women and girls;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEBEE4DE2732A46D29550B98480B2C020"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support the equal access of women to aid distribution mechanisms and services;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8740A7D8AED4ADEB06B13E6394DF33A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>collect and analyze gender data for the purpose of developing and enhancing early warning systems of conflict and violence;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B93323BD49D4CA984E6D11D70D0F100"><enum>(6)</enum><text>adjust policies and programs to improve outcomes in gender equality and the empowerment of women; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6AD509B0BDB14F048AA2384EDED7A366"><enum>(7)</enum><text>monitor, analyze, and evaluate the efforts related to each strategy submitted under section 5 and the impact of such efforts.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H3AA98AC59B5147A7BCF086C3F8F2A0E8"><enum>5.</enum><header>United States strategy to promote the participation of women in conflict prevention and peace
			 building</header>
 <subsection id="H382DA1CB6152427FACD886EE7CCD082E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and again four years thereafter, the President, in consultation with the heads of the relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and make publicly available a single government-wide strategy, to be known as the Women, Peace, and Security Strategy, that provides a detailed description of how the United States intends to fulfill the policy objectives in section 4. The strategy shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H64465D3370E14E1C9A3AD8648743E018"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support and be aligned with plans developed by other countries to improve the meaningful participation of women in peace and security processes, conflict prevention, peace building, transitional processes, and decision-making institutions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC01F4FA8C8F458F9816CD5A7A967AE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include specific and measurable goals, benchmarks, performance metrics, timetables, and monitoring and evaluation plans to ensure the accountability and effectiveness of all policies and initiatives carried out under the strategy.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF5A04A3B1D8C4B668C3C57F1A2E3F211"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Specific plans for departments and agencies</header><text>Each strategy under subsection (a) shall include a specific implementation plan from each of the relevant Federal departments and agencies that describes—</text>
 <paragraph id="H27666BC48EF24148A9E54CA58530FC19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the anticipated contributions of the department or agency, including technical, financial, and in-kind contributions, to implement the strategy; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63C6F6B478F14A4FB625037B807D0023"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the efforts of the department or agency to ensure that the policies and initiatives carried out pursuant to the strategy are designed to achieve maximum impact and long-term sustainability.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2157E10E321E470DBEED4B82BDCCA74E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President should promote the meaningful participation of women in conflict prevention, in coordination and consultation with international partners, including, as appropriate, multilateral organizations, stakeholders, and other relevant international organizations, particularly in situations in which the direct engagement of the United States Government is not appropriate or advisable.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H565F5B5F899847928D802B83F961BB81"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the President, in implementing each strategy submitted under subsection (a), should—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2D6E8981BC2D4DC586C5B7F90F1A9C34"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide technical assistance, training, and logistical support to female negotiators, mediators, peace builders, and stakeholders;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H38CC6811F7C943178813DD016E2FF466"><enum>(2)</enum><text>address security-related barriers to the meaningful participation of women;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3FCA81E1E2B4CF092860F1CA86E4064"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourage increased participation of women in existing programs funded by the United States Government that provide training to foreign nationals regarding law enforcement, the rule of law, or professional military education;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H45DC3E13B00A4D20988BEE4B6882E8F6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support appropriate local organizations, especially women's peace building organizations;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H97CC81BCEC5B484B80EF76A5F9EF9859"><enum>(5)</enum><text>support the training, education, and mobilization of men and boys as partners in support of the meaningful participation of women;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H765867CBE08E49E5B5E146EBADCF2758"><enum>(6)</enum><text>encourage the development of transitional justice and accountability mechanisms that are inclusive of the experiences and perspectives of women and girls;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC37AE0C94CC44CB9AED923AEB2874E3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>expand and apply gender analysis, as appropriate, to improve program design and targeting; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5AE577DE822411EA605E4F50BD35CC1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>conduct assessments that include the perspectives of women regarding new initiatives in support of peace negotiations, transitional justice and accountability, efforts to counter violent extremism, or security sector reform.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1D836C089CCF4E358E441D09B0C54FAC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Training requirements regarding the participation of women in conflict prevention and peace
			 building</header>
 <subsection id="H5729DC039F134A5CA2B209DA61C61236"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Foreign service</header><text>The Secretary of State, in conjunction with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall ensure that all appropriate personnel (including special envoys, members of mediation or negotiation teams, relevant members of the civil service or Foreign Service, and contractors) responsible for or deploying to countries or regions considered to be at risk of, undergoing, or emerging from violent conflict obtain training, as appropriate, in the following areas, each of which shall include a focus on women and ensuring meaningful participation by women:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA1A66E19FAAC4FF3BCB211301C1EAF0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Conflict prevention, mitigation, and resolution.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA59EFD824227418CA768FAF33203EB67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Protecting civilians from violence, exploitation, and trafficking in persons.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1080F9E6BA544CA98CBACDDF23ECBD8B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>International human rights law and international humanitarian law.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBCEB5614A98343BCA952A8360EA52542"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Department of defense</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that relevant personnel receive training, as appropriate, in the following areas:</text>
 <paragraph id="H12FBAD3EA5664CF59B70652F357DDD63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Training in conflict prevention, peace processes, mitigation, resolution, and security initiatives that specifically addresses the importance of meaningful participation by women.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A0D6C3AD25C41BA89BFD4FCBAF78A94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Gender considerations and meaningful participation by women, including training regarding—</text> <subparagraph id="H8E9D685F10EA41E6874A11E140A9F30D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>international human rights law and international humanitarian law, as relevant; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7114177859F40B89016154D3E3B640A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protecting civilians from violence, exploitation, and trafficking in persons.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H06F2B879118C4702BDF39E5582C120CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Effective strategies and best practices for ensuring meaningful participation by women.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1F94ADE13DDB4EC6872D70F4E89D9595"><enum>7.</enum><header>Consultation and collaboration</header>
 <subsection id="H65BE78613D8140FDA4F70132A30CBBB6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development may establish guidelines or take other steps to ensure overseas United States personnel of the Department of State or the United States Agency for International Development, as the case may be, consult with appropriate stakeholders, including local women, youth, ethnic and religious minorities, and other politically underrepresented or marginalized populations, regarding United States efforts to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFE81184F937C474B9940DB33E6B3474A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prevent, mitigate, or resolve violent conflict; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7ED0F962887F4B969CFB3A526BC23A60"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enhance the success of mediation and negotiation processes by ensuring the meaningful participation of women.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H29AF4E603FA646869B025B7EF84631E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Collaboration and coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State should work with international, regional, national, and local organizations to increase the meaningful participation of women in international peacekeeping operations, and should promote training that provides international peacekeeping personnel with the substantive knowledge and skills needed to ensure effective physical security and meaningful participation of women in conflict prevention and peace building.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H742BD5A8CF7E47D78B9617A0F9D5C085"><enum>8.</enum><header>Reports to congress</header>
 <subsection id="HCF982A8944E44A65B04E08579798A7B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the first submission of a strategy required under section 5, the Secretary of State, in conjunction with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development and the Secretary of Defense, shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on existing, enhanced, or newly established training carried out pursuant to section 6.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1095039194E3496BBC140BDD8730E65B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on women, peace, and security strategy</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the submission of each strategy required under section 5, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB54028B785E44634956AD634EB9FC91C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>summarizes and evaluates the implementation of such strategy and the impact of United States diplomatic efforts and foreign assistance programs, projects, and activities to promote the meaningful participation of women;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35243632784C4E45BD2F7C64775ECCA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describes the nature and extent of the coordination among the relevant Federal departments and agencies on the implementation of such strategy;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H454219DBB33B45B283727C9A0052C9FE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>outlines the monitoring and evaluation tools, mechanisms, and common indicators to assess progress made on the policy objectives set forth in section 4; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5732EFE75FB45299562A5E7E9D76253"><enum>(4)</enum><text>describes the existing, enhanced, or newly established training carried out pursuant to section 6.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC91A35654FC34BA2A37C0A2A35135408"><enum>9.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H9F0B59CCDF06475380E8A23751C7B3A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H176AC22F206D412793E46DFA2BDE27C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDDB7588FCFB4A1584FFE164DE195FF7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H623C344C01E84B769DD2A3AFA75EAEC3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relevant Federal departments and agencies</header><text>The term <term>relevant Federal departments and agencies</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HF9D3D996679740E7A1BAA7885CB1B71B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the United States Agency for International Development;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDF29C06A3D947939E5596D185F3EF51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of State;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02F7F1573C1C4948AC8032B893A17A50"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Department of Defense;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FB9A59F0280445D909969E8C8F87C3A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA503426825242B8A508EE657E8B8042"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other department or agency specified by the President for purposes of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD91A7DF501342C594C1973491C641BE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Stakeholders</header><text>The term <term>stakeholders</term> means nongovernmental and private sector entities engaged in or affected by conflict prevention and stabilization, peace building, protection, security, transition initiatives, humanitarian response, or related efforts.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


