<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8920B108F2CE4262B805EEE7840914A7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 771 IH: Equal Access to Abortion Coverage in Health Insurance (EACH Woman) Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 771</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170131">January 31, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O'Rourke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000523">Mr. Price of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000480">Mrs. Lowey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure affordable abortion coverage and care for every woman, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5AF58A7CE3344DA49319DF5D1524D750" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCD8C743F1E95440DAD1899412BB85C49" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Equal Access to Abortion Coverage in Health Insurance (EACH Woman) Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6687B3B32EEF471CABB2C8F631C82849"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB1690B119F044202A36A06090E9F111A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Affordable, comprehensive health insurance that includes coverage for a full range of pregnancy-related care, including abortion, is critical to the health of every woman.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAAAEE15AAF4942D58620D76AA41CBD11"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Neither a woman’s income level nor her type of insurance should prevent her from having access to a full range of pregnancy-related care, including abortion services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFC03B3376E4E483CAE5BEB407B8085C9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>No woman should have the decision to have, or not to have, an abortion made for her based on her ability or inability to afford the procedure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BB15972BE704A43A285B84B5DDAF8B4"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Since 1976, the Federal Government has withheld funds for abortion coverage in most circumstances. As a 2017 analysis by the Guttmacher Institute shows, this affects women of reproductive age in the United States who are insured through the Medicaid program, as well as women who receive insurance or care through other Federal health plans and programs. Of women aged 15–44 enrolled in Medicaid in 2015, 58 percent lived in the 35 States and the District of Columbia that do not cover abortion, except in limited circumstances. This amounts to roughly 7.5 million women of reproductive age, including 3.5 million women living below the Federal poverty level. Women of color are disproportionately likely to be insured by the Medicaid program: Nationwide, 31 percent of Black women and 27 percent of Hispanic women aged 15–44 were enrolled in Medicaid in 2015, compared with 15 percent of White women.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69D0EF2912E24736AD5FFB6AA0BB5CC5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Moreover, 25 States also prohibit abortion coverage in private insurance plans within or beyond health insurance marketplaces under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, according to an analysis of State policies by the Guttmacher Institute.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H945D91C17FBB4F8BA2DD1A4B5BDEEC86"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A report by the Center for Reproductive Rights details how restrictions on abortion coverage interfere with a woman’s personal decisionmaking, with her health and well-being, and with her constitutionally protected right to a safe and legal medical procedure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CD1E201D4484C81B1003DFE12FCA76B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Restrictions on abortion coverage have a disproportionate impact on low-income women, women of color, immigrant women, and young women, according to reports by both the Center for American Progress and the Guttmacher Institute. Also according to the reports, these women are already disadvantaged in their access to the resources, information, and services necessary to prevent an unintended pregnancy or to carry a healthy pregnancy to term.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H96142B0584DD4CE3BF92B790DDA34C54"><enum>3.</enum><header>Abortion coverage and care regardless of income or source of insurance</header>
			<subsection id="H195D9160F4B64F5A8BE2FE35D7263E8A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Ensuring abortion coverage and care through the Federal Government in its role as an insurer,
 employer, or health care provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government shall—</text> <paragraph id="HC905C9EF1E8D44A3ACAFFF9CB83EA869"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure coverage for abortion care in public health insurance programs including Medicaid, Medicare, and the Children’s Health Insurance Program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FC09C90699E4139AEA3ACF3D867E084"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in its role as an employer or health plan sponsor, ensure coverage for abortion care for participants and beneficiaries; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFC4682371F34CCE86CABF13B2591D10"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in its role as a provider of health services, ensure abortion care is made available to individuals who are eligible to receive services in its own facilities or in facilities with which it contracts to provide medical care.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA72E3C1B50EC4731A5607E5F86FE6904"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibiting restrictions on private insurance coverage of abortion care</header>
 <paragraph id="H498CD3326AAB4FC292C892D87BE155A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal restrictions</header><text>The Federal Government shall not prohibit, restrict, or otherwise inhibit insurance coverage of abortion care by State or local government or by private health plans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0FA7BBE86B54EBB99F3C37AC077F4FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State and local government restrictions</header><text>State and local governments shall not prohibit, restrict, or otherwise inhibit insurance coverage of abortion care by private health plans.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8CC4D4AD290A4C14A3B78A4CF055D5D8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HF093E80812974BFB85C152FE2E89268D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal Government, acting in its capacity as an insurer, employer, or health care provider, should serve as a model for the Nation to ensure coverage of abortion care; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB78D057DE6F54B85A6E29E2CCAD1E532"><enum>(2)</enum><text>moreover, restrictions on coverage of abortion care in the private insurance market must end.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H457FB834BF1A45C7B7C567448A320F2A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to have any effect on any Federal, State, or local law that includes more protections for abortion coverage or care than those set forth in this Act.</text>
 </section><section id="H945DFA1B661B4101A4823844F0A73D6A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any portion of this Act or the application thereof to any person or circumstances is held invalid, such invalidity shall not affect the portions or applications of this Act which can be given effect without the invalid portion or application.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


