<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA0D17F0A9F474E0C955DFA03401DE0A8" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2771 IH: Outdoor Recreation Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2771</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170602">June 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001250">Mr. Bishop of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001076">Mr. Chaffetz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000584">Mrs. Love</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000470">Mr. Tipton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001109">Ms. Cheney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000395">Mr. Rogers of Kentucky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to revise an exemption to the minimum wage and
			 maximum hours provisions of that Act for certain seasonal workers in
			 national parks and forests, and to amend title 41, United States Code, to
			 include an exemption for contracts providing services directly related to
			 recreational activities to the general public, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE40CE72E6CE3419A9ACDDADF8543D264" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6CA7169D6A2D47349E7B64238067A985" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Outdoor Recreation Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H599F1552F923437F98BD3C036A1D6923"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exemption for certain seasonal workers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 13(a)(3) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/213">29 U.S.C. 213(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC1A59D4BE933416CB6C693A5EE802B5B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>except that</quote> and all that follows through <quote>Secretary of Agriculture</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H34FB37F831F64865B85605D20B6E3F20"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting before the semicolon the following: <quote>, provided that, for the purposes of this paragraph, and notwithstanding the definition of establishment in section 779.23 of title 29 of the Code of Federal Regulations, an employee of an entity engaged in providing services or facilities directly related to outfitting and guiding or similar outdoor recreation activities, or rental of outdoor recreational equipment (including services, facilities, or equipment relating to rafting, boating, zip lines, campgrounds, horseback riding, bicycling, hiking, guest ranches, summer camps, hunting, and fishing), or a private entity engaged in providing services and facilities directly related to skiing, shall be considered an employee employed by an establishment which is a recreational establishment</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H64C342E09BE74713B61D20F0C2A2FABE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exemption for service contracts directly related to certain recreational activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6702(b) of title 41, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H0C96452246404370956D01EA8DC0D886"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA88C28FE288A4CAB9A14FAB9CEECF777"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking the period after <quote>stations</quote> and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1FC8855732C48DEB3C2338F5D967965"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding after paragraph (7) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E45F3BAF8EC40D5B327EB9B5A3042D3" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H4C67B2053A65406C90AD0119A893F6FF"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a contract with the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, the principal purpose of which is to provide services to the general public directly related to outfitting and guiding or similar outdoor recreation activities, or rental of outdoor recreational equipment (including services, facilities, or equipment relating to rafting, boating, zip lines, campgrounds, horseback riding, bicycling, hiking, guest ranches, summer camps, hunting, skiing, and fishing).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H56C425447AD440E6B87D6E36DA14DF32"><enum>4.</enum><header>Notification of change of exemptions</header>
 <subsection id="H8853358788124E8BBCD8127BC980DAD0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In connection with any contract, permit, license, or other agreement as described in section 6702(b)(8) of title 41, United States Code (as added by this Act), and entered into between the Federal Government and an employer of an employee described in section 13(a)(3) of the Fair Labor Standards Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/213">29 U.S.C. 213(a)(3)</external-xref>) as amended in this Act, the head of the agency that entered into such contract, permit, license, or other agreement shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE99E0BB4EC5A4E57A04BB81573A4812B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>notify the holder of such contract, permit, license, or other agreement, of the applicability of the exemptions in such sections, as amended by this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB215E8F2D8454A26BDEF2691D0EC0F61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>modify such contract, permit, license, or other agreement to reflect the change to such exemptions as a result of the amendments made by sections 2 and 3, including by removal of the contract clause set forth in Appendix A of part 10 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations, if such clause is included in such contract, permit, license, or other agreement, without requiring consideration or any other amendment to the terms and conditions of such contract, permit, license, or other agreement.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2107860AE2C44562827EBF690D56B99C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>No action taken under this section shall be considered a major Federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment within the meaning of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H03C88EBCA3E74560B8DADA620084C93A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Exemption from paid sick leave</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The contracts as described in section 6702(b)(8) of title 41, United States Code (as added by this Act), shall not be considered to be <quote>contracts</quote> or <quote>contract-like instruments</quote> within the meaning of the Executive order establishing paid sick leave for Federal contractors, issued September 7, 2015.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


