<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCFA1D160CECE4206A073A9FAD458C8BD" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4283 IH: Nicholas and Zachary Burt Memorial Carbon Monoxide Poisoning Prevention Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4283</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171107">November 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster of New Hampshire</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To encourage States to require the installation of residential carbon monoxide detectors in homes,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HD83C0E5D12FF486A847839B6B4C1432D" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCDB2381316494216A6B7717BD7C00637" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nicholas and Zachary Burt Memorial Carbon Monoxide Poisoning Prevention Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB2ECB39EA55F47109C9D6F1432E9A233"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="HA29E9E053B404288870AED45D20B122D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HE7232DA1D4B54718ADBADCD9BB71458E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Carbon monoxide is a colorless, odorless gas produced by burning any fuel. Exposure to un­healthy levels of carbon monoxide can lead to carbon monoxide poisoning, a serious health condition that could result in death.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1F7271929FE4F76B92212955F3DB31A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Unintentional carbon monoxide poisoning from motor vehicles and the abnormal operation of fuel-burning appliances, such as furnaces, water heaters, portable generators, and stoves, kills more than 400 people each year and sends more than 15,000 to hospital emergency rooms for treatment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H241C9857ECF64BEF982DB1A83663AEE4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Research shows that purchasing and installing carbon monoxide alarms close to the sleeping areas in residential homes and other dwelling units can help avoid fatalities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H11AA4FEFB33E4804821BDE75E618B7A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that Congress should promote the purchase and installation of carbon monoxide alarms in residential homes and dwelling units nationwide in order to promote the health and public safety of citizens throughout the United States.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HE64D21637B7B471081F8D55E61EBC658"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H26B07428F90C4CBFBB516241342C8AB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Carbon monoxide alarm</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>carbon monoxide alarm</term> means a device or system that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3712E84518CD4AD8891FF6197141AE76"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">detects carbon monoxide; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF57B5B97C76341FD95929F7A77225F94"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is intended to alarm at carbon monoxide concentrations below those that could cause a loss of ability to react to the dangers of carbon monoxide exposure.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3627240675084FFB89C1237784961979"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Consumer Product Safety Commission.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCF71A3882F63489380DEB726DA7ABBEB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compliant carbon monoxide alarm</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>compliant carbon monoxide alarm</term> means a carbon monoxide alarm that complies with the most current version of—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H283A32986FAA4B8BA10A50D6DA00E481"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the American National Standard for Single and Multiple Station Carbon Monoxide Alarms (ANSI/UL 2034); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBEE42C66B5BB4B569548B96BF9FB2915"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the American National Standard for Gas and Vapor Detectors and Sensors (ANSI/UL 2075).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H16FD307DC2B947758A74283373EA9BB3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Dwelling unit</header><text>The term <term>dwelling unit</term> means a room or suite of rooms used for human habitation, and includes a single family residence as well as each living unit of a multiple family residence (including apartment buildings) and each living unit in a mixed use building.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA72FB62E435849C59C2310FD72477B7C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Fire code enforcement officials</header><text>The term <term>fire code enforcement officials</term> means officials of the fire safety code enforcement agency of a State or local government.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF1C99370A67487DBB4D765282BD4ED6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>NFPA <enum-in-header>720</enum-in-header></header><text>The term <term>NFPA 720</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA135E2F35B8E420088533175E13146AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Standard for the Installation of Carbon Monoxide Detection and Warning Equipment issued by the National Fire Protection Association in 2015; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CF75E53714B42BCB58179FFF1DE1C75"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any amended or similar successor standard pertaining to the proper installation of carbon monoxide alarms in dwelling units.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB68BC304F27B4C4CB37F30A5D70A8DE9"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2052">15 U.S.C. 2052</external-xref>) and includes the Northern Mariana Islands and any political subdivision of a State.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H4FCAA170954F467BB292B26594F8B271"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grant program for carbon monoxide poisoning prevention</header>
 <subsection id="HBC16FA4DC4E0413D9F1614657A94F508"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations authorized under subsection (f), the Commission shall establish a grant program to provide assistance to eligible States to carry out the carbon monoxide poisoning prevention activities described in subsection (e).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0A8C43DE4AE94DD480E42DFB7129DB7E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>For purposes of this section, an eligible State is any State that—</text> <paragraph id="H4D255AA4334A4CFBA726DD02279B6C64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Commission that the State has adopted a statute or a rule, regulation, or similar measure with the force and effect of law, requiring compliant carbon monoxide alarms to be installed in dwelling units in accordance with NFPA 720; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F312862A1FA4D6CAE501A170E0369C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submits an application to the Commission at such time, in such form, and containing such additional information as the Commission may require, which application may be filed on behalf of the State by the fire code enforcement officials for such State.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H60E3295510774D259938327C34BDCFCE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant amount</header><text>The Commission shall determine the amount of the grants awarded under this section.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H7A544B42E62943AD9F5CF7DCAA599149"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection of grant recipients</header><text>In selecting eligible States for the award of grants under this section, the Commission shall give favorable consideration to an eligible State that—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HB805E819AD334AE9810568D0FCD12C97"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requires the installation of compliant carbon monoxide alarms in new or existing educational facilities, childcare facilities, health care facilities, adult dependent care facilities, government buildings, restaurants, theaters, lodging establishments, or dwelling units—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H993C8ED99CE540FA8CE3A9668779ABEC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>within which a fuel-burning appliance is installed, including a furnace, boiler, water heater, fireplace, or any other apparatus, appliance, or device that burns fuel; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H524B861BA2604C73AACEFC581B01563F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which has an attached garage; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD895DAEC83AB469FADDE5353AB60E348"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has developed a strategy to protect vulnerable populations such as children, the elderly, or low-income households.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H079BD688A9104A93BA7FDCA47989A29F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of grant funds</header>
 <paragraph id="HC358309EC193498D892085176714CD7D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible State receiving a grant under this section may use such grant—</text> <subparagraph id="H4CB2DF471EC144E9A1C5E6E2D6A092BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to purchase and install compliant carbon monoxide alarms in the dwelling units of low-income families or elderly persons, facilities that commonly serve children or the elderly, including childcare facilities, public schools, and senior centers, or student dwelling units owned by public universities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC46C19B58D64F0D987C14DF4386E10E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to train State or local fire code enforcement officials in the proper enforcement of State or local laws concerning compliant carbon monoxide alarms and the installation of such alarms in accordance with NFPA 720;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5E6CB2D01EF4BB2900C9CA7AABA59EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for the development and dissemination of training materials, instructors, and any other costs related to the training sessions authorized by this subsection; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H878D73182737412BA39C9185D6CF4D87"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to educate the public about the risk associated with carbon monoxide as a poison and the importance of proper carbon monoxide alarm use.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE39083BCD19B4797913AFEF882625CA0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header>
 <subparagraph id="HAF27D9F1C20C4FFD93AAAC98DA7E05A1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>Not more than 10 percent of any grant amount received under this section may be used to cover administrative costs not directly related to training described in paragraph (1)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H751BBEB0519A49AAACEDBDAF6885A70D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public outreach</header><text>Not more than 25 percent of any grant amount received under this section may be used to cover costs of activities described in paragraph (1)(D).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3492DBD2EE97401B875CFF050589B6FB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="H18B16EC1FF8A4380B5C73A5EF2ACA288"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), there is authorized to be appropriated to the Commission, for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2022, $2,000,000, which shall remain available until expended to carry out this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96BF8AC4693A4619B93FD233947AA029"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on administrative expenses</header><text>Not more than 10 percent of the amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to carry out this section may be used for administrative expenses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB6D63363D271460DA191867E0AFE46D4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Retention of amounts</header><text>Any amounts appropriated pursuant to this subsection that remain unexpended and unobligated on September 30, 2022, shall be retained by the Commission and credited to the appropriations account that funds the enforcement of the Consumer Product Safety Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2051">15 U.S.C. 2051</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H73A302F5CAAF439AB637448A3306FE99"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Offset</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Government Publishing Office for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022 the amount that is $2,000,000 less than the amount appropriated for such Office for fiscal year 2017.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE891473AFD11413CB373461AAE37039F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the last day of each fiscal year for which grants are awarded under this section, the Commission shall submit to Congress a report that evaluates the implementation of the grant program required by this section.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


