<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H487771C83E8E49939639CB18AD91D1C5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2244 IH: Patient Experience in Research Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2244</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170428">April 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out a pilot project under which no more than 3 sponsors agree to evaluate the psychological and social distress experienced by patients participating in a clinical trial, conducted by the respective sponsor, of a drug or biological product that is intended to treat a serious or life-threatening disease or condition, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB59BD502584F4A08A8A4402A41337758" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCB10191A6E4445DD9E0F05804ECDAAC8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Patient Experience in Research Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HACEC0C8BBCA04F10A9A3C199FD7E344B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot project for evaluation of psychological and social distress experienced by patients in certain clinical trials</header> <subsection id="HCC60450219D240F2AE58C874D4A87AAB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out a pilot project under which—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2139B49C527A4F189FFE1AAE44228D3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>no more than 3 sponsors each agree to evaluate—</text> <subparagraph id="H8954A6CFFC654B2B9A9F0F768BBB93F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the psychological and social distress experienced by patients participating in a qualified clinical trial, conducted by the respective sponsor, of a drug or biological product that is intended to treat a serious or life-threatening disease or condition; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF0AB7315EE4B4F45818C1D8095E9D23A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the effects of providing psychological and social support to any such patients showing signs of distress on the primary outcome measures in the clinical trial; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H839FA0B0841A41B48E1FE5C5B86FCF73"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary waives the fee that would otherwise apply under section 736(a)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379h">21 U.S.C. 379h(a)(1)</external-xref>) to the submission by the respective sponsor of one human drug application for such drug or biological product that includes the data resulting from such evaluation.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H81B1855C70E34260952478B457B17E09"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall select the sponsors referred to in subsection (a) on a competitive basis not later than the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H230691E003534AE1B903226E5D96D59F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Meeting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall grant at least one meeting to each sponsor selected under subsection (b) for the specific purpose of discussing the activities to be carried out by the sponsor pursuant to this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HED3193C424A74E3BAEA60F776CCC3543"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H57DA96A4823F4ACABA756C766E1CFE1D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>biological product</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7481DED6BE8D41B9A8A581640CFB61A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>drug</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBCFB277B9ADB43B0AE1899C9B86B60A9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>human drug application</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 735 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379g">21 U.S.C. 379g</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC18AF2757B034203AAD43EA51CB9A061"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>qualified clinical trial</term> means a clinical trial in which all participating patients will be enrolled not later than the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2265D3A5DBA4AFE99CBB6DB75246624"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3D19CDAA587248959FCA64C49B8FD962"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>sponsor</term> means the sponsor of a drug or biological product. </text> </paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

