<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H310EDD90C1F6491FAEE5B82DFADC79B8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 512 EH: Working to Integrate Networks Guaranteeing Member Access Now Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 512</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to permit veterans to grant access to their records in the databases of the Veterans Benefits Administration to certain designated congressional employees, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HD489DAEFAA5347DFB6D1DEDD9308E3C2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H00999E5262B448D6B328A8F763706716" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Working to Integrate Networks Guaranteeing Member Access Now Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>WINGMAN Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD857EEFDDEE64479BEF95D2347A032F0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Provision of access to case-tracking information</header> <subsection id="H0FA65659064841E1A9D28AB0B1D98F08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/59">Chapter 59</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB95ED32CF0474C1FB96BA988997C3811" style="USC"> 
<section id="HB7028B53841940389A1FF031EE5C04F6"><enum>5906.</enum><header>Access of certain congressional employees to veteran records</header> 
<subsection id="HBF156CB131294A54B05832F01407FE6F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H031717B315D44C0B9B1D2BD7D6F920F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall provide to each veteran who submits a claim for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary an opportunity to permit a covered congressional employee employed in the office of the Member of Congress representing the district where the veteran resides to have access to all of the records of the veteran in the databases of the Veterans Benefits Administration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H80106CF401A14C028A7013AE762CC84A" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, upon receipt of the permission from the veteran under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall provide read-only access to such records to such a covered congressional employee in a manner that does not allow such employee to modify the data contained in such records or in any part of a database of the Veterans Benefits Administration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3534AB7EC0F04B2A9D1DFBE365530B39" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A Member of Congress may designate not more than two employees of the Member as covered congressional employees.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEAA94DCFFE1944FA91A0F4B577D9664D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not impose any requirement other than the requirements specified under subsection (e)(1) before treating an employee as a covered congressional employee for purposes of this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAF0680BDFA86427D829CB07CFB4B070B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Nonrecognition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered congressional employee may not be recognized as an agent or attorney under this chapter.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3096461FD3DF4B6EA2CB142C6FD3DC15"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the amounts made available to carry out this section may be used to design, develop, or administer any training for purposes of providing training to covered congressional employees.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBF3A9F85893442CFA24B5EA81C108C4D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H46FFE39B222C4875AF3D310EDD59100F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>covered congressional employee</term> means a permanent, full-time employee of a Member of Congress—</text> 
<subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H181BF2B0B3904CA4A197AF3A8EC2A55C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whose responsibilities include assisting the constituents of the Member with issues regarding departments or agencies of the Federal Government;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF47A27AD85CD4E3289FC589DF296C561"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who satisfies the criteria required by the Secretary for recognition as an agent or attorney under this chapter; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56851EB8E2CC43BF89D3751C93348640"><enum>(C)</enum><text>who is designated by the Member of Congress as a covered congressional employee for purposes of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H48ABB7A2214B4669B146F64736FC6EBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>database of the Veterans Benefits Administration</term> means any database of the Veterans Benefits Administration in which the records of veterans relating to claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary are retained, including information regarding medical records, compensation and pension exams records, rating decisions, statements of the case, supplementary statements of the case, notices of disagreement, Form–9, and any successor form.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47AE36289E2E4C07AF943776D5EA59DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>Member of Congress</term> means a Representative, a Senator, a Delegate to Congress, or the Resident Commissioner of Puerto Rico.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HA3F95F6AB4884503B2126C613F2FF1BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H372D63E3B066438183DCEC2EF26079D4" style="OLC"> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5906. Access of certain congressional employees to veteran records.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA7E53282CFC043E2B7076D2BAF2BE123"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section or the amendments made by this section. This section and such amendments may only be carried out using amounts otherwise authorized to be appropriated, of which, during the period of fiscal years 2018 through 2021, not more than $10,000,000 may be obligated or expended for such purpose.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20170213" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives February 13, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

