<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8C0515DD2DF24F6B82F461BCA15F78EB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3718 IH: International Communications Privacy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3718</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170908">September 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001093">Mr. Collins of Georgia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to safeguard data stored abroad, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HCE65BCF2A7C1457BAF297C765FDCD46C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9D992A4562934CFFBC12E75330B0A267" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>International Communications Privacy Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9850D211987A4F76BDF09A7B3B8E6B4A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional findings and declaration of purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC7896A01C0684001B6CFC1EAC7A8D458"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Electronic Communications Privacy Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/99/508">Public Law 99–508</external-xref>; 100 Stat. 1848) (referred to in this section as <quote>ECPA</quote>) was intended to protect the privacy of electronic communications and related records stored with providers of electronic communications services and remote computing services, while providing law enforcement agencies with the appropriate legal tools to compel production of information from such providers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H733881C6BB784FE591A0F0CBDE39E585"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ECPA authorized governmental entities to obtain certain categories of communications data from providers using established, pre-existing forms of process, including search warrants and subpoenas. It also created a new form of court order, in section 2703(d) of title 18, United States Code, that governmental entities could use to obtain additional types of communications data.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8896CE60979F4F4BACFB46266EAA0E42"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Congress recognizes that there are often many interests that must be recognized when law enforcement agencies seek information from providers, such as—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC436161D00854A6DBE9787E770995A9A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the legitimate needs of law enforcement agencies in the United States to obtain, through lawful process, electronic communications relevant to criminal investigations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FE5CAF54F924D05985FE548407AE256"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the privacy interests of all customers of the services offered by electronic communication service providers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26C1F9B6346C427F96077EC1F65B7CFC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the legitimate interests of governments to protect the human rights, civil liberties and privacy of their nationals and residents.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H67B9F0A5FA4C464C83E8B63ADF5821FD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Therefore, where the Government seeks to obtain the contents of electronic communications of a national of a qualifying foreign government who is located outside of the United States, this Act authorizes the use of search warrants to compel production of that information only if the foreign government receives prior notice of the request and does not object or a judge determines that the interests of the United States in obtaining the information outweigh the interests of the qualifying foreign government in preventing the disclosure.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HA57D69C26DEE41889B4A61AB831D03F1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Extension and clarification of warrant requirement</header>
 <subsection id="H2644595AD8CC41DEA3676DFDB09AD4F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/121">Chapter 121</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6E0E42FC69284016B0CFF87964FADBCF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 2702(a), by amending paragraph (3) to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4C0618A51674A918DE0B285390E7B5B" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HC28BE09886A749708F3F7B85583D2DC4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a provider of remote computing service or electronic communication service to the public shall not knowingly divulge to any governmental entity the contents of any communication described in section 2703(a), or any record or other information pertaining to a subscriber or customer of such service.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C8412AE547A4212A801EACE025C0328"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 2703—</text> <subparagraph id="HF92726C94B0144C9A65C20FC441C5FEA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsections (a) and (b) and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2AD70FEEDA4488688AA7FDCA40C5944" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H8C1FBBFEE562407D9093F796BD218F83"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Required disclosure</header><text>A governmental entity may require the disclosure by a provider of electronic communication service or remote computing service of the contents of a wire or electronic communication that is stored, held, or maintained by the provider, regardless of where such contents may be in electronic storage or otherwise stored, held, or maintained, only pursuant to a warrant issued using the procedures described in the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure (or, in the case of a State court, issued using State warrant procedures) by a court of competent jurisdiction.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF00A90E1C9604F8EA55F5728C95CF04C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) through (g) as subsections (b) through (f), respectively;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56A507B10F54412B8F02A0C215116E46"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (c), as so redesignated, in the first sentence—</text>
 <clause id="H3642F15060634A3A8FBBE19A6DD7085C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(b) or</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="HB78EDC4447424597A3A4D90E014FAC22"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the contents of a wire or electronic communication, or</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE070CA76670C44B9A1E8489602A08946"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>sought, are</quote> and inserting <quote>sought are</quote>; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8BD125DE398484494EA89B62AC5A64A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6FB7686D2F954A11B8B6FE614B49B652" style="OLC">
							<subsection id="HBA214EE4C8134B8D948F89DE1DD4E2D9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Application for warrant seeking contents of wire or electronic communication</header>
 <paragraph id="H4ADCABC192C0489A82EC11104C9A3A32"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An application for a warrant under this section seeking the contents of a wire or electronic communication of a subscriber or customer of an electronic communication service provider or remote computing service provider that is stored, held, or maintained by such provider shall state the nationality and location of the subscriber or customer whose communications are being sought, unless the nationality and location cannot reasonably be determined.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5D17EC0F5DE74504AA8D1D2815C848F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nationality and location not reasonably determined</header><text>If the nationality and location of the subscriber or customer cannot reasonably be determined, the application shall include a full and complete statement of the investigative steps taken to ascertain the nationality and location of the subscriber or customer.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="HC003ED362CFD4C4B9DA3311835461AF6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3E72224076184B7CA17EC745E5E10EE1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) shall take effect 14 days after the date on which the Attorney General first publishes a list of not less than 1 qualifying foreign country under section 2703A(e)(3).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B02D5EE556C47CAA9D56019971DD831"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) shall not apply during any period of time in which no country is determined by the Attorney General to be a qualifying foreign country.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2FAECDD93BC48A9B8130D863ECDB0C0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Jurisdiction over offense</header><text>A court may issue a warrant under this section for the contents of a wire or electronic communication only if the warrant application was made—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7B28D1877D3C4BECB5539B2F62F35715"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by a governmental entity in connection with an investigation of a criminal offense for which that entity has jurisdiction; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H519BD692BE0949B29DD9862CD0D2913C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on behalf of a foreign government investigating a criminal offense for which that foreign government has jurisdiction.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5A11FD29E27546A88470C0AD7AC0827F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of construction related to legal process</header><text>Nothing in this section, section 2702, or section 2703A shall be construed to limit the authority of a governmental entity to use an administrative subpoena authorized under a Federal or State law or to use a Federal or State grand jury, trial, or civil discovery subpoena to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDAF7410247D44BBCB807B234F8616EBA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>require an originator, addressee, or intended recipient of an electronic communication to disclose the contents of the electronic communication to the governmental entity; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDCE0610A2C9F4E7389E49127F261654E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require an entity that provides electronic communication services to the officers, directors, employees, or agents of the entity (for the purpose of carrying out their duties) to disclose the contents of an electronic communication to or from an officer, director, employee, or agent of the entity to a governmental entity, if the electronic communication is held, stored, or maintained on an electronic communications system owned or operated by the entity.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H90D2806E34D84678920BB3D67371D2F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after section 2703 the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7DCD569C586148D18DA9A08274DE6673" style="USC"> <section id="H2AF563BE2378484BB0BBF9492E7ED99B"><enum>2703A.</enum><header>Special rule for communications of non-United States subscriber or customer in qualifying foreign country</header> <subsection id="H109DB328A5864F84ADB6A2898288B829"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="H6BD0F2AAA38E462987C8B42EFCFB63FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice and opportunity to object</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), if a subscriber or customer whose communications are being sought is physically located outside the United States, is not a United States person, and is a national of or located in a qualifying foreign country, the court may issue a warrant under section 2703 for the contents of such communications only if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H45DAD7DC91E24E268340A00935C22312"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the qualifying foreign country has been provided notice of the warrant application; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H089246D11FC44E9393A876243F4C9863"><enum>(B)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1F46C6A3E62F46B39B7B36F5BD7E96FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Central Authority of the qualifying foreign country has provided written certification that the disclosure may be had;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1692FF8A60B84C2CB8CB2B6FBEB25134" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>14 days have passed since the date on which the notice was provided under subparagraph (A) and the Central Authority of the qualifying foreign country has not initiated a challenge under subsection (c)(1); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5CDE72DC70B84B8F92D797E215386103" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Central Authority of the qualifying foreign country has initiated a challenge under subsection (c)(1) and the court has denied the challenge.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H635F518FAF594F4DA775E6BAB66086F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nationality and location not reasonably determined</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply if—</text> <subparagraph id="HE68A1CB062FA4CC58CF051FEF31437D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the nationality and location of the subscriber or customer whose communications are being sought cannot reasonably be determined; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15134C36AF02448181747D7D8F03025C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the requirements of section 2703(g)(2) have been met.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF43C0CA38A914E19AB107529915D9CFA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of notice</header><text>The notice required under subsection (a)(1)(A) shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6F318A46972148F094C1C2AEE477B3D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the name, nationality, and location of the subscriber or customer whose communications are being sought;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H383FC76E6E9A432196D145AF65BFBA3E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the name, nationality, and location of the service provider; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F4FD589975843C18536B00DA2BDAC66"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of the events or offenses under investigation and how the communications sought are relevant and material to the investigation.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C9C2510807D4EC9BBF12CBF6F5D8449"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Challenge to warrant seeking contents of wire or electronic communication</header>
 <paragraph id="H21C6751E3AB94B1CA82F9125FB5B822F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon a motion made promptly by a service provider or by the Central Authority of a qualifying foreign country, a court receiving a warrant application under section 2703 or issuing a warrant under section 2703 for the contents of a wire or electronic communication of a subscriber or customer who is physically located outside the United States and who is not a United States person shall deny, modify, or quash the warrant, as appropriate, if the court finds that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA257A7623E3045AB83D8F5738FDB7C64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the subscriber or customer is a national of or located in a qualifying foreign country and the qualifying foreign country was not provided notice of the warrant application in accordance with subsection (a)(1)(A), unless the court issued an order under subsection (d)(2)(A) waiving the requirements of subsection (a)(1); or</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A0BCB9F1B3C40D4BF9A29BF9305D90F"><enum>(B)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE86369EF2D6C4D57B0054D2160F1DC18"><enum>(i)</enum><text>disclosure would cause the service provider to violate the laws of a foreign country; and</text> </clause><clause id="HA866D846E9D64F9B9BD8E7E01390345A" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>based on the totality of the circumstances, the warrant should not be issued or enforced because the interests of the foreign country in preventing the disclosure and the penalties the service provider or any employees of the service provider would likely suffer as a result of violating the laws of the foreign country outweigh the investigative interests of the governmental entity seeking to compel the disclosure.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H534B50AB00CD4BABB5713C0DFE698FBE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comity analysis</header><text>For purposes of making a determination under paragraph (1)(B)(ii), the court shall take into account, as appropriate—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8421A22FC9494BD18754FB4AC2185F7B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the laws of the foreign country;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C0D146F861C45768FF53A6F76B14558"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the investigative interests of the governmental entity seeking to compel the disclosure;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6C465BECAF54835AC4DE42033573936"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the interests of the foreign government in preventing the disclosure;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC331F1B627A4836AC022688426FD649"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the reasons, if any, for the objection of the foreign government;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H645154A9E34A46D8B39DC244AAA3824C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the penalties the provider or any employees of the provider would likely suffer as a result of violating the laws of the foreign country;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC5DD6CDE5124E129E5D184172E4D2FC"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the location and nationality of the subscriber or customer whose communications are being sought;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H305CD6F580FF4BC78455472286CAB12A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the location and nationality of the victims;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF183CE35CB64438D99E4E82A825D7C1A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the location of the offense;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H263BCD0A93AB49918C55C3E3669DA2FD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the seriousness of the offense;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D9CBC41859D4411B7C58E8D83F70551"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the importance of the sought-after data to the investigation; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF9EE00B00C14A5E9FADFEF306645496"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the possibility of timely accessing the data through other means.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H12E7B86994BB49D3AC77662562F32C98"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disclosure obligations during pendency of challenge</header><text>A service provider shall not be obligated to produce the contents of the communications sought during the pendency of a challenge brought under this subsection.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H70625E1B224C4EB1A81E7C8F98236320"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exceptions to 14-Day notice period</header>
								<paragraph id="H5E405E560AAE4930B2FD654AB0C96B7E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Expedited treatment</header>
 <subparagraph id="H8311CE90878F4E2AA6DFA5331EB32C37"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A court may issue an order shortening the time period described in subsection (a)(1)(A) to a time period not less than 7 days, if the court finds, based on specific and articulable facts, that such expedited treatment is necessary to avoid one or more of the adverse results identified in section 2705(a)(2).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B9317D7CFD24CAE904392A9D171D401"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>An order issued under subparagraph (A) shall be served upon a representative of the Central Authority of the qualifying foreign country in a timely manner.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H44CD741C6D6549D58DDD5F922AD063D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delay of notice in exceptional circumstances</header>
									<subparagraph id="H6096232BD5B74B6A9528EAC2B4C92C7F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Delay of notice</header>
 <clause id="H659F3A20E47B4BA7958B92693B6D3DBF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A court receiving an application for a warrant under section 2703 for the contents of a wire or electronic communication of a subscriber or customer who is physically located outside the United States, who is not a United States person, and who is a national of or located in a qualifying foreign country may issue an order waiving the requirements of subsection (a)(1) for 90 days, if the court finds, based on specific and articulable facts, that providing notice of the warrant application to the qualifying foreign country would—</text>
 <subclause id="HE4A9864715E04C92B11203F8A5F88BA0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>jeopardize national security; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="HE24A661C58BD44ECBD3BD1273A7A4508"><enum>(II)</enum><text>result in one or more of the adverse results identified in section 2705(a)(2) because—</text>
 <item id="H2A682241767048C88F98DFB02AEE25BE"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the potential criminal activity under investigation is sponsored or directed by the qualifying foreign country; or</text>
 </item><item id="H6731A1D19E2F4D76AA94CE1C03E94C72"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>there is reason to believe that, notwithstanding the certification required under subsection (e)(1)(A)(ii), the qualifying foreign country would notify the subject of the investigation of the existence of the investigation, the existence of the warrant application, or both.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H5644CCF2F6CC43B9811DBD5C895A8986"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Issuance of warrant</header><text>Upon a finding described in clause (i), and following issuance of an order under clause (i), the court may issue the warrant forthwith.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A6D8D84CFA9435A9FB21768DA064C14"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extension of order delaying notice</header><text>An order waiving the requirements of subsection (a)(1) may be extended in 90-day increments until the investigation is completed. Any extension of an order under this subparagraph shall be made only upon a finding by the court, based on specific and articulable facts, that providing notice to the qualifying foreign country would lead to one or more of the adverse results identified in subparagraph (A)(i)(II).</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FD94A403D8B4C0DA4F20E6BA5CE74B1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect of expiration or nonrenewal</header>
 <clause id="H2CB73C3C1820485BA094D971250C357A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon expiration or nonrenewal of an order issued under subparagraph (A) the court shall suspend the warrant.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA3CD317DF9884FDE8DD063984BE66AAC"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Duration of suspension</header><text>The suspension of a warrant under clause (i) shall remain in effect until—</text> <subclause id="H0F048801F7BE4D5D9F8360B88FAF30D0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the qualifying foreign country is provided notice of the warrant application; and</text>
											</subclause><subclause id="H87D318D578774ACBBB9AC0875FF7F450"><enum>(II)</enum>
 <item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H26094BC11F6B4189AF23E4911BD2507E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the Central Authority of the qualifying foreign country provides written certification that the disclosure may be had;</text>
 </item><item id="H76D09571674E4C649F91958E3E1BD40E" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date on which the notice described in clause (i) was provided to the qualifying foreign country, if during the 14-day period the Central Authority of the qualifying foreign country does not initiate a challenge under subsection (c)(1); or</text>
 </item><item id="H4F9499DE9BE34154B877820D6723CFE9" indent="up1"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the Central Authority of the qualifying foreign country initiates a challenge under subsection (c)(1) and the court rules on the challenge.</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H730F559603B24256BC46A62F24648308"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Immediate lift of suspension</header><text>For purposes of clause (ii)(II)(cc), if the court denies the challenge, the court shall immediately lift the suspension.</text>
										</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF78FB6B31EB4B6CB8C07809884482F9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Qualifying foreign country</header>
 <paragraph id="HE25CEA02CC1D456AAB59A4B3FE1601D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>qualifying foreign country</term> means a foreign country that—</text> <subparagraph id="HB51CF16C03914E74B66075A9BF7D37A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has certified to the Attorney General that—</text>
 <clause id="H02DAC71760C8459096CE8E5D5E31E3A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>it will provide to the United States Government substantive and procedural opportunities similar to those under this section when the foreign country is seeking information about United States persons from electronic communications service providers or remote computing service providers subject to its jurisdiction; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H53729EDBFDFB40DE8C70E8CDA52AD097"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the event it is provided notice of an application for a warrant under subsection (a)(1)(A), upon request from the United States Government it will not notify the subject of the investigation of the existence of the investigation, the existence of the warrant application, or both; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A1AF84A20864434943002D6D17E12C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State, has determined—</text> <clause id="H5C01A762C45E4C5DB2F7E3DE6A901E0A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>affords robust substantive and procedural protections for privacy and civil liberties;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6911B94A77C34B75AAC2055A4273ACA9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>adheres to applicable international human rights obligations and commitments;</text> </clause><clause id="H371AF90AD0DE4557A463BD1CCB7F7F97"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provides to the United States Government substantive and procedural opportunities similar to those under this section when the foreign country is seeking information about United States persons from electronic communication service providers or remote computing service providers subject to its jurisdiction; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4E720B2DDCD64ABFAFFE1AE16D666E64"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>will not unnecessarily impede legitimate criminal investigations or otherwise undermine the foreign relations of the United States as a result of receiving notice of warrant applications and the opportunity to initiate a challenge to such applications.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7766405B42B4440A07E736B6B04C687"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination required</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the Attorney General receives the certifications described in paragraph (1)(A) from a foreign country, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall determine whether the country satisfies the requirements described in paragraph (1)(B). If the Attorney General determines a country satisfies the requirements described in paragraph (1)(B), the Attorney General shall add the country to the list of qualifying foreign countries under paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C0052AF5B0245A383EF9BE3770F7AC1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>List of qualifying foreign countries</header><text>The Attorney General shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H067C6BF781D24B73B4276666EEC3FCB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publish and make publicly available a list of the countries that satisfy the requirements described in paragraph (1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC946D9EEC0C047409596C56FCB25EDB2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>add to the list published under subparagraph (A) any country that comes into compliance with the requirements described in paragraph (1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB12A1E3A5E0C4B8B9755B100D11A5CF9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>remove from the list published under subparagraph (A) any country that ceases to comply with the requirements described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7B4FD24BDB154878A2DEE07073AD5C94"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction related to national security and intelligence operations</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect, impact, or in any way impede terrorism investigations, military operations, or operations or activities under the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref> et seq.).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8255B93D25E34AFCB9F59E242855D4E9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 2704(a)(1), by striking <quote>section 2703(b)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 2703</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4878DC0183C741F2A93F77D6CF71E19E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 2711—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEED03ABDA4AE4EAB9673E2C507C4361E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(B) by striking <quote>warrants; and</quote> and inserting <quote>warrants;</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BAF7268A86B455EA1D70B442894ACB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4) by striking <quote>thereof.</quote> and inserting <quote>thereof;</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE480E8537F6048E7888C7EE1920D0039"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA8B85550E6C64C59BA41B6141B50767B" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HE089B8955E2E4FDCB74FC38D454E09B6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>United States person</term> means a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence (as defined in section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref>));</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H053E7DE6EA474E968B1FBDB8FE560E7F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>Central Authority</term> means the agency, department, office, or authority of a country responsible for administering law enforcement requests between that country and another country; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5281BFB35AF8476BADE4374A2348847B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>national of a foreign country</term> means a citizen, a lawful resident, or an entity organized under the laws of a foreign jurisdiction.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB65831ACCECC456EADF949439ABEE597"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text>Title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HA397CBC6DEC24EAE8B17FED5A7E439EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 2258A(h)(1), by striking <quote>section 2703(f)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 2703(e)</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H764306FF7281491088D15FD74342FE71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 2705—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H8625B9F6690148BB840CC8989FF761EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1), by striking <quote>section 2703(b)</quote> each place the term appears and inserting <quote>section 2703</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9643E32C7D7342918506A862FDEC1F58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>section 2703(b)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 2703</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2F2BE23D26354860A2FFBC2027E3F1FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 2707—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4448C3725DCC4BD9BD6C6FF8ECFE1CFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>section 2703(e)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 2703(d)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H13CBF6CF2E4D4E0082596D4826072339"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(1), by striking <quote>section 2703(f)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 2703(e)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFA8E8828547A437BB985BC998E9EB250"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 3486(a)(1)(C)(i), by striking <quote>section 2703(c)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 2703(b)(2)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H10240D7891B64F4C9F4740004EBF4A6F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall be construed to expand the investigative authority of any governmental entity.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7B6588DD81C44B8688B2D8DDA1580AD4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/121">chapter 121</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/2703">section 2703</external-xref> the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H4FD575134C5044D899F40CE4813A28F2" style="USC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry idref="H2AF563BE2378484BB0BBF9492E7ED99B" level="section">2703A. Special rule for communications of non-United States subscriber or customer in qualifying
			 foreign country.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H4CC79D6D26314414BCDA9CC23E1E88F6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Mutual legal assistance treaty reforms</header>
			<subsection id="H1A03FE1DC3B74D8B93C3CC8E19DDB528"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mutual legal assistance treaty transparency and efficiency</header>
 <paragraph id="HDD8CA481CE8F47659B829C8323905297"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall establish—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2732EF80B0224FCD8965F66B62F8101A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a form for use by a foreign government filing a mutual legal assistance treaty request (referred to in this section as an <quote>MLAT request</quote>), which shall—</text>
 <clause id="H442674C230DD4F03BA9F17C857AABE23"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be made available on the website of the Department of Justice; and</text> </clause><clause id="H32D03A088D9B424B80E10A9F5D5B2950"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>require sufficient information and be susceptible for use by a foreign government to provide all the information necessary for the MLAT request;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B163E6C34814FED9DABB87A1178832E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an online docketing system for all MLAT requests, which shall allow a foreign government to track the status of an MLAT request filed by the foreign government; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D0E2C7C565D4B61A236A13A9074B5E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a process through which certified approval may be sought for disclosure pursuant to warrants issued under section 2703(a).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1BC803D91D049708FA7DB379C33D2D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual publication</header><text>Beginning not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and each year thereafter, the Attorney General shall publish on the website of the Department of Justice statistics on—</text>
					<subparagraph id="H36BCCD8693B44764A554203761968A1D"><enum>(A)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAEB6A3F34B8D436991EE86E59EEA2428"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of MLAT requests made by the Department of Justice to foreign governments for the purpose of obtaining the contents of an electronic communication or other information or records from a provider of electronic communications or remote computing services; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5274B36FB8CF4AD3B51C62F8F9896631" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average length of time taken by foreign governments to process the MLAT requests described in clause (i);</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EDDF26C7EB24C3B87A39BCDED329341"><enum>(B)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H48CD53259E884DE59639247C9EF11B39"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of MLAT requests made to the Department of Justice by foreign governments for the purpose of obtaining the contents of an electronic communication or other information or records from a provider of electronic communications or remote computing services; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H400E916FFC2D4B899AAD7BF120591095" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average length of time taken by foreign governments to process the MLAT requests described in clause (i); and</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87268D708C924927ABC4A2DE93886627"><enum>(C)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE696B6F9FE844AD1A9181A66CD7892CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of MLAT requests made to the Department of Justice by foreign governments for the purpose of obtaining the contents of an electronic communication or other information or records from a provider of electronic communications or remote computing services; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H07336DF5C21D4FA89F91DC635EE7EAEF" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average length of time taken by the Department of Justice to process the MLAT requests described in clause (i).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H92C260FD8A7744A5B08EBD334F256FD7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice to department of state</header><text>The Attorney General shall notify the Secretary of State not later than 7 days after the date on which disclosure of electronic communications content to a foreign government is made pursuant to an MLAT request.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H210B08A89AF14368AE1AF29682F7CBDF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preservation of records</header><text>The Attorney General may issue a request pursuant to section 2703(e) of title 18, United States Code, as so redesignated by section 3, upon receipt of an MLAT request that appears to be facially valid.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6D389F444F4C4DCD88A4E0A850089C91"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification to provider of MLAT request</header><text>When the Attorney General makes use of the process provided in section 2703 of title 18, United States Code, to obtain information from an electronic communications provider or a remote computing provider based on an MLAT request, the Attorney General shall notify that provider in writing that the request has been made pursuant to a mutual legal assistance treaty.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HA7A99794CC6441ACA960DF440B0FAA9C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HAB4C1F6AE96E49BE9A7087B10EDC78C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>data localization requirements imposed by foreign governments on data providers are—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6BAA6D78FBC644BAA3E877365473E2E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>incompatible with the borderless nature of the Internet;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF10463890ED84FC8B5434A5F83E406E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an impediment to online innovation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE458201531884D988BDED49203DDA5D5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>unnecessary to meet the needs of law enforcement; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H540FE8B0D1D5449093A0A1DA4315C583"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Department of Justice, the Department of State, and the United States Trade Representatives should pursue open data flow policies with foreign nations.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


