<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3AB264F6BDB24996A18E97BF51775FBA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 614</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170123">January 23, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000462">Mr. Tiberi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require each owner of a dwelling unit assisted under the section 8 rental assistance voucher program to remain current with respect to local property and school taxes and to authorize a public housing agency to use such rental assistance amounts to pay such tax debt of such an owner, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1F7AE2DC70F24AA79AA05ABF93FFC6BF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H18389C53439F4F83B292C702E20AF474" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Our Schools from Tax Delinquents Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0F8159BBF1A34EA8AA983C2D39469B0E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Obligation for owners of assisted units to remain current on local property and school taxes</header> <subsection id="H35E4FF4FAACD48DFA11847E137F727AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (o) of section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4448FE3AE8C4F319EAB652B4CD1124B" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H804B3D73F1894A53ABB1EDB28F762D04"><enum>(21)</enum><header>Obligation for owners To remain current on local property and school taxes</header> 
<subparagraph id="H2FB8C744EFBD486289D15B0A37C6EA68"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Obligation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each housing assistance payments contract entered into by a public housing agency and the owner of a dwelling unit shall provide that the owner of the dwelling unit assisted under the contract shall pay, on a timely basis, all covered taxes validly assessed against the property in which such dwelling unit is located.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2BC109194DED415BB9154E4919FCDAA9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority to provide for use of assistance amounts to pay delinquent taxes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A housing assistance payments contract entered into by a public housing agency and the owner of a dwelling unit may provide that, upon notification by a taxing authority that the owner of a dwelling unit assisted under this subsection is delinquent with respect to payment of any covered taxes assessed by such taxing authority against the property in which such dwelling unit is located and identification of the amount of such delinquency—</text> 
<clause id="H78590702953A4F83A943055AA0FF3493"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the public housing agency shall abate all of the assistance amounts under this subsection with respect to such property until the transfer of amounts pursuant to subparagraph (B) is completed; and</text></clause> <clause id="H054DF728D96A4FB09C09DB3CCAB8B6E9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the agency shall transfer to such taxing authority, on a monthly basis, an amount equal to the monthly assistance amounts under this subsection with respect to such dwelling unit (or such lesser amount as may be agreed to by the agency and such authority) until the delinquency identified in such notification is eliminated (or for such shorter period, as may be agreed to by the agency and such authority).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9DF26D0B2EC441EB8CF9AC3E8DE847FE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirements and procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish such requirements as may be necessary to implement the requirements of subparagraphs (A) and (B), including, with respect to subparagraph (B), such requirements regarding any notification and transfer of amounts as may be necessary to ensure that amounts are not so transferred except for actual and confirmed taxes assessed to and owed by an owner of a dwelling unit to ensure—</text> <clause id="H24C6906131B342A2889035B457D2FCDD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that no amounts are transferred in excess of the amount of such taxes owed; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1764CCD3B2AC4244A179CBF204706341"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the timely commencement and termination of such transfer.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2365AE0E765046019B378EF76AEF4A22"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Treatment of tenants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to authorize, or establish any cause or grounds for, the termination of the tenancy of any tenant from any dwelling unit assisted under this subsection.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H93D720BE2914423B8CDDD876DBE77EFA"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Database</header> 
<clause id="H23D4F914DD0D4C2E9028463D09CA9CA1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall maintain a database of information regarding—</text> <subclause id="H56A612C0600341B19A5598BA3CCEAC8B"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">owners of dwelling units assisted under this subsection whose housing assistance payments contracts have been terminated for failure to comply with subparagraph (A); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H06A1D1F7EFD7436683CDED8C2A49F428"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">owners of such dwelling units with respect to whom assistance amounts have been abated and transferred to a taxing authority pursuant to subparagraph (B).</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H331C575E3A09474E829DCB543A5E42F2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such database shall include information that identifies the owner, the property for which such assistance was provided, the amount transferred, and the period over which such abatement and transfer occurred.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD73BE6D01BFB46CB951591ACADE55CCF"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Information from public housing agencies</header><text>The Secretary shall require public housing agencies to submit information regarding the abatement and transfer of assistance amounts pursuant to subparagraph (B) sufficient for the Secretary to maintain such database.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCC64714115F74A6F8A595AA04566B45C"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the following definitions shall apply:</text> 
<clause id="H82EF05BFCB6940A4AAEBAEEE3D5F6B94"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Covered taxes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered taxes</term> means any tax under the law of a State or any political subdivision of a State that is assessed upon real property or the revenue of which is dedicated for use only for schools or for costs of education.</text></clause> <clause id="H46CAA45A0C8B4E1A82846CE2EAC08DE9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Taxing authority</header><text>The term <term>taxing authority</term> means any State or political subdivision of a State, including any agency or authority thereof, having authority to assess and collect covered taxes.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9EE71320720C4283A417AA49180C9FE5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall issue any regulations necessary to carry out this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

