<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD1FAFA33E67449C3B3401789A371F9FC" key="H" public-private="public">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3138 IH: Tribal Tax and Investment Reform Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3138</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20170629">June 29, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000578">Mr. Reichert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to treat Indian tribal governments in the same manner as State governments for certain Federal tax purposes, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form> 
<legis-body id="H3B10B1D584E54E2FB4FFB621F583C4EA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD58AF5310BA74FFA97DEDDFF74293E4C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tribal Tax and Investment Reform Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section commented="no" id="HC6E12484C38742AD9A9996E4FC32B804" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H770621E7B9014893AAE03791651E9092"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is a unique Federal legal and political relationship between the United States and Indian tribes.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H9E5579F54CB24639B836C8F4D6517E39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Indian tribes have the responsibility and authority to provide governmental programs and services to tribal citizens, develop tribal economies, and build community infrastructure to ensure that Indian reservation lands serve as livable, permanent homes.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2E6097855B8D4B0D92FB408A06811B76"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Constitution, U.S. Federal Court decisions, Executive orders, and numerous other Federal laws and regulations recognize that Indian tribes are governments, retaining the inherent authority to tax and operate as other governments, including (inter alia) financing projects with government bonds and maintaining eligibility for general tax exemptions via their government status.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H84BC68848FBE409B9F1674626D5D0DB1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Codifying tax parity with respect to tribal governments is consistent with Federal treaties recognizing the sovereignty of tribal governments.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF928470FF5B04BCAB406F48C5430EAE8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>That Indian tribes face historic disadvantages in accessing the underlying capital to build the necessary infrastructure for job creation, and that certain statutory restrictions on tribal governance further inhibit tribes’ ability to develop strong governance and economies.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H34C65CAEC580499CA4493E6C850A6275"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Indian tribes are sometimes excluded from the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 in key provisions which results in unfair tax treatment for tribal citizens or unequal enforcement authority for tribal enforcement agencies.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE23002C1D4524DAD936CB07E9732267B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Congress is vested with the authority to regulate commerce with Indian tribes, and hereby exercises that authority in a manner which furthers tribal self-governance, and in doing so, further affirms the United States government-to-government relationship with Indian tribes.</text> </paragraph></section> <section id="HDA22F44D37644A9D89EA6A8976ACD44A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Treatment of Indian tribes as States with respect to bond issuance</header> <subsection id="H2E530E5BFCC1438F9F2140144D5DB327"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (c) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7871">section 7871</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to Indian tribal governments treated as States for certain purposes) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HD46226890125457BBB948DAE6947ACB7" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H77E294494A2843538DAACF81A406D63C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rules for tax-Exempt bonds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In applying section 146 to bonds issued by Indian tribal governments (or subdivisions thereof) the Secretary of the Treasury shall annually—</text> <paragraph id="HC9997C484B8C4573B53F75121A318CAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a national bond volume cap based on the greater of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB188062B4CFF46208E4D7657C0A13A2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the State population formula approach in section 146(d)(1)(A) (using national tribal population estimates supplied annually by the Department of the Interior in consultation with the Census Bureau), and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H636CEEEB535B46919B0A50A5B6DE9548"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the minimum State ceiling amount in section 146(d)(1)(B) (as adjusted in accordance with the cost of living provision in section 146(d)(2)), and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0541E7F8DC9A4AABA29DA26907316EA2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>allocate such national bond volume cap among all Indian tribal governments seeking such an allocation in a particular year under regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection id="H567B47522AC94975A0BBB3CB875104F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal of essential governmental function requirements</header><text>Section 7871 of such Code is further amended by striking subsections (b) and (e).</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HAF003A69EA284283936DB5FE5220F1AB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header> 
<paragraph id="H77FA0987A2A7406081C9DBB98AC06A2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Subsection <enum-in-header>(a)</enum-in-header></header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to obligations issued in calendar years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A856E60D43C450982B72B9948A0479D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsection <enum-in-header>(b)</enum-in-header></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The repeals made by subsection (b) shall apply to transactions after, and obligations issued in calendar years beginning after, the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HADC98A85FBDB4B1882BC39435AE622A6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Treatment of pension and employee benefit plans maintained by tribal governments</header> 
<subsection id="HD057A57D13834E12B3178DAB8BE0E96C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments to the Internal Revenue Code of 1986</header> 
<paragraph id="H629E2B9F7BBE4365887411BE0C5B953B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified public safety employee</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/72">Section 72(t)(10)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (defining qualified public safety employee) is amended by—</text> <subparagraph id="H6423FCE849044E42B24C3E5871F129BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>striking <quote>or political subdivision of a State</quote> and inserting <quote>, political subdivision of a State, or Indian tribe</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9F952B4A3864424AB641B96AB4826763"><enum>(B)</enum><text>striking <quote>such State or political subdivision</quote> and inserting <quote>such State, political subdivision, or tribe</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H346920B27C1444D29694647D3D839DEF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Governmental plan</header><text>The last sentence of section 414(d) of such Code (defining governmental plan) is amended to read as follows: <quote>The term <term>governmental plan</term> includes a plan established or maintained for its employees by an Indian tribal government (as defined in section 7701(a)(40)), a subdivision of an Indian tribal government (determined in accordance with section 7871(d)), an agency, instrumentality, or subdivision of an Indian tribal government, or an entity established under Federal, State, or tribal law which is wholly owned or controlled by any of the foregoing.</quote>.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H94AEC48B4BD34ED08FA1DC832A95D5E9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Domestic relations order</header><text>Section 414(p)(1)(B)(ii) of such Code (defining domestic relations order) is amended by inserting <quote>or tribal</quote> after <quote>State</quote>.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H00A4B9A679084B2499597377C41CE6C7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exempt governmental deferred compensation plan</header><text>Section 3121(v)(3) of such Code (defining governmental deferred compensation plan) is amended by inserting <quote>by an Indian tribal government or subdivision thereof,</quote> after <quote>political subdivision thereof,</quote>.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H134511F5EA9D4730B11640D0046E96C1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Grandfather of certain deferred compensation plans</header><text>Section 457 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block id="H2DE35B144C4F475EAE21445599EDBA00" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H172D4C10129F448C9ED460290C55C851"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Certain Tribal Government Plans Grandfathered</header><text>Plans established before the date of enactment of this subsection and maintained by an Indian tribal government (as defined in section 7701(a)(40)), a subdivision of an Indian tribal government (determined in accordance with section 7871(d)), an agency, instrumentality, or subdivision of an Indian tribal government, or an entity established under Federal, State, or tribal law which is wholly owned or controlled by any of the foregoing, in compliance with subsection (b) or (f) shall be treated as if established by an eligible employer under subsection (e)(1)(A).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7BD68FAA664641B49203AD6C091F7ED6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendments to the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974</header> 
<paragraph id="H8633FA297FF14EE19663A84D4B0F1FF5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The last sentence of section 3(32) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002(32)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows: <quote>The term <term>governmental plan</term> includes a plan established or maintained for its employees by an Indian tribal government (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7701">section 7701(a)(40)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986), a subdivision of an Indian tribal government (determined in accordance with section 7871(d) of such Code), an agency, instrumentality, or subdivision of an Indian tribal government, or an entity established under Federal, State, or tribal law which is wholly owned or controlled by any of the foregoing.</quote>.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3E12FA62A1A485A9FB9BE8F9E03EB61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Domestic relations order</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 206(d)(3)(B)(ii)(II) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1056">29 U.S.C. 1056(d)(3)(B)(ii)(II)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or tribal</quote> after <quote>State</quote>.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB8E6DAF6CC8F40D0B7D7BF1BE2BD69F6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<subparagraph id="H02604AEF656F42DDA2F80AEDDEE3D8B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 4021(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1321">29 U.S.C. 1321(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of paragraph (12), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (13) and inserting <quote>; or</quote>, and by inserting after paragraph (13) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H01B966A424944E428F028425754901E0" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HFB7409CB684C41008FFB2E7E95622A15"><enum>(14)</enum><text>established or maintained for its employees by an Indian tribal government (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7701">section 7701(a)(40)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986), a subdivision of an Indian tribal government (determined in accordance with section 7871(d) of such Code), an agency, instrumentality, or subdivision of an Indian tribal government, or an entity established under Federal, State, or tribal law which is wholly owned or controlled by any of the foregoing.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4DE4B158CA90474496E78ADC67644E82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 4021(b)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1321">29 U.S.C. 1321(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>, or which is described in the last sentence of section 3(32)</quote> and inserting a comma.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4472AFAD27CA4CE1BC064E1BAE9D5515"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section>
<section commented="no" id="H66F9BD721FE94B0081D954A7889BBAF6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Treatment of tribal foundations and charities like charities funded and controlled by other governmental funders and sponsors</header> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H4317EBF80F56405B8B32B84354E0150F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">Section 170(b)(1)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>For purposes of clause (vi), the term <term>governmental unit</term> includes an Indian tribal government (determined in accordance with section 7871(d) of such Code), an agency, instrumentality, or subdivision of an Indian tribal government, or an entity established under Federal, State, or tribal law which is wholly owned or controlled by any of the foregoing.</quote>.</text> </subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H53BE151DD0944B22A41B316A6A63D231"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certain supporting organizations</header><text>Section 509(a) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>For purposes of paragraph (3), an organization described in paragraph (2) shall be deemed to include an Indian tribal government (determined in accordance with section 7871(d) of such Code), an agency, instrumentality, or subdivision of an Indian tribal government, or an entity established under Federal, State, or tribal law which is wholly owned or controlled by any of the foregoing.</quote>.</text> </subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HB1EC90104C9F426F8C3D9D76F7F82432"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H01AC1FA8296B4E289BD640C862AD73DC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Improving effectiveness of tribal child support enforcement agencies by parity of access to the Federal parent locator service and Federal tax refund offsets</header> <subsection id="H54FBC05A78FC42AAAA7683E1445C5639"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Access to federal parent locator service</header><text>Section 453(c) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/653">42 U.S.C. 653(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF3703064DEE445208BB6A9D453AA08DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (4);</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HADC1344CA4B24AFA9A4AF891E1527ECE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (5) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H535146B6850B4EC290BC0EEF8C1A6EE1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HFCFF357B75C343D3AC0F66188C0B63D9" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H529302344525440B8177D05B83AF6012"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the child support enforcement agency of an Indian tribe or tribal organization that is eligible for a grant under section 455(f).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H669DAF50AAC1420895701D5DBF48102E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Improving the collection of past-Due child support from Federal tax refunds</header> 
<paragraph id="H8B4531DB67F34A2382F76E386A23A298"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amendment to the Social Security Act</header><text>Section 464 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/664">42 U.S.C. 664</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HFE2F7B6D01174F618679A845C6F37202" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H8C130F2162F24663B65BF7532503D316"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability to Indian tribes and tribal organizations eligible for a grant under this part</header><text>This section, except for the requirement to distribute amounts in accordance with section 457, shall apply to an Indian tribe or tribal organization eligible for a grant under section 455(f) in the same manner in which this section applies to a State with a plan approved under this part.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7D0EECF38A5C44839C99FC6706E8305B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amendment to the Internal Revenue Code</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (c) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6402">section 6402</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>For purposes of this subsection, any reference to a State shall include a reference to any Indian tribe or tribal organization described in section 464(d) of the Social Security Act.</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HADC6FC3438F94C3AA29FB3F0569CA6F8"><enum>7.</enum><header>Recognizing Indian tribal governments for purposes of determining under the adoption credit whether a child has special needs</header> <subsection id="H86E1837193D74AF2A1776FFFF8E121BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/23">Section 23(d)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (defining child with special needs) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA8ACDF874E5A43E2AEB5D2860588116F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or Indian tribal government</quote> after <quote>a State</quote>; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H7722BF965FC64842900C9EBD9F4E0BE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>or Indian tribal government</quote> after <quote>such State</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE177C1FFA4F24364B6E54A57D04A8B7E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

