<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD68187BC064C4401A5DB9342A6416C94" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1027</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170213">February 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XXI of the Social Security Act to improve access to, and the delivery of, children&#8217;s health services through school-based health centers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC6ACAC908660474FBA080161872B4E9B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD7AC90B7585A4E3DBE1F3F6C77FA6936" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hallways to Health Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA4F7AD6AA2694AAD862169792A78482C"><enum>2.</enum><header>School-based health centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title XXI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397aa">42 U.S.C. 1397aa</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB3CDDF565C7E483DA5CE8201E5CF9871" style="OLC">
<section id="H1FD95D5F209748068E874F54697D067B"><enum>2114.</enum><header>Grants and programs to improve access to, and the delivery of, children's health services through school-based health centers</header>
<subsection id="H25C207327C514BF38A7AF77F1296DFF4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants to school-Based health centers To encourage children To adopt healthy behaviors</header>
<paragraph id="HB636F57CAE5D4B9089BB9967AE7672CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall publish criteria to enable school-based health centers to apply for grants for the purpose of assisting eligible children under this title and title XIX and other children by providing funding for community health workers to facilitate children's access to services that encourage children to adopt healthy behaviors and to improve the quality and cultural competence of the delivery of such services. Not later than 2 years after such date, the Secretary shall award grants to school-based health centers for such purposes.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A155E46AA924AFFA263B30634A97C4C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A school-based health center that employs individuals who meet the Bureau of Labor Statistics standard occupational definition of <quote>health educator</quote> (21–1091 or any successor classification number) or <quote>community health worker</quote> (21–1094 or any successor classification number) shall be eligible for a grant under this subsection.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD2ED1B7DA96B4E009CFA3237C01A330A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reporting</header>
<subparagraph id="H4ADA350DAA2240A4980B4CEC7FAC6204"><enum>(A)</enum><header>By grantees</header><text>A grantee under this subsection shall annually submit to the Secretary a report containing a description of the services provided under the grant, the data collected with respect to such services, a description of the efficacy of such services, any other information determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H42BDC24CCC254C64A3979BC64A683CCD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>By secretary</header><text>The Secretary biennially shall submit to Congress a report on the efficacy of the grant program established under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF69D612195884EA4BD064A5830BBE7B2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection. Funds appropriated under the preceding sentence shall remain available until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H81E505A084304994BB735788ABB26C28"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment and expansion of demonstration programs to provide tele-health services at school-based health centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2114 of the Social Security Act (as added by section 2), is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE376DD6B4CE94B1EA7EBF023C4B2D850" style="OLC">
<subsection id="H8EDFA503E3BB4F2695CF212090F87841"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment and expansion of tele-Health services demonstration programs</header>
<paragraph id="HF2693A8925AE46EBB49FB31B42F9E913"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall publish criteria for the establishment of a demonstration program to provide new tele-health services, or to expand existing tele-health service programs, located at school-based health centers. A school-based health center's receipt of funds under the demonstration program under this subsection shall not preclude the school-based health center from being reimbursed by public or private health insurance programs according to State law and regulation for items and services furnished by or through the center.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0C80B13CE6F40E084465A6B5CE3D5DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection. Funds appropriated under the preceding sentence shall remain available until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="H36901EDC01F24BD7BE68215EADF346C5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Assurance of payment under Medicaid and CHIP for covered items and services furnished by certain school-based health centers</header>
<subsection id="H4F4D2DABC24E4BD390050A54B69EC077"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State plan requirement</header><text>Section 1902(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC49B3CEDE35D4A33A8EEF827677EAA14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (82), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB205C6E9C2804A5C9633C3654CFCD8C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (83)(B)(ii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE45254FD01B4007895C25BA0F93E6B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (83) the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9DB039758DC34FF19DA0D6AFC7BB7C07" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H29F294D0F02A433BBE79A9D9029F8FDB"><enum>(84)</enum><text>provide that the State shall certify to the Secretary that the State has implemented procedures to pay for medical assistance (including care and services described in subsections (a)(4)(B) and (r) of section 1905 and provided in accordance with section 1902(a)(43)) furnished in a school-based health center (as defined in section 2110(c)(9)), if payment would be made under the State plan for the same items and services if furnished in a physician's office or other outpatient clinic (including if such payment would be included in the determination of a prepaid capitation or other risk-based rate of payment to an entity under a contract pursuant to section 1903(m)).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1F6F8840893F42FAB8E65FE2AC976D38"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application to CHIP</header><text>Section 2107(e)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397gg">42 U.S.C. 1397gg(e)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H64365A2B58244F5FB42DC1081625DCB3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (G) through (R) as subparagraphs (H) through (S), respectively; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE0232224EFB4AC49EAF90D54F303CBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (F), the following new subparagraph:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H24723AB9667447AC82DC0DDEAE74468E" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="H06938482E1B74239B43E8E6DFA1202B2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Section 1902(a)(84) (relating to procedures to ensure payment for covered services furnished in a school-based health center).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB98AEEAC53CB41A48AD21E0EF4303A11"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section take effect on October 1, 2017.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HDC5FD448983A455EB9FA78AD555FBE59"><enum>5.</enum><header>Other improvements</header>
<subsection id="HD07374B263E64043AFA80689E6207AD7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 399Z–1 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280h-5">42 U.S.C. 280h–5</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3C523A08416E45B886265CBA38FFD1E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>either in person or via telehealth,</quote> after <quote>health centers,</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB06EFB33BBC344698BF4AEB4F03E8D3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(3)(A), by inserting before the semicolon the following: <quote>, and includes universities, accountable care organizations, and behavioral health organizations</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB05C291C7D94846AE484C3008F5792D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(2)(C)(iv), by inserting <quote>and health education</quote> after <quote>health services</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFBB0049A9446484EA96DD60465D3F37B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by striking <quote>may—</quote> and all that follows through the end and inserting <quote>may, upon a showing of good cause, waive the requirement that the SBHC provide all required comprehensive primary health services for a period not to exceed 2 years.</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCDFDADC049934632901FA897D4F8ACCE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (i), by inserting before the period the following: <quote>, including using existing quality performance measures funded by the Federal Government for such entities</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H81B670DCAB714FA4A747253DD7212AEE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (l)—</text> <subparagraph id="H43D9A6D2B8A04173951FF73B3562841B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2014</quote> and inserting <quote>2022</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBD5191CDEE2D4EBDA2BC19169B61DD4C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating such subsection as subsection (n); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA4B8FCB3A3345BA9C0A5C305F1C5795"><enum>(7)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (k), the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1AFAB3C6F2A4670A5BC2980C3A149E9" style="OLC">
<subsection id="H7BEE325A15FD4CA4B25B7DD4577B6463"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary, acting directly or through awarding grants or contracts to private, nonprofit entities, shall establish or support existing State school-based health center resource centers that—</text> <paragraph id="HC98EA6F995F644F48EA36EE3425C01B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide advocacy, training, and technical assistance to school-based health centers, including maximizing Federal and State resources;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0B350EA360BD4966BC42C1556E92031F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support the development of school-based health centers; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03448A7813E548FCAB4DF12AA1DF7F86"><enum>(3)</enum><text>enhance the operations and performance of school-based health centers.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HEA5F5DCE463D48778A5E1628BAAAD659"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For purposes of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H374A06FC2BD147C9AE979C5F922ECDF4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>Section 340B(a)(4) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/256b">42 U.S.C. 256b(a)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3533A6E7008E4980AB049F152CD2D3B7" style="OLC">
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9306DC3530964BB696D1005C90942DE8"><enum>(P)</enum><text>A school-based health center.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H1D9A2B635D7E4F6E94AE98867670EDD6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified health plans</header><text>Section 1311(c)(1)(C) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18031">42 U.S.C. 18031(c)(1)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, providers defined in section 2110(c)(9) of the Social Security Act,</quote> after <quote>Public Health Service Act</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

