<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H59E3D78DF07B4761AE2A1314F3BF4DE1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4144 IH: Port Drivers’ Bill of Rights Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4144</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171026">October 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a task force on truck leasing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H73BCEA474D3B4CD9AAEE9BEF5754E324" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6D12ACF69BAC404AA0A0A7A12926684B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Port Drivers’ Bill of Rights Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H49CDB8D0BCB54944921BA6AB9AA20A65"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H0B6E9219092543E79F2B06F7D3F2681E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The labor of drayage and intermodal truck drivers is vital to the movement of goods and to our Nation’s economic prosperity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H19F87138AC3F4AD48F91CC08BC3C7D26"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Independent studies have repeatedly documented the low pay and rampant worker misclassification in the port drayage and intermodal industries.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC17A35549A12410F842EA03293D1C8CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Subcommittee on Highways and Transit of the House Transportation and Infrastructure Committee held a hearing on May 5, 2010, on the negative economic and environmental impacts of port trucking.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFA3CD88A75349E483E7AF0C5395A779"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An investigation published in USA Today on June 16, 2017, titled <quote>Rigged</quote>, detailed disturbing employer abuses and called the work arrangements for many port truck drivers modern-day indentured servitude.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC5C59A4969E444CBEC5F1560C21500D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The California Labor Commissioner has issued decisions awarding over 400 port drivers in excess of $40 million in back pay due to wage and hour violations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H482EC65BECC142678DBC9D18A4001546"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Federal and State courts have consistently upheld the California Labor Commissioner’s authority to adjudicate these claims and have rejected complaints that wage claims brought by truck drivers with the Labor Commissioner are preempted by the Federal Aviation Administration Authorization Act of 1994.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6115CD163F1F4BDF8B662DFC31160F46"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The California Employment Development Department and the New Jersey Department of Labor have awarded at least 50 port drivers unemployment and disability benefits.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F956DC7EBD7497CBDA7A5A27CF55EF1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Regions 21 and 5 of the National Labor Relations Board have issued several complaints against port trucking companies for allegedly committing unfair labor practices after investigations determined port drivers were being misclassified.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F3A07B1661D4B1A9F49647D5E3D8823"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Drayage drivers at the Ports of Los Angeles and Long Beach have engaged in at least 15 unfair labor practice strikes over the past 3 years to protest misclassification, which have caused picketing at marine terminals that delayed cargo and created congestion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA48A7211F984A8CA736BA75B24B29EC"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Many stakeholders in the movement of goods and licensed motor carriers, including beneficial cargo owners and third-party logistics providers, contribute to negative working conditions for port truck drivers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BB916A78C674A19AC67BBD1DD566BD5"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Government officials have an opportunity and a responsibility to improve the working conditions of port truck drivers.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H9BBAC92261484105B61A6419717006DC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that truck drivers, including drayage drivers, have the right to—</text> <paragraph id="H137ED749F4B242C9BE2F065FE8A31992"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be treated with honesty and respect;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3A8D89689F5498AA759D8CA8D4C45DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have full-time work guarantee a basic standard of living;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1197C681391C48DD9E74A360F7987584"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be covered by Federal, State, and local labor and employment laws;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFAFE95D7FB3481BB836ED3EE05F3BA5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>be covered by workplace safety and health laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H827AA3092BB94149B6F7B51DD89DB339"><enum>(5)</enum><text>be free from exploitative truck lease or rental arrangements;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA005CFA7A046467CB424AEFF96A8EBFA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>not be misclassified as independent contractors and denied legal protections, benefits, and pay; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8CE0253A2ACE425A962621F6E6B37773"><enum>(7)</enum><text>bargain collectively for better wages and working conditions.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H2AD6E3444FCB466889A88E5913238E03"><enum>4.</enum><header>Truck Leasing Task Force</header> <subsection id="HA44055EF978E4E3E8CDACF7B4036B61F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall establish the Truck Leasing Task Force (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>Task Force</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H13CBCBB8802A4C9C9F6093BD48759AF8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation shall select not more than 15 individuals to serve as members of the Task Force from the following groups:</text>
 <paragraph id="H312D00D54FA849AEB96160ED1F328735"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Labor organizations.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9BDD24906F954D6ABD6BC7E215FF7296"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The motor carrier industry.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4B9074D5C3B421ABA47CA279BDC42D6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Consumer protection groups.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF3B4733A0AC4AECB882504EA18A3CAA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Safety groups.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H617B1FE9981447A58D976331FA08AD22"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Members of the legal profession who specialize in consumer finance issues.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD44DFC0626E549CC816D6EDC31D2497C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Task Force shall examine <quote>lease-to-own</quote> agreements that commercial truck drivers have entered into, with a focus on—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6CCE2517351F44FA85E6B7DA80D005B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the operation of agreements that drayage drivers have entered into; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC097B34458984CAC8C3B9822992FAE41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such agreements at the Port of Los Angeles and the Port of Long Beach.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H332786FF36B949609572EA6032C74453"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Powers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Task Force may conduct site visits and field hearings, as necessary, to assist its efforts.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HBAD88A8667D74F208BCBE9BDE44F4AB8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="HFDFB904344B5482ABC59CE6BD7A9D8A6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Task Force shall create a report containing the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H349D52CA21E74502AFBAA6CEACF5957C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The impact of truck leasing agreements on the take-home pay of truck drivers.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89872B094DB245138B6FE7F52F775E27"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Whether the truck leasing agreements comply with applicable local, State, and Federal law.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB16E54659E3344D2AF651EDF0F4CC0C1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the Task Force determines that legislation is necessary to protect the ability of truck drivers to earn a living wage and, if so, recommendations on such legislation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF38894362A8475A8C44EC1D73CA7A05"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the Task Force determines that changes in regulations are necessary to protect the ability of truck drivers to earn a living wage and, if so, recommendations to the Secretary of Transportation and the Secretary of Labor on such changes.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C3FDEF6FDAA4424B695D6EAC97C7D96"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Task Force is established pursuant to subsection (a), the report created pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be submitted to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H41D1F21FCEB34637956B2BFB8D6805CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the House Transportation and Infrastructure Committee;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40704BAF56974F64924E764828DAFBFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the House Education and the Workforce Committee;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB097EFF5E48C4E9E926CA1D57CFB777C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7EC6E60782843399A0A32F858CA71C1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE0B4D474D28640E481A4575989AC983E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 month after the date of submission of the report pursuant to subsection (e), the Task Force shall terminate.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


