<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H40900D152AC34025BE91AA291A4706B2" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1900 : National Veterans Memorial and Museum Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1900</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20171108">November 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To designate the Veterans Memorial and Museum in Columbus, Ohio, as the National Veterans Memorial
			 and Museum, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H7809BE8D262346C0BB7906CAECA608FB" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC1D276B3BDF647AD8C6FD57476A4835A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Veterans Memorial and Museum Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF5577A9F229E46829B55C06B30BFABA1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of National Veterans Memorial and Museum</header> <subsection id="HD9934A54895F4FD3B8B4703B68D6F779"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the condition described in subsection (b), the memorial and museum that is, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, being constructed on an approximately 7-acre area on West Broad Street, Columbus, Ohio, bounded by the Scioto River and the Scioto Greenway, shall be designated as the <quote>National Veterans Memorial and Museum</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9E9FD40568A64E0A938F2ADA0339429C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Withdrawal of designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The designation under subsection (a) may be withdrawn no earlier than 5 years after the date on which the museum opens the public, pursuant to an Act of Congress, if the progress and operation of the museum are found to be unsatisfactory based on the report submitted under subsection (c).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H6683C0885FA34491849BB44552FC0BAF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header>
 <paragraph id="HBD4B239A968C49C3896F16ADC214EFDA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As a condition of the designation under subsection (a), the director of the memorial and museum described in that subsection shall submit to Congress a report on the memorial and museum by not later than the date specified in paragraph (2). Such report shall include each of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H08A1814D1E4D41E59734C3E6EC7B4F4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The projected budget for the memorial and museum for the 5-year period beginning on the date the memorial and museum is expected to open to the public.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EFDDFBCFB434F0F8524A1A96D29EDD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the outreach conducted by the memorial and museum to veterans across the United States to receive input about the design and contents of the memorial and museum.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED76B775CE27488FAEAACA3A04ABFCE1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of the process by which decisions are made about the contents of the exhibits displayed at the memorial and museum.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7380D93462C4421A3EF94EEB2ED17CF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A description of the organizational structure of the memorial and museum.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AD5038BE4DE4BDC8122ABDF58F8A92D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A copy of the bylaws and rules of the memorial and museum.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1D6D30BB2084763BEA80B250A36ABAA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A list of any organizations or entities that have accredited the memorial and museum.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H00A0CCEACD234BDBB4A2AA0DB80156BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline for report</header><text>The date specified in this paragraph is the earlier of the following dates:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF7EB30B4626E46688989BF9F8B9536FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The date that is 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C06CB060C564340B18A99DF4B1582BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The date that is 30 days before the date on which the memorial and museum is first open to the public.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC4D498C52CA44765A5A83239DD279DB0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effect of designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The national memorial and museum designated by subsection (a) is not a unit of the National Park System, and the designation of the national memorial and museum shall not be construed to require Federal funds to be expended for any purpose related to the national memorial and museum.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20171107">Passed the House of Representatives November 7, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


