<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H083646FDC9AF4DAE97D1AFA636D0F091" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1638 RH: Iranian Leadership Asset Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 335</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1638</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–453, Part I]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170320">March 20, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000611">Mr. Poliquin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>December 7, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported from the Committee on <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Financial Services</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>December 7, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>The <committee-name committee-id="HFA00"> Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to
			 be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 20, 2017</action-instruction></action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to submit a report to the appropriate congressional
			 committees on the estimated total assets under direct or indirect control
			 by certain senior Iranian leaders and other figures, and for other
			 purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HF5A5798821A249EA93F284A6369CF88C" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="H21479C1D9B1C4542B9060144E705594B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Iranian Leadership Asset Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA4F458AC84EA45E9B250CC307DF19AB9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA7D54611D1664392A1B6C981C3DDD390"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Iran is characterized by high levels of official and institutional corruption, and substantial involvement by Iran’s security forces, particularly the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC), in the economy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H653BCDE3D728400E8C2281B404D2FECE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Many members of Iran’s senior political and military leadership have acquired significant personal and institutional wealth by using their positions to secure control of significant portions of Iran’s national economy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0028C196573D4DE4895001F439BBD464"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Sanctions relief provided through the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action has resulted in the removal of many Iranian entities that are tied to governmental corruption from the list of entities sanctioned by the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1DDB77989473478DB0379EB6AF27F3EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Department of Treasury in 2011 designated the Islamic Republic of Iran’s financial sector as a jurisdiction of primary money laundering concern under section 311 of the USA PATRIOT Act, stating <quote>Treasury has for the first time identified the entire Iranian financial sector; including Iran’s Central Bank, private Iranian banks, and branches, and subsidiaries of Iranian banks operating outside of Iran as posing illicit finance risks for the global financial system.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H200412BECE754B97B8A25A185716B3FD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Iran continues to be listed by the Financial Action Task Force (FATF) among the <quote>Non-Cooperative Countries or Territories</quote>—countries which it perceived to be non-cooperative in the global fight against terror finance and money laundering.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC1CF00646D249B69F78258D35CE6B2F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Iran and North Korea are the only countries listed by the FATF as <quote>Non-Cooperative Countries or Territories</quote> against which FATF countries should take measures.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD24DA4D62074DF4B84C611BC73737BF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Transparency International index of perceived public corruption ranks Iran 130th out of 168 countries surveyed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5896CE5FF9FC4D17AF2FBA9368F96631"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The State Department identified Iran as a <quote>major money-laundering country</quote> in its International Narcotics Control Strategy Report (INCSR) for 2016.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE84B00099FC4038980DDDC51822DF52"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The State Department currently identifies Iran, along with Sudan and Syria, as a state sponsor of terrorism, <quote>having repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H860D965FB4F94D21BFA04D018BBD881D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The State Department’s <quote>Country Reports on Terrorism</quote>, published last in July 2017, noted that <quote>Iran continued to sponsor terrorist groups around the world, principally through its Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps–Qods Force (IRGC–QF). These groups included Lebanese Hizballah, several Iraqi Shia militant groups, Hamas, and Palestine Islamic Jihad. Iran, Hizballah, and other Shia militia continued to provide support to the Asad regime, dramatically bolstering its capabilities, prolonging the civil war in Syria, and worsening the human rights and refugee crisis there.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H726A4E816C434253911598CA4B1C5E5E"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Iranian Government’s tolerance of corruption and nepotism in business limits opportunities for foreign and domestic investment, particularly given the significant involvement of the IRGC in many sectors of Iran’s economy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H54565DBA3F51405B8C593AB0125CB189"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The IRGC and the leadership-controlled bonyads (foundations) control an estimated one-third of Iran’s total economy, including large portions of Iran’s telecommunications, construction, and airport and port operations. These operations give the IRGC and bonyads vast funds to support terrorist organizations such as Hezbollah and Hamas.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE1F4AF9A1064935885821B365922205"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">By gaining control of major economic sectors, the IRGC and bonyads have also served to further disadvantage the average Iranian.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H35DE6001D0C74A26BB974C194F2C26AF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report requirement relating to assets of Iranian leaders and certain senior political figures</header>
 <subsection id="H565FB2F8EDFF45B3AC483AFAEB083A62"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter (or more frequently if the Secretary of the Treasury determines it appropriate based on new information received by the Secretary) for the following 2 years, the Secretary of the Treasury shall, in furtherance of the Secretary’s efforts to prevent the financing of terrorism, money laundering, or related illicit finance and to make financial institutions’ required compliance with remaining sanctions more easily understood, submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees containing—</text>
 <paragraph id="H90F8802DCE824159B8FEBB282DE0042B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the estimated total funds or assets held in accounts at U.S. and foreign financial institutions that are under direct or indirect control by each natural person described in subsection (b) and a description of such assets;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDCEA2958C46409D8085AA9B86B16DAC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of any equity stake such natural person has in an entity on the Department of the Treasury's list of Specially Designated Nationals or in any other sanctioned entity;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9027BA5F060B4B7CA4BD877ABF954020"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how such funds or assets or equity interests were acquired, and how they have been used or employed;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H55D50997823040BE9F78335BC45EC0A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any new methods or techniques used to evade anti-money laundering and related laws, including recommendations to improve techniques to combat illicit uses of the U.S. financial system by each natural person described in subsection (b);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6CBED08F640E4BCB9F105B9B166BB97D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for how U.S. economic sanctions against Iran may be revised to prevent the funds or assets described under this subsection from being used by the natural persons described in subsection (b) to contribute to the continued development, testing, and procurement of ballistic missile technology by Iran;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE7CF4F97A424FD895820C70096991C1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a description of how the Department of the Treasury assesses the impact and effectiveness of U.S. economic sanctions programs against Iran; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7B69AAB2FCC247FD96801BA086A12E08"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for improving the ability of the Department of the Treasury to rapidly and effectively develop, implement, and enforce additional economic sanctions against Iran if so ordered by the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act or other corresponding legislation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2AB4BB1C10944DF8970EECCD8D07FE45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Persons described</header><text>The natural persons described in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph id="H5C9CC3F623CC490E8B7E3D6A88FAFC18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Supreme Leader of Iran.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H513BFAD6F10F4D67AC7D7C67651FCD52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The President of Iran.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA13C4DE0F3848CE9B765C730C63F310"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Members of the Council of Guardians.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7F2A48E298945A0A1930B309DFD595A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Members of the Expediency Council.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BE44F7A43B24A9787816FE0C5F4A69E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Minister of Intelligence and Security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H415BC418AD0C4BEEBC434F95714B4BE3"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commander and the Deputy Commander of the IRGC.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC40501B117A7435DA173879972CF743B"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commander and the Deputy Commander of the IRGC Ground Forces.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H51D032E6074647CDA9E24969E97725AD"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Commander and the Deputy Commander of the IRGC Aerospace Force.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H281FC0311EE14A568EB3C8DD74D17991"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Commander and the Deputy Commander of the IRGC Navy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5413496DA4DC47E3B4331B0D23004836"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Commander of the Basij-e-Mostaz’afin.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E970DC96C854D9AB39D12C090A9DF98"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Commander of the Qods Force.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEBD613027FE44AE7BF76BFB9B7D682FA"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Commander in Chief of the Police Force.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCBD5F89DBC6E4157BAA498298F450663"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The head of the IRGC Joint Staff.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H332773DDCCEE43C2BB47F74996043A8C"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The Commander of the IRGC Intelligence.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBCD8F2DA7C954A98AFCAEA7CD6F06722"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The head of the IRGC Imam Hussein University.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DBA51F8A30A4E1D9F5C1B65CEEDE775"><enum>(16)</enum><text>The Supreme Leader’s Representative at the IRGC.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H787FB3F933CD4484B55F95D8FDB42D54"><enum>(17)</enum><text>The Chief Executive Officer and the Chairman of the IRGC Cooperative Foundation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5D781865643A47A69E48F4DE1B227ACC"><enum>(18)</enum><text>The Commander of the Khatam-al-Anbia Construction Head Quarter.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5265BBDE3E7449795E2A119EC23902B"><enum>(19)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief Executive Officer of the Basij Cooperative Foundation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CD1B23343D14B8DAF077433E7293A74"><enum>(20)</enum><text>The head of the Political Bureau of the IRGC.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C10AE8B2EE64A99944EFF599E17EDEC"><enum>(21)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of the Atomic Energy Organization of Iran.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE511207B46E5471396A8402624BE14B5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form of report; public availability</header>
 <paragraph id="HA5EEE515543B43F183DAB4CDE10EAC87"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF364B6F845840F39080ABF88BCC6DDB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The unclassified portion of such report shall be made available to the public and posted on the website of the Department of the Treasury—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4258A910366745FC9A162EC56EFE7B41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in English, Farsi, Arabic, and Azeri; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82C89AE2393C4421A796C6B594D1261A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in precompressed, easily downloadable versions that are made available in all appropriate formats.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H02A3967D982947DB9A15FD640860D5D2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sources of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In preparing a report described under subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury may use any credible publication, database, web-based resource, public information compiled by any government agency, and any information collected or compiled by a nongovernmental organization or other entity provided to or made available to the Secretary, that the Secretary finds credible.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB9F4A713C8844190929D2AFF0CF2E4F9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="HFC0B013922834222A71726B34728C55F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the Committees on Financial Services and Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H703BD01B26FB4F6F9DEC6D3893314D01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>funds</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H0B9639BDC37644F39A6FCD9DF9F942FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>cash;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F9FA6F5AD5A4FD7B0C65F31A4F5EF3C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>equity;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45E4E55C810842F6AC8B6C7DF4E35296"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other intangible asset whose value is derived from a contractual claim, including bank deposits, bonds, stocks, a security as defined in section 2(a) of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77b">15 U.S.C. 77b(a)</external-xref>), or a security or an equity security as defined in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42AEA073FB5E45CA94AC9D6CCEBFB906"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">anything else that the Secretary determines appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBD9FC7E7D6C943AF9B7EAE3D9ED2D984"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that in preparing the reports required under section 3, the Secretary of the Treasury should consider acquiring information from sources that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5A66FE85542E45E1A75250A0BE0B9331"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collect and, if necessary, translate high-veracity, official records; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA434600033ED48339EC47C4B68CC236F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide search and analysis tools that enable law enforcement to have new insights into commercial and financial relationships.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>December 7, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported from the Committee on <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Financial Services</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc>
		<action-date>December 7, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>The <committee-name committee-id="HFA00"> Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to
			 be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


