<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H73E53C0311F04149B8073CE6FD57DEBA" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2800 IH: Aviation Funding Stability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2800</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170607">June 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000127">Mr. Nolan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Appropriations</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to ensure improvement of air traffic control services, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H32DABACD05334DDA8617649508A698D5" style="OLC">
 <section id="H526F5EB453CE48C4862060E77894EB15" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Aviation Funding Stability Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HEE496E1951C24DA7ABCCEF7D89E8ED32"><enum>2.</enum><header>Trust fund off budget</header> <subsection id="HB232120D3B2C401EA581D2738976001D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Trust fund off budget</header><text>Section 48114 of title 49, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HBDF97D8D34044B048C96F3D1F109DB24" style="USC">
					<section id="HE8C6D282E98A4D86B8FFCD792BAFB51D"><enum>48114.</enum><header>Trust fund off budget</header>
 <subsection id="H10A96CF93CAC454393F24FAB1A07CE80"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Airport and airway trust fund guarantee</header><text>Beginning October 1, 2017, receipts and disbursements of the Airport and Airway Trust Fund established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9502">section 9502</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall not be subject—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8B58C7B9152344A7A4FBCD1C9550C49B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to any sequestration order issued under the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 or any subsequent law requiring such sequestration;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE7F4CED9BEF147208F0A67554DD3CE4C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to apportionment pursuant to section 1513(b) of title 31, United States Code;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H110184F395454B9293FEA1A681DC8BF6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to appropriation and shall be authorized and made available immediately for obligation and expenditure; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBBE0BC36A7C243B2827D532A588696B1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to any legal requirement, directive, or other provision of law of or related to the Office of Management and Budget.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H33F108A1C754420A8B04294631241AE2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>General fund share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts made available under subsection (a), there is further authorized to be appropriated from the general fund of the Treasury such sums as may be necessary for the Federal Aviation Administration Operations account. Such funds shall not be subject to any sequestration order issued under the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 or any subsequent law requiring such sequestration.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7D6C00D1B2454D19BFF67EBD9DB72285"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization To transfer certain funds To prevent reduced operations and staffing</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, within any fiscal year, the Administrator may transfer, to the account funding Administration operations, up to 5 percent of funds available for any budget activity in any other account of the Federal Aviation Administration to prevent reduced operations and staffing of the Federal Aviation Administration and to ensure a safe and efficient air transportation system.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD1A5D85E2291466A8053B1264A322626"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Essential air service</header><text>Section 41742 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking paragraph (2) of subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H2442280F074B41BCB2B92B150029346B" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HD706ED6F587E4E83885C75BD99A7D5AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional funds</header><text>Beginning October 1, 2017, from amounts deposited into the Airport and Airway Trust Fund, the sum of $175,000,000 for each fiscal year is authorized and shall be made available immediately, in addition to amounts made available under paragraph (1) and subsection (b), for obligation and expenditure to carry out the essential air service program under this subchapter.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H791583185A1340A6A70DA87EA058848A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Flexibility</header>
 <subsection id="HD9A56E75CA9B43AA886396D251FCEE1E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Office of management and budget</header><text>The Federal Aviation Administration shall be exempt from any order, directive, rule, or other requirement of the Office of Management and Budget.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2E86D6FADAEC4E01B2ED0EB44BE885BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Office of the secretary of transportation</header><text>The revisions to the procurement and personnel systems of the Federal Aviation Administration under sections 6(a) and 7(a) shall not be subject to approval, modification, or review by the Secretary of Transportation.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H4AC33DD660844D79932A6740A0162124"><enum>4.</enum><header>Management advisory council input</header>
 <subsection id="H40C676904B7F4F9BB93549E734EFDD5D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Air traffic control system performance</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/401">Chapter 401</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HC44F6DB819A44E188DFA66A0D36C820F" style="USC"> <section id="HA399E0F974204BFB81862B06311DF005"><enum>40131.</enum><header>Air traffic control system performance</header> <subsection id="HB1FAE75F7D89412BBD9A5162599EB2E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal Aviation Management Advisory Council established under section 106(p) shall, in addition to performing the responsibilities under such section—</text>
 <paragraph id="H121F9EE3F2934915A8BBC9C2530F258A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assess the performance of the air traffic control system and the Administrator’s policy and strategic decisions with respect to operation and modernization of the system; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A6D7CC8AEB04424BCB62890533296FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make recommendations to the Administrator to improve the system.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1CEAB626D88F4AAD94F793001BFB973A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public response</header><text>The Administrator shall publicly respond in writing to each recommendation of the Council under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3A780352DB144424A09DE31F9F7889A4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A response by the Administrator under subsection (b) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H1DD69334C0D941F192EC03524CDC9FD5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a restatement of the recommendation to which the response is directed;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8DFC060176394DC8BFAC58D8F3F790AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Administrator’s analysis of the recommendation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H16DDE75DFBF544D58EF0E72860C8ECB1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if the Administrator intends to implement the recommendation, a detailed schedule for implementation; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC1A35E6CB16460A9C02ACBF63169FDD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>if the Administrator does not concur in the recommendation, a statement explaining the reasons for such nonconcurrence.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3796838F599E4886B37FA6B83E8F5DD5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the Administrator’s receipt of a recommendation under subsection (a), each response by the Administrator under this section shall be posted on the internet website of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB366D4B0F9EF4EC1BF0D92F097B6AA7A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 106(p)(1) is amended by striking the period at the end and adding <quote>, except as provided in section 40131.</quote>.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H316D23DA413243B888880F393CA9BFEB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Air traffic control facility modernization and sustainment</header> <subsection id="HFBF35A9CBDE84EDFAEA25C702639BBE3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Facility modernization and sustainment</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/481">Chapter 481</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HBD2F83A5C046483BA4B5558518BCC69F" style="USC">
					<section id="H686D7E10A7914CE9B9510A6CDCAA9B33"><enum>48115.</enum><header>Air traffic control facility modernization and sustainment </header>
 <subsection id="HE52C9061D2CE4FA9986950A09ABC2CCB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Modernization and sustainment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any fiscal year between 2018 and 2030, in addition to amounts made available under section 48101, there is further authorized to be appropriated from the uncommitted balance of the Airport and Airway Trust Fund such sums as are necessary to bring any air traffic control facility of the Federal Aviation Administration into acceptable condition.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9C4DF0374AB64FB3A1830A36FE93D36F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before taking any action under subsection (a) to modernize or sustain air traffic control facilities of the Federal Aviation Administration, the Administrator shall consult with the exclusive bargaining representatives of air traffic controllers and airway transportation system specialists certified under section 7111 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDC9F0F17C0C34CC39146DFF954018E58"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/481">chapter 481</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/48114">section 48114</external-xref> the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HC0EFF979E29B43E7B98D7FECBA54B91C" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">48115. Air traffic control facility modernization and sustainment.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H2B761113E2D14AB696CBDE0D1EC0D947"><enum>6.</enum><header>Acquisition reform</header>
 <subsection id="H0EC6087D518041D29B91986FDDB18D16"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall develop and implement a revised system governing all of the Administration’s acquisitions, including services, facilities, equipment, and real, personal, and intellectual property.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB96C713469794A518D9D6F4473FB3A7D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Streamlined process</header><text>The system revised under subsection (a) shall take advantage of the independence already provided by Congress from all acquisition and acquisition-related laws to further streamline processes for acquisitions that substantially improve the flexibility and cost effectiveness of the Administration’s acquisitions process. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the only rules, policies, and procedures that shall govern or affect this system are those promulgated by the Administrator.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE13AC1C406AC4105BAB1EE50EF839377"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Design of system</header><text>The system revised under subsection (a) shall, at minimum—</text> <paragraph id="H08A3101C3A2B4F2EB1863E5101E91F00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>account for the complexity and multiple stages of acquisitions of interdependent systems that constitute the Next Generation Air Transportation System;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE76BB7C8595F4BCEAB2BF68A99939541"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include measures for appropriate program managers to verify the readiness of software-intensive programs prior to acceptance;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D4AEF4F08E648C686E7B701069BDD32"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include measures for the Administrator to identify and implement cost reductions across the Administration according to such timelines and metrics as the Administrator shall identify;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8003613A13AA4B9586C562CBCEF0ADCC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>include measures for the Administrator to reliably estimate the cost of each segment with respect to each acquisition, along with reliable estimates of all costs that are reasonably expected to be incurred as a result of such acquisition; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2848DD5AAAC44A50AEC75145BB9BBEF7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>incorporate private-sector best practices for major capital investments in information technology, telecommunications, and other relevant systems.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEBB85B20A848456B897D8452C8E973D5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator shall ensure that any requirement or provision of the acquisition management system of the Administration in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9F182449A77440DFA36A45C829071F53"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is necessary to promote transparency, accountability, and cost effectiveness;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3152334095D5467BA67C3894005EFBCB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not materially affect the Administration’s ability to reduce costs associated with acquisitions programs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA84BB66F168747C2879823D7BB31BAD4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is necessary to protect the interests of the Administration in any potential claim or defense in litigation arising from an acquisition; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD1C49DEAEDAB48EB99CAD8DC2DC9AC28"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is necessary to provide for the continuity of one or more acquisition programs.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAB9FBB6D20924E65B1F9265F18DABBD4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Acquisition of services</header><text>In developing a revised system governing the Administration’s acquisitions under subsection (a), the Administrator shall consult with the exclusive bargaining representative of airway transportation system specialists certified under section 7111 of title 5, United States Code, before taking any action related to services acquisition.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0D63A0AB84B34FE5A06253178D75DCF5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 12 months after revising the system required under subsection (a), the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on the revised process.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H1126970155574F11A56FF33DB85591EE"><enum>7.</enum><header>Personnel reform</header>
 <subsection id="H49F1D8EA11F74BB7AAE0B50B56809745"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reform of personnel management system</header><text>Not later than 1 year after completion of the review required under subsection (b), the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall make changes to the personnel management system developed under section 40122(g) of title 49, United States Code, to improve the productivity, cost effectiveness, and technical proficiency of that part of the Administration’s workforce that is not represented by an exclusive representative recognized under section 7111 of title 5, United States Code, or eligible to be represented by such a labor organization. The changes required under this subsection shall include new performance incentive policies, including awards for performance, and shall, notwithstanding any other provision of law, include procedures for the Administration to take expedited personnel actions with respect to employees not covered by valid collective bargaining agreements. In no instance may the changes implemented under this subsection alter or otherwise affect the terms and conditions of employment of any employee represented or eligible to be represented by an exclusive representative recognized under section 7111 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1E0ABE8535DD4BF8BEFCCDCC208B9860"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall conduct a comprehensive review of the legal requirements, including policies, standards, rules, and orders of the Administration, pertaining to the Administration’s personnel management system, except to the extent that such requirements may affect or relate to the terms and conditions of employment or dispute resolution processes governing employees who are represented or eligible to be represented by an exclusive bargaining representative recognized under section 7111 of title 5, United States Code. This review shall identify—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF03C2A7C663B4699842E9F7BC7FE9404"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any requirements that do not substantially contribute to the system’s cost effectiveness, administrative flexibility, and transparency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H160EF476A32145F0821C5EC1C99FF9C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any requirement not related to maintaining collective bargaining and due process;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H43F1CD2FC8F341118EEC1351979C589F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any requirements not reasonably related to the Administration’s efforts to maintain a strong, mutually beneficial relationship between employees and management of the Administration; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEEF48C354FAC4128ACDC214297E85A27"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any requirements with respect to personnel management that the Administration applies through circulars, guidance, or other documents issued by the Office of Management and Budget or the Office of Personnel Management.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA7F389119FA147319B11B9AB4AAE7772"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 6 months after completion of the review required in subsection (b), the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on the results of the review.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H2DFFAADB7E0C4A448DC62D4365F9FC13"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Air traffic controller staffing</header>
 <paragraph id="HD1FFC5F1337142E9B26AFF4B7DE1A9AB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Staffing report</header><text>Section 44506(e) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H65A62AB0AC3E411BA0ECD9596598DDAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) and (3) as paragraphs (3) and (4), respectively; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84D310CE4B3C44EFB946A7166D3EFAA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H76A2FDE3FA9C4ECC87A3DF64611D597D" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H25506D52C47445F3B9FBAE10AEF70A30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each facility in the system, the current certified professional controller staffing levels, the operational staffing targets for certified professional controllers, and the anticipated certified professional controller attrition for each of the next 3 years;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H18D82E96722F4521A28289D0670D410C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Staffing standard</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration and the exclusive bargaining representative of air traffic controllers certified under section 7111 of title 5, United States Code, shall jointly develop a staffing standard to determine the number of certified professional controllers and trainees needed to operate each air traffic control facility operated by the Administration. Once developed, this standard shall be used for the staffing report referenced in section 44506(e) of title 49, United States Code.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H73DC0E02D57F4EF0892E386DBA02B234"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Airway transportation system specialist staffing models</header>
 <paragraph id="H486695FFFB5E492F96336425913897F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall implement, after consultation with the National Academy of Sciences, and notwithstanding section 7106(b)(1) of title 5, United States Code, after negotiations with the exclusive bargaining representative of airway transportation system specialists certified under section 7111 of title 5, United States Code, appropriate airway transportation system specialists staffing levels for each of the Administration’s facilities that support the National Airspace System. If the Administrator and the exclusive bargaining representative are unable to reach agreement, they shall use the process set forth in clauses (i) through (v) and (vii) of section 40122(a)(2)(C) of title 49, United States Code, to resolve the dispute.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE23D1DE01EE4142B09B7AC96B3F1BCC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Airway transportation system specialists placement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon determination of staffing levels under paragraph (1), and notwithstanding section 7106(b)(1) of title 5, United States Code, the Administrator shall negotiate with the exclusive bargaining representative of airway transportation system specialists certified under section 7111 of title 5, United States Code, to develop and implement measures to place airway transportation system specialists at all relevant facilities of the Administration. If the Administrator and the exclusive bargaining representative are unable to reach agreement, they shall use the process set forth in clauses (i) through (v) and (vii) of section 40122(a)(2)(C) of title 49, United States Code, to resolve the dispute.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E5CBA5B4EC449DE99D1DD5C8D8FD24F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Aviation safety inspectors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 7106(b)(1) of title 5, United States Code, the Administrator shall negotiate with the exclusive bargaining representative of aviation safety inspectors certified under section 7111 of title 5, United States Code, regarding appropriate total staffing levels for aviation inspectors and facilities that support inspection activities of the Administration. If the Administrator and the exclusive bargaining representative are unable to reach agreement, they shall use the process set forth in clauses (i) through (v) and (vii) of section 40122(a)(2)(C) of title 49, United States Code, to resolve the dispute. Any agreement or award shall include a plan to implement such staffing levels.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7A9B37302A2E4C6284BADD5C682124D6"><enum>8.</enum><header>Anti-silos requirement</header>
 <subsection id="H8110F27B3F98469F8839F9D21F96F5EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Organizational streamlining</header><text>The Administrator shall take appropriate measures, including development of internal policies and procedures, to organize the Administration’s assignments of personnel in a manner that facilitates open communication and collaboration among the Administration’s employees across the Administration’s lines of business and offices. Such measures shall promote the cross-utilization of employees whenever feasible to leverage the employees’ knowledge and skill sets across disciplines.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H484AE038CBFC49CBB17040F19CB49FB3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on the measures required under subsection (a) and the effectiveness of such measures in reducing organizational barriers and stovepipes.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H38DC4C4D506E4818B7550691657F7E7A"><enum>9.</enum><header>Air traffic employees assigned to Guam</header>
 <subsection id="H2F1ECEB787774546BB7B50E35D98FDDE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Services for certain employees</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall provide military medical treatment facilities, commissary, and exchange access to employees of the Federal Aviation Administration assigned to Guam, their spouses, and their dependent children through the Defense Enrollment Eligibility Reporting System and the Real Time Automated Personnel Identification System.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H43BC598CD3444D85A1B92606D8662626"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reimbursement for expenses</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall reimburse the Secretary of Defense for expenses incurred by the Department of Defense for enrollment of Federal Aviation Administration employees, their spouses, and their dependent children for services provided under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HF505F53A08E04690BE648E16F0C5912F"><enum>10.</enum><header>Technical revisions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 40122(g)(2) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H557087C1FB174420816512A56FAC1DEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8070266F7EAA4796B41BBE629EEC5211"><enum>(A)</enum><text>striking <quote>(b)</quote> after <quote>2302</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EB6FBA9A70D461CA5181C77F44320E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>inserting <quote>prohibited personnel practices and</quote> before <quote>whistleblower protection</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6276F95210540409DCD9795C2C1998E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by—</text> <subparagraph id="H8AA5D35763154F2E94CD703E0B000048"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inserting <quote>3304,</quote> before <quote>3308–3320,</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB57E2479ED7E49C3A1ABEB52EB0CC149"><enum>(B)</enum><text>inserting <quote>3330a, 3330b, 3330c, and 3330d,</quote> before <quote>relating to veterans’ preference;</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4925B630D2404A5B8E37003659E21507"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I)(iii) by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H905EC371DD95427BB88080D5F08019F4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subparagraph (J) by striking <quote>leave.</quote> and inserting <quote>leave; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E7DE5618B2340AE8BD51240AFCA4111"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by inserting at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H7043F6CF2190473F82F18E3E0BDA9DBD" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H5562777A74FD4B468ED08D67A6A0C801"><enum>(K)</enum><text>section 5596 relating to back pay due to unjustified personnel action.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

