<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC6EBE4660A6D4675AB29DB5AC9B73334" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 1228 ENR: To provide for the appointment of members of the Board of Directors of the Office of Compliance to replace members whose terms expire during 2017, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Fifteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress><session display="yes">At the First Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Tuesday, the third day of January, two thousand and seventeen</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1228</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To provide for the appointment of members of the Board of Directors of the Office of Compliance to replace members whose terms expire during 2017, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H8D7E9DCF6B0F454B84A1A2E93C11F0DC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H63CDD675335B4E358CC55EFB1ECDA9C5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Appointment of members of Board of Directors of Office of Compliance</header> 
<subsection id="H84205B9A10924D9787E07D5CEE1BE24D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appointment of members</header> 
<paragraph id="H6EA3E820E0BD4DF9856A887C73A80529"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Members replacing members whose terms expire in March 2017</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the first sentence of section 301(e) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1381">2 U.S.C. 1381(e)</external-xref>), of the members of the Board of Directors of the Office of Compliance who are appointed to replace the 3 members whose terms expire in March 2017—</text> <subparagraph id="H78D62F550760490F88007E447D2E4CB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>one shall have a term of office of 3 years; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFF7B673F9106484BB1ADC4C17A88501B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>2 shall have a term of office of 4 years,</text> </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">as designated at the time of appointment by the persons specified in section 301(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1381">2 U.S.C. 1381(b)</external-xref>).</continuation-text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2318D743E3904FB88001495F2164CB73"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Members replacing members whose terms expire in May 2017</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with the first sentence of section 301(e) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1381">2 U.S.C. 1381(e)</external-xref>), the members of the Board of Directors of the Office of Compliance who are appointed to replace the 2 members whose terms expire in May 2017 shall each have a term of office of 5 years.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4A1A9E4AC072415881F0574522BCDC32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Service of current members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the second sentence of section 301(e) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1381">2 U.S.C. 1381(e)</external-xref>) or section 3 of the Office of Compliance Administrative and Technical Corrections Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/6">Public Law 114–6</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1381">2 U.S.C. 1381</external-xref> note)—</text> <paragraph id="H9242D072DCDC4D43BD49CC642887195D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an individual serving as a member of the Board of Directors of the Office of Compliance whose term expires in March 2017 may be reappointed to serve one additional term at the length designated under paragraph (1) of subsection (a), but may not be reappointed to any additional terms after that additional term expires; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H13A8A387F4384FF8B9330FAF1C85BDBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an individual serving as a member of the Board of Directors of the Office of Compliance whose term expires in May 2017 may be reappointed to serve one additional term at the length referred to in paragraph (2) of subsection (a), but may not be reappointed to any additional terms after that additional term expires.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5B87CCDCF46845BFA1A9D33B39BA68EC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Permitting members To serve until appointment of successors</header><text>Section 301(e) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1381">2 U.S.C. 1381(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8CF8D09C0A2D472FA0A29347939B3001" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H5A378AB264664ADE90A97A191AE7CB63"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Permitting service until appointment of successor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member of the Board may serve after the expiration of that member’s term until a successor has taken office.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H336F7ED82546449E81BEAB5EDDDE58AF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authority of Congressional leadership in making appointments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 301(b) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1381">2 U.S.C. 1381(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the period at the end of the second sentence and inserting the following: <quote>, who are authorized to take such steps as they consider appropriate to ensure the timely appointment of the members of the Board consistent with the requirements of this section.</quote>. </text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill> 


