<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1EEF7F7F45734E4095D2DDB0E534C8DF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2043 IH: Fair Day in Court for Kids Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2043</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide access to counsel for children and other vulnerable populations.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2B547C47919C4A12896ECBD39624E8DD" style="OLC">
 <section id="H03CE0529F259456F996DD2C18C935935" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Day in Court for Kids Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HEB9C9E0282F3435AA2A60FFFED21D578"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving immigration court efficiency and reducing costs by increasing access to legal information</header> <subsection id="H77AE018697C9410FAD60C042BE7030C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appointment of counsel in certain cases; right To review certain documents in removal proceedings</header><text>Section 240(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1229a">8 U.S.C. 1229a(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H44FE4F39BD6749F6BA3AC588B6D3988E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text> <subparagraph id="HA9151BBC4D9B4DC8BE7C9505C741A4DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <clause id="H5B5842DA22E247F3A1199E60EAB6114E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, at no expense to the Government,</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H5E80DBA669024A3DA881997C79DEF239"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking the comma at the end and inserting a semicolon;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50CDE8EC0076462289A3EFA51DD78AF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (B) and (C) as subparagraphs (D) and (E), respectively;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52A279A771614B1F9848D7C7C37CCE24"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC060253D80E0499882071AC912A8F383" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H2B99A1DC12A74987882B12AF99F60BCD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Attorney General may appoint or provide counsel, at Government expense, to aliens in immigration proceedings;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H131EFA181874424282811F11F9BA81B4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the alien shall, at the beginning of the proceedings or as expeditiously as possible, automatically receive a complete copy of all relevant documents in the possession of the Department of Homeland Security, including all documents (other than documents protected from disclosure by privilege, including national security information referred to in subparagraph (D), law enforcement sensitive information, and information prohibited from disclosure pursuant to any other provision of law) contained in the file maintained by the Government that includes information with respect to all transactions involving the alien during the immigration process (commonly referred to as an <quote>A-file</quote>), and all documents pertaining to the alien that the Department of Homeland Security has obtained or received from other government agencies, unless the alien waives the right to receive such documents by executing a knowing and voluntary written waiver in a language that he or she understands fluently;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CD17DE3C40B426699347AB715E3304C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), as redesignated, by striking <quote>, and</quote> and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA16EFAC209104B11885F9FB5B9A747FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9289CB36C54347E9AE40F757B26E2F4B" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H00EF488A25104B53BF412360CAD6012B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Failure to provide alien required documents</header><text>In the absence of a waiver under paragraph (4)(C), a removal proceeding may not proceed until the alien—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4650D296DFAD496293F907F433D6AE81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has received the documents as required under such paragraph; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC56536C8D31E49EB80EC789F2ABDA33D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been provided meaningful time to review and assess such documents.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF8D18EC3F7504C2CB1F4FDE8CA273CD3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification regarding the authority of the Attorney General To appoint counsel to aliens in
 immigration proceedings</header><text>Section 292 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1362">8 U.S.C. 1362</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H0C4767FE57A94A5387E0F1902E9C64A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>In any</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H40128F91B9234A519CA987D9979CD70B" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HE35EE97822E443759FD8FD250E1C863F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any proceeding conducted under section 235, 236, 238, 240, 241, or any other section of this Act,</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE372929860E49299934E6E50E0025E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a), as redesignated—</text> <subparagraph id="H9ABFFB988AEE40EFB155D238487E4AE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(at no expense to the Government)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAB1DF0159B442B097DCBB58EA6DBB86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>he shall</quote> and inserting <quote>the person shall</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H12A3442DC6D2423CA29C32F3CAAD580F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1BEB69EA6DB45EDB26CE31F9350AF5F" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HD4B70BCB875D47B49FD322F7C962927C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Access to counsel</header><text>The Attorney General may appoint or provide counsel to aliens in any proceeding conducted under section 235, 236, 238, 240, or 241 or any other section of this Act. The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that aliens have access to counsel inside all immigration detention and border facilities.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0D8C8749215F4487A038D3B2E78AA261"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appointment of counsel for children and vulnerable aliens</header>
 <paragraph id="HC984FF88D575472B8106C525FB04559B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 292 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1362">8 U.S.C. 1362</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (b), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H251D9565EF7644ACBEBFFCF33AC5DBFD" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H4BEB597872E54E4A8820674DABED7702"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Children and vulnerable aliens</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (b), the Attorney General shall appoint counsel, at the expense of the Government if necessary, at the beginning of the proceedings or as expeditiously as possible, to represent in such proceedings any alien who has been determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Attorney General to be—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6C9910FDF09A438DB9FAA1BEE456D431"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a child (as defined in section 101(b)(1) of this Act);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDFB2EFC3809745DB8ECCC199CB0AF27C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a particularly vulnerable individual, such as—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9794BDDE03674863BA2421D2D0B22FFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a person with a disability; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B65F583946C4874801BB912EF31C13F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a victim of abuse, torture, or violence; or</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD03F01E563004753B7516F44D3724901"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an individual whose circumstances are such that the appointment of counsel is necessary to help ensure fair resolution and efficient adjudication of the proceedings.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H886D4837983845578DE1A2C0FD482A04"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Extension to consolidated cases</header><text>If the Attorney General has consolidated the case of any alien for whom counsel was appointed under subsection (c) with that of any other alien, and that other alien does not have counsel, then the counsel appointed under subsection (c) shall be appointed to represent such other alien.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC96251074C9C4093875E5379E82DE829"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Executive Office of Immigration Review of the Department of Justice such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE7F8A5A90C547F19F5B59649CE82A6F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Attorney General shall promulgate regulations to implement section 292(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by paragraph (1), in accordance with the requirements set forth in section 3006A of title 18, United States Code.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5CF97843B7B6427F8853187F636E0672"><enum>3.</enum><header>Access by counsel and legal orientation at detention facilities</header>
 <subsection id="H22038352B83241299FEE0E097B9E6FD8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Access to counsel</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall facilitate access to counsel for all aliens detained in facilities under the supervision of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement or of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, including providing information to aliens in detention about legal services programs at detention facilities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H96D53F68B51042D7B662BA1719DEB0E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Access to legal orientation programs</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall establish procedures to ensure that legal orientation programs are available for all detained aliens, including aliens held in U.S. Customs and Border Protection facilities, to inform such aliens of the basic procedures of immigration hearings, their rights relating to those hearings under Federal immigration laws, information that may deter such aliens from filing frivolous legal claims, and any other information that the Attorney General considers appropriate, such as a contact list of potential legal resources and providers. Access to legal orientation programs shall not be limited by the alien’s current immigration status, prior immigration history, or potential for immigration relief.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB6C714EFB65A459C9240BB43F43F1EA4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pilot project for nondetained aliens in removal proceedings</header><text>The Attorney General shall develop and administer a 2-year pilot program at not fewer than 2 immigration courts to provide nondetained aliens with pending asylum claims access to legal information. At the conclusion of the pilot program, the Attorney General shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that describes the extent to which nondetained aliens are provided with access to counsel.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBEA2D6EB722443B891BB1F63853787AD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Executive Office of Immigration Review of the Department of Justice such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HB2220B06ED5D4A7883BAC9B248DF87F2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Case management pilot program to increase court appearance rates</header>
 <subsection id="H166463D6F75C49498640674818171C7F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Contract authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish a pilot program to increase the court appearance rates of aliens described in section 292(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 2(c)(1), by contracting with nongovernmental, community-based organizations to provide appropriate case management services to such aliens. This pilot program shall not be used to monitor individuals designated as unaccompanied alien children under Section 462 of the Homeland Security Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H59E85CE84C4E4C59AA5736B3EA79B32C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope of services</header><text>Case management services provided under subsection (a) shall include assisting aliens with—</text> <paragraph id="H33E7FB68A1C6410AAE6EAFFA85BC2229"><enum>(1)</enum><text>accessing legal counsel;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52047E7E5A794F129090FD64B4088FE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>complying with court-imposed deadlines and other legal obligations;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF3C0FFC05A647B8A60A426BC1D7C9B2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>procuring appropriate housing;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H38B1CE77F98B42228260753D424519CC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>enrolling their minor children in school; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0DDFD46B6DD4382B7C93E69330A5268"><enum>(5)</enum><text>acquiring health services, including, if needed, mental health services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC64E8B1E35B2495C8CD42EB2E83EB3E9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Homeland Security such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HC9072024E0404E7F977EE2C54E82FDE2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on access to counsel</header>
 <subsection id="H9F62B8E59A5747329E0B69D5D48322A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than December 31 of each year, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall prepare and submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name> regarding the extent to which aliens described in section 292(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 2(c)(1), have been provided access to counsel.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H36A0579F22EB4DC38D45B645B87FDC4C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report submitted under paragraph (a) shall include, for the immediately preceding 1-year period—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB25833CA2084478EB625EF2D89CDE593"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number and percentage of aliens described in paragraphs (1), (2), and (3), respectively, of section 292(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 2(c)(1), who were represented by counsel, including information specifying—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC9AFA1A9C2794D5FAF0327E710335F4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the stage of the legal process at which the alien was represented; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FE2175A00FB4C779F9B33B754C8290F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the alien was in government custody; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H912DD209BD504237A0E9F87F7545D85E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number and percentage of aliens who received legal orientation presentations.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF4DDDC6E73B94271B178082435DD7058"><enum>6.</enum><header>Motions to reopen</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 240(c)(7)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1229a">8 U.S.C. 1229a(c)(7)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6836A8D515194E09853FDBCBF3F953DD" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H00F3BCB0F12F48D283B1E26E4A0A137F"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Special rule for children and other vulnerable aliens</header><text>If the Attorney General fails to appoint counsel for an alien in violation of section 292(c)—</text> <subclause id="H1D26000D25C74A65B38330744ADEEE99"><enum>(I)</enum><text>no limitation under this paragraph pertaining to the filing of any motion under this paragraph by such alien shall apply; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4F74B98FAB374BFA89BDBE23F3C4FFA0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the filing of such a motion shall stay the removal of the alien.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section></legis-body></bill> 

