<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H365EB92FEEDC490A979DB0280982FC79" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3892 IH: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide an exception for certain spun-off voluntary employees’ beneficiary associations to the limitation on the exemption from tax on unrelated business taxable income of amounts set aside for qualified benefits.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3892</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170928">September 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson of Indiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide an exception for certain spun-off voluntary
			 employees’ beneficiary associations to the limitation on the exemption
			 from tax on unrelated business taxable income of amounts set aside for
			 qualified benefits.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H815F4E203ABE4001B8863C150B198EEB" style="OLC">
		<section id="HE5F32E7FAAC549BCA1AD2C2874CFF575" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Exception from tax on unrelated business taxable income for certain spun-off voluntary employees’
			 beneficiary associations</header>
 <subsection id="H1D890DAAAFB74DF781C99735C676043F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/512">Section 512(a)(3)(E)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7773C88BDA6C4FF8A03CF95C806B139E" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H06A3C388012649D59E4590885ED199F9"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Certain spun-off voluntary employees’ beneficiary associations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subparagraph shall not apply to any voluntary employees’ beneficiary association described in section 501(c)(9) for any taxable year if—</text>
 <subclause id="HC6CE69BB98AA47969AA3120C43A3747E"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such organization was originally established before the date of the enactment of this clause by an employer to provide benefits described in section 501(c)(9) for eligible employees and retirees and their dependents and beneficiaries,</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H42E91EBCC3804BF0A63842FB3D734915"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the only benefits provided by such organization are post-retirement medical and life benefits,</text> </subclause><subclause id="H8D39E10852444FDB9CF017E4E8C26248"><enum>(III)</enum><text>such employer has (before the beginning of such taxable year) delegated all authority and responsibility with respect to such organization to one or more independent persons who do not have an employment relationship with the members entitled to benefits from such organization,</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HCA08DDFFBA57400B977751ECE22ED738"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>no member entitled to benefits from such organization is entitled to benefits from any other organization described in section 501(c)(9) as a result of employment with such employer, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6EF4D5859EB94DBFB931F0116CABA149"><enum>(V)</enum><text>such employer, as of the close of such taxable year, has no obligation to make any contribution to such organization and has not made a contribution to such organization at any time during the 11-taxable-year period ending with such taxable year.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBDBFFCC3396D47C1A8840494BBC7E37A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2017.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

