<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1281CBA344A24E6F80395A6424655376" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1566 IH: National Opposition to Hate, Assault, and Threats to Equality Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1566</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170316">March 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide incentives for hate crime reporting, grants for State-run hate crime hotlines, a Federal
			 private right of action for victims of hate crimes, and additional
			 penalties for individuals convicted under the Matthew Shephard and James
			 Byrd, Jr. Hate Crimes Prevention Act.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HCC637F721B3D4BA286A07D334C367FC1" style="OLC">
 <section id="HF6842166149A4244B69155527954F5D8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Opposition to Hate, Assault, and Threats to Equality Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or <quote><short-title>NO HATE Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3DD5FDCE689144E887FF7D5359711618"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA16FB7BE0B9E4FE9A9B4AF491076A306"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The incidence of violence motivated by the actual or perceived race, color, religion, national origin, gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, or disability of the victim, known as hate crimes or crimes motivated by bias, poses a serious national problem.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFC9AD038261A43868F06F028AB8338F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Such violence disrupts the tranquility and safety of communities and is deeply divisive.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H97FF1DDC229C4AA48128394282EC5C1D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A prominent characteristic of a violent crime motivated by bias is that it not only devastates the actual victim and the family and friends of the victim, but also frequently ravages the community sharing the traits that caused the victim to be selected.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC91DFDDB5DDC4738AE9C533331B6BA58"><enum>(4)</enum><text>According to data obtained by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the incidence of such violence increased in 2015, the most recent year for which data is available, in comparison to prior years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC973AE9403240AF9EA5BC8C4CEB41D6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Hate Crimes Statistics Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/101/275">Public Law 101–275</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/534">28 U.S.C. 534</external-xref> note) and the Matthew Shepard and James Byrd, Jr. Hate Crimes Prevention Act (division E of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/84">Public Law 111–84</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 2835) have enabled Federal authorities to understand and, where appropriate, investigate and prosecute hate crimes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA006614D9CC4148869C83376AAD5D8B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>However, a complete understanding of the national problem posed by hate crimes is hindered by incomplete data from Federal, State, and local jurisdictions obtained through the Uniform Crime Reports program authorized under section 534 of title 28, United States Code, and administered by the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD917515F03704F7FB72C19CF9A514B83"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Increased implementation of the National Incident-Based Reporting System will enable the Federal Bureau of Investigation to obtain more detailed and accurate information on many crimes, including violence motivated by the actual or perceived race, color, religion, national origin, gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, or disability of the victim.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD465F29E62944356A91EABF2EAC7782D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>State-run hotlines that direct victims or witnesses of hate crimes to law enforcement or local support services will allow State and local law enforcement agencies, as well as local community-based service providers, to understand hate crimes more fully and to act accordingly.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEA49B6BEF97F47109F2A0DBF554AEDDB"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A Federal private right of action provides an additional option of recourse for individuals who are targeted for violence based on actual or perceived race, color, religion, national origin, gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, or disability.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2AED5FBB0B654946A04E0989EED14810"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Many perpetrators of crimes motivated by bias may benefit from educational programming or volunteer service conducted in conjunction with, under the guidance of, or with the input of the community targeted by the hate crime.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB1DB1396748F4451981A626509B0E899"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Federal financial assistance with regard to certain violent crimes motivated by bias enables Federal, State, and local authorities to work together as partners in the investigation and prosecution of such crimes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBBF5A8C7C84242B6BFABB774E53F32B1"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The problem of crimes motivated by bias is sufficiently serious, widespread, and interstate in nature as to warrant Federal financial assistance to States and local jurisdictions.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HAADBC25303B1470181A3A314C9D88267"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reporting of hate crimes</header>
 <subsection id="HEAA808C3B62A4BA19BBB9E14ACF23109"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A708B5A5E854C2CB268EB6E05F338D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>hate crime</term> means a criminal offense against a person or property motivated in whole or in part by an offender’s bias against a race, color, religion, national origin, gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, or disability; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56DDC60C5311407DABD925938DE5F319"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Uniform Crime Reports</term> means the reports authorized under section 534 of title 28, United States Code, and administered by the Federal Bureau of Investigation that compile nationwide criminal statistics for use—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5DC4BDE80F0F4218B1DEE80464841B97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in law enforcement administration, operation, and management; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H436D33B60BE44BAD9CBF105CBE6BEBFA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to assess the nature and type of crime in the United States.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF544F82F0D241D193438EA0B9CE3C29"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation grants</header>
 <paragraph id="H92C07C0C5F5E408E99C8F9929995ED3C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may make grants to States and units of local government to assist the State or unit of local government in implementing the National Incident-Based Reporting System, including to train employees in identifying and classifying hate crimes in the National Incident-Based Reporting System.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H65798F65432F48D7B0E0A2C6615D3707"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making grants under paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall give priority to States and units of local government with larger populations.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3D102D0676749C1932543BEADBA426E"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reporting</header>
				<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2AE3ECF8C2C46BE940FCCBFDE0CF3B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compliance</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H82C59241D4044B42AEF4DF4C1E473609"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), in each fiscal year beginning after the date that is 3 years after the date on which a State or unit of local government first receives a grant under subsection (b), the State or unit of local government shall provide to the Attorney General, through the Uniform Crime Reporting system, information pertaining to hate crimes committed in that jurisdiction during the preceding fiscal year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B0C21C2466448AB93E12308252C3691"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extensions; waiver</header><text>The Attorney General—</text> <clause id="H063D4D9943B3404BBBE6B2E83232BF48"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may provide a 120-day extension to a State or unit of local government that is making good faith efforts to comply with subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HA038192736FD485F8E116BD7F9CF21DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall waive the requirements of subparagraph (A) if compliance with that subparagraph by a State or unit of local government would be unconstitutional under the constitution of the State or of the State in which the unit of local government is located, respectively.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16147C82A3B64F94A69D89F2E61069D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Failure to comply</header><text>If a State or unit of local government that receives a grant under subsection (b) fails to substantially comply with paragraph (1) of this subsection, the State or unit of local government shall repay the grant in full, plus reasonable interest and penalty charges allowable by law or established by the Attorney General.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB78816119A3749009EC8E2897CFB3813"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grants for State-run hate crime hotlines</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H97F646A443DC4F0AB8C3290C595BEE88"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>hate crime</term> means a criminal offense against a person or property motivated in whole or in part by an offender’s bias against a race, color, religion, national origin, gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, or disability.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HCFB49C32AC9D4F4A8FB84D0F8E37118E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header>
 <paragraph id="H265F2C3038774F87B1DE80F9F44E3A84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall make grants to States to create State-run hate crime reporting hotlines.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7B4CF114A3D04D438EFA9BA2BA5B0A96"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant period</header><text>A grant made under paragraph (1) shall be for a period of not more than 5 years.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFEEBE4DC6B26498A83B9409F4178C60E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Hotline requirements</header><text>A State shall ensure, with respect to a hotline funded by a grant under subsection (b), that—</text> <paragraph id="HFCAB6404C7DA4BE89CE0355A8DD82833"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the hotline directs individuals to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1F0F723545344834A9127CFEE489DD1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>law enforcement if appropriate; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B740257DE484E5B86ABFE57BA465EE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>local support services;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H77A35ADBF31E49169A04581E6F65E582"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any personally identifiable information that an individual provides to an agency of the State through the hotline is not directly or indirectly disclosed, without the consent of the individual, to—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0D3228C960E4327923A19036D76D6FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any other agency of that State;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE18C783DA63040AC9A94D632D2D97BC2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDAAC64F5CB2D4AE48B7C172B6926570B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Federal Government; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9691E4A257324370A7A5CEB52690EAB7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other person or entity;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H64C8EA72E47B4FBD94AA17D3D5A2162F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the staff members who operate the hotline are trained to be knowledgeable about—</text> <subparagraph id="H7905F5B03EA64A758639B7A3E09E5579"><enum>(A)</enum><text>applicable Federal, State, and local hate crime laws; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AC1FDC738F548B79D0B42A07EC2AFF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>local law enforcement resources and applicable local support services; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3FEE9E16A3D48F6B1DC744E338C5BCB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the hotline is accessible to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H913FCC87D4AA4E188DEBF150C53C2971"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individuals with limited English proficiency, where appropriate; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D4AB9055C3E4EF2A300958883C00EE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>individuals with disabilities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H614EFB62EA7547C3AE6D6FE5FBB24ABC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>The Attorney General shall issue guidance to States on best practices for implementing the requirements of subsection (c).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H33325135A01C4E2B88D2CC8DC72024CE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Private right of action for crimes motivated by actual or perceived race, color, religion, or
			 national origin</header>
 <subsection id="HB8C45FFA120E4BF7BEA39883DEA043A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="HDE6860F6652842A9B698A58812252867"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>crime</term> means an act or series of acts that would constitute a criminal offense under Federal or State law, whether or not the act or acts—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD7BD3E242A5D4AFAA721E377667A7208"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have actually resulted in criminal charges, prosecution, or conviction; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H393FCACD72AE468681F4F0BE36FCBC7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>were committed in the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States or in a Federal prison; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H527F165EE5AA42C7BEB33AB9919FC8AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>crime motivated by actual or perceived race, color, religion, or national origin</term> means a crime committed because of actual or perceived race, color, religion, or national origin.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8A61CDB123A74FCFA11F65DCDDC4C5AA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>Pursuant to the affirmative power of Congress to enact this section under section 2 of the Thirteenth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, as well as under section 8 of Article I of the Constitution, the purpose of this section is to protect the civil rights of victims of crimes motivated by actual or perceived race, color, religion, or national origin and to promote public safety, health, and activities affecting interstate commerce by establishing a Federal civil rights cause of action for victims of crime motivated by actual or perceived race, color, religion, or national origin.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAE892F483A40489C9F3C2AD453725176"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Right To be free from certain crimes</header><text>All persons within the United States shall have the right to be free from crimes motivated by actual or perceived race, color, religion, or national origin.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H53F2B1294BB64F45B2F8352036A8FCEA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cause of action</header><text>A person (including a person who acts under color of any statute, ordinance, regulation, custom, or usage of any State) who commits a crime motivated by actual or perceived race, color, religion, or national origin, and thus deprives another of the right declared in subsection (c), shall be liable to the party injured, in an action for the recovery of compensatory and punitive damages, injunctive and declaratory relief, and such other relief as a court may deem appropriate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1AA07F66AEDA464B8BEAFE298B404C63"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Damages</header><text>In any civil action brought under this section in which the plaintiff prevails, the court—</text> <paragraph id="H898CEE7620804455B1CC12560A59D047"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall award treble compensatory damages and a reasonable attorney's fee; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H103A5C558464402380D7E7DD82E56B27"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may, in its discretion, award equitable relief.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H635430F7227342C7A80CA4C17A8D69E3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitations</header> <paragraph id="H36BFDD8094DC4A99A525EC42019D3632"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Period of limitations</header><text>An action under this section may not be commenced later than 3 years after the date of the act complained of.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H625A4823120E46CBA3A487F371EEDC2A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize a cause of action under subsection (d) for—</text> <subparagraph id="H45F952DE421D4C5CBF779AE454977775"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a random act unrelated to actual or perceived race, color, religion, or national origin; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26D90CD3890D4DCF9A1C4EBCA8936C51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an act that cannot be demonstrated, by a preponderance of the evidence, to be a crime motivated by actual or perceived race, color, religion, or national origin.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6EAC65516EFF4A28918CDCDD25A85267"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Concurrent jurisdiction</header><text>The district courts of the United States shall have original jurisdiction, concurrent with State courts, of an action under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0308906EE3EE43F985F5A7E1DFBAE97E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>No prior criminal action</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require a prior criminal complaint, prosecution, or conviction to establish the elements of a cause of action under subsection (d).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HD834956EE9E64D0E8C766EB3DC28C31A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Private right of action for crimes motivated by actual or perceived religion, national origin,
			 gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, or disability</header>
 <subsection id="H48FC6033F2784F54B06562DF9BB10D9B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H8F439070CFF144D1A1221A837ABC48E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>crime</term> means an act or series of acts that would constitute a criminal offense under Federal or State law, whether or not the act or acts have actually resulted in criminal charges, prosecution, or conviction; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B64A71ACA38491288F0188CD197BF87"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>crime motivated by actual or perceived religion, national origin, gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, or disability</term> means a crime committed because of actual or perceived religion, national origin, gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, or disability.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H32BFE7BCEDF74A83B9D52A51BB86AE8E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>Pursuant to the affirmative power of Congress to enact this section under clause 3 of section 8 of Article I of the Constitution of the United States (commonly known as the <term>Commerce Clause</term>), the purpose of this section is to protect the civil rights of victims of crimes motivated by actual or perceived religion, national origin, gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, or disability and to promote public safety, health, and activities affecting interstate commerce by establishing a Federal civil rights cause of action for victims of crime motivated by actual or perceived religion, national origin, gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, or disability.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H44FCD11F54E142449DAFCF0463523698"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Right To be free from certain crimes</header><text>All persons within the United States shall have the right to be free from crimes motivated by actual or perceived religion, national origin, gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, or disability.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H497B0F390E414367AFA3EA992B5ED7E7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cause of action</header>
 <paragraph id="H65FDBC964C824613B7295D70D5C25CA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person (including a person who acts under color of any statute, ordinance, regulation, custom, or usage of any State), in any circumstance described in paragraph (2) or within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States or a Federal prison, who commits a crime motivated by actual or perceived religion, national origin, gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, or disability, and thus deprives another of the right declared in subsection (c), shall be liable to the party injured, in an action for the recovery of compensatory and punitive damages, injunctive and declaratory relief, and such other relief as a court may deem appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H97BCA10C7EE44E1F975575D49B8112BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Circumstances described</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the circumstances described in this paragraph are that—</text> <subparagraph id="HBDB8419555E640F08F877D89A468E992"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the conduct described in paragraph (1) occurs during the course of, or as the result of, the travel of the defendant or the victim—</text>
 <clause id="H9AAF1897242C4BA7A8A04BD4A43DCB26"><enum>(i)</enum><text>across a State line or national border; or</text> </clause><clause id="H5A38A4E178404513A1590C8EC5AD23C7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>using a channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1068B920B149440D8122D08278870F7E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the defendant uses a channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce in connection with the conduct described in paragraph (1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H966891DBE72A419CAADBE1A63F4C5DFB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in connection with the conduct described in paragraph (1), the defendant employs a firearm, dangerous weapon, explosive or incendiary device, or other weapon that has traveled in interstate or foreign commerce;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEE3C09F233B4E459CDCA6E5104D13E0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the conduct described in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="H89B6700C1A25429ABB2FFEBD2A720821"><enum>(i)</enum><text>interferes with commercial or other economic activity in which the victim is engaged at the time of the conduct; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H70FA06ED0DDB48EEB48997376E104685"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>otherwise affects interstate or foreign commerce.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7BEE6535630B4EDCA0F162F3C68D45DE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Damages</header><text>In any civil action brought under this section in which the plaintiff prevails, the court—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC65DBA93AEC54A3C8ECFF6CE18258A1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall award treble compensatory damages and a reasonable attorney's fee; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2B4AD0987C543E6A24097350F505E39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may, in its discretion, award equitable relief.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HECF2533D282B45DDB90BC86D36B0D2DE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitations</header>
 <paragraph id="H7D65C5ED5D174D2EBACBA12481A351F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Period of limitation</header><text>An action under this section may not be commenced later than 3 years after the date of the act complained of.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H38DD21F2523049D89765085CCF40827B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize a cause of action under subsection (d) for—</text> <subparagraph id="HC6E36A307475416C99C2F5BF584FC5FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a random act unrelated to actual or perceived religion, national origin, gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, or disability; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB39F4F0F1F6145BF9F507311B2E856B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an act that cannot be demonstrated, by a preponderance of the evidence, to be a crime motivated by actual or perceived religion, national origin, gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, or disability.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6D61D8FED13E40818AB9559AD51D7A76"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Concurrent jurisdiction</header><text>The district courts of the United States shall have original jurisdiction, concurrent with State courts, of an action under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF80E68635D24B559BE7AE7531A07096"><enum>(h)</enum><header>No prior criminal action</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to require a prior criminal complaint, prosecution, or conviction to establish the elements of a cause of action under subsection (d).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H402EFA0577BE4D5D9DE37B72E62CC73E"><enum>7.</enum><header>Additional criminal penalties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 249 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE2FAE44116C4AD9B93AA0FBE3E7652B" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HB5FB57CDFB194EFEBBB6D0C7F98C72A6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Supervised release</header><text>If a court includes, as a part of a sentence of imprisonment imposed for a violation of subsection (a), a requirement that the defendant be placed on a term of supervised release after imprisonment under section 3583, the court may order, as an explicit condition of supervised release, that the defendant undertake educational classes or community service directly related to the community harmed by the defendant's offense.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


