<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H48625E9D1E4E4013AA8E2BC6B0FCC562" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3030 IH: Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3030</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170622">June 22, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000244">Mr. Sensenbrenner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000594">Mr. Paulsen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001111">Mr. Crist</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001077">Mr. Coffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000608">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Thomas J. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Permanent Select Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To help prevent acts of genocide and other atrocity crimes, which threaten national and
			 international security, by enhancing United States Government capacities
			 to prevent, mitigate, and respond to such crises.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF3EB34103AB54B8AB938F3BF7F294DF2" style="OLC">
		<section id="HB96F22B9DD8345D594A0C80EA092F077" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H3EC645C8DA314807B22565CC0FE3AA4C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HED3BCF410FE648EBA503C74D6CCD05D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc>
					<toc-entry idref="HB96F22B9DD8345D594A0C80EA092F077" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8D16E723BDF14C81AD536CE803639B59" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H45AFEE26F0DE401D97CAADA06312BA4F" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H28F9328CDCC14875B673A9FD925AA0AF" level="section">Sec. 4. Statement of policy regarding genocide and other atrocity crimes prevention.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5931082491554296A39549CD1F3793DE" level="section">Sec. 5. Mass Atrocities Task Force.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HDD60CE200DFF4380912653E599C28C62" level="section">Sec. 6. Training of Foreign Service officers in conflict and atrocity crimes prevention.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4AEE6F82153F44C5B566CE2B7A47C019" level="section">Sec. 7. Report of the Director of National Intelligence.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H7BCF7F5C3DFD432DBC8B6F7CDC3E16C7" level="section">Sec. 8. Complex Crises Fund.</toc-entry></toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="H8D16E723BDF14C81AD536CE803639B59"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="HFA0389FF33244A6FA268D233F99434BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The nature of genocide and other atrocity crimes, including war crimes, crimes against humanity, and ethnic cleansing, includes shocking acts of violence perpetrated by governments and non-state actors, which have killed millions of civilians and other innocent individuals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HECD1A03441AC43339CC51EAA01E69BF5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The commitment to prevent acts of genocide and other atrocity crimes has been a centerpiece of policy by consecutive administrations of the United States Government.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C195E757B574406BBF939EE15D9368C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States was the first country in the world to sign the Convention on the Prevention and Punishment of the Crime of Genocide, signed at Paris December 9, 1948, and President Ronald Reagan signed implementing legislation allowing the United States to become a party to the Convention on November 25, 1988.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE956F16A08A4346963F782050A6454B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In the 2006 National Security Strategy, President George W. Bush highlighted the <quote>moral imperative that states take action to prevent and punish genocide</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DC755BA0948434C91F7F97E1F914377"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In 2008, the bipartisan Genocide Prevention Task Force, which was co-chaired by former Secretary of Defense William Cohen and former Secretary of State Madeleine Albright—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFBFA956234264AB489C6B22DFA11F924"><enum>(A)</enum><text>stated <quote>genocide and mass atrocities also threaten core U.S. national interests</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE85DA49F086F44FD812A8CCB550EF122"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommended the creation of <quote>a new standing interagency mechanism for analysis of threats [of genocide and other mass atrocities] and coordination of appropriate preventive action</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A1BCE0642684C7B9920FB6545608A34"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In December 2010, the Senate unanimously passed Senate Concurrent Resolution 71, which recognized the United States <quote>national interest in helping to prevent and mitigate acts of genocide and other mass atrocities against civilians, and supporting and encouraging efforts to develop a whole of government approach to prevent and mitigate such acts</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H95E6A180E57D46E4BC2026018447211B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In 2012, President Obama, in Presidential Study Directive 10, which ordered the creation of the Atrocities Prevention Board, stated that he would ensure that the United States Government has the required structures, tools, and mechanisms to better prevent and respond to atrocity crimes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEAC907FC51DF4371A79CB4CF9560D75B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In February 2014, James Clapper, the former Director of National Intelligence, stated in his annual national security threat assessment to Congress—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5D5805EDB76D41E48BF15B8C0D6FBD8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text><quote>The overall risk of mass atrocities worldwide will probably increase in 2014 and beyond.</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA70E9127F2D4F0494FACA3B2BD3BC30"><enum>(B)</enum><text><quote>Many countries at risk of mass atrocities will likely be open to influence to prevent or mitigate them.</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H499A7FA00E2B40CF80F14B36D161A5C3"><enum>(C)</enum><text><quote>Much of the world will almost certainly turn to the United States for leadership to prevent and respond to mass atrocities.</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H17AD59A848274943951411119FA60396"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In February 2016, former Director of National Intelligence Clapper stated, in his annual national security threat assessment to Congress, <quote>Risks of atrocities, large-scale violence, and regime-threatening instability will remain elevated in 2016.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BD7435DAC0E4458BC63BC38B45BC9E5"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The United States can strengthen its atrocity crimes prevention and peacebuilding efforts by—</text> <subparagraph id="HA014A7C367DB4AB79B0D9D5C548E8828"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supporting civil society which serves a central role in promoting nonviolent conflict resolution and supporting early warning;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD87A6C6EDDA74938B66381553E2D9DF9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enhancing cooperation and understanding among ethnic and religious groups, communities, and factions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFEE883F37D54B38959059D2C7C17E23"><enum>(C)</enum><text>working with the international community to ensure shared responsibility by enhancing multilateral and regional mechanisms that seek to prevent genocide and other atrocity crimes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF0383C5287641D5A85BF515363967BC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>promoting effective accountability mechanisms to deter individuals and entities that may incite or commit genocide or other atrocity crimes; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAE1430F9EE24BB0BB7F17324FDD0D3A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>implementing policies that hold accountable individuals and entities that incite or commit genocide or other atrocity crimes.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H45AFEE26F0DE401D97CAADA06312BA4F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H82F76BB7E10949C7809C58275076FE92"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Atrocity crimes; mass atrocities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>atrocity crimes</term> and <term>mass atrocities</term> mean large scale and deliberate acts of violence against civilians and include genocide, war crimes, crimes against humanity, and ethnic cleansing.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1EEB35A0E054E32965209AD3C2FA30C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Genocide</header><text>The term <term>genocide</term> has the meaning given the term in section 1091(a) of title 18, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H37CA686D0ED548DA8D5EFF953268C15C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Peacebuilding</header><text>The term <term>peacebuilding</term> means nonviolent activities designed to prevent conflict through—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H026021C0F82D411091C83D455676F046"><enum>(A)</enum><text>addressing root causes of violence;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77DB44B6AEA040909B5F97F4F771DF54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promoting sustainable peace;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD52C92A5485C47439905A0858A36EBDE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>delegitimizing violence as a dispute resolution strategy;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FBE776A4B1449B6BC8CFE2A00744D09"><enum>(D)</enum><text>building capacity within society to peacefully manage disputes, including the capacity of governments to address citizen grievances; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C636B5EA5954CD5B15DCA471CD4C72C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>reducing vulnerability to triggers that may spark violence.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H84EE40DF6EB8464FB19854AF9479C07B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD267FEF1F694C02B7A500A4247A1EBB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>War crime</header><text>The term <term>war crime</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2441(c) of title 18, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H28F9328CDCC14875B673A9FD925AA0AF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Statement of policy regarding genocide and other atrocity crimes prevention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1A53ADC29930443E8DDC6D8EE7B5DE2B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to regard the prevention of genocide and other atrocity crimes as a core national security interest and a core moral responsibility;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F126D4F251F43DA9603314278AB15D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to mitigate threats to United States security by addressing the root causes of insecurity and violent conflict to prevent—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF92DF41E91D54A37AC13666B920335FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the mass slaughter of civilians;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD22F226C722B4CD2AEE14C312A8B2C29"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conditions that prompt internal displacement and the flow of refugees across borders; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7094673EDBAD43A198B2CF29B4364B6B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other violence that wreaks havoc on regional stability and livelihoods;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF11FBB178F4645C9974ABF07CDE97119"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to enhance our Nation’s capacity to identify, prevent, address, and respond to the drivers of atrocity crimes and violent conflict as part of our humanitarian, development, and strategic interests;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99C5B1C122274C44817D1028C253EDEB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to pursue a Government-wide strategy to prevent and respond to the risk of genocide and other atrocity crimes by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8C671878C89847D4AB4C8902AE833D73"><enum>(A)</enum><text>strengthening the diplomatic, risk analysis and monitoring, strategic planning, early warning, and response capacities of the United States Government;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79D8C747083D4A9BB883D1457A0600C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improving the use of foreign assistance to respond early, effectively, and urgently in order to address the root causes and drivers of violence, systemic patterns of human rights abuses, and atrocity crimes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB58FCE0A0E504944B735F1BBC11CA12B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>strengthening diplomatic response and the use of foreign assistance to support transitional justice measures, including criminal accountability, for past atrocity crimes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B810BF54C6C4AA6AB1F41F9D8D28E8B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>supporting international atrocity crimes prevention, conflict prevention, peacekeeping, and peacebuilding mechanisms;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00768C84512F45E78A881ED03536180F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>supporting and strengthening local civil society, including human rights defenders and others working to help prevent and respond to atrocity crimes, and protecting their ability to receive support from and partner with civil society at large; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2B97091E75047A0A96898F7E0C57058"><enum>(F)</enum><text>promoting financial transparency and enhancing anti-corruption initiatives as part of addressing a root cause of insecurity; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H41C810F685F24818B70EC6B32FC1177F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to employ a variety of unilateral, bilateral, and multilateral means to prevent and respond to conflicts and atrocity crimes by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9E1ACFA9CD38485D8E0B7450D3AC6195"><enum>(A)</enum><text>placing a high priority on timely, preventive diplomatic efforts; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF16A25234E94BE183FFD3E44156ADBE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>exercising a leadership role in promoting international efforts to end crises peacefully.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H5931082491554296A39549CD1F3793DE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Mass Atrocities Task Force</header>
 <subsection id="HB4CC3CEEB307402594DE49C04384B26F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The President shall instruct the Secretary to establish a Mass Atrocities Task Force (referred to in this section as the <quote>Task Force</quote>) with the mandate—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1C8ACF6B3A0044E98F2994B9E5B8B99D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to strengthen the Department of State’s efforts at atrocity prevention and response; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5D7AA9B8D22F43C889915876694A3E8A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to assist other departments and agencies in their efforts to do the same.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA220EFC2C07F476192043FFBE1D85819"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Leadership</header><text>The Under Secretary of State for Civilian Security, Democracy, and Human Rights, or another position of equivalent rank, shall serve as the Chair of the Task Force and shall report to the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H13607C20231C4C4A801A06B59EBAF2E6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>Under the direction of the Chair, the Task Force shall—</text> <paragraph id="H462DC2D2287841C99D4FD344C5DDCEDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>meet regularly to ensure that atrocity crimes and the risk of atrocity crimes throughout the world are adequately considered and addressed;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFFC1CB4396E74AD78FF71EA33C75AD7D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>facilitate the development and execution of policies and tools to enhance the capacity of the United States to prevent and respond to atrocity crimes worldwide;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56B0173EBF5846A0A531D72E61CD3A09"><enum>(3)</enum><text>monitor developments throughout the world that heighten the risk of atrocity crimes;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7726C77A061F4D97ABBAEF97F3BA5336"><enum>(4)</enum><text>analyze and closely review specific atrocity crimes threats or situations of heightened concern;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7483D2BBC41241B7A6FA5E1193C9D8EB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify any gaps in United States foreign policy concerning regions or particular countries related to atrocity crimes prevention and response;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H077706C7253E4176AD42F0529D978E16"><enum>(6)</enum><text>incorporate lessons learned from past United States Government efforts to prevent and respond to atrocity crimes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1BB2A17DB7E45B3BDE7241DDB321D0D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>provide the Secretary with recommendations and potential improvements to policies, programs, resources, and tools related to atrocity crimes prevention and response;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7B1355C7D4A4A259023D613E796DBD0"><enum>(8)</enum><text>coordinate the Department of State’s engagement in interagency processes led by the National Security Council that share the Task Force’s objectives;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H190F6BFF06BB4DFFB21D51EF1666900B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>conduct outreach, including consultations, not less frequently than biannually, with representatives of nongovernmental organizations dedicated to atrocity crimes prevention and response and other appropriate parties—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3C99685C607440A89AA2EDFD8C606FCA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to receive assistance for the Task Force’s efforts to address emerging atrocity crimes threats or situations and develop new or improved policies and tools; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72012DEA21A745C59AB8E52EDB89D172"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide an appropriate public understanding of the work of the Task Force;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1EEA259D4D743E5B48612EEDC2C601F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>in carrying out paragraphs (1) through (9), focus on particular ways for the United States Government to develop, strengthen, and enhance its capabilities to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H89A4CAD485EA42839F875AC1709D084B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>monitor, receive early warning of, and coordinate responses to potential atrocity crimes;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEDD220C830B48B4B241908572BA33E0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>deter and isolate perpetrators of atrocity crimes through all available authorities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H793AF64EF9BF435B99C0179B0CD99EAC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promote criminal accountability and deny impunity for perpetrators of atrocity crimes within the United States and throughout the world;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78D25AC80335444F9F1B9EA103FCCFB5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>engage allies and partners, including the United Nations Office on Genocide Prevention and the Responsibility to Protect and other multilateral and regional institutions, to build capacities and mobilize action for preventing and responding to atrocity crimes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F22904E7A6F44A3B51A7FDA8F9346EB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>encourage the deployment of civilian advisors to prevent and respond to atrocity crimes;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC16031F103D74A8E9D1389E8DFCA83C5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>increase capacity and develop doctrine for the United States Foreign Service, civil service, Armed Forces, development professionals, and other actors to engage in the full spectrum of atrocity crimes prevention and response activities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D07EF8547AC404DAC5290E3A2CA92E4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>develop and implement tailored foreign assistance programs that address and mitigate the risks of atrocity crimes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EC763B82A1745718E4C2161DB6884E7"><enum>(H)</enum><text>ensure intelligence collection, analysis, and sharing of appropriate information; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB706B15FA45F474886657CB7A95985EF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>address any other issues that the Task Force determines to be appropriate; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H882C6DAD52C4494A8EF84DDB64D53FFB"><enum>(11)</enum><text>in carrying out paragraphs (1) through (9), receive support from—</text> <subparagraph id="H521043CE21EC4D5AB0D9948386B80445"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Bureau of Conflict and Stabilization Operations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0B9193290C340CC88E999BC8F78190E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Office of Global Criminal Justice;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA12637FE025B4508B89760FD7CEEDF0F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights and Labor;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E46B89D2ACB4CE797B4734A3C952C0C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H941332918C7A4F70AC4E096DED239147"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Bureau of International Organization Affairs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H569AC905736A4A458FE9AE79012F1F97"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other bureaus and offices of the Department of State, as appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B10042BB98D44849CE88A1BD2CF0766"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Task Force shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2275008ACE1649E5930024657B22855C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>seek to ensure that its efforts complement and support interagency processes led by the National Security Council that share the Task Force’s objectives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADCE1A08539F453493EE40C4BE0D9767"><enum>(2)</enum><text>operate with regular consultation and participation of designated representatives, at the Assistant Secretary level or higher, of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA3C807942D6C419C815F02DF49603B8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Department of State;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14E80AF656A2443CA17565043A082B10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the United States Agency for International Development;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE81CA0D4D6C43D4BFACA48A4657EFD8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Department of Defense;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H647E688291CC4867B058A6CC2759DAE1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Department of Justice;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0605365F35464A87AFE2549D7FDEC7AB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Department of the Treasury;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF380D0D4A2F4B61BB8A42146DE7BF68"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53130FE1E95D424C9E424EE038EBA420"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Central Intelligence Agency;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B7A92874806479B97BE0FF9402A0774"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Office of the Director of National Intelligence;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA010C1CDD274E3E8675DD6E18C23BA1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the United States Mission to the United Nations;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE644F9A8220146B98FC45365305B8213"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9CD662CF6844ABD89927E99C738393B"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the National Security Council; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50CFF235D9AB4207B866D07EA30D4268"><enum>(L)</enum><text>such other executive departments, agencies, or offices as the Chair may designate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C3605BA678C48D187A5A37EDCCFE498"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and every three years thereafter for the following six years, the Secretary, in consultation with the Task Force, shall submit an unclassified report, with a classified annex if necessary, to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="H02A3DD29F2C14DD997DF55CCF6F08581"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a review, in consultation with the representatives listed in subsection (d), consisting of—</text> <subparagraph id="H104C3DEB92624EEF932A764887A23BAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an evaluation of the efficacy of current efforts based on United States and locally identified indicators, including capacities and constraints for Government-wide detection, early warning and response, information-sharing, contingency planning, and coordination of efforts to prevent and respond to situations of atrocity crimes and other mass violence, such as gender-based violence;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD8149632B5246F68FB7BDD57AB35BDA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of the funding expended by relevant Federal agencies on atrocity crimes prevention activities, including transitional justice measures and the legal, procedural, and resource constraints faced by the Department of State and the United States Agency for International Development throughout respective budgeting, strategic planning, and management cycles to support conflict and atrocity crimes prevention activities in countries identified to be at risk of atrocity crimes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF23E68FF13D47ECABBE91A982290990"><enum>(C)</enum><text>current annual global assessments of sources of instability, conflict, and atrocity crimes;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H175C372297CC4FF2A50BCEEA66EF62F7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations to further strengthen United States capabilities described in subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H347EE18D143F499FB230554C4425FEB8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>consideration of analysis, reporting, and policy recommendations to prevent and respond to atrocity crimes produced by civil society, academic, and other nongovernmental organizations and institutions;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA553CF9C3C0D489C9D715C0F712541DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations to ensure shared responsibility by—</text> <subparagraph id="H2FE00DD0770E4A84A702B9E333CBF4A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enhancing multilateral mechanisms for preventing atrocity crimes, including strengthening the role of international organizations and international financial institutions in conflict prevention, mitigation, and response; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CCA8CE63DB849F183D39F9D98BF9EBA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>strengthening regional organizations; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBB789A6C0ED443697B5C8448A1CEE73"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the implementation status of the recommendations contained in the review described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H62BEEB76E85E4D288AAF389D6D88F9C6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Materials and briefings</header><text>The Chair and members of the Task Force shall annually (or more often as appropriate)—</text> <paragraph id="HC575DD1CB8EF4F5D8A756211BD5521F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide briefings to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF74928AD2564F7182104EDA654DFEB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide briefings and materials, as appropriate, to the relevant congressional committees.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H49104A1A6F61480B83AFEE01B931EFBA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 2018, 2019, and 2020 to carry out this section.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HDD60CE200DFF4380912653E599C28C62"><enum>6.</enum><header>Training of Foreign Service officers in conflict and atrocity crimes prevention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of section 708(a) of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4028">22 U.S.C. 4028(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H53F37E992B3D41FFACEA41F0B9D0DC2A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAABEDBF5E62C418ABA21FA7A95F5723A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5EB9252B3EAD4996BE808682E8E75C03"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H386336F382EB4295A1C701E39243CC16" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H04C9D6A8017A4D66937763F0216C930F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>instruction on recognizing patterns of escalation and early warning signs of potential atrocity crimes or violence, including gender-based violence, and methods of conflict assessment, peacebuilding, mediation for prevention, early action and response, and transitional justice measures to address atrocity crimes.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H4AEE6F82153F44C5B566CE2B7A47C019"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report of the Director of National Intelligence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director of National Intelligence is encouraged to include in the Director’s annual (or more often as appropriate) unclassified testimony, accompanied by a classified annex, if necessary, to Congress on threats to United States national security—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB95A559912CF45169A0B66BD5642FE58"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a review of countries and regions at risk of atrocity crimes; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0282A91544FF4B8D918E4D2B846D1886"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whenever possible, specific mention of countries and regions at immediate risk of atrocity crimes, including most likely pathways to violence, specific risk factors, potential groups of perpetrators, and at-risk target groups.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H7BCF7F5C3DFD432DBC8B6F7CDC3E16C7"><enum>8.</enum><header>Complex Crises Fund</header>
 <subsection id="HF1C78976862A49A5B4B9C5E7366D5212"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund, which shall be known as the <quote>Complex Crises Fund</quote> (referred to in this section as the <quote>Fund</quote>), to enable the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development to support programs and activities to prevent or respond to emerging or unforeseen foreign challenges and complex crises overseas, including potential atrocity crimes.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8D7FFCB27CAC4B33B5E0C5915B60F71D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes of assistance</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, except section 620M of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2378d">22 U.S.C. 2378d</external-xref>), amounts in the Fund may be used to carry out the provisions of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151</external-xref> et seq.) to support programs and activities that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC7D5E55B3CD249F18348A1F793CA6511"><enum>(1)</enum><text>mitigate or respond to emerging or unforeseen complex crises, including urgent humanitarian, political, social, justice, or economic challenges that threaten stability in any country or region;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DD5105C18A34DA3A74313A4C0F2673B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prevent, counter, and respond to the rise of violent conflict and instability, including atrocity crimes; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7FBACB0D16BA4246A8DCFA37EDB3E428"><enum>(3)</enum><text>advance the consolidation of peace and democracy.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF8910EDFB2904B848D1568B568B85E57"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header> <paragraph id="HF5B9DFFC7C634AA0BE59C24366FBB89D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Amounts in the Fund may not be expended for lethal assistance or to respond to natural disasters.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7FB0C679B8042A68E424F4F77E2B925"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>Not more than five percent of the amounts in the Fund may be used for administrative expenses.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52B139429DB1461780D6CDAC15773539"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header><text>Not later than five days before amounts from the Fund are obligated, the Secretary of State or the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, as appropriate, shall submit notification of such obligation to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5FD0CA392FA34E95B7385C986CA28CD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</committee-name></text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC655E11D4234F85A24D6B8301609EFA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H526D2A8BA44C44528606671D9A8F9353"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H90CD0B5637A44129B713354ACD49537E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD396CE435CD481A9DEAADB332038F17"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The notification requirement under subsection (d) may be waived if—</text> <paragraph id="H2BB810CE6D6A4AFE92C73BBF77E9C2FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>failure to do so would pose a substantial risk to human health or welfare; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7C76DA87D0344B0B286B503084C5EE4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the congressional committees set forth in subsection (d)—</text> <subparagraph id="H592A621AFBFF4E588C9B5DFCD0FE7260"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are notified not later than three days after an obligation of funds; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B3EE1B08F82440C8D4EE6CB1C094763"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are provided with an explanation of the emergency circumstances that necessitated the waiver.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

