<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7FEE5C71FC024AB19FB9698E15B55421" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1267 IH: Personal Health Investment Today Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1267</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170301">March 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001293">Mr. Bishop of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to treat certain amounts paid for physical activity, fitness, and exercise as amounts paid for medical care.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9BDAEFF3505442ADBAEB9EBDE2D7DC1B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDCF07FF84A4E4336B49063BF3EBDA833" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Personal Health Investment Today Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PHIT Act.</short-title></quote></text></section> <section id="H58952576853A4AAAB194FDD81A8C5566"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header> <subsection id="HA2E1259E8F6443B89A20B62BA7E5D6EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H581C8A7593EC46848A91A372115C72F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>almost 20 percent of American children between the ages of 2 and 19 are overweight or suffer from obesity;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4DAAB2A661E74595A4320977E8E45DD3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>8 of the 9 most expensive illnesses in the United States are more common among overweight and obese individuals;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF11497BD749F4792906240FA40173318"><enum>(3)</enum><text>according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the increase in the number of overweight and obese Americans between 1987 and 2001 resulted in a 27 percent increase in per capita health care costs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6017DB085D2E41BEA2C36C1DD0D22F65"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the World Health Organization determined that in the United States a $1 investment in physical activity alone (in time and equipment) would reduce medical expenses by $3.20;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6D57A615C94347FCA3A4069A29B11CE2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>research indicates that 2 in 5 Americans would become more physically active if offered a financial incentive;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0CA9A53880C84DA8B05828452A97BFAE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the United States ranks last in the world in reducing the number of preventable deaths resulting from obesity-related chronic illnesses; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B1FE8C3E18146F0AF353D91C4E571D6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>engaging in physical activities at young ages when children are learning lifelong behaviors can have a significant impact on their long-term health.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3C85B152784B431EAC427007D7EA925B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to promote health and prevent disease, particularly diseases related to being overweight and obese, by—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5EB16DCA57DE472DBD76F687D5C9A25D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>encouraging healthier lifestyles;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H29BA182FFFD54499AB234D95CEA54FD4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing financial incentives to ease the financial burden of engaging in healthy behavior; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8785576D9B374C5C9B4CB014D3B78FC3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increasing the ability of individuals and families to participate in physical fitness activities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HFF94353224E447B9A130C974646C9284"><enum>3.</enum><header>Certain amounts paid for physical activity, fitness, and exercise treated as amounts paid for medical care</header> <subsection id="HD2181A9142D4465E922D98BE5B1EF9BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/213">Section 213(d)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (C), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (D) and inserting <quote>, or</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H45D8DD35DA2C420FA934B30C293566C5" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H64C861858E50409A9B6D233C71768DA7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>for qualified sports and fitness expenses.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HD369BC1A13AC4E5B97B7A7A5F6AEDB13"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified sports and fitness expenses</header><text>Section 213(d) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H6FA1EFC58FDD4223A1DAAEF4F2AA4057" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HE1F9D900F5E44A1EA40B6389A25AA251"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Qualified sports and fitness expenses</header> 
<subparagraph id="HCD3090FE8CFE49688B676A178094E420"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified sports and fitness expenses</term> means amounts paid exclusively for the sole purpose of participating in a physical activity including—</text> <clause id="H8144413C356C4E339D202506D016C958"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for membership at a fitness facility,</text></clause> 
<clause id="H25C6C09E0BD54E949ECAC0C3A78EFC39"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for participation or instruction in a program of physical exercise or physical activity, and</text></clause> <clause id="H4BBD72B38F354FC7BA3694973FBB598E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for equipment for use in a program (including a self-directed program) of physical exercise or physical activity.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9FF2FE2DB90145C48683F6186A44F0EE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Overall dollar limitation</header><text>The aggregate amount treated as qualified sports and fitness expenses with respect to any taxpayer for any taxable year shall not exceed $1,000 ($2,000 in the case of a joint return or a head of household (as defined in section 2(b))).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF4E9F5C8A9A341EB8F961276848BCB7F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Fitness facility defined</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(i), the term <term>fitness facility</term> means a facility—</text> 
<clause id="H4E01D71F233346039B26213B64FB29D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>providing instruction in a program of physical exercise, offering facilities for the preservation, maintenance, encouragement, or development of physical fitness, or serving as the site of such a program of a State or local government,</text></clause> <clause id="H5DD5BC97F86C40DD9F24C1DD101773BD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which is not a private club owned and operated by its members,</text></clause> 
<clause id="H24AC2F11AE2D4B9AAD3AD7CCB4F5DD77"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>which does not offer golf, hunting, sailing, or riding facilities,</text></clause> <clause id="H7D6110C314444CD9ADE3D125AA7FB2FB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>whose health or fitness facility is not incidental to its overall function and purpose, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H082D03BD680545B38AF2911FA04FA541"><enum>(v)</enum><text>which is fully compliant with the State of jurisdiction and Federal anti-discrimination laws.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9444E98007B846C78171BE654CF25DB0"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Treatment of exercise videos, etc</header><text>Videos, books, and similar materials shall be treated as described in subparagraph (A)(ii) if the content of such materials constitute instruction in a program of physical exercise or physical activity.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2ACF4DAB27F0422996381F7EB93F6772"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Limitations related to sports and fitness equipment</header><text>Amounts paid for equipment described in subparagraph (A)(iii) shall be treated as a qualified sports and fitness expense only—</text> <clause id="H836CC35A526D41BE8D5283601255389A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>if such equipment is utilized exclusively for participation in fitness, exercise, sport, or other physical activity programs,</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB285A0A65F4C42B59ECB985CCE45EB4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if such equipment is not apparel or footwear, and</text></clause> <clause id="H2E63B236573246C98F1E5AE90D281639"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of any item of sports equipment (other than exercise equipment), with respect to so much of the amount paid for such item as does not exceed $250.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB3BFD3C7D6164CE7987FA8DC570A27CC"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Programs which include components other than physical exercise and physical activity</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of section 213(d)(6) shall apply in the case of any program that includes physical exercise or physical activity and also other components. For purposes of the preceding sentence, travel and accommodations shall be treated as an other component.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H7FD4ACBFF7CF4DE2844E9DABEE64F6CF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

