<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H17926BD3572D4185A2E3AC1105D3D385" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 559</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170113">January 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001293">Mr. Bishop of Michigan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide for an alternative removal for performance or misconduct for Federal employees.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H178E5B573C3F484788A9579556310F22" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2BDC03683E534E5D960ACFBBB4C583D8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Modern Employment Reform, Improvement, and Transformation Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MERIT Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H05F2C0F4EFEB4C169189DAE22661C2F6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Alternative removal for performance or misconduct</header> <subsection id="HDE8E5E9F83FB4529A5138C8D35CC2454"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/75">Chapter 75</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H3901183D440842EEBB595D1E0966A859" style="USC"> 
<subchapter id="H9B9C017020ED4BFBB638C0F018219241"><enum>VI</enum><header>Alternative removal for performance or misconduct</header> 
<section id="H27C54A3480D644B59D305E6FF916C9D9"><enum>7551.</enum><header>Removal for performance or misconduct</header> 
<subsection id="H9B2592A869BA44A19F1BB78E373D6686"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of an agency may remove an employee from the civil service if the head determines the performance or misconduct of the individual warrants such removal.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H23A2429648A54E689BC1373C32617689"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procedure</header> <paragraph id="H8173417C81194C30BA873581CEFBA1D9" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not less than 7 days and not more than 21 days before taking a personnel action described in subsection (a) against an employee, the head of the applicable agency shall provide the employee with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDC7116D6356048F2BC7A042B8AD7B27E" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notice in writing of the proposed personnel action, including the reasons for such action and including the forecasted final date of employment; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H407A726660AF414D8D64E6BE5BB8F9A5" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an opportunity to respond to the proposed personnel action within the remaining employment period beginning on the date of receipt of notice.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC777F7E64FAD433B94E5975A35995979" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum> 
<subparagraph id="HFE5966B059344DDA94551E4CE3CD8B56" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), any removal under subsection (a) may be appealed to the Merit Systems Protection Board under section 7701.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1CDE29C32F8D49348821DC2228B3AD6A" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An appeal under subparagraph (A) of a removal may only be made if such appeal is made not later than 7 days after the date of such removal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF28B35D73DB454CBF0651F60D105CA8" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>No procedures under section 7513(b) or section 7543(b) may be applied to a removal or under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE773D0317A114D0E8662F9EC76299F55"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expedited review by Merit Systems Protection Board</header> <paragraph id="H4CA56FC6F2624EC997F806AFD68A424C" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Upon receipt of an appeal under subsection (b)(2)(A), the Merit Systems Protection Board shall issue a decision not later than 30 days after the date of the appeal. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6820474433934029859662510FA889B6" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Notwithstanding section 7701(c)(1)(B), the Merit Systems Protection Board shall uphold the decision of the head to remove an employee under subsection (a) if the decision is supported by substantial evidence.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37A027FACE244F0495340C9330BF3DA8" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the Merit Systems Protection Board judge cannot issue a decision in accordance with the 30-day requirement under paragraph (1), the removal is final. In such a case, the Merit Systems Protection Board shall, within 14 days after the date that such removal is final, submit to Congress, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives a report that explains the reasons why a decision was not issued in accordance with such requirement. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE84355E43D2C4D0CBD7D9F7DEFE66182" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Merit Systems Protection Board may not stay any removal under this section unless the basis for the appeal of such removal is a violation of paragraph (8) or (9) of section 2302(b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB7182857C574479A5804ACFE96A2D95" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>During the period beginning on the date on which an individual appeals a removal from the civil service under subsection (b)(2)(A) and ending on the date that the Merit Systems Protection Board issues a final decision on such appeal, such individual may not receive any pay, awards, bonuses, incentives, allowances, differentials, student loan repayments, special payments, or benefits.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6D7632A841C149C7A0EE32961DC465D4" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the head shall provide to the Merit Systems Protection Board such information and assistance as may be necessary to ensure an appeal under this subsection is expedited.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6559A12FC8454E869DFFB4956F2E4031"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional authority</header><text>The authority provided by this section is in addition to the authority otherwise provided under this chapter.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD3DCD52C17A046158E4737338AFC6871"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H6260EF92B6EF432AABFD212EA2B9253D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>employee</quote> means any individual covered by subchapter II or V of this chapter.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H84D3A3D06B254370926811F28F26686A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>misconduct</quote> includes neglect of duty, malfeasance, failure to accept a directed reassignment, the commitment of a prohibited personnel practice, a violation of protocol, and failure to accompany a position in a transfer of function.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HD00EEAD733804F18BBE30F7CF1970011"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HBE7C12484DA74A21B62D145F54655996" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="subchapter">Subchapter VI—Alternative removal for performance or misconduct</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">7551. Removal for performance or misconduct.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

