<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H32A2C3A2D1DB44AD82D39F1C09B3F5AB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3127 IH: To amend section 111 of the Clean Air Act to exclude energy efficiency projects, pollution control projects, and reliability projects from the definition of a modification.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3127</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170629">June 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000297">Mr. Jenkins of West Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend section 111 of the Clean Air Act to exclude energy efficiency projects, pollution control
			 projects, and reliability projects from the definition of a modification.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H108A08B264CD47D7ABC65E9E38DDC8E4" style="OLC">
		<section id="HCA8A27A43FE347ECBC4EB1F287AFE0CF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Exclusion of energy efficiency projects, pollution control projects, and reliability projects from
 the definition of a modification</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 111(a) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6A2EDFE513BC440BAF2DA9229C8FC648"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF03A2627F17B4B9FB4267CDEE5DEE604"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The term <term>modification</term> means</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H48513D7F5ECE442C95565C0083EB6BE7" style="OLC"> <text>The term <term>modification</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H5607B34E9B2F40DD9D0BC10C97DDEE9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H265B1C2282704BC499F63A8EE4A2847B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of the paragraph and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2799C345C360450795ADF361DEEBD694"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2519C7C364304802B8E6CE2298113025" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H469C8AAD2A2A4998982D692F22F9B573"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">excludes any energy efficiency project, pollution control project, or reliability project.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB65B5EDD81F44F26B1E262358D0E1BA1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H81FFC0F9057E42FAB726E10F54015055" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H446A2167500B42A889AD706479BC4F1F"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (4)(B):</text>
 <subparagraph id="H44A4BFC778CF43F98633E85B1B94526A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>energy efficiency project</term> means any project or activity undertaken at a stationary source (including any physical change in, or change in the method of operation of, such source) or any group of projects, activities, or changes undertaken during the same outage period—</text>
 <clause id="H6E90E9CD4BAF4BB78CCADB9B460FA4B9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as a result of which the maximum hourly carbon dioxide emissions rate of the source is lower than it was immediately before such project or activity, or such group of projects, activities, or changes, was undertaken; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2EC4A4AFAEB44A6F8354D89EE6C4A0E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>after which the maximum hourly emission rate for any other regulated pollutant is no more than either the facility-wide or unit-specific permitted emission rate.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H038D9F2BFFE5440686B637ABB34EB7FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pollution control project</term> means any project or activity undertaken at a stationary source (including any physical change in, or change in the method of operation of, such source) or any group of projects, activities, or changes undertaken during the same outage period, that is undertaken to reduce the emission of any pollutant.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB807146C3D82401A9F8EB2965E3EE1EA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>reliability project</term> means any project or activity undertaken at a stationary source (including any physical change in, or change in the method of operation of, such source) or any group of projects, activities, or changes undertaken during the same outage period, that improves the ability of the electric system—</text>
 <clause id="HBBC0D4E1233B4644AD73831BFCF27D6B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to supply the aggregate electric power and energy requirements of the electricity consumers at all times, taking into account scheduled and reasonably expected unscheduled outages of system components; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAEB6D0E2DF48459791A9D3A0D75922F4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to withstand sudden disturbances such as electric short circuits, the unanticipated loss of system components, or disturbances caused by manmade physical or cyber attacks.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


