<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H765DD80589F94F30B8167357EB423CEC" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1698 : Iran Ballistic Missiles and International Sanctions Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1698</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20171030">October 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To expand sanctions against Iran with respect to the ballistic missile program of Iran, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H81C8F36BD6A94702BC6D66587E08BFB0" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9A8487E3AC14428A804EDBB3F2B16E7C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Iran Ballistic Missiles and International Sanctions Enforcement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H943831861C2A4FE89077448F9EC800A3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sanctions relating to efforts by the Government of Iran with respect to ballistic missile-related goods, services, and technologies</header> <subsection id="H074A7D4A439D4A729D56FAFCB866F058"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H12E8AE6DF3B444B5AD5D6BC0D7C873E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015)—</text> <subparagraph id="H904AEAFE885F4E3396E4C8AEE16EE679"><enum>(A)</enum><text>calls upon Iran <quote>not to undertake any activity related to ballistic missiles designed to be capable of delivering nuclear weapons, including launches using such ballistic missile technology</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08EE5DB3004848D9934DD80B529EFB0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requires member states to <quote>take the necessary measures to prevent, except as decided otherwise by the UN Security Council in advance on a case-by-case basis, the supply, sale, or transfer of arms or related materiel from Iran</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0C76570AB3345849025A093C8E1098D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The United States maintains bilateral sanctions against Iran for its efforts to manufacture, acquire, possess, develop, transport, transfer or use ballistic missiles or ballistic missile launch technology, and its acquisition of destabilizing types and amounts of conventional weapons.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBACE6533BE9B4DCDA29B56717F6874CB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>According to the 2016 Worldwide Threat Assessment, the United States intelligence community judges <quote>that Tehran would choose ballistic missiles as its preferred method of delivering nuclear weapons, if it builds them. Iran’s ballistic missiles are inherently capable of delivering [weapons of mass destruction], and Tehran already has the largest inventory of ballistic missiles in the Middle East. Iran’s progress on space launch vehicles—along with its desire to deter the United States and its allies—provides Tehran with the means and motivation to develop longer-range missiles, including ICBMs.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE2AF2A1149F2467484137B9B76821D7F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Since the passage of United Nations Security Council 2231, Iran has conducted numerous tests of ballistic missiles designed to be capable of delivering nuclear weapons, and has acquired destabilizing types of conventional weapons.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB11DF9A1D2B34C478413425D1013E647"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Iran has pursued the ability to indigenously produce ballistic missile and cruise missile goods, services, and technologies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4D548EC9277A48D993ED1DF22760F634"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to prevent Iran from undertaking any activity related to ballistic missiles designed to be capable of delivering nuclear weapons, including launches using such ballistic missile technology.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HA174A35037A74694960778B33E321480"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on supply chain of Iran’s ballistic missile program</header>
 <paragraph id="H4E94697F00814536B49754A4865BE0CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H64362173B25B4AE49CBACA2F59CE6FB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An analysis of the foreign supply chain and domestic supply chain in Iran that directly or indirectly significantly facilitates, supports, or otherwise aids the Government of Iran’s ballistic missile program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA13F0FB4DDA74FB79F007318671D12AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the geographic distribution of the foreign and domestic supply chain described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C86B594B5BC44E7909372E97B2E7534"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of the Government of Iran’s ability to indigenously manufacture or otherwise produce the goods, services, or technology necessary to support its ballistic missile program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42056A00DE7D4FD5B9B0BFB613E63598"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An identification of foreign persons that have, based on credible information, directly or indirectly facilitated or supported the development of the Government of Iran’s ballistic missile program, including the foreign and domestic supply chain described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64E8F5ADA328464EBE9AE78C7CA1E0B2"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination with respect to each foreign person identified under subparagraph (D) as to whether the foreign person meets the criteria for designation under—</text>
 <clause id="HF3BD8F4CB0BA4F23B701FCCC75A63896"><enum>(i)</enum><text>paragraph (1) of section 5(b) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note), as amended by this section;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5EEB82C467464E808C202F916408FC5B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 104 of the Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/44">Public Law 115–44</external-xref>); or</text> </clause><clause id="H8C08B08B84784A44844BDB854515FB9B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Executive Order No. 13382 (2005).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8993951CE242447EAA123151883AFE0E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D7E99631F144481ABE85ED57EB4B96A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sanctionable activities with respect to weapons of mass destruction</header><text>Paragraph (1) of section 5(b) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H09CB54896D8A40899845ED99456D6169"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Exports, transfers, and transshipments</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Weapons of mass destruction; ballistic missiles; conventional weapons</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H93A8456902F54255959AE5D70F09D0B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Except as</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEBA11D3797784543A27641933CE125A1" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HCDBC3FDD2CB44771A2BFAD882676F5AC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Weapons of mass destruction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF638535134684D0F9D9D68679C73ED87"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(A) on or after the date of the enactment of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H79E0EC8E2C4B4BE1872F4A4322087BB4" style="OLC">
						<clause id="H2694FFDCE7554010855F5EA613D208B8"><enum>(i)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H983C33212FD54A59AF90F93CA4F2755B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>on or after the date of the enactment of the Iran Ballistic Missiles and International Sanctions Enforcement Act</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE3805A39F2FA4A049AD57EE7CE22B2DF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(B) knew</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCEBBAF5930FA4DDBA7CB744A82F6FDB7" style="OLC"> <clause id="H0958B65008DA41359F252DB58FCF4E55"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knew</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H098E5C23526047AAAAA27D27483A082B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(i) the export</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F40EEE8BB29428697A6B35AB4EBC8B0" style="OLC"> <subclause id="H78C9DE3764184CAC9BDEA1948F831788"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the export</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC5011111C29041A090BD974D878A3278"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by striking <quote>would likely</quote> and inserting <quote>may</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2BD85C8E8D904124ADBF099A96573979"><enum>(7)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(ii) the export</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD158124092F24A3599594C9501762BDD" style="OLC">
 <subclause id="HCC143DF445B44057910CF2E26547F77A"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the export</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C3E85EE19E0499B9E37F529DFA6872B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(I) acquire</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2FA67E11FE2A409E922F569BC584786C" style="OLC">
 <item id="H10DD36D37ADA4644BB89A18507437610"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acquire</text></item><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF70A02F8DA2B49798EB2BF722F813B6C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>by striking <quote>; or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (A)(ii)(II)(bb)(AA) (as so redesignated);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1A695060D254FB495C1011E0A854C9F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A)(ii)(II)(bb)(AA) (as so redesignated) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H641F40A698A04E3F934F3C1642E01509" style="OLC"> <item id="H194A00223178497A95F1A61F84FE78DE"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acquire or develop ballistic missiles or ballistic missile launch technologies; or</text></item><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B4429A94E4247CB8D6AB9CDF1B86B6B"><enum>(11)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(II) acquire</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBFA7E757A656471BA51B459B93FD728E" style="OLC"> <item id="H1E2D3AF077CD47A6A9C984F7599B0778"><enum>(CC)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acquire</text></item><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H469BE865100049D5A1F768EBCFC868AF"><enum>(12)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (A)(ii)(II)(bb)(CC) (as so redesignated) and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H82C7B0603E9246FCB4A1318548611A08"><enum>(13)</enum><text>by adding at the end of subparagraph (A) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1AA21E09A0514D7BA68D8AB5EC919FF3" style="OLC"> <clause id="HE966B48700D94292AD469F09CEAEB8EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knowingly exports or transfers, or permits or otherwise facilitates the transshipment or re-export of, goods, services, technology, or other items to Iran that materially supports Iran’s efforts to—</text>
 <subclause id="H097727A1685045A0B70F3794A3B5611B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>acquire or develop ballistic missiles or ballistic missile launch technologies; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="HE594DBB24E714812969089889658F6E6"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acquire or develop destabilizing numbers and types of advanced conventional weapons (as such term is defined in paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 1608 of the Iran-Iraq Arms Non-Proliferation Act of 1992).</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4BF4777621E34FA0A4CBCF53ED0D75A4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sanctionable activities with respect to ballistic missiles</header><text>Paragraph (1) of section 5(b) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note), as amended by subsection (e), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B2DA6BF44C2424FBA2327DA9B280600" style="OLC">
					<subparagraph id="H27A716EF55CB4340AB71FED0266A561B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional ballistic missile-related goods, services, and technology</header>
 <clause id="H08A5B87CBDA643F2B85D543E9F0482B0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Additional authority</header><text>The President shall impose the sanctions described in paragraph (8), (10), or (12) of section 6(a), as the case may be, with respect to—</text>
 <subclause id="HCEEA110BF75148E09B6C34C29D334BEB"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an agency or instrumentality of the Government of Iran if the President determines that the agency or instrumentality, on or after the date of the enactment of this subparagraph, knowingly seeks to develop, procure, or acquire goods, services, or technology that materially supports efforts by the Government of Iran with respect to ballistic missile-related goods, services, and technologies as described in clause (iii);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE172CEC10CFD448F80D054976A2916DD"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a foreign person or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state if the President determines that the person or agency or instrumentality knowingly, on or after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, provides significant material support to the Government of Iran that supports efforts by the Government of Iran with respect to ballistic missile-related goods, services, and technologies as described in clause (iii); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8BCB16AF50AB42C0BEF02BE763707F2F"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a foreign person that the President determines knowingly engages in a significant transaction or transactions with, or provides significant financial services for, a foreign person or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state described in subclause (I) or (II) with respect to ballistic missile-related goods, services, and technologies as described in clause (iii).</text>
							</subclause></clause><clause id="H2837D286694545758AFEBC84B57C71E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Determination and report on ballistic missile tests</header>
 <subclause id="H667128B10F614E5599A4712054C68C73"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date on which the President determines that the Government of Iran has conducted a test of a ballistic missile that fails to comply with, violates, or is in defiance of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015), the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that identifies each senior official of the Government of Iran that the President determines is responsible for ordering, controlling, or otherwise directing the missile test.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF52E93A073784524A791C1DB613FBA24"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text>The report required by subclause (I) should include available information on the ballistic missile or the generic class of ballistic missile or space rocket that was launched; the trajectory, duration, range, and altitude of the missile flight; the duration, range, and altitude of the flight of each stage of the missile; the location of the launch point and impact point; the payload; and other technical information that is available.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H05A085520E144DBDB41DCE3B21F34CA9"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subclause (I) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text>
							</subclause></clause><clause id="H32AC0865DD1049D296FC3709179E6656"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Efforts by the Government of Iran with respect to ballistic missile-related goods, services, and
			 technologies described</header>
 <subclause id="H7DDC1CE34F564A35B2A8106FECBB0059"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of subclauses (I), (II), and (III) of clause (i), and except as provided in subclause (II) of this clause, efforts by the Government of Iran with respect to ballistic missile-related goods, services, and technologies described in this subsection are efforts by the Government of Iran to manufacture, acquire, possess, develop, transport, transfer, test or use ballistic missiles or associated goods, services, or technology by the Government of Iran, including efforts by the Government of Iran to manufacture, acquire, possess, develop, transport, transfer, purchase—</text>
 <item commented="no" id="HC0B341470D224614BD0C6D1BD5DE5A89"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>goods, services, or technology listed on the Missile Technology Control Regime Equipment and Technology Annex of October 8, 2015, and subsequent revisions that have been acquired outside of the Procurement Working Group or not otherwise approved by the United Nations Security Council; or</text>
 </item><item commented="no" id="H6424BF3FCFBC4376A4F3A519C3492755"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>goods, services, or technology not described in the matter preceding item (aa) or item (aa) but which nevertheless the President determines would be, if such goods, services, or technology were United States goods, services, or technology, prohibited for export to Iran because of their potential to materially support the development of ballistic missile systems or ballistic missile launch technologies.</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H6CEE962C1D1C445C8FD9F4FAA784A135"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subclause (I) shall not apply with respect to efforts by the Government of Iran with respect to ballistic missile-related goods, services, and technologies that have been approved under paragraph 4 of Annex B of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H72BFD791039A460A9FFBEF53D866159A"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Procurement Working Group defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In clause (iii)(I), the term <quote>procurement working group</quote> means the Procurement Working Group of the Joint Commission established under Annex IV of the applicable provisions in Annex A of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015).</text>
						</clause><clause id="H7CC3DF20D6BB417599523312A72459D2"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Additional report on ballistic missile tests</header>
 <subclause id="H39C824ECAE674713B470B8885E196F77"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 31 of each calendar year, the President should submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report that specifies the number and generic class of ballistic missiles and space rockets launched by Iran during the preceding calendar year and the dates of each missile launch and the type of missile launched on each relevant date. The report should include definitions used for classifying the generic classes of missiles.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7BE83AFF232C4554BEFE6DB88B36DC5A"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subclause (I) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H05FE87B3F73D40F5A54E22B27BF34F82"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Sanctionable activities with respect to conventional weapons</header><text>Paragraph (1) of section 5(b) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note), as amended by subsections (e) and (f), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H78EEBDF5B69444CCB92183D27974143E" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H5C8D303895A34E77A45A99544C6F4E11"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Conventional weapons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall impose the sanctions described in paragraph (8) or (12) of section 6(a), as the case may be, with respect to a foreign person or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state if the President determines that the person or agency or instrumentality knowingly, on or after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, imports, exports, or re-exports to, into, or from Iran, whether directly or indirectly, any significant arms or related materiel prohibited under paragraph (5) or (6) of Annex B of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H22ACE158591B465CB364640B78FED242"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exception and definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of section 5(b) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note), as amended by subsections (e), (f), and (g), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE2FBA68E628144F79506D420FED8E454" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H51FCFD2E7C69486EB0A04E568CE31F5C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may not impose sanctions under subparagraph (B) or (C) with respect to a foreign person or a United States person if the President determines that the person has exercised due diligence in establishing and enforcing official policies, procedures, and controls to ensure that the person does not sell, supply, or transfer to or from Iran materials the sale, supply, or transfer of which would subject a person to the imposition of sanctions under subparagraph (B) or (C), as the case may be, or conduct or facilitate a financial transaction for such a sale, supply, or transfer.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE586E54E601C4E959CF0862156A6AE8E"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In subparagraphs (B) and (C) of this paragraph:</text> <clause id="HC0761A2B44234AF79D1587856C33B03D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Agency or instrumentality</header><text>The term <quote>agency or instrumentality</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1603(b) of title 28, United States Code.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H67A7A40E44A743719E55461C5C408224"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Foreign state</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>foreign state</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1603(a) of title 28, United States Code.</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H0E22A08A46104A47AC9C2EAA82DD168D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Government of Iran</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Government of Iran</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 560.304 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section was in effect on January 1, 2016.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HADF1F69B75BE42DA85E4D12944B61BAD"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Significant transaction or transactions; significant financial services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>significant transaction or transactions</quote> and <quote>significant financial services</quote> shall be determined in accordance with section 561.404 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section 561.404 was in effect on January 1, 2016.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9BC8047A33C44201B3E00338FCBAE144"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6(a) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE282F419185D49F48F22407FFDFF8CEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (10) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H691A7A19EA954E9FB5E5F5883380920D" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H2ADAD923BC52466D9A346807A4EEFA35"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Inadmissibility to United States</header> <subparagraph id="HFED0AFAD180741FCB0155DF7045D88A4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may direct the Secretary of State to deny a visa to, and the Secretary of Homeland Security to exclude from the United States and, if the individual has been issued a visa or other documentation, revoke, in accordance with the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> et seq.) the visa or other documentation of any alien that—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HEDCF209C7C524E62BD3CCB4201195B6D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is designated pursuant to subparagraph (B) or (C) of section 5(b)(1); or</text> </clause><clause id="H73D58FE4197D4B64B4697BB59AF909E9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the President determines is a corporate officer or principal of, or a shareholder with a controlling interest in, a sanctioned person.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H589CA9F1A18D4864B561E291981C05FB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception to comply with United Nations Headquarters Agreement</header><text>Sanctions under subparagraph (A) shall not apply to an alien if admitting the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB62EFDDD55C841A88526CB25129995FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (12) as paragraph (13); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5615C82992A44E86BF172A247933FB4F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (11) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0F278EDC40441648A8865DA836C65D9" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HECB96D98D0BA429593AAA7F0EF71CF23"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Export sanction</header><text>In the case of an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state, no item on the United States Munitions List or Commerce Munitions List may be exported to that foreign state for a period of 2 years.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HFAA36F66C0474357B8DBA74D3C2FAFCE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sanctions that are required to be imposed under this section and the amendments made by this section are in addition to other similar or related sanctions that are required to be imposed under any other provision of law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H83E2D8F14DE04F61B53CC413284A8B3C"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1702">50 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref> and 1704) to carry out any amendments made by this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9C9C8B1FA09F46EEB5CBBE055FC343DA"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a plan to implement—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4C801E5432A34589843D7FC547D55E53"><enum>(1)</enum><text>paragraph (1) of section 5(b) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note), as amended by this section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC64735DBE694EBABF80905A7903EB9B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>section 104 of the Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/44">Public Law 115–44</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H072524053E5541B1A9A3CB39F9AEE8C6"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Effective date</header> <paragraph id="H1826BF900D8A44DDB1B99C051CCF512A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEBBACC979F884CAFAE83668F92C8FB52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01AA7D2846614A5CBC40D98B933D5759"><enum>(B)</enum><text>apply with respect to an activity described in subsection (b) of section 5 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996, as amended by this section, that is commenced on or after such date of enactment.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H114D15DFC16F4941807B6EADD6E7CD01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability to ongoing activities relating to certain activities</header><text>A person that, before the date of the enactment of this Act, commenced an activity described in section 5(b) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996, as in effect on the day before such date of enactment, and continues the activity on or after such date of enactment, shall be subject to the provisions of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996, as amended by this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H26518E9B7735483F96346E76345BDDB0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on sanctionable activities</header>
 <subsection id="HD9DF2FF044A34FFCBD8B230402EA1855"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter for a period not to exceed 3 years, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains the following information:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC28D20F7C88244A0A42CC9F04182D90A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any credible information regarding Iran’s attempts to develop, procure, or acquire goods, services, or technology with respect to which sanctions may be imposed pursuant to subparagraphs (B) and (C) of section 5(b)(1) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note), as added by section 2 of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6965322CB71C4829B0FCA0A95ABD29B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any credible information regarding Iran’s acquisition or attempted acquisition of significant arms and related material in violation of paragraph 5 of Annex B of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A97218A0BD5494FAACFBC34E0210CC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any credible information regarding Iran’s export or attempted export of significant arms and related material in violation of paragraph 6 of Annex B of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H98FA8AA004EB4A0B93168F372E88592A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any approval granted by the United Nations Security Council for the export of significant arms and related material identified under paragraphs 5 or 6 of Annex B of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDBA2852C1C746D1B1E69339E3FB8A11"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any credible information regarding violations of travel restrictions described in paragraph 6 of Annex B of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H455DCC291DE649C89ECD94715B7CD3AA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any approval granted by the United Nations Security Council for exemptions to the travel restrictions described in paragraph 6 of Annex B of United Nations Security Council Resolution 2231 (2015).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF3F128D92EC04DB0B5A76C6EE85F2F02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H04A84C6617A2409DA2F43031857F5B77"><enum>4.</enum><header>Determinations with respect to the imposition of sanctions for the sale or transfer of
			 destabilizing types and amounts of conventional weapons to the Government
			 of Iran</header>
 <subsection id="H73CABFF5B03E4146A33C162D8DD76625"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notification of sales and transfers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which the President receives credible information that destabilizing numbers and types of conventional weapons have been sold or transferred to Iran, the President shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of the sale or transfer.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HD26F345843CB4C38B2C237C42F2EFF5C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determinations with respect to sanctions</header>
 <paragraph id="H222B0B4895BF4C22ACEFA1C4155D3CB0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date on which the President notifies the appropriate congressional committees of a sale or transfer under subsection (a), the President shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE4CE79F057B44A84AA09BB78D74686CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine whether such sale or transfer meets the requirements to impose sanctions under each provision of law specified in subsection (c); and</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A3DDB63B2614639858DC68576CB9DF9"><enum>(B)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDF65DF4C46D84EF580C898E7AC7A462F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>if the determination is that the sale or transfer is subject to any such sanctions, the President shall—</text>
 <subclause id="HBBCA423F398A4135A85D24E150FAB334" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>make a determination whether to impose or waive such sanctions with respect to such sale or transfer; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD6301B69E8A14C06B0B9536DBF733DC7" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>submit that determination to the appropriate congressional committees; or</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H7EA591A6DDA34830A22113A6113E0B2C" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the determination is that the sale or transfer is not subject to any such sanctions, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a detailed report on the determination and the specific reasons for the determination.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H416874DB0C084C66AE68152E54CBD80E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The determination in paragraph (1) shall be provided in an unclassified form, and may contain a classified annex.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H37BB32AFC41B4929933DC351AB00E9D3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Provisions of law specified</header><text>The provisions of law specified in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph id="HD73D261252014DF9BE46229726A5CBBE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 5(b)(1) of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note), as amended by section 2 of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C1801DC1004483F94DE52970FB02063"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Iran-Iraq Arms Non-Proliferation Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9C6DECF28714ED19BFB212FA94AE028"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Iran, North Korea, and Syria Nonproliferation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3DB63DE013FA4916BDDBE6A2DD0A8E98"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>destabilizing numbers and types of advanced conventional weapons</quote>—</text> <paragraph id="HB1F93C8996D24D19822B1396DD20B946"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has the meaning given the terms <quote>advanced conventional weapons</quote> and <quote>cruise missile</quote> as defined in paragraphs (1) and (2), respectively, of section 1608 of the Iran-Iraq Arms Non-Proliferation Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H134A26ADF9104B81854CCF401C7863FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes the S–300 and S–400 missile defense systems and air superiority fighters.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8BAF05322F30472492594140A24ADB2F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Determination on use by the Government of Iran of commercial passenger aircraft and related services for illicit military or other activities</header> <subsection id="HD0DA942D691D49E1B704D555999797CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter for 3 years, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a determination on use by the Government of Iran of commercial passenger aircraft and related services for illicit military or other activities on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1BE6B4FC532C46CD810862E6951D44BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements of determination</header><text>The determination required under subsection (a) shall include a description of the extent to which—</text> <paragraph id="H7D854CA56F324EB2A590858CBE042A88"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commercial passenger aircraft in Iran are being used to transport—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H372D470F35924FE8AD64DB4075F5F682"><enum>(A)</enum><text>arms or related materiel, including defense articles, defense services, or technical data that are controlled on the United States Munitions List established under section 38 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2778">22 U.S.C. 2778</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94C43B5574054645AAF7A6724E818D58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any item that is, or would be, if located in the United States, controlled by Export Control Classification Number 600 series listed on the Commerce Control List maintained under Supplement No. 1 to part 774 of the Export Administration Regulations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA154BCC930447FBB2097249DF62C683"><enum>(C)</enum><text>items used to facilitate the development or production of a chemical or biological weapon or other weapon of mass destruction and their means of delivery, including ballistic missiles and cruise missiles; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE95E59C1B2AA4C37B19DF4DC882FC810"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any foreign person that facilitates the transfer of any of the articles described in subparagraphs (A) through (C);</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3415103C110F4CDD9251140BE33B31CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commercial passenger aircraft licensed by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury are being used for activities described in paragraph (1); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H987BCA5924D74E22988F26717BD2D307"><enum>(3)</enum><text>foreign governments and persons have facilitated the activities described in paragraph (1), including allowing the use of airports, services, or other resources.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6363F1FF43B94E1B99C55178C56271C9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form of determination</header><text>The determination required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H801F191CBDFF4058AC53C7F1406402F2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H97C96BD82AD64BBC96EC648B9D27C418"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commercial passenger aircraft</header><text>The term <quote>commercial passenger aircraft</quote> includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6F646D5C56CD4852B6FF424F2F63242E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an aircraft of United States origin and that is classified under Export Control Classification Number (ECCN) 9A99l on the Commerce Control List maintained under Supplement No. 1 to part 774 of the Export Administration Regulations; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A3BEA472174461590E6B0703E0691B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an aircraft not of United States origin of which United States-controlled content constitutes 10 percent or more of the total value of the aircraft and that is—</text>
 <clause id="H02C2BB32149E45A8A87FDFF3F11C1E7F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>classified under Export Control Classification Number (ECCN) 9A99l on the Commerce Control List maintained under Supplement No. 1 to part 774 of the Export Administration Regulations; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2C4748E677E6416E856010BC17C82F17"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is registered in a jurisdiction other than the United States.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H841B41DEDB3A4E91919F5B04B1A3A3EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Export Administration Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Export Administration Regulations</quote> means subchapter C of chapter VII of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E170EB41E1E4659B63140C9C4AEAAF2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Related services</header><text>The term <quote>related services</quote>, with respect to a commercial passenger aircraft, includes—</text> <subparagraph id="HE250962ADF8947A1AAAB671A56616B75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the export, re-export, sale, lease, or transfer to Iran of spare parts and components; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H880F3AE29F034FFBA0511B1BA3F2F0AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>warranty, maintenance, and repair services.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA8ECF5525A9A44F0A2A59BBF6979973B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header> <subsection id="H2346C696A7664737B4ED73CE7CD1B5AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall, not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, promulgate regulations as necessary for the implementation of this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HED770A0E81B3454C8FE9F7D4335EBA7F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification to Congress</header><text>Not less than 10 days before the promulgation of regulations under subsection (a), the President shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of the proposed regulations and the provisions of this Act and the amendments made by this Act that the regulations are implementing.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H61477B8E6C4D45C3820ED17D116C77B6"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H4DDD8279DA8E41D89227B271FE976A24"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBBE3E54E72B04DEEAE7FC273E7F057D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF6108C6A81A4C1BA2F3DBF8BAD2179E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Finance, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65EDF327E39344DA86618642A7909DDD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Credible information</header><text>The term <quote>credible information</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 14 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/172">Public Law 104–172</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0C6E2D1089CE4064AB75ABE08C0FD57A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Government of Iran</header><text>The term <quote>Government of Iran</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 560.304 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section was in effect on January 1, 2016.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20171025">Passed the House of Representatives October 26, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


