<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H125CEB85C18F43A7AF620AEF037E8E5C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2663 IH: Home Health Documentation and Program Improvement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2663</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001158">Mr. Marchant</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to make changes to documentation of eligibility for
			 Medicare home health services, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H569D7ED5A6C147ECA3B3838F35C95B96" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6CB78BE5AE9D4E59AD244793BC64A32A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Home Health Documentation and Program Improvement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5FB2816DE44B49289A14370B069E2762"><enum>2.</enum><header>Information to satisfy documentation of Medicare eligibility for home health services</header> <subsection id="H057270443DCC4F44BB31829FC15FDCAB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Part A</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1814(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395f">42 U.S.C. 1395f(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before <quote>For purposes of paragraph (2)(C),</quote> the following new sentence: <quote>For purposes of documentation for physician certification and recertification made under paragraph (2) on or after January 1, 2018, and made with respect to home health services furnished by a home health agency, in addition to using documentation in the medical record of the physician who so certifies or the medical record of the acute or post-acute care facility (in the case that home health services were furnished to an individual who was directly admitted to the home health agency from such a facility), the Secretary shall use documentation in the medical record of the home health agency as supporting material, as appropriate to the case involved.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB202ED1A56224304A13CA51BD00925C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Part B</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1835(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395n">42 U.S.C. 1395n(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before <quote>For purposes of paragraph (2)(A),</quote> the following new sentence: <quote>For purposes of documentation for physician certification and recertification made under paragraph (2) on or after January 1, 2018, and made with respect to home health services furnished by a home health agency, in addition to using documentation in the medical record of the physician who so certifies or the medical record of the acute or post-acute care facility (in the case that home health services were furnished to an individual who was directly admitted to the home health agency from such a facility), the Secretary shall use documentation in the medical record of the home health agency as supporting material, as appropriate to the case involved.</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H26D90CAC2CBD4D17A2FAD4ADB72C1B1D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Voluntary settlement of home health claims</header>
			<subsection id="HEC8CF5E08EC345C18932B449F63601EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Settlement process for home health claims</header>
 <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5B2ACD4406F74C4E8EDD886A96F85727"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish a settlement process under which a home health agency entitled to an eligible administrative appeal has the option to enter into a settlement with the Secretary that is reached in a manner consistent with the succeeding paragraphs of this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H401E5B969CEA4CE4B287CF53347B1A35"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Process and consideration of home health claims</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A settlement under paragraph (1) with a home health agency that is with respect to an eligible administrative appeal may only be reached in accordance with the following process:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCB7BA9F22D24421BAE4859969A174685"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A settlement under such paragraph with the home health agency shall be with respect to all claims by such agency, subject to paragraph (4), that, as of the date of such settlement, are under an eligible administrative appeal.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49464CF79561410099DCF5B75CC0F718"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the duration of the settlement process with such agency, an eligible administrative appeal that is with respect to any such claim by such agency shall be suspended.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H50E9F63EBFD747BFB23B5220199EF209"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the settlement process, the Secretary shall determine an aggregate amount to be paid to the home health agency with respect to all claims by such agency that are under an eligible administrative appeal in the following manner:</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H32518E74BF914C4F9344374FB2E4A4B1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, for purposes of applying clause (ii) with respect to all settlements under paragraph (1), select a percentage. In selecting such percentage, the Secretary shall consider the percentage used under the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services hospital appeals settlement that began on October 31, 2014.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HB778900AF1A14448953F543BA0AB75B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, with respect to each denied claim for such agency that is under an eligible administrative appeal, calculate an amount (referred to in this subparagraph as an <quote>individual claim amount</quote>) by multiplying the net payable amount for such claim by the percentage selected under clause (i).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H40419F71A0034159B6BC16A10197F696"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Such aggregate amount with respect to such agency shall be determined by calculating the total sum of all the individual claim amounts calculated under clause (ii) with respect to such agency.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB07F952AE2B14648A96689520BBF001B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect of process</header>
					<subparagraph id="HFE72197102004CA099C60E0CEA411068"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Effect of settlement</header>
 <clause id="H28BA5271E43A4F8F8F1589C86E5F7282"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Further appeal</header><text>As part of any settlement under paragraph (1) between a home health agency and the Secretary, such home health agency shall be required to forego the right to an administrative appeal under section 1869 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ff">42 U.S.C. 1395ff</external-xref>) or section 1878 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395oo">42 U.S.C. 1395oo</external-xref>) (including any redetermination, reconsideration, hearing, or review) with respect to any claims for home health services that are subject to the settlement.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFF6C172B685A4B6D9685AE92F387A9EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be no administrative or judicial review under such section 1869 or otherwise of a settlement under paragraph (1) and the claims covered by the settlement.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1CDFBAA192044B9A6B2AC28B14866A7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect of no settlement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event that the process described in paragraph (2) does not, with respect to a home health agency, result in a settlement under paragraph (1) with such agency, any appeal under such section 1869 that is with respect to a claim by such agency that was suspended pursuant to paragraph (2)(B) shall resume under such section.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H489E7A12F6BA438A95E2F2C16BC8B803"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coordination with law enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish a process under which individuals in the Department of Health and Human Services responsible for executing a settlement under paragraph (1) may, in order to avoid the inadvertent settlement of cases that involve fraud or other criminal activity, coordinate with appropriate law enforcement agencies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HFC9A447ABC9E419A9F13ADE225392021"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No entitlement to settlement process</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as creating an entitlement to enter into a settlement process established pursuant to subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6FC53AE5FF7B447E83C2D7FE2C2CBC89"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible administrative appeal defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>eligible administrative appeal</quote> means an appeal under section 1869 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ff">42 U.S.C. 1395ff</external-xref>) (including any redetermination, reconsideration, hearing, or review)—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H9A6B8054484D4C4D85987565C10B26A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is with respect to one or more claims that—</text> <subparagraph id="H7B380A1C466C4CEC8DB4461FB87255E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are for home health services that—</text>
 <clause id="H4292687F32E54C19ACF5880C399E8481"><enum>(i)</enum><text>were furnished on or after January 1, 2011, and before January 1, 2015; and</text> </clause><clause id="H52C5F8CDFA444DA982674BBD695137CD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">were reasonable and necessary under section 1862(a)(1)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(a)(1)(A)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H163E918F330048508091B5EBFB5324B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">were timely filed consistent with section 1814(a)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395f">42 U.S.C. 1395f(a)(1)</external-xref>) or sections 1835(a)(1) and 1842(b)(3) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395n">42 U.S.C. 1395n(a)(1)</external-xref>, 1395u(b)(3)); and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6B70D4FC9A7A4363917A83A704BD167E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>either—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HFA2772C2DF4647B1ACFACB4018FDD645"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was timely filed consistent with section 1869 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ff">42 U.S.C. 1395ff</external-xref>) and is pending; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H05ECE168DDE44816B28348B5DEA0AF90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for which the applicable time frame to file an appeal has not expired.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC4FA02A2C40744C1ABFC23EAED830DCC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 1869 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ff">42 U.S.C. 1395ff</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H291E5F2980A74E1390710B21A2210A2A" style="OLC">
 <subsection commented="no" id="H4518CFC850CF4B2CA6DA49EFDFE0AB5E"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Application with respect to certain home health claims</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the application of the provisions of this section with respect to certain claims for home health services that were furnished on or after January 1, 2011, and before January 1, 2015, see section 3 of the <short-title>Home Health Documentation and Program Improvement Act of 2017</short-title>.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


