<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Received-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4BF230941E7944DFBBA2A9C50E83C289" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 428 : Red River Gradient Boundary Survey Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 428</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date>February 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received</action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To survey the gradient boundary along the Red River in the States of Oklahoma and Texas, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H399873B7FDE64E198E0E34ABA7788F65" style="OLC">
 <section id="H16542A29B2C341F08D1B75AE968CEC93" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Red River Gradient Boundary Survey Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H516AA18B240A4FDDAF617C2917A46F71"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
			<paragraph id="H310168EBF7D9423EA47186E7197FDC3C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affected area</header>
 <subparagraph id="HFD788B229DBA4CCBBF9A8832D340B1D0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>affected area</quote> means land along the approximately 116-mile stretch of the Red River, from its confluence with the north fork of the Red River on the West to the 98th meridian on the east.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9EC377400EB44E2B523787F48AD4605"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <quote>affected area</quote> does not include the portion of the Red River within the boundary depicted on the survey prepared by the Bureau of Land Management entitled <quote>Township 5 South, Range 14 West, of the Indian Meridian, Oklahoma, Dependent Resurvey and Survey</quote> and dated February 28, 2006.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8056DB213CC48988C80776FE365D516"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gradient boundary survey method</header><text>The term <quote>gradient boundary survey method</quote> means the measurement technique used to locate the South Bank boundary line in accordance with the methodology established in Oklahoma v. Texas, 261 U.S. 340 (1923) (recognizing that the boundary line along the Red River is subject to change due to erosion and accretion).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H12C8A14F0E8542C58E1C127B98FAFF65"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Landowner</header><text>The term <quote>landowner</quote> means any individual, group, association, corporation, federally recognized Indian tribe or member of such an Indian tribe, or other private or governmental legal entity that owns an interest in land in the affected area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE8254F8910449C9839533BD4CF75A13"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC05051C2CF2D498ABBD422FFCB5D78EE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>South bank</header><text>The term <quote>South Bank</quote> means the water-washed and relatively permanent elevation or acclivity (commonly known as a <quote>cut bank</quote>) along the southerly or right side of the Red River that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC558BAAACA704D3490F6B772034D3B93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>separates the bed of that river from the adjacent upland, whether valley or hill; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C0CE1347D4244BDB2AE09FE36FDE76C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>usually serves, as specified in the fifth paragraph of Oklahoma v. Texas, 261 U.S. 340 (1923)—</text>
 <clause id="H096DC266D29F451FA05EFFF8A431BCF8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to confine the waters within the bed; and</text> </clause><clause id="H777496EFB8C0495AB4D06F9C4A5DB307"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to preserve the course of the river.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA68AFE37142402F911F16E7EE6A6E33"><enum>(6)</enum><header>South bank boundary line</header><text>The term <quote>South Bank boundary line</quote> means the boundary, with respect to title and ownership, between the States of Oklahoma and Texas identified through the gradient boundary survey method that does not impact or alter the permanent political boundary line between the States along the Red River, as outlined under article II, section B of the Red River Boundary Compact enacted by the States and consented to by Congress pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/288">Public Law 106–288</external-xref> (114 Stat. 919).</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HA6DEF78885D541428DCE7982183EB93B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Survey of south bank boundary line</header>
			<subsection id="HBBF32FC989A24846A9401CC1889C67FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Survey required</header>
 <paragraph id="HF2E010D62EE246B487511801621C1281"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall commission a survey to identify the South Bank boundary line in the affected area.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6447C1F2CB4E43ADA97B5F9B2D5F9353"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The survey shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H04141C9DDDDA45E1A16CE3B7AA9351CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>adhere to the gradient boundary survey method;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23D2ABC4EFE545E5B9C3F82FE311DC97"><enum>(B)</enum><text>span the length of the affected area;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B3AD6EE22E147A8BCD17BD9E362396D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be conducted by surveyors that are—</text>
 <clause id="H746BE9474F324B758CB05286FCD18D25"><enum>(i)</enum><text>licensed and qualified to conduct official gradient boundary surveys; and</text> </clause><clause id="H51F63C9201B54102A50C6F1A3402C962"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>selected jointly by and operating under the direction of—</text>
 <subclause id="HAC1A4B58411A4BBCA9EF1DC4ACDE15BC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Texas General Land Office, in consultation with each affected federally recognized Indian tribe; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA6E0A5EC4E434B36A8AEA868496EB4CF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Oklahoma Commissioners of the Land Office, in consultation with the attorney general of the State of Oklahoma and each affected federally recognized Indian tribe; and</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02E2F5B966494FFD9FBBEB94E97555E1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>be completed not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBB869D711AB24C2D8E25B61969CB01A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Approval</header> <paragraph id="H3239C3F87DCD466998FA19B153565CF9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State approval</header> <subparagraph id="H3C1864E5977B473C9D7675E3FD8AC091"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the survey under subsection (a)(1) is completed, the Secretary shall submit the survey for approval to—</text>
 <clause id="H35290662D7164D6994E966E8831A800C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Texas General Land Office, in consultation with each affected federally recognized Indian tribe; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA1B1C428AED346D18792A63891F33832"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Oklahoma Commissioners of the Land Office, in consultation with the attorney general of the State of Oklahoma and each affected federally recognized Indian tribe.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCE8723F370940E58ED9BD98568747A1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timing of approval</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of receipt of the survey under subparagraph (A), the Texas General Land Office, in consultation with each affected federally recognized Indian tribe, and the Oklahoma Commissioners of the Land Office, in consultation with the attorney general of the State of Oklahoma and each affected federally recognized Indian tribe, shall determine whether to approve the survey.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF3EFED8E1404967894DD9FBE8B39843"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Surveys of individual parcels</header>
 <clause id="HDF9D90BD31E34D11991775A5422F76AA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Surveys of individual parcels in the affected area shall be conducted in accordance with this section.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H12A12D6FCB3449E3936A41942B6F274E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Approval or disapproval</header><text>A survey of an individual parcel conducted under clause (i) shall be approved or disapproved, on an individual basis, by the Texas General Land Office, in consultation with each affected federally recognized Indian tribe, and the Oklahoma Commissioners of the Land Office, in consultation with the attorney general of the State of Oklahoma and each affected federally recognized Indian tribe, by not later than 60 days after the date of receipt of the survey.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H635A91B067354D9DB567B8846FFA6241"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No federal approval required</header><text>The survey conducted under subsection (a)(1), and any survey of an individual parcel described in paragraph (1)(C), shall not be submitted to the Secretary for approval.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C3CE505A07B400FA3F7C6E9F9DC4826"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notices</header>
 <paragraph id="HF7A4857E7EEA472EBF171373862435CB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which a survey for an individual parcel is approved by the Texas General Land Office and the Oklahoma Commissioners of the Land Office, in consultation with the attorney general of the State of Oklahoma, under subsection (b)(1)(C), the heads of those offices shall submit to the Secretary—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H949301134DBD4044A4CE3CFCF700DA5E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a notice of the approval of the survey; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAB6BA901F7143BAA8BE4C92947E748A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a copy of—</text>
 <clause id="H654F17A69A904A36B7F237B9AC0FEF23"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the survey; and</text> </clause><clause id="HF344804B3B0D4DDA9F6FBBE5589EFEA7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any field notes relating to the individual parcel.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D6838DF8F5D4697BDB76A6845A5D2BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adjacent landowners</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary receives a notice relating to an individual parcel under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall provide to each landowner of land adjacent to the individual parcel—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H21C30A3EC169493C933AD3F0D9998C53"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a notice of the approval of the survey; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3076077E10A4540BAC0542EDE4AC400"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a copy of—</text>
 <clause id="HA97B1166132644AE8D53DCCF7B1185D5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the survey; and</text> </clause><clause id="HC97912CBA88C4A61884FCB85FA03D8E8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any field notes relating to the individual parcel.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H763E5E1FCF474D7FA18ADE3B7A83FB93"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effect of act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H4FCED94187E64A618E0BD8770512E379"><enum>(1)</enum><text>modifies any interest of the State of Oklahoma or Texas, or the sovereignty, property, or trust rights of any federally recognized Indian tribe, relating to land located north of the South Bank boundary line, as established by the survey;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF8AD46898AC4115A52BFCBB51AEB47E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>modifies any land patented under the Act of December 22, 1928 (45 Stat. 1069, chapter 47; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1068">43 U.S.C. 1068</external-xref>) (commonly known as the <quote>Color of Title Act</quote>), before the date of enactment of this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3CBF5D370B4F4627A78D77D27F3E83CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>modifies or supersedes the Red River Boundary Compact enacted by the States of Oklahoma and Texas and consented to by Congress pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/288">Public Law 106–288</external-xref> (114 Stat. 919);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCFEA8ABC8EDD438780D7951601F983FD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>creates or reinstates any Indian reservation or any portion of such a reservation; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3672DD1E2ED94E309268EBD05F8B75EC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>alters any valid right of the State of Oklahoma or the Kiowa, Comanche, or Apache Indian tribes to the mineral interest trust fund established under the Act of June 12, 1926 (44 Stat. 740, chapter 572).</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HF2D51688FA994BB1A27E42D41B3962AB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this Act $1,000,000.</text> </section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170214">Passed the House of Representatives February 14, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

