<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H03001CBF402D479B891204E045FF8037" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2908 IH: Climate Change National Security Strategy Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2908</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170615">June 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001200">Mr. McEachin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct Federal departments and agencies to perform certain functions to ensure that climate
			 change-related impacts are fully considered in the development of national
			 security doctrine, policies, and plans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8F2C79EFB5F048648DBF917FE6DC54B3" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE32D704B3E2542C48C13E9C4982A2607" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short Title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Climate Change National Security Strategy Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4D56EFAEFE7A401BB62A8F69239CDA03"><enum>2.</enum><header>Policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the Federal Government to ensure that the current impacts of climate change, and those anticipated in the coming decades, be identified and considered in the development and implementation of relevant national security doctrine, policies, and plans.</text>
		</section><section id="H6AC66DD53A214B658338313FC0FFC52A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Coordination on Climate Change and National Security</header>
 <subsection id="HE7FF804C246A4534938DF5F9A8F63C23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Security Advisor and the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, acting jointly, shall establish an interagency working group, to be known as the Climate and National Security Working Group, to coordinate the development of a strategic approach to identify, assess, and share information on current and projected climate-related impacts on national security interests and to inform the development of national security doctrine, policies, and plans.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D258B443A5647A29D6355FD80D1629D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Functions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Working Group, in close collaboration with the United States Global Change Research Program, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H83DD9EBE6ACE4798AC059F22A0A58031"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify the U.S. national security priorities that are within the scope of the mission of the Working Group;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H77BEA1773FB640849A4BCDD793873F7B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop recommendations for requirements for climate and social science data and intelligence analyses, as appropriate, that support national security interests;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3907FBC6A8F40D4A38140F9FB816819"><enum>(3)</enum><text>catalog climate science data, intelligence analyses, and other products and programs that support or should be considered in the development of national security doctrine, policy, and plans, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H187210383DB8409BBA4015792BECBD9E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>climate and social science data repositories and analytical platforms;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01C53B135EF240E1A56D966C7B04C843"><enum>(B)</enum><text>climate modeling, simulation, and projection capabilities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5616B06FB700411CA1FDCD5774C44278"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information-sharing tools and resources supporting climate risk analyses and assessments, such as the Climate Data Initiative, the Climate Resilience Toolkit, the Global Change Information System, and the National Climate Assessment;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED7A91CF81D54F0783922FBAAF50F6DC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify information and program gaps that limit consideration of climate change-related impacts in developing national security doctrine, policies, and plans and provide descriptions of these gaps to Federal science agencies and the United States intelligence community to inform future research requirements and priorities, including collection priorities on climate data, models, simulations, and projections;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2D7393C00DA4B9AA66F91AD8DCD39ED"><enum>(5)</enum><text>facilitate the production and exchange of climate data and information with relevant stakeholders, including the United States intelligence community, and private sector partners, as appropriate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB1BD20C2DBF84115AFAACDE6123E3BA2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>produce, as appropriate, and make available science-informed intelligence assessments to agencies having responsibilities in the development of national security doctrine, policies, and plans in order to identify climate change-related impacts and pri­or­i­tize actions related thereto;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE64E300AF520444391EEBE9551ADBD4A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>establish, by consensus, guidance for Working Group members on coordinating, sharing, and exchanging climate science data among the members, and with the National Science and Technology Council;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCF243D352B664F81A02A7103EE2FE951"><enum>(8)</enum><text>provide a venue for enhancing the understanding of the links between climate change-related impacts and national security interests and discussing the opportunities for climate mitigation and adaptation activities to address national security issues;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE5C3602C1E2048E7885EB3ED95514C7F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>work to improve the Federal Government's capability and capacity to characterize greenhouse gas sources and sinks accurately at sub-continental scales;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD83D79544724B9D989AF3DAB7AED113"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommend research guidelines, in coordination with the National Science and Technology Council, concerning the Federal Government's ability to detect climate intervention activities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAFEB5930220349AC8DF733116065EEDD"><enum>(11)</enum><text>develop, by consensus, guidance for Working Group members on building climate resilience in countries vulnerable to climate change-related impacts;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD3FE4490E0664633ABB163203F406C18"><enum>(12)</enum><text>take into account defined requirements and current capabilities described in paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection to facilitate the consideration of climate change-related impacts into national security doctrine, policies, and plans;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H204C1AFC8F5A41199C97B69D4E032A3C"><enum>(13)</enum><text>have classified and unclassified capabilities, as required and appropriate, to consolidate and make available climate change-related impact information, intelligence analyses, and assessments for access and use by Working Group member agencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEEB050BAF8064CFE96967BD179845002"><enum>(14)</enum><text>identify the most current information on regional, country, and geographic areas most vulnerable to current and projected impacts of climate variability in the near-, mid-, and long-term (as defined in section 5), in order to support assessments of national security implications of climate change, and identify areas most vulnerable to these impacts during these timeframes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1A2449F973C4BC7A5FA0CC02482576A"><enum>(15)</enum><text>develop recommendations for the Secretary of State to help ensure that the work of United States embassies, including their planning processes, are informed by relevant climate change-related analyses; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H68BB2E919539452E8F634D0FF5A4BA58"><enum>(16)</enum><text>coordinate on the development of quantitative models, predictive mapping products, and forecasts to anticipate the various pathways through which climate change may affect public health as an issue of national security.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63D488BD5EBF4E16B4D9373EA26AF401"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <paragraph id="HB91AAD35583C47DBB617555AFBA937BB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members of the Working Group shall include the following officials and representatives (or their designees)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H66C92CC766FA4CA596751196B4496BFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the National Security Advisor;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A2547984384451DB48311444D7B3771"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B3F84CD48FF45FF88BC30A84EEC46BD"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the representatives, appointed by the National Security Advisor and the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy (acting jointly), at the Assistant Secretary or equivalent level, of—</text>
 <clause id="H0B04046CAE074D45AF019414D4608628"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of State;</text> </clause><clause id="H26B63D24C53F430294E9D289362222EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Department of the Treasury;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2382BE7B9AB544FBB63D3DE8D419EB35"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Department of Defense;</text> </clause><clause id="H88D9FBD0E6F140A9969440B84E72C092"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Department of Justice;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H71FBD2F17A8E420998A610951C5A3B93"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior;</text> </clause><clause id="H3CC7DF702EE14F12A8B0C27AFEB9BD07"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8A51316347FB4AD78AEB0627B6FA08AC"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the Department of Commerce;</text> </clause><clause id="HA81ED38F449C41E3BC75219BC2D81C2B"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the Department of Health and Human Services;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H77C5B345F37A4D13AA29A95810552DA9"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the Department of Transportation;</text> </clause><clause id="H704F9DCAB0344B03BE7D1A34FE14C97B"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the Department of Energy;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1D039A9A21AA4D62911A1632D31AE525"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security;</text> </clause><clause id="H43075811114148A79B7D82FA7644D2F4"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>the United States Agency for International Development;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCC46336F813641F0B2378460C2AD821C"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>the Environmental Protection Agency;</text> </clause><clause id="H977CCB4684ED4BADA0329044C8AC5DDE"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H64A82D626023434289FCBC8094726001"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>the Office of the Director of National Intelligence;</text> </clause><clause id="HE1F1EACB33C9469294E7D4846C0AE309"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text>the U.S. Mission to the United Nations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9BC7DF163B9349A4A4866725AD57D6A7"><enum>(xvii)</enum><text>the Office of Management and Budget;</text> </clause><clause id="HB8A79337D6C0499A8036C1180441344D"><enum>(xviii)</enum><text>the Council on Environmental Quality;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8E7988C13A0E4E80A790CDCC19DAAB3C"><enum>(xix)</enum><text>the Millennium Challenge Corporation; and</text> </clause><clause id="H8F547006459741388251758CBF657691"><enum>(xx)</enum><text>any other agency or office as designated by the Co-Chairs.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DAA8EE8D3994313AB690C2BFB3585DE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Co-Chairs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Security Advisor and the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, or their designees, shall co-chair the Working Group.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFA99502B320C4D2ABCD0D05E4193C1B1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Action Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Working Group shall, by consensus, develop an action plan, that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCBDF47B101B0487DA59F2EBBA16BF132"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies specific steps that are required to perform its functions;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8364F0FE8AAB46AEA6EA8173AA2CD6E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes specific objectives, milestones, timelines, and identification of agencies responsible for completion of all actions described therein;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA4103AB1233146B9A5B5E8464E3E5423"><enum>(3)</enum><text>includes recommendations to inform the development of agency implementation plans, as described in section 4; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3879686D8B684BEDB4A956683EB330A2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>be submitted to the co-chairs and the appropriate congressional committees, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HF7E55EB6392B49B3B68B7276359BF8E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC69F8150823E42F6B2D0E3B34475AADB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81B17B0999B844749D541F8BB41F020B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Senate Committee on Armed Services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E96D779CE42438AB446CF1776E47BC3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the House Armed Services Committee;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60F1520441F04542859435DAB03D96A3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the House Committee on Natural Resources; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FD347C5229D408C8C8C08D00FCD1E1D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H704B81F01E0D46B3AFF410BA10371DC8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Federal Agency Implementation Plan</header> <subsection id="H0637FFA111544121874AA0952870029F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 150 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the departments and agencies listed in subsection 3(c) shall each develop an appropriate implementation plan supporting the policy described in section 2. Such implementation plans may be classified, as required, to meet specific agency requirements.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H97BD8CE34B42445EBE1952395D435AD0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of Implementation Plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Implementation plans shall consider for inclusion a description of how the respective departments and agencies will accomplish the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H3E6533887750405DA9258ABCA8756BFF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identifying, sustaining, and strengthening climate-related data repositories, tools, and modeling products that inform climate change-related impacts on national security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF573068598A4B3BAA47944C8EF72A6D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identifying climate change-related risks to departments and agency missions, and risks that may be caused by departments and agency policies, programs, and actions concerning international development objectives, fragility, and regional stability.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BFC1708D3F44E12A517AC671D086494"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuing departments and agency adaptation strategies and methods that address climate change-related impacts on national security and homeland defense.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D1CA15A31904FA6986DDD589A884FAB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Identifying and implementing climate change-related information-sharing opportunities and arrangements through international development activities, military-to-military engagements, and government-to-government climate-related data exchanges.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9236EF509F154E73BFD008A7B9DFE63F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Identifying economic considerations arising from the impacts of climate change globally and the resulting specific impacts on national security, including macroeconomic analyses and data-sharing mechanisms.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H29AF7938B40C488CA8C4D1A16D6AC0A6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Identifying the potential impact of climate change on human mobility, including migration and displacement, and the resulting impacts on national security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33D1E552D43848DA82AC4D4C24D162E0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Identifying climate change-related impacts on global water, food security, and nutrition and the resulting impacts on national security, and recommending actions to mitigate these impacts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H725810D6DD3347E1946DA03120FE1D4B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Identifying climate change-related global health security concerns affecting humans, animals, and plants, and developing options to address them.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H53BE4D808A994AC08FBC5216021BBDC5"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing a department or agency-specific approach to address climate-related hazards and threats to national security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F52DBC1061A42C58A83A228F335C0D0"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Determining and acting on climate change-related threats to infrastructure at the asset, system, and regional level and acting to strengthen the safety, security, and resilience of infrastructure critical to national security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H28A15C7C868344EEACD8816B24EC1B53"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Incorporating climate change-related impact information and considerations into department and agency technical and executive education and training programs.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C80DD9AFA87496F948ADBC313429B01"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Federal agencies shall update their implementation plans required by this section not less than annually.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H976C4652F74A4F69A6E890ED7F5F1AD3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H6FDED2DCC3604D62B453C644551AD1B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Adaptation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>adaptation</quote> refers to the adjustment in natural or human systems in anticipation of or in response to a changing environment in a way that effectively uses beneficial opportunities or reduces negative effects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4B9F6712E194324B271DDA47D62DF01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Climate</header><text>The term <quote>climate</quote> refers to the prevailing meteorological conditions over a period of several decades, including the typical frequency and duration of extreme storms, heat waves, precipitation, droughts, cloudiness, winds, ocean temperatures, and other events that a region is likely to encounter.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B1170978EF24D7EBA08BE6273654F0D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Climate change</header><text>The term <quote>climate change</quote> refers to detectable changes in one or more climate system components over multiple decades, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2424946A364D41EAA030CCA2B022EA4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>changes in the average temperature of the atmosphere or ocean;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H975D2C9A23AE4541AF63E6AE585E57D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>changes in regional precipitation, winds, and cloudiness; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B9BC5F34B784F7DB5C27A67030413F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>changes in the severity or duration of extreme weather, including droughts, floods, and storms.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H874EE931FD884FC8B8435266814266E9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Climate modeling</header><text>The term <quote>climate modeling</quote> refers to the mathematical representation of the set of interdependent components of the climate system, including the atmosphere and ocean, cryosphere, ecology, land use, natural greenhouse gas emissions, and anthropogenic greenhouse emissions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFEDBBB16DC1243FFB7CD5D618D4C4F49"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Fragility</header><text>The term <quote>fragility</quote> refers to a condition that results from a dysfunctional relationship between state and society and the extent to which that relationship fails to produce policy outcomes that are considered effective or legitimate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03EBB48F7FF54B848989350776DE1757"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Global health security</header><text>The term <quote>global health security</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="H5BE1D39FC5AD42A9826982C9DA5286AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>refers to activities required, both proactive and reactive, to minimize vulnerability to acute public health events that endanger the collective health of populations living across geographical regions and international boundaries; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CA110DED9B54B6AB3211EFA85552DF7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes the efforts of the Global Health Security Agenda to establish capacity to prevent, detect, and respond to disease threats, whether naturally occurring, deliberate, or accidental.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E8E597E2AB84A748A9AB443BDEC415B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Intelligence community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>intelligence community</quote> has the meaning given to that term in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD668DEC1CD22435195167B10738534B8"><enum>(8)</enum><header>National Security</header><text>The term <quote>National security</quote> refers to the protection of the Nation and its people and interests.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB6FB6699A614EC7B662FB1661347291"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Near-, mid-, and long-term</header><text>The term <quote>near-, mid-, and long-term</quote> means current to 10 years, 10 to 30 years, and more than 30 years, respectively.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H30923F8A99B34D1A95EC2666102D11E7"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Resilience</header><text>The term <quote>resilience</quote> refers to the ability—</text> <subparagraph id="H1F1D0308A4A5487DB2EA714D32A42DC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to anticipate, prepare for, and adapt to changing conditions; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEED10EFAFAB74711A4651271C049D184"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to withstand, respond to, and recover rapidly from disruptions.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CD0045BA053469F9ABE0FA4E3EA3A44"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Working Group</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Working Group</quote> means the Climate and National Security Working Group established pursuant to section 3(a).</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


