<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB51EF770567D41A59E3723BE9A9EFE6E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3786 IH: Great Lakes Environmental Sensitivity Index Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3786</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170914">September 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere to update periodically the environmental
			 sensitivity index products of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric
			 Administration for each coastal area of the Great Lakes, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9DDE75A588F14C968CF32071C6C0424C" style="OLC">
 <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H74B125BF092A4A0DAF7205CA71B12E5D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Great Lakes Environmental Sensitivity Index Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6FF07333F3A5449493F61D468B13B147" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Update to environmental sensitivity index products of National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration for Great Lakes</header> <subsection id="H8C1850EB92B84CDFB22C8E44291E2D5F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Update required environmental sensitivity index products for Great Lakes</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere shall commence updating the environmental sensitivity index products of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration for each coastal area of the Great Lakes.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE53C4BC2999948DFA67136B08A01E278"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Periodic updates for environmental sensitivity index products generally</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations and the priorities set forth in subsection (c), the Under Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE43CEBED5A564CAEB219764F430E869D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>periodically update the environmental sensitivity index products of the Administration; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H422A3A48D4DA4F699FED2D1E96B422B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>endeavor to do so not less frequently than once every 7 years.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H867208AD24F5499784D411EC35B2E25E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priorities</header><text>When prioritizing geographic areas to update environmental sensitivity index products, the Under Secretary shall consider—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5D3DF3A926184BA694C7E990C46B2592"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the age of existing environmental sensitivity index products for the areas;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HED4988F86F82479C86ECDEBC14522921"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the occurrence of extreme events, be it natural or man-made, which have significantly altered the shoreline or ecosystem since the last update;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99B2920DF2934F4BBF261FD207012572"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the natural variability of shoreline and coastal environment; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC1E97EB99CC0435899631B2DBF21A4C9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the volume of vessel traffic and general vulnerability to spilled pollutants.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H66D07E465561421794668323FB0835D1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Environmental sensitivity index product defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>environmental sensitivity index product</term> means a map or similar tool that is utilized to identify sensitive shoreline, coastal or offshore, resources prior to an oil spill event in order to set baseline priorities for protection and plan cleanup strategies, typically including information relating to shoreline type, biological resources, and human use resources.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H7F3CEB18EE5F421C943B2AA010844264"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="H4B07FF97317043588BAB9399F68726EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Under Secretary $7,500,000 to carry out subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD310031423FB414D91ACF7C18A3C4B53"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts appropriated or otherwise made available pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be available to the Under Secretary for the purposes set forth in such paragraph until expended.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


