<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H921B80F48EA043BEAA1D37A78A9B6978" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1854 IH: Prescription Drug Monitoring Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1854</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170403">April 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000297">Mr. Jenkins of West Virginia</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the use of prescription drug monitoring programs and to facilitate information sharing
			 among States.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5C0AA1D19A8E405A94B0DD87146EAA01" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB01DDCE215D14D6B8D77E85AB8EA917E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prescription Drug Monitoring Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H900EB9A7E8394C319B582A172412D500"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="HDADA254717934229BAD6B375A4163E1A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Controlled substance</header><text>The term <term>controlled substance</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3359EA7D1F56482B906B6F15CB4E5698"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered State</header><text>The term <term>covered State</term> means a State that receives funding under the Harold Rogers Prescription Drug Monitoring Program established under the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/77">Public Law 107–77</external-xref>; 115 Stat. 748) or the controlled substance monitoring program under section 399O of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g-3">42 U.S.C. 280g–3</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CF0D207FBB944259F9969395422EA5B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Dispenser</header><text>The term <term>dispenser</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H69E8055FE47C45489D6743CC8E90C929"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means person licensed or otherwise authorized by a State to deliver a prescription drug product to a patient or an agent of the patient; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA9DC62A912D48D5870251928429FC1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a person involved in oversight or payment for prescription drugs.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B9FCD32E5C34AD2B0C544258D5DEA26"><enum>(4)</enum><header>PDMP</header><text>The term <term>PDMP</term> means a prescription drug monitoring program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H454B54C274064529B185013B5080C0FB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Practitioner</header><text>The term <term>practitioner</term> means a practitioner registered under section 303(f) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823(f)</external-xref>) to prescribe, administer, or dispense controlled substances.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3CB7E04F731D470BA3941C7609F9D49C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States and the District of Columbia.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HB7370A46CCE54963867CAB85D5188D56" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prescription drug monitoring program requirements</header> <subsection id="HC261FFBA31BB4CD9BF6DBEA1B55EEEAC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, each covered State shall require—</text>
 <paragraph id="H48D67D5C386B458AAA71D98D58A612E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each prescribing practitioner within the covered State or their designee, who shall be licensed or registered healthcare professionals or other employees who report directly to the practitioner, to consult the PDMP of the covered State before initiating treatment with a prescription for a controlled substance listed in schedule II, III, or IV of section 202(c) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/812">21 U.S.C. 812(c)</external-xref>), and every 3 months thereafter as long as the treatment continues;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A332B5B01D64DE9AFAFC620308DE444"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the PDMP of the covered State to provide proactive notification to a practitioner when patterns indicative of controlled substance misuse, including opioid misuse, are detected;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H433B4048B6D44919AB0FA61A0EDA4FA2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>each dispenser within the covered State to report each prescription for a controlled substance dispensed by the dispenser to the PDMP not later than 24 hours after the controlled substance is dispensed to the patient;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H31AACEE8053C4B9A850874A6D14D2F0A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>that the PDMP make available a quarterly de-identified data set and an annual report for public and private use, which shall, at a minimum, meet requirements established by the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1FC69E4365DB4BFFB2F3EE4A8366658B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>that the data contained in the PDMP of the covered State is made available to other States.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H56BA95ED13D74EFE847E847BC2D7A153"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Noncompliance</header><text>If a covered State fails to comply with subsection (a), the Attorney General or the Secretary of Health and Human Services, as appropriate, may withhold grant funds from being awarded to the covered State under the Harold Rogers Prescription Drug Monitoring Program established under the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/77">Public Law 107–77</external-xref>; 115 Stat. 748) or the controlled substance monitoring program under section 399O of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g-3">42 U.S.C. 280g–3</external-xref>).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HCC9E9E995BAD428FBDC6B5106356BA6E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data-Sharing Single technology solution</header>
 <paragraph id="HCF61AC86734F426EAC0A6C8D730788D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purpose of assisting States in complying with subsection (a)(5), the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Comprehensive Opioid Abuse Grant Program established under section 3021 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3797ff">42 U.S.C. 3797ff</external-xref>), shall award, on a competitive basis, a grant to an eligible entity to establish and maintain an inter-State data-sharing single hub to facilitate the sharing of PDMP data among States and the accessing of such data by practitioners.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC382B0E65C41489193C77ED90062D790"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The data-sharing single hub established under paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H4600EF6033FC40748B4CD7EFFAFD2058"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall—</text>
 <clause id="H2C7BF06459C84F0FBDBDE26611724B82"><enum>(i)</enum><text>allow States to retain ownership of the data submitted by the States;</text> </clause><clause id="H90521E8CC8C240859ECAEE8709534F72"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide a source of de-identified data that can be used for statistical, research, or educational purposes;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H58EDC4E861434F7AA5BBBAB1EA29A725"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>allow State authorized users to access data from a PDMP of a covered State without requiring a user fee; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD9EE47F1A8F0455C95E9D39FA3F5B4B5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>conform with the standards of the Prescription Monitoring Information Exchange; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38835184ADCF41EB9C4B4EB2FA43DE54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not—</text>
 <clause id="H5E20DAA93A804E15A95ECA73C908A73E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>distribute, in whole or in part, any PDMP data without the express written consent of the PDMP State authority; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H97E02D82074042C6BC82B81698AD0506"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>limit, in whole or in part, distribution of PDMP data as approved by the PDMP State authority.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

