<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H874212C4ECD94F168076010990E084C8" key="H" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2122 RH: To reinstate and extend the deadline for commencement of construction of a hydroelectric project involving Jennings Randolph Dam.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 119</calendar>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2122</legis-num>
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 115–175]</associated-doc>
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20170425">April 25, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<action>
<action-date date="20170612">June 12, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
</action>
<action>
<action-desc><pagebreak/></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To reinstate and extend the deadline for commencement of construction of a hydroelectric project involving Jennings Randolph Dam.<pagebreak/></official-title>
</form> 
<legis-body id="HFA0CD11DD98548D6881973A2143A24C4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCB101CD1FDC5429985672ACD10C7BF2A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Reinstatement and extension of time for a Federal Energy Regulatory Commission Project involving Jennings Randolph Dam</header> 
<subsection id="H93ECD80761424AF6ACAEBB13FAD24456"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension of time</header><text>Notwithstanding the time period specified in section 13 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/806">16 U.S.C. 806</external-xref>) that would otherwise apply to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission project numbered 12715 (referred to in this section as the <quote>project</quote>), the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (referred to in this section as the <quote>Commission</quote>) may, at the request of the licensee for the project, and after reasonable notice, in accordance with the good faith, due diligence, and public interest requirements of, and the procedures of the Commission under, that section, extend the time period during which the licensee is required to commence the construction of the project for not more than 3 consecutive 2-year periods that begin on the date of the expiration of the extension originally issued by the Commission.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H9A267A3265AE4B7EA407083B28140A37"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Obligation of licensee</header><text>Any obligation of the licensee for the project for the payment of annual charges under section 10(e) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/803">16 U.S.C. 803(e)</external-xref>) shall commence on the expiration of the time period to commence construction of the project, as extended by the Commission under subsection (a).</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H5BC6DE0996FA4CEB83E3FD21D0B8F391"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reinstatement of expired license</header> 
<paragraph id="H322E8DE332FB4D3296D1084E166474A1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the period required for the commencement of construction of the project has expired before the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission may reinstate the license effective as of the date of the expiration of the license.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H80BFC979A84740AAB6BC3DA1DE692042"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>If the Commission reinstates the license under paragraph (1), the first extension authorized under subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of the expiration of the license.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
<endorsement display="yes">
<action-date date="20170612">June 12, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill> 


