<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9E51A5B1AB6C4DD9B1B8924C8D7B2C09" key="H" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1664 IH: Investing in America: A Penny for Progress Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1664</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20170322">March 22, 2017</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to index the gas and diesel tax and rebuild our roads, bridges, and transit systems.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H93EA2100CE7C4FB79645B8EC6FFB8C39" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H83B3AD57081743FD8009AF38D3FF7C80" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Investing in America: A Penny for Progress Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H8DF55DBB09A840F0BAD5490E862DEE0F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Double indexation of gasoline and diesel fuels tax</header> <subsection id="H6BAE22543F544219B278BD413D170C03"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4081">section 4081(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAFEBA3B04F1D4429BF1BB8B648F8E44A" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H3A4B4C34E3C8492F8D247A586BA25718"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Index for highway construction cost inflation and fuel efficiency</header> 
<clause id="HF327BD8FCA8C4BDB98EB1FADD07B0A54"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any calendar year after 2017, the 18.3 cents rate in subparagraph (A)(i), the 24.3 cents rate in subparagraph (A)(iii), and the 19.7 cents rate in subparagraph (D), shall each be increased by an amount equal to—</text> <subclause id="HEEAF10127C684AFA889AD55B9ECC5CE0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="H9ADEBD763A674CDD8D8D021BE5FBB076"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the double indexation for the calendar year.</text> </subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">Any increase determined under this subparagraph shall be rounded to the nearest tenth of a cent.</continuation-text></clause> <clause id="H869641EFEC9B47E08BF5A835672D9213"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception for fuel used in aviation</header><text>The adjustment under clause (i) shall not apply with respect to the rate of tax under subparagraph (A)(iii) for fuel referred to in subparagraph (C).</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H36B4C47F40434015B5228F34F63B543D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Special rules to stabilize rates</header> 
<subclause id="HEB5DC25DD0084A22B7FF7D8175755DEF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>If an adjustment of rates under clause (i) for a calendar year would result in rates in subparagraphs (A)(i), (A)(iii), and (D) in effect for the calendar year greater than 1.5 cents more than the rates in effect under such subparagraphs for the preceding calendar year—</text> <item id="H1F8152E3BA764AC88390017E55F976E0"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the rates in subparagraphs (A)(i), (A)(iii), and (D) for the calendar year shall be the rates in effect under such subparagraphs for the preceding calendar year plus 1.5 cents,</text> </item> 
<item id="H15D5E2D010BA42CE818AEEB4C1024101"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any adjustment of rates that would have occurred under clause (i) if item (aa) were not in effect shall be applied under that clause—</text> <subitem id="H4F1FF7FC1A404DC09876A5990AC96531"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the succeeding calendar year or years after the rate is established under clause (i) for that year, and</text> </subitem> 
<subitem id="HE253DB2B3CDD4EC4893F11BE1F70E4AB"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>until the cumulative adjustment of rates equals the adjustment that would have applied under clause (i) if item (aa) were not in effect, and</text> </subitem></item> <item id="HB7EEC6E145AB45A19059F63FD36AA252"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an adjustment of rates under item (bb) remains subject to item (aa).</text> </item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9F0509F1F22E4E3DA61B037ECE7EEE95"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an adjustment of rates under clause (i) for a calendar year would result in rates in subparagraphs (A)(i), (A)(iii), and (D) in effect for the calendar year less than the rates in effect under such subparagraphs for the preceding calendar year—</text> <item id="H81E56B20B426481DB721ABB2C5B9E507"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>no adjustment of such rates shall be made for the calendar year, and</text> </item> 
<item id="H4001320EE7E24D028B9D0D1C5CFECE22"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the rates in subparagraphs (A)(i), (A)(iii), and (D) for the calendar year shall be the rates in effect under such subparagraphs for the preceding calendar year.</text> </item></subclause></clause> <clause id="HB63D8F19875D41DDB438AF6C35D34936"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Double indexation</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the double indexation for any calendar year is the sum of—</text> 
<subclause id="H9879EB85ACC64DCFB3EF11EC47525F19"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the highway construction cost adjustment, and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H7A1DC31F07AE44FEAEFD0AC4397640B0"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the CAFE fuel saved adjustment.</text> </subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H1CD50DCB4B3540F49983A1ADFF13DCFB"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Highway construction cost adjustment</header><text>For purposes of clause (iv), the highway construction cost adjustment for any calendar year is the percentage (if any) by which—</text> <subclause id="HA66C8868BB594EF7B63ADDB37F562302"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Highway Construction Cost Index for the preceding calendar year, exceeds</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="HA2A573A1E308428DB16E67C724E61671"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Highway Construction Cost Index for calendar year 2016 or, if applicable, the first year of a successor index.</text> </subclause></clause> <clause id="H8FEA3530589545C58EA1600A7D5E790C"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>National Highway Construction Cost Index for any calendar year</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (v), the National Highway Construction Cost Index for any calendar year is the average of the National Highway Construction Cost Index as of the close of the 12-month period ending on June 30 of such calendar year.</text> </clause> 
<clause id="HE77FC4282CBA452F91BB14A3EF6B15CD"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>National Highway Construction Cost Index</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (v), the term <term>National Highway Construction Cost Index</term> means the last National Highway Construction Cost Index published by the Department of Transportation or successor index.</text> </clause> <clause commented="no" id="H45FA1C11F2024A69A61F1BD45147D745"><enum>(viii)</enum><header>CAFE fuel saved adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (iv), the CAFE fuel saved adjustment for a calendar year is the percentage (if any) by which annual motor fuel use is reduced by the estimated CAFE fuel saved for that calendar year from the annual motor fuel use for the prior calendar year.</text> </clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H5D5C6E94DFD04B15879E77FDF09E4A60"><enum>(ix)</enum><header>Estimated CAFE fuel saved</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>estimated CAFE fuel saved</term> for a calendar year means—</text> <subclause id="HD24554C5867243DEA957919CA3A6301E"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of the 18.3 cents rate in subparagraph (A)(i), the combined gasoline fuel saved estimates issued by the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration and the Environmental Protection Agency for passenger automobiles and light trucks published in the Federal Register on May 7, 2010, and October 15, 2012, and for medium and heavy-duty engines and vehicles published in the Federal Register on September 15, 2011, and October 25, 2016, as part of final rules to implement corporate average fuel economy standards, and such successor estimates included in successor rules.</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="HCF88C25728FA40FC8697029AFE5A8079"><enum>(II)</enum><text>In the case of the 24.3 cents rate in subparagraph (A)(iii) and the 19.7 cents rate in subparagraph (D), the combined diesel fuel saved estimates issued by the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration and the Environmental Protection Agency for medium and heavy-duty engines and vehicles published in the Federal Register on September 15, 2011, and October 25, 2016, as part of final rules to implement corporate average fuel economy standards, and such successor estimates included in successor rules.</text> </subclause></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H8EBE0BBF4CDF4B5CAB2D1D0DD7EA2568"><enum>(x)</enum><header>Annual motor fuel use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>annual motor fuel use</term> means—</text> 
<subclause id="HE8A7C090AD554D9AAEB823FE4361F394"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of the 18.3 cents rate in subparagraph (A)(i), the total number of gallons of gasoline used in a calendar year in highway use, as published by the Federal Highway Administration as part of its annual motor fuel data survey.</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H46F400C6F34047E1A877C2D45773F821"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of the 24.3 cents rate in subparagraph (A)(iii) and the 19.7 cents rate in subparagraph (D), the total number of gallons of diesel used in a calendar year in highway use, as published by the Federal Highway Administration as part of its annual motor fuel data survey.</text> </subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HBB5FA73D328B4B38AA34F801814BD956"><enum>(xi)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 15, 2017, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall publish the rates of tax as adjusted under this subparagraph for the succeeding calendar year.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection id="HFA96157F196546059AEB80016576BFDC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Retail fuel excise tax</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 4041 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E948D7AAC7447988D0BDCB851601392" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H0B4FD10B0CC94A6EA892F3508C7C6DA5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Highway inflation adjustment</header><text>If an increase in rates is made under section 4081(a)(2)(E) for any calendar year after 2017, then each dollar amount in paragraphs (1)(C)(iii)(I), (2)(B)(i), (2)(B)(ii), (2)(B)(iv), and (3)(A) of this subsection and in subsections (b)(2)(A)(i), (b)(2)(C)(i), and (m)(1) shall be increased in the same manner and subject to the same conditions that are applicable under section 4081(a)(2)(E).</text> </paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D56C27135284150A0F4CA173608701D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of section 4081(a)(2) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>The rate</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), the rate</quote>.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H71850EF00DDC4B3AAAACB5645D153527"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to periods beginning after July 31, 2017.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H8A0292AEF85F4110B0E43CBC4FF5C7C5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transportation bonds</header> <subsection id="HE797F57CD98E49369D31D401FC43E510"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Issuance</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall, pursuant to subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, issue bonds, to be known as <quote>Invest in America Bonds</quote>, which meet the terms and conditions of subsection (b), and the bond revenue shall be transferred to the Highway Trust Fund with 80 percent allocated to the Highway Account (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9503">section 9503(e)(5)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) and 20 percent allocated to the Mass Transit Account.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC8009F74B6E842F19903225CB8804E16"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header> 
<paragraph id="HBFCDA3A7733148A593A77E7799D242C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Term</header><text>Bonds issued under subsection (a) shall have terms of 30 years.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H93A42CBFA00C4083ADC2C6EFC712E9D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>Bonds shall be issued under subsection (a) every fiscal year.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H125AB6AC49644177806C47405B0C464F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Face amount formula for fiscal years 2017 through 2020</header><text>Bonds issued under subsection (a) for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2020 shall have a face amount that equals, for that fiscal year—</text> <subparagraph id="HDEB34228CEDE4D4C8781D75888958F38"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal share (as defined in section 503(b)(8)(C)(v) of title 23, United States Code, and section 308(e)(3)(E) of title 49, United States Code) of the most recent estimates required under section 503(b)(8)(C)(iv) of title 23, United States Code, and section 308(e)(3)(D) of title 49, United States Code; minus</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H03A188065F8F4CD58946B654A57E28D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the sum of the amount authorized in section 5338(a)(1) of title 49, United States Code, the amounts authorized in section 1101(a) of the FAST Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/94">Public Law 114–94</external-xref>; 129 Stat. 1322), the amounts authorized in section 4001(a) of the FAST Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/94">Public Law 114–94</external-xref>; 129 Stat. 1497), and the amounts authorized in section 31104(a) and 31110(a) of title 49, United States Code, for that fiscal year.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC56CB06AD30748EDB4DD856978B6022E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Face amount formula for fiscal years 2021 through 2013</header><text>Bonds issued under subsection (a) for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2030 shall have a face amount that equals, for that fiscal year—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7AD42998DF1F46C6A740E0EA0D4A1F99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal share (as defined in section 503(b)(8)(C)(v) of title 23, United States Code, and section 308(e)(3)(E) of title 49, United States Code) of the most recent estimates required under section 503(b)(8)(C)(iv) of title 23, United States Code, and section 308(e)(3)(D) of title 49, United States Code; minus</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5743E8A265C14491894ADF6E5798EA00"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the expected revenue deposited into the Highway Trust Fund for the corresponding fiscal year not including revenues attributed to this section.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0EE851B737FE4F218BC3F02D6C4116C9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Amount outstanding</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraphs (3) and (4), the total face amount of bonds issued under subsection (a) may not exceed the amount the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Transportation determines can be redeemed, taking into account this section and <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9503">section 9503(g)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HB25F9B47E2DF465DAA6B7921178A534C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>No bonds may be issued under subsection (a) after September 30, 2030.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H84D8884DC3284194BEAD449881BAE619"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Capital investment grant special rule</header><text>Prior to the application of section 105 of title 23, United States Code, for a fiscal year, an amount equal to a percentage of bond revenue transferred to the Highway Trust Fund and allocated to the Mass Transit Account equal to the ratio of the funds appropriated in the preceding fiscal year to carry out section 5309 of title 49, United States Code, to the funds made available in the same fiscal year to carry out section 5338(a)(1) of title 49, United States Code, shall be available to make additional grants pursuant to section 5309 of title 49, United States Code.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H1BCC6F74C287403D8EC8CD06EB884E7E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Set-Aside special rule</header> <paragraph id="H246F7CC5FF274D02B59CCAC46AC63A6A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the additional amounts of contract authority to be made available under section 105 of title 23, United States Code, for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall make adjustments under section 105(c)(1) of title 23, United States Code, for a set-aside from the Highway Account (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9503">section 9503(e)(5)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) or Mass Transit Account referred to in paragraph (2)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB9C96DEAAF58471C85CFE72E59AD65B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by determining the ratio that—</text> <clause id="HB0CE81EEFB054CC49BEC6F13E185E256"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount authorized to be appropriated for the set-aside from the account for that fiscal year; bears to</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H0B512E3C51DC4FB6809CAE175A6C87C5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total amount authorized to be appropriated for that fiscal year for all programs (except as provided in section 105(d) of title 23, United States Code) under such account;</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H47BCB6D842C54ED099930FB729685DC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by multiplying the ratio determined under subparagraph (A) by the amount of the adjustment for the account determined under section 105(b)(1)(B) of title 23, United States Code; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H523B33BFE5A24979BFEF69EADB98C274"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adjusting the amount that the Secretary would have allocated for the set-aside for that fiscal year but for section 105 of title 23, United States Code, by the amount calculated under subparagraph (B).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H644AE1145EAF417FB5D5F62512707EEE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Set-asides</header><text>The set-asides referred to in paragraph (1) are the amounts reserved for a fiscal year under each of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4E9D8E194F374D3CA329D236CDC27333"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 104(b)(5)(B) of title 23, United States Code;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7BD035F2689249FD8D57360FBB729CE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sections 104(h)(1) and 104(h)(2) of title 23, United States Code;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA7989999DA3546399743B5FEC53CF073"><enum>(C)</enum><text>section 130(e)(1) of title 23, United States Code;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H40980D90CFA24A4D8FBE3776BDA9F9D3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>section 133(h)(1)(A) of title 23, United States Code;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0D353B0FE0D7443283AB82865F9FD2A2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>section 1519(a) of MAP–21 (126 Stat. 524), as amended by section 1418 of the FAST Act (129 Stat. 1423); and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDDB48E9361E34DCC9BD67E72AB91E168"><enum>(F)</enum><text>section 5336(h)(1) of title 49, United States Code.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF79FFA1B6714297B05526440174C91C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 105(g) of title 23, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H1C9BB992FCD545B39820C58081FD2113"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) by inserting <quote>or the Temporary Transportation Bond Repayment Account</quote> before the period at the end; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7E709C6A0BCD44E4931AC1C65AA11350"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86302166CBCE41DC9D3361110588E643" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H46B573B6D54C4956B4C577F9470F21A3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Temporary Transportation Bond Repayment Account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Temporary Transportation Bond Repayment Account</term> means the Temporary Transportation Bond Repayment Account of the Highway Trust Fund established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9503">section 9503(g)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDE07C4199388450D85B7E615565E3FAE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Temporary transportation bond repayment account</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9503">Section 9503</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block id="H55A1E4A220974B618DED4829EBF80975" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H636D4679EE9A4CA8847D611DD53B8A51"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Establishment of temporary transportation bond repayment account</header> <paragraph id="HB223FDD596AA4545AD3198624F47EA9F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Creation of account</header><text>There is established in the Highway Trust Fund a separate account to be known as the <quote>Temporary Transportation Bond Repayment Account</quote> consisting of such amounts as may be transferred or credited to the Temporary Transportation Bond Repayment Account as provided in this section.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90302046C6F148929850DC1F980C6937"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfers to temporary transportation bond repayment account</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer to the Temporary Transportation Bond Repayment Account the portion of the amounts appropriated to the Highway Trust Fund under subsection (b) which are attributable to the increase in taxes under—</text> <subparagraph id="HF00F0A415DCA4456A81142B9385BFC73"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 4041 by reason of section 4041(a)(4), and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4BC687EDAA504D90A56FAAA7BDAA15EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 4081 by reason of section 4081(a)(2)(E).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3FCCAA13AB84A018B2A1A8BAA93A07A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Expenditures from account</header><text>Amounts in the Temporary Transportation Bond Repayment Account shall be available for redeeming bonds and paying interest payments issued under section 3 of the <short-title>Investing in America: A Penny for Progress Act</short-title>.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2548CD4594B744378F26E7DFE3428345"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>When all bonds issued under section 3 of the <short-title>Investing in America: A Penny for Progress Act</short-title> have been redeemed—</text> <subparagraph id="H6FBF53FC59FD4078A6F60A85DC577EB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Temporary Transportation Bond Repayment Account shall close, and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0230CAAE784A45438568296414473B5C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all amounts in the account (and all future revenue that, absent this paragraph, would have been transferred to the account pursuant to paragraph (2)) shall be transferred to the Highway Trust Fund with 80 percent allocated to the Highway Account (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9503">section 9503(e)(5)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) and 20 percent allocated to the Mass Transit Account.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection id="HC4413BC9BD34490B99F63B89D9F682D7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9503">Section 9503(e)(5)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>or the Temporary Transportation Bond Repayment Account</quote> before the period at the end.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H718863AC7AF541B7A5D21D04B0F8F0E7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply upon enactment of this law.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H1A55751DF7C04203B8CAA6CD07A5B538" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Conditions and performance reporting</header> <subsection id="H294B0CD64BA94174829951FC7A1E1139"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report on infrastructure investment needs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 503(b)(8) of title 23, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13F045CEFE5C49C6B78263C62CD2C4CD" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H8F3E5B445FC9478093D46F01C415155A"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Report on infrastructure investment needs</header> 
<subparagraph id="H408A98345ECE490790A8C611228692D7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than July 31, 2018, and July 31 of every second year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a report that describes—</text> <clause id="H55E7625E2E8842D1B9C72521032E4273"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the current conditions and performance of highway and bridge facilities in the United States, including the backlog of current highway and bridge needs; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="HC6C2BDE24594419492DA589681B9A6D9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the future needs of highway and bridge facilities in the United States.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8320268F214D4E5EAA3E44A2D29230C6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Comparisons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A report under this paragraph shall include all information necessary to relate and compare the conditions and performance measures used in the previous biennial reports to the conditions and performance measures used in the current report.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC4EB173B16614239B0120998EDF02ACB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Report requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing a report under this paragraph, the Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="HB9C2287D79CD4A1CB50542FCC4C070CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prepare a complete assessment of highway and bridge facilities in the United States;</text> </clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HB676A4A9BE174015B440EF7B79DC5514"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for the succeeding 20-year period, estimate future capital requirements for highway and bridge facilities in the United States at specified levels of service;</text> </clause> <clause id="HF0557798F11F4E54AA8ADCBBA6C35666"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for the succeeding 20-year period, estimate the annual expenditures necessary to fund capital projects in the United States that—</text> 
<subclause id="H1E6B65D0E253403B899F3155F6F145E5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are necessary to address the current and future needs of highway and bridge facilities; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H9117FF572A304C039597735C15360185"><enum>(II)</enum><text>have a benefit-cost ratio greater than or equal to 1;</text> </subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HCC3B0F456A9943F593583136994AF7DC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>for the period ending December 31, 2036, estimate the annual expenditures necessary to fund capital projects in the United States that—</text> <subclause id="H652E9E34C9B149EB8A6FFF59175822CE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are necessary to address the current and future needs of highway and bridge facilities; and</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="H88D8699DF391442291F9F1EE3272A56A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>have a benefit-cost ratio greater than or equal to 1; and</text> </subclause></clause> <clause id="H737F3D4F180D4333B4DD0DCFD7CE1527"><enum>(v)</enum><text>for the preceding 10-year period, estimate the average annual percentage of the total expenditures made for highway and bridge capital projects by all levels of government that was derived from Federal funds.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HFD3D57E2274A479385444E7440DC80C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on public transportation investment needs</header><text>Section 308(e) of title 49, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2AE74953041F4F2A898679571770426E" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H7DA666D541C84E48A4BEF78F1E2F7741"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report on public transportation investment needs</header> <paragraph id="H6CBB3468ED0C4A2CA48E63FAEE0AA107"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than July 31, 2018, and July 31 of every second year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate a report that describes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0FD8564FBD14419D903B413A257C2C8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the current conditions and performance of public transportation systems in the United States, including the state of good repair backlog among existing public transportation systems; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFC55E4C46A5F4A7393137FEB4CEF5E0C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the future needs of public transportation systems in the United States.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEDC58914AF9C42D9B6A65CCBA224B109"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comparisons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A report under this subsection shall include all information necessary to relate and compare the conditions and performance measures used in the previous biennial reports to the conditions and performance measures used in the current report.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H851EAC9EE33C49EBAD81FF216640C594"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing a report under this subsection, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H58699961501F4EAEBD1CFE86073BCC21"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prepare a complete assessment of public transportation systems in the United States;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9AAC7F019CE641A0A6565CA6E5D672AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for the succeeding 20-year period, estimate the future capital requirements for public transportation systems in the United States at specified levels of service;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFE1CB0F9ED844AC39E0122D9B0034294"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the succeeding 20-year period, estimate the annual capital expenditures necessary to fund capital projects in the United States that have a benefit-cost ratio greater than one and are necessary—</text> <clause id="HE3BFF888FD294087AB2131DCDE73F6D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to achieve and maintain a state of good repair for public transportation systems; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="HE95BAD649F164FBF818A023F598B6FFB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to support the long-term trend rate of public transportation ridership growth, plus an additional 0.3 percent; and</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC09640D2E3614F8DAE04A96BA2282D51"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the period ending December 31, 2036, estimate the annual capital expenditures necessary to fund capital projects in the United States that have a benefit-cost ratio greater than one and are necessary—</text> 
<clause id="H9B55A72DBF7048DD845F473589161B7D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to achieve and maintain a state of good repair for public transportation systems; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H24F1DF869EBF437E923374EADB0BC205"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to support the long-term trend rate of public transportation ridership growth, plus an additional 0.3 percent; and</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF0164F88D81943ACAE2448B2FC52634E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>for the preceding 10-year period, estimate the average annual percentage of the total expenditures made by all levels of government for public transportation capital expenditures that was derived from Federal funds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection id="H7A53A693E7564C929381A8E2163BACFD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Interim reporting method</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to the publication of the reports required under the amendments made by subsections (a) and (b), the Secretary of Transportation shall provide to the Secretary of the Treasury the data necessary to calculate the bond face amount under section 3(b) using the most recent published reports required by section 503(b)(8) of title 23, United States Code, and section 308(e) of title 49, United States Code.</text> </subsection></section> 
<section id="H9C8FA73AC1A44BEDA948C81A64856889"><enum>5.</enum><header>Repeal of FAST Act rescission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1438 of the FAST Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/94">Public Law 114–94</external-xref>; 129 Stat. 1432), and the item relating to that section in section 1(b) of that Act, are repealed.</text> </section> </legis-body> </bill> 

