<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HB81A6B6536CF401D94BC175490AE9456" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1372 EH: Homeland Security for Children Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1372</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to ensure that the needs of children are considered in homeland security planning, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HBD211674B43440EEB449ACB362CF0D76" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H711FB72C76864DA58E2894B5818DA411" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Homeland Security for Children Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3AC399BF2DAF46578676647492F3DA27"><enum>2.</enum><header>Responsibilities of the Under Secretary for Strategy, Policy, and Plans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (6) of section 709(c) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/349">6 U.S.C. 349(c)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including feedback from organizations representing the needs of children,</quote> after <quote>stakeholder feedback</quote>. </text></section>
<section id="HC416B949C44F41BC87BEC70E4597D633"><enum>3.</enum><header>Technical expert authorized</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of section 503(b) of the Homeland Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/313">6 U.S.C. 313(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H77A2CA3A876946B48DE212E76BCE174D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H184A1E9CC8E04419ACDC9C3263286E33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02D1B0DD534846478D758140B3791F2E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H10B9A6C1F0E14468B11543AA2E2F92C7" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subparagraph id="H6CAC4E17E737435EBA6D8B698CC3202A"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify and integrate the needs of children into activities to prepare for, protect against, respond to, recover from, and mitigate against the risk of natural disasters, acts of terrorism, and other manmade disasters, including catastrophic incidents, including by appointing a technical expert, who may consult with relevant outside organizations and experts, as necessary, to coordinate such integration, as necessary.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="H05D0EC1C51994CAAB3D21507736A6C34"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter for five years, the Under Secretary for Strategy, Policy, and Plans of the Department of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report describing the efforts the Department has undertaken to review and incorporate feedback from organizations representing the needs of children into Department policy in accordance with paragraph (6) of section 709(c) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (as added by section 2 of this Act), including information on the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HE5F1EAD8BE954EE38ABB3A01BF2C0058" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The designation of any individual responsible for carrying out such paragraph (6).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B2357C39959478088E83F0D5BB38E6F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any review, formal or informal, of Department policies, programs, or activities to assess the suitability of such policies, programs, or activities for children and where feedback from organizations representing the needs of children should be reviewed and incorporated.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF38528868C4C464F947C568DEBDEB3F8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any review, change, modification, or promulgation of Department policies, programs, or activities to ensure that such policies, programs, or activities are appropriate for children.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E43821D72D7448FAAA7E851F3325345" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Coordination with organizations or experts outside the Department pursuant to such paragraph (6) conducted to inform any such review, change, modification, or promulgation of such policies, programs, or activities.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20170425" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives April 25, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


