<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3BCDA50D397C4B609228822B5244C62D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 253 IH: Family First Prevention Services Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 253</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170104">January 4, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000263">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend parts B and E of title IV of the Social Security Act to invest in funding prevention and
			 family services to help keep children safe and supported at home, to
			 ensure that children in foster care are placed in the least restrictive,
			 most family-like, and appropriate settings, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H75A27748010446EDB5691884B9928F56" style="OLC">
 <section id="H66ACD028997140EE970FFE319BB1C740" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Family First Prevention Services Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7362D248CAB64650A4FD629F121FE20A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
			<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
				<toc-entry idref="H66ACD028997140EE970FFE319BB1C740" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H7362D248CAB64650A4FD629F121FE20A" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H16FA085ADDE14376AB0AA5656CBE8596" level="title">Title I—Investing in Prevention and Family Services</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HACAE84E4FE8A433B83C0CD50A6E5BB51" level="section">Sec. 101. Purpose.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HE6AB6CD6166E4C6DABFF9E5D7E220CBC" level="subtitle">Subtitle A—Prevention Activities under Title IV–E</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H160CD8FA73004F57820A5E513EEA0F50" level="section">Sec. 111. Foster care prevention services and programs.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H242CFFCF222C49C19E8E16C7C0043581" level="section">Sec. 112. Foster care maintenance payments for children with parents in a licensed residential
			 family-based treatment facility for substance abuse.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HBC372884D58E46CA88D1BB84D524B88E" level="section">Sec. 113. Title IV–E payments for evidence-based kinship navigator programs.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HF1E38F5E8F984BFD9CFF4A244F2F8666" level="subtitle">Subtitle B—Enhanced support under Title IV–B</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H06C48F52AC424D9D81355BAAA794F361" level="section">Sec. 121. Elimination of time limit for family reunification services while in foster care and
			 permitting time-limited family reunification services when a child returns
			 home from foster care.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HD72D114FD55F46EFA27370A600E2171B" level="section">Sec. 122. Reducing bureaucracy and unnecessary delays when placing children in homes across State
			 lines.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HA6EF9444204E4ECC8FF3268950FF7C82" level="section">Sec. 123. Enhancements to grants to improve well-being of families affected by substance abuse.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H6AB1082FFF1B472890AA54CF1FD567D2" level="subtitle">Subtitle C—Miscellaneous</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HF9FC39F400894EA6B55B3C124753188C" level="section">Sec. 131. Reviewing and improving licensing standards for placement in a relative foster family
			 home.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H32651A8D3E9C4B149BE2D4ABCE9088F8" level="section">Sec. 132. Development of a statewide plan to prevent child abuse and neglect fatalities.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HB690F5B4F14544A3A84C05F28B05E019" level="section">Sec. 133. Modernizing the title and purpose of title IV–E.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H7945376008C94663A374B4112FE0949A" level="section">Sec. 134. Effective dates.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H422BD07F3F5D40429CBDAA4A24BD4644" level="title">Title II—Ensuring the Necessity of a Placement that is not in a Foster Family Home</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HBF16C598AA194A8F9986F0020503A696" level="section">Sec. 201. Limitation on Federal financial participation for placements that are not in foster
			 family homes.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H47EC5C4EC39D4F5695CA643D9BF3328F" level="section">Sec. 202. Assessment and documentation of the need for placement in a qualified residential
			 treatment program.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H6467F6CFC8DB4AC1BF2EF9B1627DF57E" level="section">Sec. 203. Protocols to prevent inappropriate diagnoses.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H809A2934EB00429BBD6173F5B8F5DA68" level="section">Sec. 204. Additional data and reports regarding children placed in a setting that is not a foster
			 family home.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H052D776096644DB196F98F666719F4FB" level="section">Sec. 205. Effective dates; application to waivers.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HF0E3F4BBC8C64247A14EB64B49DC2D89" level="title">Title III—Continuing Support for Child and Family Services</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H72B7660D46D641B89509094ECAC65FE2" level="section">Sec. 301. Supporting and retaining foster families for children.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H2A199E1728BA47DF99687FDEBFCACD1E" level="section">Sec. 302. Extension of child and family services programs.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H6A0719E854FC44BFA4BEB503B16BC273" level="section">Sec. 303. Improvements to the John H. Chafee foster care independence program and related
			 provisions.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H0CA722A11EFA47E4A00933B71EFEE71C" level="title">Title IV—Continuing Incentives to States to Promote Adoption and Legal Guardianship</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H2E74F34DEB79400AA375553018C86CB1" level="section">Sec. 401. Reauthorizing adoption and legal guardianship incentive programs.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H4F18DCA6078549B8A9355D28290D7C22" level="title">Title V—Technical Corrections</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H7F42203660C64DF3BE61FA05A56152BD" level="section">Sec. 501. Technical corrections to data exchange standards to improve program coordination.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HDEACD24C7BD8486E94ACDC9B98903172" level="section">Sec. 502. Technical corrections to State requirement to address the developmental needs of young
			 children.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H0D9D122EDFCD4F6AB03697B915629038" level="title">Title VI—Ensuring States reinvest savings resulting from increase in adoption assistance</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HC1539A25EDCB4B7799C01F72A589E989" level="section">Sec. 601. Delay of adoption assistance phase-in.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H20C97C0E8457482E8F4EB796695A24CF" level="section">Sec. 602. GAO study and report on State reinvestment of savings resulting from increase in adoption
			 assistance.</toc-entry>
			</toc>
		</section><title id="H16FA085ADDE14376AB0AA5656CBE8596" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Investing in Prevention and Family Services</header>
 <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACAE84E4FE8A433B83C0CD50A6E5BB51" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>101.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this title is to enable States to use Federal funds available under parts B and E of title IV of the Social Security Act to provide enhanced support to children and families and prevent foster care placements through the provision of mental health and substance abuse prevention and treatment services, in-home parent skill-based programs, and kinship navigator services.</text>
			</section><subtitle id="HE6AB6CD6166E4C6DABFF9E5D7E220CBC" style="OLC"><enum>A</enum><header>Prevention Activities under Title IV–E</header>
				<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H160CD8FA73004F57820A5E513EEA0F50" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>111.</enum><header>Foster care prevention services and programs</header>
 <subsection id="H587630927F844AF0B9837D9BDDDC820F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State option</header><text>Section 471 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/671">42 U.S.C. 671</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8EE71919F9FB4B6DBC29F4C56210E78B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1), by striking <quote>and</quote> and all that follows through the semicolon and inserting <quote>, adoption assistance in accordance with section 473, and, at the option of the State, services or programs specified in subsection (e)(1) of this section for children who are candidates for foster care or who are pregnant or parenting foster youth and the parents or kin caregivers of the children, in accordance with the requirements of that subsection;</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5BA097DD4BFB42428B642B1C10945F57"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE814075F9B0242FE8BA07C40AE4446BC" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H23CCA9C822054B6BB5FDE764409D7C8B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prevention and family services and programs</header> <paragraph id="H3D51815096774F1981C3196159330EBF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the succeeding provisions of this subsection, the Secretary may make a payment to a State for providing the following services or programs for a child described in paragraph (2) and the parents or kin caregivers of the child when the need of the child, such a parent, or such a caregiver for the services or programs are directly related to the safety, permanence, or well-being of the child or to preventing the child from entering foster care:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF17A2857EE8F415E88F154E404DFD718"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Mental health and substance abuse prevention and treatment services</header><text>Mental health and substance abuse prevention and treatment services provided by a qualified clinician for not more than a 12-month period that begins on any date described in paragraph (3) with respect to the child.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52D0EC58C6D6440D9A3D96DF20EC0053"><enum>(B)</enum><header>In-home parent skill-based programs</header><text>In-home parent skill-based programs for not more than a 12-month period that begins on any date described in paragraph (3) with respect to the child and that include parenting skills training, parent education, and individual and family counseling.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65A011E834D84047BBFAA11BCD4D53F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Child described</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), a child described in this paragraph is the following:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D5D04DC4262428EA901177BF9800A0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A child who is a candidate for foster care (as defined in section 475(13)) but can remain safely at home or in a kinship placement with receipt of services or programs specified in paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE8DECE31F364C6780FD90B0B01928B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A child in foster care who is a pregnant or parenting foster youth.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD6B35A0C1768477987BA360550E9353B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Date described</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the dates described in this paragraph are the following:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC9F04B78AF6D49F196344CD11A992131"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The date on which a child is identified in a prevention plan maintained under paragraph (4) as a child who is a candidate for foster care (as defined in section 475(13)).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E76F5F9CA0744578D4993C0EC4BEC13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The date on which a child is identified in a prevention plan maintained under paragraph (4) as a pregnant or parenting foster youth in need of services or programs specified in paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD7DE00D104C488F8A7CE45E8B9640CA"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Requirements related to providing services and programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Services and programs specified in paragraph (1) may be provided under this subsection only if specified in advance in the child’s prevention plan described in subparagraph (A) and the requirements in subparagraphs (B) through (E) are met:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB0D8B300B8B4485A8E0F0A8FFBB5E064"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Prevention plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State maintains a written prevention plan for the child that meets the following requirements (as applicable):</text>
 <clause id="H4F9165CA2F3942AC892442882CF9F570"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Candidates</header><text>In the case of a child who is a candidate for foster care described in paragraph (2)(A), the prevention plan shall—</text>
 <subclause id="HC838CB6188704E21A9BD532C1298E013"><enum>(I)</enum><text>identify the foster care prevention strategy for the child so that the child may remain safely at home, live temporarily with a kin caregiver until reunification can be safely achieved, or live permanently with a kin caregiver;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6AE0532558494CBDB37A8772ABC468E2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>list the services or programs to be provided to or on behalf of the child to ensure the success of that prevention strategy; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8A76C803786C4FC5B33888721707E97E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>comply with such other requirements as the Secretary shall establish.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H4A2369E73C2A43EBA99F688BB0230E57"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Pregnant or parenting foster youth</header><text>In the case of a child who is a pregnant or parenting foster youth described in paragraph (2)(B), the prevention plan shall—</text>
 <subclause id="H9DE89E008E47438E930004EEA8FD38A1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>be included in the child's case plan required under section 475(1);</text> </subclause><subclause id="HBB9C60A373E5494AAAEBDC8897860052"><enum>(II)</enum><text>list the services or programs to be provided to or on behalf of the youth to ensure that the youth is prepared (in the case of a pregnant foster youth) or able (in the case of a parenting foster youth) to be a parent;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4BFC9C2BA3864864937C398393D183C2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>describe the foster care prevention strategy for any child born to the youth; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H104D6236118D4D9EBB333874E15A1A31"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>comply with such other requirements as the Secretary shall establish.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H298141E884C14E358BB28E83FD9E207A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Trauma-informed</header><text>The services or programs to be provided to or on behalf of a child are provided under an organizational structure and treatment framework that involves understanding, recognizing, and responding to the effects of all types of trauma and in accordance with recognized principles of a trauma-informed approach and trauma-specific interventions to address trauma’s consequences and facilitate healing.</text>
										</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06C33134CE3D43F5A24E94FF1C15AC6B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Only services and programs provided in accordance with promising, supported, or well-supported
			 practices permitted</header>
 <clause id="H3F1DF5731E80422A8CB22CABEDEAF5BE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Only State expenditures for services or programs specified in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) that are provided in accordance with practices that meet the requirements specified in clause (ii) of this subparagraph and that meet the requirements specified in clause (iii), (iv), or (v), respectively, for being a promising, supported, or well-supported practice, shall be eligible for a Federal matching payment under section 474(a)(6)(A).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H46BC165059D9479AA24DCD2E3063F347"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>General practice requirements</header><text>The general practice requirements specified in this clause are the following:</text> <subclause id="H6C4D3BC9D5B14336AE6C92A0F16C63E8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The practice has a book, manual, or other available writings that specify the components of the practice protocol and describe how to administer the practice.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3757A4042E7140BA9C4A6A29DF02E5BF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>There is no empirical basis suggesting that, compared to its likely benefits, the practice constitutes a risk of harm to those receiving it.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD5F6450092394102860965A5D8F4C3C5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>If multiple outcome studies have been conducted, the overall weight of evidence supports the benefits of the practice.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7F271FEC6DBF4BE6B70D00EB6A49CDF8"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Outcome measures are reliable and valid, and are administrated consistently and accurately across all those receiving the practice.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H956C6052307E4E50B0215B2132B3435C"><enum>(V)</enum><text>There is no case data suggesting a risk of harm that was probably caused by the treatment and that was severe or frequent.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H0F5A93A03C024BB9BAB3497924D63E78"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Promising practice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A practice shall be considered to be a <term>promising practice</term> if the practice is superior to an appropriate comparison practice using conventional standards of statistical significance (in terms of demonstrated meaningful improvements in validated measures of important child and parent outcomes, such as mental health, substance abuse, and child safety and well-being), as established by the results or outcomes of at least one study that—</text>
 <subclause id="H9C256F0A7B9D4D2FB8733E803B94D276"><enum>(I)</enum><text>was rated by an independent systematic review for the quality of the study design and execution and determined to be well-designed and well-executed; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEC76CE03B299429581BBC120A9874929"><enum>(II)</enum><text>utilized some form of control (such as an untreated group, a placebo group, or a wait list study).</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HB79BBB5AD8AA451585E23DA56F1F11AF"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Supported practice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A practice shall be considered to be a <term>supported practice</term> if—</text>
 <subclause id="HC5DE29E104774449BA0D9A217A7A2082"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the practice is superior to an appropriate comparison practice using conventional standards of statistical significance (in terms of demonstrated meaningful improvements in validated measures of important child and parent outcomes, such as mental health, substance abuse, and child safety and well-being), as established by the results or outcomes of at least one study that—</text>
 <item id="H938CADD00CB44D95B8C23D4E5A0A2C66"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>was rated by an independent systematic review for the quality of the study design and execution and determined to be well-designed and well-executed;</text>
 </item><item id="HB18B3EAC52B94D2D9247D89B622B0F46"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>was a rigorous random-controlled trial (or, if not available, a study using a rigorous quasi-experimental research design); and</text>
 </item><item id="HF74E679BCB3640219517F0CAB4E33F8C"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>was carried out in a usual care or practice setting; and</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="H6B299E33F1D843A0BFAF312666423088"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the study described in subclause (I) established that the practice has a sustained effect (when compared to a control group) for at least 6 months beyond the end of the treatment.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HCDBB34B06634419D8169EC558DE9F041"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Well-supported practice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A practice shall be considered to be a <term>well-supported practice</term> if—</text> <subclause id="H60CF6005FEA7402FB543AB0776B4C453"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the practice is superior to an appropriate comparison practice using conventional standards of statistical significance (in terms of demonstrated meaningful improvements in validated measures of important child and parent outcomes, such as mental health, substance abuse, and child safety and well-being), as established by the results or outcomes of at least two studies that—</text>
 <item id="H28F2B7758F65401585FA88EE36D91A97"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">were rated by an independent systematic review for the quality of the study design and execution and determined to be well-designed and well-executed;</text>
 </item><item display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9282C6DBDAFA4DEB8E7847078FDA778C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>were rigorous random-controlled trials (or, if not available, studies using a rigorous quasi-experimental research design); and</text>
 </item><item id="H369A2E08274946EB9278AB1EDCE82B62"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">were carried out in a usual care or practice setting; and</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="H70C62773C8164FA4B2429995F8040BEF"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least one of the studies described in subclause (I) established that the practice has a sustained effect (when compared to a control group) for at least 1 year beyond the end of treatment.</text>
												</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H020CF86152D84F578CFD2258CA08FFC9"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Guidance on practices criteria and pre-approved services and programs</header>
 <clause id="H0926BE3F5D334308BB1CE7504975EA54"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than October 1, 2018, the Secretary shall issue guidance to States regarding the practices criteria required for services or programs to satisfy the requirements of subparagraph (C). The guidance shall include a pre-approved list of services and programs that satisfy the requirements.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE2A05FF4EC3E43BBA17FBBAC3A6D066B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Secretary shall issue updates to the guidance required by clause (i) as often as the Secretary determines necessary.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB2460C240A6479F98BE1DA9D7967FA1"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Outcome assessment and reporting</header><text>The State shall collect and report to the Secretary the following information with respect to each child for whom, or on whose behalf mental health and substance abuse prevention and treatment services or in-home parent skill-based programs are provided during a 12-month period beginning on the date the child is determined by the State to be a child described in paragraph (2):</text>
 <clause id="H59578B91EA9540B9A03915D973F552B7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The specific services or programs provided and the total expenditures for each of the services or programs.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF747B1EEE8474660AD9039C407853090"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The duration of the services or programs provided.</text> </clause><clause id="HCBEEB6DB0C5749EFA5BA81BAC2248310"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a child described in paragraph (2)(A), the child’s placement status at the beginning, and at the end, of the 1-year period, respectively, and whether the child entered foster care within 2 years after being determined a candidate for foster care.</text>
											</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3F30AF4AAA44EF8AACBB599822663C5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State plan component</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA92349238DBA430AA5BBC8EC97AD4E19"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State electing to provide services or programs specified in paragraph (1) shall submit as part of the State plan required by subsection (a) a prevention services and programs plan component that meets the requirements of subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D0945DE82CC4266BFE03C93008B09AE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prevention services and programs plan component</header><text>In order to meet the requirements of this subparagraph, a prevention services and programs plan component, with respect to each 5-year period for which the plan component is in operation in the State, shall include the following:</text>
 <clause id="H0001485895F546888B257D8CAD6844A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How providing services and programs specified in paragraph (1) is expected to improve specific outcomes for children and families.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAD6C9620DF614A04B39E163B0BDA6549"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How the State will monitor and oversee the safety of children who receive services and programs specified in paragraph (1), including through periodic risk assessments throughout the period in which the services and programs are provided on behalf of a child and reexamination of the prevention plan maintained for the child under paragraph (4) for the provision of the services or programs if the State determines the risk of the child entering foster care remains high despite the provision of the services or programs.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBDD641483FC64E13847EC47FE66AB9CD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>With respect to the services and programs specified in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1), information on the specific promising, supported, or well-supported practices the State plans to use to provide the services or programs, including a description of—</text>
 <subclause id="H3257AA7753174B438F3B5280F7876777"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the services or programs and whether the practices used are promising, supported, or well-supported;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H27ABC6C3B69F4CB7B3CC41ADC1470EE8"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the State plans to implement the services or programs, including how implementation of the services or programs will be continuously monitored to ensure fidelity to the practice model and to determine outcomes achieved and how information learned from the monitoring will be used to refine and improve practices;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB2D74E44D6BE434F8702282CE146AE0D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>how the State selected the services or programs;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H1C68D39610244C6DBBE507B8B7D9BCA3"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the target population for the services or programs; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9178329D52B24688B5711B00E25D1E7D"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how each service or program provided will be evaluated through a well-designed and rigorous process, which may consist of an ongoing, cross-site evaluation approved by the Secretary.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HBC244625F43A4A0E9672DD06A0490FB5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A description of the consultation that the State agencies responsible for administering the State plans under this part and part B engage in with other State agencies responsible for administering health programs, including mental health and substance abuse prevention and treatment services, and with other public and private agencies with experience in administering child and family services, including community-based organizations, in order to foster a continuum of care for children described in paragraph (2) and their parents or kin caregivers.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2D595DF2984643C9AC7E3B226EB4A9EA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A description of how the State shall assess children and their parents or kin caregivers to determine eligibility for services or programs specified in paragraph (1).</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H041D80FA2B904E61B9C8BEFE91786B2F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>A description of how the services or programs specified in paragraph (1) that are provided for or on behalf of a child and the parents or kin caregivers of the child will be coordinated with other child and family services provided to the child and the parents or kin caregivers of the child under the State plan under part B.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9E28AEB5A90E4A598287DE7B66E8DAA8"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Descriptions of steps the State is taking to support and enhance a competent, skilled, and professional child welfare workforce to deliver trauma-informed and evidence-based services, including—</text>
 <subclause id="H3F9592EDB9784D0E81E1542F3AA76230"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring that staff is qualified to provide services or programs that are consistent with the promising, supported, or well-supported practice models selected; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H76753E387FD24FC8BCA043046FCC0048"><enum>(II)</enum><text>developing appropriate prevention plans, and conducting the risk assessments required under clause (iii).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HAC44A4BFD6244E558E7EAB8F5CE50B71"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how the State will provide training and support for caseworkers in assessing what children and their families need, connecting to the families served, knowing how to access and deliver the needed trauma-informed and evidence-based services, and overseeing and evaluating the continuing appropriateness of the services.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2A48CC62154D4B83862E66D353BB8D59"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>A description of how caseload size and type for prevention caseworkers will be determined, managed, and overseen.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H393B877BC0644BC8890FBB25472515B9"><enum>(x)</enum><text>An assurance that the State will report to the Secretary such information and data as the Secretary may require with respect to the provision of services and programs specified in paragraph (1), including information and data necessary to determine the performance measures for the State under paragraph (6) and compliance with paragraph (7).</text>
											</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38B3B7A272A340D7BBCDA57BAED279C1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reimbursement for services under the prevention plan component</header>
 <clause id="H493B5D276975460CB46598505D89DB38"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subclause (ii), a State may not receive a Federal payment under this part for a given promising, supported, or well-supported practice unless (in accordance with subparagraph (B)(iii)(V)) the plan includes a well-designed and rigorous evaluation strategy for that practice.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3A248B202C3D44A1A0C9E5CE8F4A4D03"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Waiver of limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may waive the requirement for a well-designed and rigorous evaluation of any well-supported practice if the Secretary deems the evidence of the effectiveness of the practice to be compelling and the State meets the continuous quality improvement requirements included in subparagraph (B)(iii)(II) with regard to the practice.</text>
											</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9A925D31A3D49A09F3B792238498475"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Prevention services measures</header>
 <subparagraph id="H887B43FD65DB4A08A4398D800E66887E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment; annual updates</header><text>Beginning with fiscal year 2021, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall establish the following prevention services measures based on information and data reported by States that elect to provide services and programs specified in paragraph (1):</text>
 <clause id="HE94EB7AA088F45539FBCCAAA46C58DB3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Percentage of candidates for foster care who do not enter foster care</header><text>The percentage of candidates for foster care for whom, or on whose behalf, the services or programs are provided who do not enter foster care, including those placed with a kin caregiver outside of foster care, during the 12-month period in which the services or programs are provided and through the end of the succeeding 12-month period.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2288794C776B4D5A9E4D8D84FB067285"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Per-child spending</header><text>The total amount of expenditures made for mental health and substance abuse prevention and treatment services or in-home parent skill-based programs, respectively, for, or on behalf of, each child described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D126EECF0D8479289A060780DA0BF73"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish and annually update the prevention services measures—</text> <clause id="H84BD5A3A6B2D494E9E496D774E9BEF2E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>based on the median State values of the information reported under each clause of subparagraph (A) for the 3 then most recent years; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H20EE50AB8B1549CA899CEC9B07A74E2B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>taking into account State differences in the price levels of consumption goods and services using the most recent regional price parities published by the Bureau of Economic Analysis of the Department of Commerce or such other data as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB68A83D979604C7B8799A160AA309E98"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Publication of State prevention services measures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall annually make available to the public the prevention services measures of each State.</text>
										</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF66B90BB2FAD40B58949AF6FE83299AC"><enum>(7)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Maintenance of effort for State foster care prevention expenditures</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB0FD5A6895E04E88A16A10491988FA4C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a State elects to provide services and programs specified in paragraph (1) for a fiscal year, the State foster care prevention expenditures for the fiscal year shall not be less than the amount of the expenditures for fiscal year 2014.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H165C2A900EAA45F2A23818CBF0D9867C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State foster care prevention expenditures</header><text>The term <term>State foster care prevention expenditures</term> means the following:</text> <clause id="H25CBDC307B294E5EAAF555070755F01F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>TANF; IV–B; SSBG</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State expenditures for foster care prevention services and activities under the State program funded under part A (including from amounts made available by the Federal Government), under the State plan developed under part B (including any such amounts), or under the Social Services Block Grant Programs under subtitle A of title XX (including any such amounts).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8B05FEC2CADC4EA68725E20A571900B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Other State programs</header><text>State expenditures for foster care prevention services and activities under any State program that is not described in clause (i) (other than any State expenditures for foster care prevention services and activities under the State program under this part (including under a waiver of the program)).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E37A87E5C554249BF7FC18A1A7AFEAF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>State expenditures</header><text>The term <term>State expenditures</term> means all State or local funds that are expended by the State or a local agency including State or local funds that are matched or reimbursed by the Federal Government and State or local funds that are not matched or reimbursed by the Federal Government.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43BE361578D344998462D87A5923B06B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Determination of prevention services and activities</header><text>The Secretary shall require each State that elects to provide services and programs specified in paragraph (1) to report the expenditures specified in subparagraph (B) for fiscal year 2014 and for such fiscal years thereafter as are necessary to determine whether the State is complying with the maintenance of effort requirement in subparagraph (A). The Secretary shall specify the specific services and activities under each program referred to in subparagraph (B) that are <term>prevention services and activities</term> for purposes of the reports.</text>
										</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC74DE83D0A94EA895DB0B2066F18271"><enum>(8)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition against use of state foster care prevention expenditures and federal iv–e prevention
 funds for matching or expenditure requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State that elects to provide services and programs specified in paragraph (1) shall not use any State foster care prevention expenditures for a fiscal year for the State share of expenditures under section 474(a)(6) for a fiscal year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA031BD0BB65344449BFA704FF898231D"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>Expenditures described in section 474(a)(6)(B)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0AAE25CFCAE44568AB1ADF45BFC0724B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not be eligible for payment under subparagraph (A), (B), or (E) of section 474(a)(3); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06CAFD0567ED4698B34A48D6A0C9C002"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be eligible for payment under section 474(a)(6)(B) without regard to whether the expenditures are incurred on behalf of a child who is, or is potentially, eligible for foster care maintenance payments under this part.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H282F889F0584435789D2038045BE72E6"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The provision of services or programs under this subsection to or on behalf of a child described in paragraph (2) shall not be considered to be receipt of aid or assistance under the State plan under this part for purposes of eligibility for any other program established under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H309B81F2D2934B2BBBE72646B4B42284"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>Section 475 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/675">42 U.S.C. 675</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H161458A42DD24580B1634A8BC33B3E92" style="OLC"> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52914BE2892C4C75B9276A5D48BA0AC7"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The term <term>child who is a candidate for foster care</term> means, a child who is identified in a prevention plan under section 471(e)(4)(A) as being at imminent risk of entering foster care (without regard to whether the child would be eligible for foster care maintenance payments under section 472 or is or would be eligible for adoption assistance or kinship guardianship assistance payments under section 473) but who can remain safely in the child's home or in a kinship placement as long as services or programs specified in section 471(e)(1) that are necessary to prevent the entry of the child into foster care are provided. The term includes a child whose adoption or guardianship arrangement is at risk of a disruption or dissolution that would result in a foster care placement.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HCCE8EE8905434B28B47E21D9BDAAFE8E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Payments under title IV–E</header><text>Section 474(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/674">42 U.S.C. 674(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H70DDC90F233E441DB0140D166A199A3F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; plus</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFCCB749CC085428DA2FA13C31DE4C99F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67D5FF38741F4724BBE024A04D65D2BE" style="OLC"> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H08CC0E299B9845C1B51A6E3EC5156111"><enum>(6)</enum><text>subject to section 471(e)—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E22648B8CA1474CB983EC8F66D52FCA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for each quarter—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H560AD1D88A16455E958492A05698FCEC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to clause (ii)—</text>
 <subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0E8CBB9CC1A401180019A72D54E0037"><enum>(I)</enum><text>beginning after September 30, 2019, and before October 1, 2025, an amount equal to 50 percent of the total amount expended during the quarter for the provision of services or programs specified in subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 471(e)(1) that are provided in accordance with promising, supported, or well-supported practices that meet the applicable criteria specified for the practices in section 471(e)(4)(C); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC1A5C58E4B6C46518F1294FFB31CC108"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning after September 30, 2025, an amount equal to the Federal medical assistance percentage (which shall be as defined in section 1905(b), in the case of a State other than the District of Columbia, or 70 percent, in the case of the District of Columbia) of the total amount expended during the quarter for the provision of services or programs specified in subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 471(e)(1) that are provided in accordance with promising, supported, or well-supported practices that meet the applicable criteria specified for the practices in section 471(e)(4)(C) (or, with respect to the payments made during the quarter under a cooperative agreement or contract entered into by the State and an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or tribal consortium for the administration or payment of funds under this part, an amount equal to the Federal medical assistance percentage that would apply under section 479B(d) (in this paragraph referred to as the <quote>tribal FMAP</quote>) if the Indian tribe, tribal organization, or tribal consortium made the payments under a program operated under that section, unless the tribal FMAP is less than the Federal medical assistance percentage that applies to the State); except that</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H60C1234907A746B69E555BAB30ABDEF9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not less than 50 percent of the total amount payable to a State under clause (i) for a fiscal year shall be for the provision of services or programs specified in subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 471(e)(1) that are provided in accordance with well-supported practices; plus</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6769B5FCFE494F0CAB2FE3290A227CAA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for each quarter specified in subparagraph (A), an amount equal to the sum of the following proportions of the total amount expended during the quarter:</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE723B56A1EE14569846671CE41A4600E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>50 percent of so much of the expenditures as are found necessary by the Secretary for the proper and efficient administration of the State plan for the provision of services or programs specified in section 471(e)(1), including expenditures for activities approved by the Secretary that promote the development of necessary processes and procedures to establish and implement the provision of the services and programs for individuals who are eligible for the services and programs and expenditures attributable to data collection and reporting; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE374418D8214180AF24EEF699996187"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">50 percent of so much of the expenditures with respect to the provision of services and programs specified in section 471(e)(1) as are for training of personnel employed or preparing for employment by the State agency or by the local agency administering the plan in the political subdivision and of the members of the staff of State-licensed or State-approved child welfare agencies providing services to children described in section 471(e)(2) and their parents or kin caregivers, including on how to determine who are individuals eligible for the services or programs, how to identify and provide appropriate services and programs, and how to oversee and evaluate the ongoing appropriateness of the services and programs.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H04213F8D21D04D10BBA6AA0A8FD7CBA5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical assistance and best practices, clearinghouse, and data collection and evaluations</header><text>Section 476 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/676">42 U.S.C. 676</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE090B62F97EB44AD84D91A67391FA0DE" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H7356796A5DF9480D961DFF1CCF7507B4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical assistance and best practices, clearinghouse, data collection, and evaluations relating to prevention services and programs</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA38F8E78CC794D6A89CAE688CD86EB20"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Technical assistance and best practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide to States and, as applicable, to Indian tribes, tribal organizations, and tribal consortia, technical assistance regarding the provision of services and programs described in section 471(e)(1) and shall disseminate best practices with respect to the provision of the services and programs, including how to plan and implement a well-designed and rigorous evaluation of a promising, supported, or well-supported practice.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58D2DA9188FC47EB9EF29F58AE42EA73"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clearinghouse of promising, supported, and well-supported practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, directly or through grants, contracts, or interagency agreements, evaluate research on the practices specified in clauses (iii), (iv), and (v), respectively, of section 471(e)(4)(C), and programs that meet the requirements described in section 427(a)(1), including culturally specific, or location- or population-based adaptations of the practices, to identify and establish a public clearinghouse of the practices that satisfy each category described by such clauses. In addition, the clearinghouse shall include information on the specific outcomes associated with each practice, including whether the practice has been shown to prevent child abuse and neglect and reduce the likelihood of foster care placement by supporting birth families and kinship families and improving targeted supports for pregnant and parenting youth and their children.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B2C68EAB7E24AF383D08114B63623F1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Data collection and evaluations</header><text>The Secretary, directly or through grants, contracts, or interagency agreements, may collect data and conduct evaluations with respect to the provision of services and programs described in section 471(e)(1) for purposes of assessing the extent to which the provision of the services and programs—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF4591EEA885240ED97AF40416A6651EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reduces the likelihood of foster care placement;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30E7CC49E3ED4462A4C341BA474F7172"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increases use of kinship care arrangements; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A66442B9C2E403CB8809966F101DB03"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improves child well-being.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H925DFD3C74134D0DABE640F9E32A49DC"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reports to Congress</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76601066D2464575894F33FA85CB2AB9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives periodic reports based on the provision of services and programs described in section 471(e)(1) and the activities carried out under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73C6CD47886F4678A3F077C034BFE8D1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary shall make the reports to Congress submitted under this paragraph publicly available.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8F3AEF8DFAC46D3BE35F2CAD9AFFB23"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, there is appropriated to the Secretary $1,000,000 for fiscal year 2017 and each fiscal year thereafter to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subsection><subsection id="H45CCA60829CC41B2B9A9066A8D3033D3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application to programs operated by indian tribal organizations</header>
 <paragraph id="H61EE6B6CBD564E4098F3F1617EA6A5E2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 479B of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/679c">42 U.S.C. 679c</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H7466FF8E86E34D999075B1A1B79F54E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)—</text>
 <clause id="H1E0AF8B8D38B419A828FE9B632BF7F86"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(i)—</text> <subclause id="H995B0ECDA45041ECA7EC54E7B711CC27"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in subclause (II), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H21EC8BCAB7754879ABC8887934223176"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subclause (III), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HF86BAE38577C4A89828F622C1E26CC38"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
										<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2289D694C7BF4071B439604B9A332025" style="OLC">
 <subclause id="HA10587FA15F9403F91C9161E5D738688"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>at the option of the tribe, organization, or consortium, services and programs specified in section 471(e)(1) to children described in section 471(e)(2) and their parents or kin caregivers, in accordance with section 471(e) and subparagraph (E).</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H6CD40B932D7846379A26433FC25C3B01"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E6B11BAB3EF484BBCB5C57859A703F6" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H2E38F47D01DB446F9AF8D71C049D77E3"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Prevention services and programs for children and their parents and kin caregivers</header> <clause id="H09561EF7F76F46C9ABEC60542443DD09"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a tribe, organization, or consortium that elects to provide services and programs specified in section 471(e)(1) to children described in section 471(e)(2) and their parents or kin caregivers under the plan, the Secretary shall specify the requirements applicable to the provision of the services and programs. The requirements shall, to the greatest extent practicable, be consistent with the requirements applicable to States under section 471(e) and shall permit the provision of the services and programs in the form of services and programs that are adapted to the culture and context of the tribal communities served.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1AAAD53769C1435CBE6255B4DE16566E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Performance measures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish specific performance measures for each tribe, organization, or consortium that elects to provide services and programs specified in section 471(e)(1). The performance measures shall, to the greatest extent practicable, be consistent with the prevention services measures required for States under section 471(e)(6) but shall allow for consideration of factors unique to the provision of the services by tribes, organizations, or consortia.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13A4E47311B1428FA4110A27FF00EA10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1), by striking <quote>and (5)</quote> and inserting <quote>(5), and (6)(A)</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59EDF35BF04247A5A16C2252388EABCD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The heading for subsection (d) of section 479B of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/679c">42 U.S.C. 679c</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">for Foster Care Maintenance and Adoption Assistance Payments</header-in-text></quote>.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H242CFFCF222C49C19E8E16C7C0043581"><enum>112.</enum><header>Foster care maintenance payments for children with parents in a licensed residential family-based
			 treatment facility for substance abuse</header>
 <subsection id="HEB9F5F3EABFF4132A87A52FEDFCE2AD1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 472 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/672">42 U.S.C. 672</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H0AE66F7359094B588B7BD47883F14369"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2)(C), by striking <quote>or</quote> and inserting <quote>, with a parent residing in a licensed residential family-based treatment facility, but only to the extent permitted under subsection (j), or in a </quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD14E98EB8BF49B3B8E7980990768431"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H932EBB25B492485E9B5CCF0B7AD73F60" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HBDFB50FCE7704229AEECC64CDBC0473C"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Children placed with a parent residing in a licensed residential family-Based treatment facility for substance abuse</header> <paragraph id="HAFC1B5DF09324734B63CE09AA31F079B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding the preceding provisions of this section, a child who is eligible for foster care maintenance payments under this section, or who would be eligible for the payments if the eligibility were determined without regard to paragraphs (1)(B) and (3) of subsection (a), shall be eligible for the payments for a period of not more than 12 months during which the child is placed with a parent who is in a licensed residential family-based treatment facility for substance abuse, but only if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB202FA48A43D4002A15359466F4C0BC9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the recommendation for the placement is specified in the child's case plan before the placement;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62448533CAA747799652712566D1683A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the treatment facility provides, as part of the treatment for substance abuse, parenting skills training, parent education, and individual and family counseling; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DAF9C50FDCE43B0965B9E8640DD02F7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the substance abuse treatment, parenting skills training, parent education, and individual and family counseling is provided under an organizational structure and treatment framework that involves understanding, recognizing, and responding to the effects of all types of trauma and in accordance with recognized principles of a trauma-informed approach and trauma-specific interventions to address the consequences of trauma and facilitate healing.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2426C8BFA4194B359723953261EC0F9B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>With respect to children for whom foster care maintenance payments are made under paragraph (1), only the children who satisfy the requirements of paragraphs (1)(B) and (3) of subsection (a) shall be considered to be children with respect to whom foster care maintenance payments are made under this section for purposes of subsection (h) or section 473(b)(3)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H92619F1D817A43B8B0B26C5CC8867E5E"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 474(a)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/674">42 U.S.C. 674(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>subject to section 472(j),</quote> before <quote>an amount equal to the Federal</quote> the first place it appears.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HBC372884D58E46CA88D1BB84D524B88E"><enum>113.</enum><header>Title IV–E payments for evidence-based kinship navigator programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 474(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/674">42 U.S.C. 674(a)</external-xref>), as amended by section 111(c), is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H05783C80B51847CC898B9D06E853B7C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; plus</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8EED5604F2F544089799D0B28EDA3E21"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H596043C5713C4A18A0F66ADF1CECDBAA" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H87BE0E0E25174C99B6E2B4C9E72E4D38"><enum>(7)</enum><text>an amount equal to 50 percent of the amounts expended by the State during the quarter as the Secretary determines are for kinship navigator programs that meet the requirements described in section 427(a)(1) and that the Secretary determines are operated in accordance with promising, supported, or well-supported practices that meet the applicable criteria specified for the practices in section 471(e)(4)(C), without regard to whether the expenditures are incurred on behalf of children who are, or are potentially, eligible for foster care maintenance payments under this part.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></section></subtitle><subtitle id="HF1E38F5E8F984BFD9CFF4A244F2F8666" style="OLC"><enum>B</enum><header>Enhanced support under Title IV–B</header>
				<section id="H06C48F52AC424D9D81355BAAA794F361"><enum>121.</enum><header>Elimination of time limit for family reunification services while in foster care and permitting
			 time-limited family reunification services when a child returns home from
			 foster care</header>
 <subsection id="H1EC6F2E4ECBD4165B1AB86F7D12DE435"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 431(a)(7) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/629a">42 U.S.C. 629a(a)(7)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE40D54EACEBD4DC1BE8680D02D9834FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Time-limited family</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Family</header-in-text></quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCAAC77BC9C4F43CEA6A109C07EE15594"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> <subparagraph id="H3042FFD690194B5491E4836C1FED1F29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>time-limited family</quote> and inserting <quote>family</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H147B4B1355AB42618FFF2DEBE10C201C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or a child who has been returned home</quote> after <quote>child care institution</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40E3A9B556F24F78923DAD42D7308084"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, but only during the 15-month period that begins on the date that the child, pursuant to section 475(5)(F), is considered to have entered foster care</quote> and inserting <quote>and to ensure the strength and stability of the reunification. In the case of a child who has been returned home, the services and activities shall only be provided during the 15-month period that begins on the date that the child returns home</quote>.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H618E108843F448A28F7ED6FF0120E0D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H9BAA25330C254BCDBDA092BB3CEA586B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 430 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/629">42 U.S.C. 629</external-xref>) is amended in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>time-limited</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABD8790A991E4D48A44A80FCFF19FEE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Subsections (a)(4), (a)(5)(A), and (b)(1) of section 432 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/629b">42 U.S.C. 629b</external-xref>) are amended by striking <quote>time-limited</quote> each place it appears.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD72D114FD55F46EFA27370A600E2171B"><enum>122.</enum><header>Reducing bureaucracy and unnecessary delays when placing children in homes across State lines</header>
 <subsection id="H41A54A5A86B24F088A64574DA32E5E1A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State plan requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 471(a)(25) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/671">42 U.S.C. 671(a)(25)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2A25007D03F14280A97AA0C2D8861C3B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>provide</quote> and insert <quote>provides</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC87A2C60621C4550893DAFA4D8773E58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, which, not later than October 1, 2026, shall include the use of an electronic interstate case-processing system</quote> before the first semicolon.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H05F665B22549447985851CADFA37DE3F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants for the development of an electronic interstate case-Processing system To expedite the
			 interstate placement of children in foster care or guardianship, or for
 adoption</header><text>Section 437 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/629g">42 U.S.C. 629g</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19254F4F8B8E4008B98BCBEA844CD7CC" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HFBDB61E6FC944FC081D68F762B887AFA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Grants for the development of an electronic interstate case-Processing system To expedite the interstate placement of children in foster care or guardianship, or for adoption</header> <paragraph id="H8B4011C5BF2E4EC4893EE1135146FAB3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this subsection is to facilitate the development of an electronic interstate case-processing system for the exchange of data and documents to expedite the placements of children in foster, guardianship, or adoptive homes across State lines.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H606F82F19A21466F8DBE5BF47C7DC530"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application requirements</header><text>A State that desires a grant under this subsection shall submit to the Secretary an application containing the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H93D71640C6DC4F62A2EAE9CF2D87FECC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the goals and outcomes to be achieved during the period for which grant funds are sought, which goals and outcomes must result in—</text>
 <clause id="HED2DE5E2AA8249CDB930A9D7412F2FDA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reducing the time it takes for a child to be provided with a safe and appropriate permanent living arrangement across State lines;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H680D9BCD0C964603BB23B8C90C5E6857"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improving administrative processes and reducing costs in the foster care system; and</text> </clause><clause id="H0EB346D4C6D7429797249D2B35FA985C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the secure exchange of relevant case files and other necessary materials in real time, and timely communications and placement decisions regarding interstate placements of children.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7DC4ADB41774F8A8F96A9C62F290193"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the activities to be funded in whole or in part with the grant funds, including the sequencing of the activities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DA3F4394A64493B9441AC806FE7DBCB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of the strategies for integrating programs and services for children who are placed across State lines.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB36CC34F2E7A49308E765F2FBBF4E1F5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Such other information as the Secretary may require.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CBB5AAE7977452AB5FF558F5B626ABD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grant authority</header><text>The Secretary may make a grant to a State that complies with paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE3CDDA689B544FA5AF269D3D0C145414"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State to which a grant is made under this subsection shall use the grant to support the State in connecting with the electronic interstate case-processing system described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE209CC106A4A4357B2B6114BBCD5F400"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Evaluations</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the final year in which grants are awarded under this subsection, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress, and make available to the general public by posting on a website, a report that contains the following information:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCAED86FA04B940588189AF438D5C16B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>How using the electronic interstate case-processing system developed pursuant to paragraph (4) has changed the time it takes for children to be placed across State lines.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H537993EBEFF340ADAA7B6C6E18635893"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of cases subject to the Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children that were processed through the electronic interstate case-processing system, and the number of interstate child placement cases that were processed outside the electronic interstate case-processing system, by each State in each year.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E1F36CD02DC44F7AD5BCF3EB4E6989D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The progress made by States in implementing the electronic interstate case-processing system.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H955DC6AF173549CB8F4FEE2720AAA399"><enum>(D)</enum><text>How using the electronic interstate case-processing system has affected various metrics related to child safety and well-being, including the time it takes for children to be placed across State lines.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B339846063E4DA49936B599A913F948"><enum>(E)</enum><text>How using the electronic interstate case-processing system has affected administrative costs and caseworker time spent on placing children across State lines.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H631DE65D49884182BB380023E150BDCE"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Data integration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretariat for the Interstate Compact on the Placement of Children and the States, shall assess how the electronic interstate case-processing system developed pursuant to paragraph (4) could be used to better serve and protect children that come to the attention of the child welfare system, by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB4ADC915D7C94BBBBC38034C55C39F99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>connecting the system with other data systems (such as systems operated by State law enforcement and judicial agencies, systems operated by the Federal Bureau of Investigation for the purposes of the Innocence Lost National Initiative, and other systems);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF6DCDC8596B4F2EAD4E30AF431F986A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>simplifying and improving reporting related to paragraphs (34) and (35) of section 471(a) regarding children or youth who have been identified as being a sex trafficking victim or children missing from foster care; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90D1B2BF6CC640EFAB4E1DC68D8BDD4D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improving the ability of States to quickly comply with background check requirements of section 471(a)(20), including checks of child abuse and neglect registries as required by section 471(a)(20)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7480636260854A068A075FA0256F788F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reservation of funds To improve the interstate placement of children</header><text>Section 437(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/629g">42 U.S.C. 629g(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F76FE77C666407F8B52715704BE0B77" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HA9A0C6E337434816B9C5CD0E71170E0F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Improving the interstate placement of children</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall reserve $5,000,000 of the amount made available for fiscal year 2017 for grants under subsection (g), and the amount so reserved shall remain available through fiscal year 2021.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="HA6EF9444204E4ECC8FF3268950FF7C82"><enum>123.</enum><header>Enhancements to grants to improve well-being of families affected by substance abuse</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 437(f) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/629g">42 U.S.C. 629g(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H09425EA7AEE14598AA0CA8F9D4D2A556"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">increase the well-Being of, and To improve the permanency outcomes for, children affected by</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">implement IV–E prevention services, and improve the well-Being of, and improve permanency outcomes for, children and families affected by heroin, opioids, and other</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B129D95A8CB45E68976023E71432799"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D6A7B449F914CE992D7109747A2EB0F" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H61501FA8BB2846AB81ECB42F9D8929BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regional partnership defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>regional partnership</term> means a collaborative agreement (which may be established on an interstate, State, or intrastate basis) entered into by the following:</text>
								<subparagraph id="H00AF98CB2D664577A6A553C62AD82828"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Mandatory partners for all partnership grants</header>
 <clause id="H5A7ADDFBAFC941359785402FED83CE8B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The State child welfare agency that is responsible for the administration of the State plan under this part and part E.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDCDF2F0DB7AA4914A36D19C39BB8B6A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The State agency responsible for administering the substance abuse prevention and treatment block grant provided under subpart II of part B of title XIX of the Public Health Service Act.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FCA700F9768435B905E1C8E5CE197CC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mandatory partners for partnership grants proposing to serve children in out-of-home placements</header><text>If the partnership proposes to serve children in out-of-home placements, the Juvenile Court or Administrative Office of the Court that is most appropriate to oversee the administration of court programs in the region to address the population of families who come to the attention of the court due to child abuse or neglect.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD881F99861A496FA94D527F3CBD0ECD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Optional partners</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the option of the partnership, any of the following:</text> <clause id="HB2EF74931C9347EA89B6CC0D68282EDB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An Indian tribe or tribal consortium.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H66B9E01F73C1486DA9199182C27A0EFE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Nonprofit child welfare service providers.</text> </clause><clause id="HB3F4C7CF201548ECA1F7D14461EF2E5C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For-profit child welfare service providers.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H26D33FD35FC24F87B855166D431783C8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Community health service providers, including substance abuse treatment providers.</text> </clause><clause id="H7265CD76789244D69EADCC07ABCFD083"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Community mental health providers.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H64A38861912E4B2B974037848F65AFBA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Local law enforcement agencies.</text> </clause><clause id="H840F02DFFBA74451A6E4567FF34EF943"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>School personnel.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA1DBAB19226149CBBD8E5C35687158E8"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Tribal child welfare agencies (or a consortia of the agencies).</text> </clause><clause id="H2A8E17FD960E4B5E8B9A91FEFB18C958"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Any other providers, agencies, personnel, officials, or entities that are related to the provision of child and family services under a State plan approved under this subpart.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H171DCA87A2904EA2BA8D178F642EE9D6"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Exception for regional partnerships where the lead applicant is an indian tribe or tribal consortia</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an Indian tribe or tribal consortium enters into a regional partnership for purposes of this subsection, the Indian tribe or tribal consortium—</text>
 <clause id="H3C2882621D8A4738B4341F05C296066E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may (but is not required to) include the State child welfare agency as a partner in the collaborative agreement;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBB79128793E4470AAF3D08F7A70D649E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may not enter into a collaborative agreement only with tribal child welfare agencies (or a consortium of the agencies); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBD9C23E5B57A4F2095255E063B21BF74"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if the condition described in paragraph (2)(B) applies, may include tribal court organizations in lieu of other judicial partners.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H425496C26BB340A28DBA402AE944928D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <subparagraph id="HFB15B86DCF624ADFA7B67528521F5657"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <clause id="H5354F726C884493A95F79BB8184CB786"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2012 through 2016</quote> and inserting <quote>2017 through 2021</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HB8B851ECA3A84C19996EB7FEC2BBEC9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$500,000 and not more than $1,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$250,000 and not more than $1,000,000</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD40CEA773E64DD7AD8804834B131359"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <clause id="H2B4F3FFFD2574F36B11743588A66C2F5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subparagraph heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">; planning</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">approval</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H544BA29B79C94088AB437D2FFB820793"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>clause (ii)</quote> and inserting <quote>clauses (ii) and (iii)</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H43BBF6E91A114E0BB75CD84524FFEC73"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
								<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB040C70C2F944FE29B03CC0C674672D0" style="OLC">
 <clause id="HA33EEDCDA27D40E6917E31A923774065"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Sufficient planning</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded under this subsection shall be disbursed in two phases: a planning phase (not to exceed 2 years); and an implementation phase. The total disbursement to a grantee for the planning phase may not exceed $250,000, and may not exceed the total anticipated funding for the implementation phase.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1930BB5E04C64EAC9EA9A5D3B634D1C3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2DE14099E6A74C17A745593160F55ADB" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H0B5B11BE822A4FE7A5C1FE38A2133996"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limitation on payment for a fiscal year</header><text>No payment shall be made under subparagraph (A) or (C) for a fiscal year until the Secretary determines that the eligible partnership has made sufficient progress in meeting the goals of the grant and that the members of the eligible partnership are coordinating to a reasonable degree with the other members of the eligible partnership.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EABCBF50D5C49F09CB443D47D63C5BF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text> <subparagraph id="H50D5B4FC98C8495E95CE4DB2A240E6C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text>
 <clause id="H0DD02E9BF6434B82937CDE6A55DCD60D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i), by inserting <quote>, parents, and families</quote> after <quote>children</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="H3AA5B2C3FA214C359421AAD8DB5A34BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>safety and permanence for such children; and</quote> and inserting <quote>safe, permanent caregiving relationships for the children;</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAD69CC417DF346458E5E8839E664A850"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>or</quote> and inserting <quote>increase reunification rates for children who have been placed in out of home care, or decrease</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H5371DAA10D934CE9A6F11F3E24CA84E0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (iii) as clause (v) and inserting after clause (ii) the following:</text>
								<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1AB4E72B86C94A39ACA10D4FF4EE61D0" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H17B433CCCC644BC488A0FBFD7BB42E72"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve the substance abuse treatment outcomes for parents including retention in treatment and successful completion of treatment;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDF6D5E7E837745D58D05B1A514DA6CCD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate the implementation, delivery, and effectiveness of prevention services and programs under section 471(e); and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D79A3CC3C904B9BB857A29348338F8E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>where appropriate,</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H431E3E80BC234EB4BA59D7F18ED5996B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subparagraphs (E) and (F) and inserting the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D3A7CA818674C5AAABD6DF4F9306D4F" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HB8B5B0AAB4B649A1B52E3D72DABD1C02"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of a plan for sustaining the services provided by or activities funded under the grant after the conclusion of the grant period, including through the use of prevention services and programs under section 471(e) and other funds provided to the State for child welfare and substance abuse prevention and treatment services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H249431A31A3B4B789D2D0785A66CE47B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Additional information needed by the Secretary to determine that the proposed activities and implementation will be consistent with research or evaluations showing which practices and approaches are most effective.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H71731DCC1760423E81D258D9A25FF777"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(A), by striking <quote>abuse treatment</quote> and inserting <quote>use disorder treatment including medication assisted treatment and in-home substance abuse disorder treatment and recovery</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC93A33C9042045CBA5BBBA382B81778A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in paragraph (7)—</text> <subparagraph id="HBC1A817F307749DAA966DEBA986A5409"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (C); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H444D778ACFC3493F96F53666ED8FB3B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (E) and inserting after subparagraph (C) the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51815B2921AC4F47A7315EEDD10DC0B8" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H5FD21D66D99047B9A9A2824436C031A5"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrate a track record of successful collaboration among child welfare, substance abuse disorder treatment and mental health agencies; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC283F59F609B437F9EF68CD31BC09AAC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in paragraph (8)—</text> <subparagraph id="HAFC5FF8543F24CEB85C800A6E9F9F129"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text>
 <clause id="H341268E197EA4C6FB07ECE2226EB2E8E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>establish indicators that will be</quote> and inserting <quote>review indicators that are</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H1432F57EEA1B4D0899193B8B1EA18AFF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>in using funds made available under such grants to achieve the purpose of this subsection</quote> and inserting <quote>and establish a set of core indicators related to child safety, parental recovery, parenting capacity, and family well-being. In developing the core indicators, to the extent possible, indicators shall be made consistent with the outcome measures described in section 471(e)(6)</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F50D9CF8F5B4F69AB9B3AD27FD0D77F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <clause id="HEA34BFB00B1B43369E87A79A3D0A1ACD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>base the performance measures on lessons learned from prior rounds of regional partnership grants under this subsection, and</quote> before <quote>consult</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H94EFB0A24A1A402EBD93CAAE353581C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking clauses (iii) and (iv) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1372271478F74813884BC7BB2ED48BB0" style="OLC"> <clause id="H8B2B1F9576A1404CAC434933866E5ECA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other stakeholders or constituencies as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED602488FD6449598601ECE0135C6171"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in paragraph (9)(A), by striking clause (i) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02053D9F96F04C22A83237E14A181080" style="OLC"> <clause id="H364D23A0F2AE45CE970B4FF68A694E9F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Semiannual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30 of each fiscal year in which a recipient of a grant under this subsection is paid funds under the grant, and every 6 months thereafter, the grant recipient shall submit to the Secretary a report on the services provided and activities carried out during the reporting period, progress made in achieving the goals of the program, the number of children, adults, and families receiving services, and such additional information as the Secretary determines is necessary. The report due not later than September 30 of the last such fiscal year shall include, at a minimum, data on each of the performance indicators included in the evaluation of the regional partnership.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FAAD428BE254CDAB11E070076E5E490"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), by striking <quote>2012 through 2016</quote> and inserting <quote>2017 through 2021</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section></subtitle><subtitle id="H6AB1082FFF1B472890AA54CF1FD567D2" style="OLC"><enum>C</enum><header>Miscellaneous</header> <section id="HF9FC39F400894EA6B55B3C124753188C"><enum>131.</enum><header>Reviewing and improving licensing standards for placement in a relative foster family home</header> <subsection id="HCB161C980700461FB18452CB1881B989"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification of reputable model licensing standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than October 1, 2017, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall identify reputable model licensing standards with respect to the licensing of foster family homes (as defined in section 472(c)(1) of the Social Security Act).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB7B22FFFEF48469D91874C28098E13CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State plan requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 471(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/671">42 U.S.C. 671(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H15047BB792CA4D168EA13B74814A1891"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (34)(B), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7CB149FFDC0F4797A0F6E34786329AD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (35)(B), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H86389C05DBF7401A8D5810A2DBD97712"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H05DAB9599AFC4A799169F61AFBBC96A3" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H88D8D368BD3A4EC3B14493A81235CEE3"><enum>(36)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides that, not later than April 1, 2018, the State shall submit to the Secretary information addressing—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H327CA6F8C10643FABAF0B54C88CD99D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the State licensing standards are in accord with model standards identified by the Secretary, and if not, the reason for the specific deviation and a description as to why having a standard that is reasonably in accord with the corresponding national model standards is not appropriate for the State;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2800E64D76AE458E946D9FFE5D2D9162"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the State has elected to waive standards established in 471(a)(10)(A) for relative foster family homes (pursuant to waiver authority provided by 471(a)(10)(D)), a description of which standards the State most commonly waives, and if the State has not elected to waive the standards, the reason for not waiving these standards;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC73E25D634294A94BC992627714B0064"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if the State has elected to waive standards specified in subparagraph (B), how caseworkers are trained to use the waiver authority and whether the State has developed a process or provided tools to assist caseworkers in waiving nonsafety standards per the authority provided in 471(a)(10)(D) to quickly place children with relatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1BBF2825CF84DEA974039EF754C3871"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of the steps the State is taking to improve caseworker training or the process, if any; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H32651A8D3E9C4B149BE2D4ABCE9088F8"><enum>132.</enum><header>Development of a statewide plan to prevent child abuse and neglect fatalities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 422(b)(19) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/622">42 U.S.C. 622(b)(19)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7317167D1D704B1497D3DB221D2EDF51" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HC28C994EAB094413AECCBA718A52278C"><enum>(19)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">document steps taken to track and prevent child maltreatment deaths by including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H579CC8E8E4404E11ADB57C6068490109"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the steps the State is taking to compile complete and accurate information on the deaths required by Federal law to be reported by the State agency referred to in paragraph (1), including gathering relevant information on the deaths from the relevant organizations in the State including entities such as State vital statistics department, child death review teams, law enforcement agencies, offices of medical examiners or coroners; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC412FDA14EE4A3F9FC8A4FE23CCA312"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the steps the State is taking to develop and implement of a comprehensive, statewide plan to prevent the fatalities that involves and engages relevant public and private agency partners, including those in public health, law enforcement, and the courts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</section><section id="HB690F5B4F14544A3A84C05F28B05E019"><enum>133.</enum><header>Modernizing the title and purpose of title IV–E</header>
 <subsection id="H177ED0738D2E497187FB77D61618CD0D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Part heading</header><text>The heading for part E of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/670">42 U.S.C. 670 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21EB8906E1ED4C01902C62A1734F19AC" style="OLC">
							<part id="H702EAA36BC594BD5A1750CA8C2D290F2"><enum>E</enum><header>Federal Payments for Foster Care, Prevention, and Permanency</header></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE3EC12E12C3D485291CC06655D21C234"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The first sentence of section 470 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/670">42 U.S.C. 670</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2481DCBACEFD4157A7A47AB97CAFF804"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>1995) and</quote> and inserting <quote>1995),</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DABF7FD173F48CABBBA30D7CEEA13E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>kinship guardianship assistance, and prevention services or programs specified in section 471(e)(1),</quote> after <quote>needs,</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H991FA3AC82A443FEA7BBFCC7DD898855"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(commencing with the fiscal year which begins October 1, 1980)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7945376008C94663A374B4112FE0949A"><enum>134.</enum><header>Effective dates</header> <subsection id="HB25650C63EEF4A4AA20DD6DF1CF0CAA0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Effective dates</header> <paragraph id="H5330EDBCDC154817A29674F0776CDE70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), subject to subsection (b), the amendments made by this title shall take effect on October 1, 2017.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A32C87EFCA448B0A90B9151E6CA7FF1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The amendments made by sections 131 and 133 shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H97D678EE9CA344159C4D67030C585102"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transition rule</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H92540328BF5B465CB0A19113D58D6F35"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a State plan under part B or E of title IV of the Social Security Act which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) in order for the plan to meet the additional requirements imposed by the amendments made by this title, the State plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such part solely on the basis of the failure of the plan to meet such additional requirements before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session shall be deemed to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E760C61F9B34E2F8B49353AF067BF33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application to programs operated by indian tribal organizations</header><text>In the case of an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or tribal consortium which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires time to take action necessary to comply with the additional requirements imposed by the amendments made by this title (whether the tribe, organization, or tribal consortium has a plan under section 479B of the Social Security Act or a cooperative agreement or contract entered into with a State), the Secretary shall provide the tribe, organization, or tribal consortium with such additional time as the Secretary determines is necessary for the tribe, organization, or tribal consortium to take the action to comply with the additional requirements before being regarded as failing to comply with the requirements.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection></section></subtitle></title><title id="H422BD07F3F5D40429CBDAA4A24BD4644" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Ensuring the Necessity of a Placement that is not in a Foster Family Home</header>
			<section id="HBF16C598AA194A8F9986F0020503A696"><enum>201.</enum><header>Limitation on Federal financial participation for placements that are not in foster family homes</header>
				<subsection id="H1ACE2DCB51B94E0EA2CE4A9D2BDB7CEF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitation on federal financial participation</header>
 <paragraph id="H0E1CEFDA1F5540848FCC0942CFD55EA3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 472 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/672">42 U.S.C. 672</external-xref>), as amended by section 112, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H39705A489AD4441A9CA3D628E5045370"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2)(C), by inserting <quote>, but only to the extent permitted under subsection (k)</quote> after <quote>institution</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A7D44634A734B739AC14044B3AEA239"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10660799A8D741B188668658B96ADCBD" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H509FA15BF02A4FE3883DCB12B45648D9"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Limitation on federal financial participation</header> <paragraph id="HB0AAB74A0F49463798F58BBCEF512853"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning with the third week for which foster care maintenance payments are made under this section on behalf of a child placed in a child-care institution, no Federal payment shall be made to the State under section 474(a)(1) for amounts expended for foster care maintenance payments on behalf of the child unless—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H54841ED44F3C4455AF30B8AB24C1B728"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the child is placed in a child-care institution that is a setting specified in paragraph (2) (or is placed in a licensed residential family-based treatment facility consistent with subsection (j)); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6AF1F50FE1A48E0A20BF0ACA8EA2E3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a child placed in a qualified residential treatment program (as defined in paragraph (4)), the requirements specified in paragraph (3) and section 475A(c) are met.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H17B85DAF28B44D25A90CF51ED636C19F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specified settings for placement</header><text>The settings for placement specified in this paragraph are the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H2B8AEA6EC60541D89F70EE6FD3985041"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A qualified residential treatment program (as defined in paragraph (4)).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAEACAE05A684834B306DB3F01A4C445"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A setting specializing in providing prenatal, post-partum, or parenting supports for youth.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0CB5B5AC86E4B019F7C071F1C0D5CD8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>In the case of a child who has attained 18 years of age, a supervised setting in which the child is living independently.</text>
										</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4AF0CADE0154E8296A882531AF04A75"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assessment to determine appropriateness of placement in a qualified residential treatment program</header>
 <subparagraph id="HD2D186BA68F140EB99AF941F7D177377"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Deadline for assessment</header><text>In the case of a child who is placed in a qualified residential treatment program, if the assessment required under section 475A(c)(1) is not completed within 30 days after the placement is made, no Federal payment shall be made to the State under section 474(a)(1) for any amounts expended for foster care maintenance payments on behalf of the child during the placement.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0B2174B78614708802721AB5AB98493"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deadline for transition out of placement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the assessment required under section 475A(c)(1) determines that the placement of a child in a qualified residential treatment program is not appropriate, a court disapproves such a placement under section 475A(c)(2), or a child who has been in an approved placement in a qualified residential treatment program is going to return home or be placed with a fit and willing relative, a legal guardian, or an adoptive parent, or in a foster family home, Federal payments shall be made to the State under section 474(a)(1) for amounts expended for foster care maintenance payments on behalf of the child while the child remains in the qualified residential treatment program only during the period necessary for the child to transition home or to such a placement. In no event shall a State receive Federal payments under section 474(a)(1) for amounts expended for foster care maintenance payments on behalf of a child who remains placed in a qualified residential treatment program after the end of the 30-day period that begins on the date a determination is made that the placement is no longer the recommended or approved placement for the child.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1C0489946F247C789EA6051C027A409"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualified residential treatment program</header><text>For purposes of this part, the term <term>qualified residential treatment program</term> means a program that—</text> <subparagraph id="H7C1E86535CC943A2A9EC109310F49870"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has a trauma-informed treatment model that is designed to address the needs, including clinical needs as appropriate, of children with serious emotional or behavioral disorders or disturbances and, with respect to a child, is able to implement the treatment identified for the child by the assessment of the child required under section 475A(c);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA2DBE581BAB42438DF1550ED48CE3C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has registered or licensed nursing staff and other licensed clinical staff who—</text> <clause id="H84CF0AB26DA6442FABA2AB285094BE57"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide care within the scope of their practice as defined by State law;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5EFC8307D41E4B849C07FB14456F1B0F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are on-site during business hours; and</text> </clause><clause id="HEB11B4B9801F44E2AAB767867D3CD569"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>are available 24 hours a day and 7 days a week;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EC35BCF502F49DBB0D5D80A796C050D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to the extent appropriate, and in accordance with the child’s best interests, facilitates participation of family members in the child’s treatment program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0A62DBE071C424EBBBB08B8C4C8CD88"><enum>(D)</enum><text>facilitates outreach to the family members of the child, including siblings, documents how the outreach is made (including contact information), and maintains contact information for any known biological family and fictive kin of the child;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CE94422D9454A94B6B61CC0A00F92EB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>documents how family members are integrated into the treatment process for the child, including post-discharge, and how sibling connections are maintained;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6056253ED40E42E7974C971B9CCBF377"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provides discharge planning and family-based aftercare support for at least 6 months post-discharge; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C2D65EA56844D46A2EA6225BD30989F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>is licensed in accordance with section 471(a)(10) and is accredited by any of the following independent, not-for-profit organizations:</text>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD380AB34FAED48BB8B3D7CD8C084F04A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission on Accreditation of Rehabilitation Facilities (CARF).</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H53BA39993DA04F7B8E5EC9F6AEE0B81A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations (JCAHO).</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E5276A0E00F45558DCB53A0A7EE7E12"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council on Accreditation (COA).</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3F21878DACF456D98FD6B339E340D47"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Any other independent, not-for-profit accrediting organization approved by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC3CE8A4995384252A32B3FF95AB9D89F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 474(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/674">42 U.S.C. 674(a)(1)</external-xref>), as amended by section 112(b), is amended by striking <quote>section 472(j)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (j) and (k) of section 472</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B132C343EB64727A3E648E1942D0651"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of foster family home, child-Care institution</header><text>Section 472(c) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/672">42 U.S.C. 672(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1999231B0D3C4239B9071C4252F1EFEA" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HE33DC5E40019481796CA6E20D83E4123"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this part:</text>
							<paragraph id="HCE2AEC6076C34B99B5FB2F96E3D2EDF6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Foster family home</header>
 <subparagraph id="H1A337273484D42A782BE33F0F209A0B9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>foster family home</term> means the home of an individual or family—</text> <clause id="H2ACAE6C7AEB048EFB76FACC0ED8B5D85"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that is licensed or approved by the State in which it is situated as a foster family home that meets the standards established for the licensing or approval; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2DF829992D5144EEBDB996867ED4B588"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in which a child in foster care has been placed in the care of an individual, who resides with the child and who has been licensed or approved by the State to be a foster parent—</text>
 <subclause id="H70796BE4CD9846FD9B62A8CE2AFA61A4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that the State deems capable of adhering to the reasonable and prudent parent standard;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H97A8D7ADA30344EB8BC6E7361983A20D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that provides 24-hour substitute care for children placed away from their parents or other caretakers; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9473483EA62F46CE98B32793ABC8A762"><enum>(III)</enum><text>that provides the care for not more than six children in foster care.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBE9F27A06E8441E97DF06186862B4FB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State flexibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of foster children that may be cared for in a home under subparagraph (A) may exceed the numerical limitation in subparagraph (A)(ii)(III), at the option of the State, for any of the following reasons:</text>
 <clause id="H9568694F1AFB49AD88F54B9BAE3D5C21"><enum>(i)</enum><text>To allow a parenting youth in foster care to remain with the child of the parenting youth.</text> </clause><clause id="H5D78C3D265C34E51A2E2112BFF571C10"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>To allow siblings to remain together.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1790F6CF5EC94E53B4972CC34423F415"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>To allow a child with an established meaningful relationship with the family to remain with the family.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0A8BAB0D1416468CAB72B82576056C83"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>To allow a family with special training or skills to provide care to a child who has a severe disability.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8764C7247D1548E0A5C2930E8CB83C0B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not be construed as prohibiting a foster parent from renting the home in which the parent cares for a foster child placed in the parent’s care.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B7632A9CA5F45EC921EAF70E6206FD6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Child-care institution</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8020A4FA36284749B2960DE08BEE75ED"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>child-care institution</term> means a private child-care institution, or a public child-care institution which accommodates no more than 25 children, which is licensed by the State in which it is situated or has been approved by the agency of the State responsible for licensing or approval of institutions of this type as meeting the standards established for the licensing.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H87E4E06C793940549BC73F7F7968A8AD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Supervised settings</header><text>In the case of a child who has attained 18 years of age, the term shall include a supervised setting in which the individual is living independently, in accordance with such conditions as the Secretary shall establish in regulations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H406A2F6BFAFA447E881E68C5D6E75923"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term shall not include detention facilities, forestry camps, training schools, or any other facility operated primarily for the detention of children who are determined to be delinquent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA593C04DC3124EF28E0C0E8BD31E4E55"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Training for state judges, attorneys, and other legal personnel in child welfare cases</header><text>Section 438(b)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/629h">42 U.S.C. 629h(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) by inserting <quote>shall provide for the training of judges, attorneys, and other legal personnel in child welfare cases on Federal child welfare policies and payment limitations with respect to children in foster care who are placed in settings that are not a foster family home,</quote> after <quote>with respect to the child,</quote>.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H66EF6A1193A848D8BD899D2D10634804"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Assurance of nonimpact on juvenile justice system</header>
 <paragraph id="H7BB9FB2E1BE642BFB1C9CC3917F53544"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State plan requirement</header><text>Section 471(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/671">42 U.S.C. 671(a)</external-xref>), as amended by section 131, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD20946B92144FCEA5787F999CE30559" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8830213EB2A74BFCBBD4BD96C21570B0"><enum>(37)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes a certification that, in response to the limitation imposed under section 472(k) with respect to foster care maintenance payments made on behalf of any child who is placed in a setting that is not a foster family home, the State will not enact or advance policies or practices that would result in a significant increase in the population of youth in the State’s juvenile justice system.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E34F5D6A76642438EAB38FD8F7C8C7C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>GAO study and report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall evaluate the impact, if any, on State juvenile justice systems of the limitation imposed under section 472(k) of the Social Security Act (as added by section 201(a)(1)) on foster care maintenance payments made on behalf of any child who is placed in a setting that is not a foster family home, in accordance with the amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) of this section. In particular, the Comptroller General shall evaluate the extent to which children in foster care who also are subject to the juvenile justice system of the State are placed in a facility under the jurisdiction of the juvenile justice system and whether the lack of available congregate care placements under the jurisdiction of the child welfare systems is a contributing factor to that result. Not later than December 31, 2023, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the evaluation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H47EC5C4EC39D4F5695CA643D9BF3328F"><enum>202.</enum><header>Assessment and documentation of the need for placement in a qualified residential treatment program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 475A of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/675a">42 U.S.C. 675a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5918901BDE43400BB4F17645A9F65964" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H15EDA4443A8E4920AAA2D23923491EDA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assessment, documentation, and judicial determination requirements for placement in a qualified
 residential treatment program</header><text>In the case of any child who is placed in a qualified residential treatment program (as defined in section 472(k)(4)), the following requirements shall apply for purposes of approving the case plan for the child and the case system review procedure for the child:</text>
						<paragraph id="H88842DAF21384A28A1EEC32D6A3A6A82"><enum>(1)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H88D94A1C992C411998362C9560FFCF59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Within 30 days of the start of each placement in such a setting, a qualified individual (as defined in subparagraph (D)) shall—</text>
 <clause id="HD55EDD553E984BE49176E09666207E83" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assess the strengths and needs of the child using an age-appropriate, evidence-based, validated, functional assessment tool approved by the Secretary;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1BE55001A8D8480995E3987CEEB86B94" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>determine whether the needs of the child can be met with family members or through placement in a foster family home or, if not, which setting from among the settings specified in section 472(k)(2) would provide the most effective and appropriate level of care for the child in the least restrictive environment and be consistent with the short- and long-term goals for the child, as specified in the permanency plan for the child; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H02F6C543BB044A829FF6ECADCC30409C" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>develop a list of child-specific short- and long-term mental and behavioral health goals.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1C224A80A0C4EBABEE46DBACC32B484" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF84F83155B184634B0D859037C850408"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The State shall assemble a family and permanency team for the child in accordance with the requirements of clauses (ii) and (iii). The qualified individual conducting the assessment required under subparagraph (A) shall work in conjunction with the family of, and permanency team for, the child while conducting and making the assessment.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7F8EC6BCC8FE40E29F83B01E5BEF0BA6" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The family and permanency team shall consist of all appropriate biological family members, relative, and fictive kin of the child, as well as, as appropriate, professionals who are a resource to the family of the child, such as teachers, medical or mental health providers who have treated the child, or clergy. In the case of a child who has attained age 14, the family and permanency team shall include the members of the permanency planning team for the child that are selected by the child in accordance with section 475(5)(C)(iv).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H17B34CD99A4A4DE3BB403DF546865496" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The State shall document in the child's case plan—</text> <subclause id="H8BF24E35FDBF4EBB97F70A1CAE0F8151"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the reasonable and good faith effort of the State to identify and include all such individuals on the family of, and permanency team for, the child;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB597F01AAE8A48C8A61E1530C26FE16F"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all contact information for members of the family and permanency team, as well as contact information for other family members and fictive kin who are not part of the family and permanency team;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HCA9601E1D1344C95AE79554C189CDFF6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>evidence that meetings of the family and permanency team, including meetings relating to the assessment required under subparagraph (A), are held at a time and place convenient for family;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HADEA992FF08E4F9789944E00E48D034C"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>if reunification is the goal, evidence demonstrating that the parent from whom the child was removed provided input on the members of the family and permanency team;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HBB2E4E13AFC44E378423252450C31EEE"><enum>(V)</enum><text>evidence that the assessment required under subparagraph (A) is determined in conjunction with the family and permanency team; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE754DDADD6DB47648F9D7166A36301D8"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the placement preferences of the family and permanency team relative to the assessment and, if the placement preferences of the family and permanency team and child are not the placement setting recommended by the qualified individual conducting the assessment under subparagraph (A), the reasons why the preferences of the team and of the child were not recommended.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37D3175445FF4457935C46716B87F344" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>In the case of a child who the qualified individual conducting the assessment under subparagraph (A) determines should not be placed in a foster family home, the qualified individual shall specify in writing the reasons why the needs of the child cannot be met by the family of the child or in a foster family home. A shortage or lack of foster family homes shall not be an acceptable reason for determining that a needs of the child cannot be met in a foster family home. The qualified individual also shall specify in writing why the recommended placement in a qualified residential treatment program is the setting that will provide the child with the most effective and appropriate level of care in the least restrictive environment and how that placement is consistent with the short- and long-term goals for the child, as specified in the permanency plan for the child.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFC5A4B0B824412CAA6955C08C3F551E" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H335AEA6DB7574582B181092A8AA123B6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Subject to clause (ii), in this subsection, the term <term>qualified individual</term> means a trained professional or licensed clinician who is not an employee of the State agency and who is not connected to, or affiliated with, any placement setting in which children are placed by the State.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H760E7D24CBA64167AE91E0CF05FF30B6" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Secretary may approve a request of a State to waive any requirement in clause (i) upon a submission by the State, in accordance with criteria established by the Secretary, that certifies that the trained professionals or licensed clinicians with responsibility for performing the assessments described in subparagraph (A) shall maintain objectivity with respect to determining the most effective and appropriate placement for a child.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6531C547EBC49C89EE6FFF5D2BB90F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Within 60 days of the start of each placement in a qualified residential treatment program, a family or juvenile court or another court (including a tribal court) of competent jurisdiction, or an administrative body appointed or approved by the court, independently, shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H815C947D42F3424B9A828DB6C1F60359"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider the assessment, determination, and documentation made by the qualified individual conducting the assessment under paragraph (1);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA92A19970FC6469590DCE8E485FF4C00"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determine whether the needs of the child can be met through placement in a foster family home or, if not, whether placement of the child in a qualified residential treatment program provides the most effective and appropriate level of care for the child in the least restrictive environment and whether that placement is consistent with the short- and long-term goals for the child, as specified in the permanency plan for the child; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EF0B463D9164A27B67AC6D57B6D50C0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>approve or disapprove the placement.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE2A50548EAD8414DB10EF9D84958DE6A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The written documentation made under paragraph (1)(C) and documentation of the determination and approval or disapproval of the placement in a qualified residential treatment program by a court or administrative body under paragraph (2) shall be included in and made part of the case plan for the child.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD0D5F5DA4C2E449B938E3800CD3C8C93"><enum>(4)</enum><text>As long as a child remains placed in a qualified residential treatment program, the State agency shall submit evidence at each status review and each permanency hearing held with respect to the child—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8A9988F9152F41649FFAEF3EAF5E0223"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstrating that ongoing assessment of the strengths and needs of the child continues to support the determination that the needs of the child cannot be met through placement in a foster family home, that the placement in a qualified residential treatment program provides the most effective and appropriate level of care for the child in the least restrictive environment, and that the placement is consistent with the short- and long-term goals for the child, as specified in the permanency plan for the child;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A8DC77632764B5F9EE984B69277B54C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>documenting the specific treatment or service needs that will be met for the child in the placement and the length of time the child is expected to need the treatment or services; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25DA5941A7B54628985CE597F188BFAC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>documenting the efforts made by the State agency to prepare the child to return home or to be placed with a fit and willing relative, a legal guardian, or an adoptive parent, or in a foster family home.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H66B5D74D590A49438E4F08D6806B4903"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In the case of any child who is placed in a qualified residential treatment program for more than 12 consecutive months or 18 nonconsecutive months (or, in the case of a child who has not attained age 13, for more than 6 consecutive or nonconsecutive months), the State agency shall submit to the Secretary—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3B658C4D186448088E2EE47732659289"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the most recent versions of the evidence and documentation specified in paragraph (4); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A1110DBF8CE4A61BD991C15EA735A90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the signed approval of the head of the State agency for the continued placement of the child in that setting.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section><section id="H6467F6CFC8DB4AC1BF2EF9B1627DF57E"><enum>203.</enum><header>Protocols to prevent inappropriate diagnoses</header>
 <subsection id="HEA1066FBB0F34E14BB83AF5C9A6F5922"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State plan requirement</header><text>Section 422(b)(15)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/622">42 U.S.C. 622(b)(15)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H36396D0D804D49809E188D4F9061959A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (vi), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE95494A3711E4BB6B39585B5E11B5790"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (vii) as clause (viii); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H142053D939EE4418BE634C1B8257D98F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (vi) the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10B28948F50F445CBC63C0D2A57B3264" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H7F7350656C4C4EC7957ACF08DB7A6411"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the procedures and protocols the State has established to ensure that children in foster care placements are not inappropriately diagnosed with mental illness, other emotional or behavioral disorders, medically fragile conditions, or developmental disabilities, and placed in settings that are not foster family homes as a result of the inappropriate diagnoses; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C14B376E8B04BC0939B3B5956F7A1AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Section 476 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/676">42 U.S.C. 676</external-xref>), as amended by section 111(d), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C165B0569814BFC8DCDE5B94BCE3B42" style="OLC">
						<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H41FFCFAE82C94885B6CDEA32C1674F89"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evaluation of State procedures and protocols To prevent inappropriate diagnoses of mental illness
 or other conditions</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct an evaluation of the procedures and protocols established by States in accordance with the requirements of section 422(b)(15)(A)(vii). The evaluation shall analyze the extent to which States comply with and enforce the procedures and protocols and the effectiveness of various State procedures and protocols and shall identify best practices. Not later than January 1, 2019, the Secretary shall submit a report on the results of the evaluation to Congress.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="H809A2934EB00429BBD6173F5B8F5DA68"><enum>204.</enum><header>Additional data and reports regarding children placed in a setting that is not a foster family home</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 479A(a)(7)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/679b">42 U.S.C. 679b(a)(7)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking clauses (i) through (vi) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF97B6E37F11748E193E6B8B638EB62C0" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H469B3C21D7774B4D8912B5B5827C8F8D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to each such placement—</text> <subclause id="H6E6B14613CB0474BBFE46CB49B893871"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the type of the placement setting, including whether the placement is shelter care, a group home and if so, the range of the child population in the home, a residential treatment facility, a hospital or institution providing medical, rehabilitative, or psychiatric care, a setting specializing in providing prenatal, post-partum or parenting supports, or some other kind of child-care institution and if so, what kind;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE3915EBBF5694370A083B0E95EC1F5D8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of children in the placement setting and the age, race, ethnicity, and gender of each of the children;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HDB3CA253428340149791AAC410C4E7BE"><enum>(III)</enum><text>for each child in the placement setting, the length of the placement of the child in the setting, whether the placement of the child in the setting is the first placement of the child and if not, the number and type of previous placements of the child, and whether the child has special needs or another diagnosed mental or physical illness or condition; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5F6A4CC0375F48FB907A9B2FF0DC873D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the extent of any specialized education, treatment, counseling, or other services provided in the setting; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H033F8A131C464E2FA93ADD5E00B11621"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>separately, the number and ages of children in the placements who have a permanency plan of another planned permanent living arrangement; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section><section id="H052D776096644DB196F98F666719F4FB"><enum>205.</enum><header>Effective dates; application to waivers</header>
				<subsection id="H10ABA8E5714E477DB29B001E06A7AD65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Effective dates</header>
 <paragraph id="H83FA872FE0384F3386AB92AABDC416E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2) and subsections (b) and (c), the amendments made by this title shall take effect on October 1, 2017.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE9511031C1DB4C969044407E73342F08"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transition rule</header><text>In the case of a State plan under part B or E of title IV of the Social Security Act which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation (other than legislation appropriating funds) in order for the plan to meet the additional requirements imposed by the amendments made by this title, the State plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such part solely on the basis of the failure of the plan to meet the additional requirements before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session shall be deemed to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC00846C30BD04E4A8DF06658FC8F2A6A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on federal financial participation for placements that are not in foster family homes
 and related provisions</header><text>The amendments made by sections 201(a), 201(b), 201(d), and 202 shall take effect on October 1, 2019.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A0317FEAC1548F9BE7E86BBEEBC4E58"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application to States with waivers</header><text>In the case of a State that, on the date of enactment of this Act, has in effect a waiver approved under section 1130 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320a-9">42 U.S.C. 1320a–9</external-xref>), the amendments made by this title shall not apply with respect to the State before the expiration (determined without regard to any extensions) of the waiver to the extent the amendments are inconsistent with the terms of the waiver.</text>
				</subsection></section></title><title id="HF0E3F4BBC8C64247A14EB64B49DC2D89"><enum>III</enum><header>Continuing Support for Child and Family Services</header>
			<section id="H72B7660D46D641B89509094ECAC65FE2"><enum>301.</enum><header>Supporting and retaining foster families for children</header>
 <subsection id="H4E48AD65A2F94AF1ACD4D2E7D9511A6B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Supporting and retaining foster parents as a family support service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 431(a)(2)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/631">42 U.S.C. 631(a)(2)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by redesignating clauses (iii) through (vi) as clauses (iv) through (vii), respectively, and inserting after clause (ii) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBF167DD9D8FB4BEBA52CDA7949C4A39B" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H334E6B3237374D03AD83C4A74627BE2B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To support and retain foster families so they can provide quality family-based settings for children in foster care.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H683D5FC9A62B4ABAA120A6F3CBC1CA8B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Support for foster family homes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 436 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/629f">42 U.S.C. 629f</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7543A7DB8AC24967B786861BD5F79A4B" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H435C43C83205404FBB5A936EF0AA82DC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Support for foster family homes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated to the Secretary for fiscal year 2018, $8,000,000 for the Secretary to make competitive grants to States, Indian tribes, or tribal consortia to support the recruitment and retention of high-quality foster families to increase their capacity to place more children in family settings, focused on States, Indian tribes, or tribal consortia with the highest percentage of children in non-family settings. The amount appropriated under this subparagraph shall remain available through fiscal year 2022.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="H2A199E1728BA47DF99687FDEBFCACD1E"><enum>302.</enum><header>Extension of child and family services programs</header>
 <subsection id="H74630D85B70C400BB1073283BA8C2C92"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension of Stephanie Tubbs Jones child welfare services program</header><text>Section 425 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/625">42 U.S.C. 625</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2012 through 2016</quote> and inserting <quote>2017 through 2021</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H5AAAD7C0A60C43F0A09CFFBDEBB13BE6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extension of promoting safe and stable families program authorizations</header> <paragraph id="H28D8609B9DF2432AAA34654FAC2A322C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 436(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/629f">42 U.S.C. 629f(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking all that follows <quote>$345,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D7529B519AE40429FF0538E68FE7EF2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Discretionary grants</header><text>Section 437(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/629g">42 U.S.C. 629g(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2012 through 2016</quote> and inserting <quote>2017 through 2021</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2811C32F29B4456A9807972CDFA332FE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Extension of funding reservations for monthly caseworker visits and regional partnership grants</header><text>Section 436(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/629f">42 U.S.C. 629f(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2ABD30FA1732439FB84DEDB8893CFB79"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(A), by striking <quote>2012 through 2016</quote> and inserting <quote>2017 through 2021</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE05F20DC1C345C1A382567D2BECA924"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>2012 through 2016</quote> and inserting <quote>2017 through 2021</quote>.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE29B8D468C304856A86AAF6D4124269B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reauthorization of funding for state courts</header>
 <paragraph id="H2DC254104FEE4AB894C779E45C27E969"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Extension of program</header><text>Section 438(c)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/629h">42 U.S.C. 629h(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2012 through 2016</quote> and inserting <quote>2017 through 2021</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B02E441EF0A4260BF8E8FE41EABB3EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension of Federal share</header><text>Section 438(d) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/629h">42 U.S.C. 629h(d)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2012 through 2016</quote> and inserting <quote>2017 through 2021</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9DA6FEB57DE941DCA6CC66F3898BE7B5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Repeal of expired provisions</header><text>Section 438(e) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/629h">42 U.S.C. 629h(e)</external-xref>) is repealed.</text> </subsection></section><section id="H6A0719E854FC44BFA4BEB503B16BC273"><enum>303.</enum><header>Improvements to the John H. Chafee foster care independence program and related provisions</header> <subsection id="H30E7C8CFC0194022BFF2637A102CF412"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To Serve Former Foster Youth Up To Age 23</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 477 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/677">42 U.S.C. 677</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDBA4AE2EA46B4AFF8843A584486BAD9F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(5), by inserting <quote>(or 23 years of age, in the case of a State with a certification under subsection (b)(3)(A)(ii) to provide assistance and services to youths who have aged out of foster care and have not attained such age, in accordance with such subsection)</quote> after <quote>21 years of age</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0871CA9073864BCBA628686A8F68FC39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3)(A)—</text> <subparagraph id="H568A78550CB240B698646B10FEA31969"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(i)</quote> before <quote>A certification</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DEC606C943D4C75A5831BC8675F75DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>children who have left foster care</quote> and all that follows through the period and inserting <quote>youths who have aged out of foster care and have not attained 21 years of age.</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87C0F108109A440C93CE574C35F44F92"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block id="H5768CC499FFA4C41814449700D872C38" style="OLC">
 <clause id="HE36BF5FC933F41878A13759F219EE4B6" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If the State has elected under section 475(8)(B) to extend eligibility for foster care to all children who have not attained 21 years of age, or if the Secretary determines that the State agency responsible for administering the State plans under this part and part B uses State funds or any other funds not provided under this part to provide services and assistance for youths who have aged out of foster care that are comparable to the services and assistance the youths would receive if the State had made such an election, the certification required under clause (i) may provide that the State will provide assistance and services to youths who have aged out of foster care and have not attained 23 years of age.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FFC778EC19447879C5578884068F87D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3)(B), by striking <quote>children who have left foster care</quote> and all that follows through the period and inserting <quote>youths who have aged out of foster care and have not attained 21 years of age (or 23 years of age, in the case of a State with a certification under subparagraph (A)(i) to provide assistance and services to youths who have aged out of foster care and have not attained such age, in accordance with subparagraph (A)(ii)).</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCBEF9675B6D6471CA22DB7007A471BA0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority To redistribute unspent funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 477(d) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/677">42 U.S.C. 677(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD341BAF7D59A47EF94E30C04C0D0E463"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by inserting <quote>or does not expend allocated funds within the time period specified under section 477(d)(3)</quote> after <quote>provided by the Secretary</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H62D17549617F4C1598C13ABE1FB0C9C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HE5429B5E969E41208F020D1DBD5790CB" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HA9C6CEE1B7344E1EA618BCB932EF6635"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Redistribution of unexpended amounts</header> <subparagraph id="HD827080DA0B1470A975F5CB70DE93915"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Availability of amounts</header><text>To the extent that amounts paid to States under this section in a fiscal year remain unexpended by the States at the end of the succeeding fiscal year, the Secretary may make the amounts available for redistribution in the second succeeding fiscal year among the States that apply for additional funds under this section for that second succeeding fiscal year.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42047EE4D48844B59F6DD4AEAF6B329B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Redistribution</header>
 <clause id="H048C5EACACB2459D9BB5F511E5CFB3D3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall redistribute the amounts made available under subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year among eligible applicant States. In this subparagraph, the term <term>eligible applicant State</term> means a State that has applied for additional funds for the fiscal year under subparagraph (A) if the Secretary determines that the State will use the funds for the purpose for which originally allotted under this section.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4532F63200584F0A91FAEEE644A2F49F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amount to be redistributed</header><text>The amount to be redistributed to each eligible applicant State shall be the amount so made available multiplied by the State foster care ratio (as defined in subsection (c)(4), except that, in such subsection, <quote>all eligible applicant States (as defined in subsection (d)(5)(B)(i))</quote> shall be substituted for <quote>all States</quote>).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H910B7BD9AB6645A2AC7924FC28F4865A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Treatment of redistributed amount</header><text>Any amount made available to a State under this paragraph shall be regarded as part of the allotment of the State under this section for the fiscal year in which the redistribution is made.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B830628D9DD43BBB975714408FE14AF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Tribes</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>State</term> includes an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or tribal consortium that receives an allotment under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H59F7A0F49E384260BE5618A897587F40"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expanding and clarifying the use of education and training vouchers</header>
 <paragraph id="H855F3147B8924C6196BA3DD411875D69"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 477(i)(3) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/677">42 U.S.C. 677(i)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HC93C11D4B2B84EA987BE45B7E29B5E4D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>on the date</quote> and all that follows through <quote>23</quote> and inserting <quote>to remain eligible until they attain 26</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC39B009C767423E971D0583DD4EF93D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, but in no event may a youth participate in the program for more than 5 years (whether or not consecutive)</quote> before the period.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC307E84F063546D399CA732EF4ED4B27"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 477(i)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/677">42 U.S.C. 677(i)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>who have attained 14 years of age</quote> before the period.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2CDC65B0E0D84ACEA905413543493A3F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Other improvements</header><text>Section 477 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/677">42 U.S.C. 677</external-xref>), as amended by subsections (a), (b), and (c), is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB9C2E151EACE43EC9174DA5E4AE3F05D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Independence Program</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Program for Successful Transition to Adulthood</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C4EED433EAE450183936080CD1594EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5EADBB03BCE476DAD6B8EE45EA1BEC2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="HCB1CC01CB1D949EE96ECAE6D5ADFD74B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>identify children who are likely to remain in foster care until 18 years of age and to help these children make the transition to self-sufficiency by providing services</quote> and inserting <quote>support all youth who have experienced foster care at age 14 or older in their transition to adulthood through transitional services</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF359CE077B2C4D61A620D46B05DF4C59"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and post-secondary education</quote> after <quote>high school diploma</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H4C32D24E8F184BE18E72E0B76A2D6FA7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>training in daily living skills, training in budgeting and financial management skills</quote> and inserting <quote>training and opportunities to practice daily living skills (such as financial literacy training and driving instruction)</quote>;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7850770AAC3245B1818F17E1EE2F300C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>who are likely to remain in foster care until 18 years of age receive the education, training, and services necessary to obtain employment</quote> and inserting <quote>who have experienced foster care at age 14 or older achieve meaningful, permanent connections with a caring adult</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD79B43DB97F417AB54F1C6749D76EE2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>who are likely to remain in foster care until 18 years of age prepare for and enter postsecondary training and education institutions</quote> and inserting <quote>who have experienced foster care at age 14 or older engage in age or developmentally appropriate activities, positive youth development, and experiential learning that reflects what their peers in intact families experience</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76C7660E9FD24ADE82A2AA220A6C3423"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (4) and redesignating paragraphs (5) through (8) as paragraphs (4) through (7);</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A0877D8A29444BBA2D4AD10480CA4F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H4B70ACD6229141438E3C6F7E09C1259C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(D), by striking <quote>adolescents</quote> and inserting <quote>youth</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9EDEC91BAEC436A824E77254B09E786"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <clause id="HFFA86F0EE6A54049A46A65B552F00447"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)—</text>
 <subclause id="HB0F9CEE21630458E9D1D31C71EBBAA3C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>including training on youth development</quote> after <quote>to provide training</quote>; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H855CD0D5F00C4D7795895C19F536D5E0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>adolescents preparing for independent living</quote> and all that follows through the period and inserting <quote>youth preparing for a successful transition to adulthood and making a permanent connection with a caring adult.</quote>;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HE436D8F34D804576894D9A1B4861A40A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), by striking <quote>adolescents</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>youth</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HFFA610DF06C54C70B618427445D5414F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (K)—</text>
 <subclause id="H1AE9E52110FB4E33BF1970C78FDCF056"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>an adolescent</quote> and inserting <quote>a youth</quote>; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H394AF9AFD9CA402CAC6690EAE769C924"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the adolescent</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>the youth</quote>; and</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H57FC349239ED4A419D622BB286D63A5E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HA61943C3D6334FFD9EF2EC1DC24CEE56" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HA6983F85562B4A419C758CA6A9377038"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>Not later than October 1, 2017, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on the National Youth in Transition Database and any other databases in which States report outcome measures relating to children in foster care and children who have aged out of foster care or left foster care for kinship guardianship or adoption. The report shall include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H050B56CAA02A46F08E70AF19E4474727"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the reasons for entry into foster care and of the foster care experiences, such as length of stay, number of placement settings, case goal, and discharge reason of 17-year-olds who are surveyed by the National Youth in Transition Database and an analysis of the comparison of that description with the reasons for entry and foster care experiences of children of other ages who exit from foster care before attaining age 17.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H919FAB16428C44AAA83EE39475BC2C51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the characteristics of the individuals who report poor outcomes at ages 19 and 21 to the National Youth in Transition Database.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D5B22A9C3944DCBBC522C8D36F53ECD"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Benchmarks for determining what constitutes a poor outcome for youth who remain in or have exited from foster care and plans the executive branch will take to incorporate these benchmarks in efforts to evaluate child welfare agency performance in providing services to children transitioning from foster care.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA0C5FF745624721A88D540921D0DADE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An analysis of the association between types of placement, number of overall placements, time spent in foster care, and other factors, and outcomes at ages 19 and 21.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E9FDED07630483481A6B1371853090D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An analysis of the differences in outcomes for children in and formerly in foster care at age 19 and 21 among States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6EDBCE51666E4DBFAA2AA67D484C9AA5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Clarifying documentation provided to foster youth leaving foster care</header><text>Section 475(5)(I) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/675">42 U.S.C. 675(5)(I)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>REAL ID Act of 2005</quote> the following: <quote>, and any official documentation necessary to prove that the child was previously in foster care</quote>.</text> </subsection></section></title><title id="H0CA722A11EFA47E4A00933B71EFEE71C"><enum>IV</enum><header>Continuing Incentives to States to Promote Adoption and Legal Guardianship</header> <section id="H2E74F34DEB79400AA375553018C86CB1"><enum>401.</enum><header>Reauthorizing adoption and legal guardianship incentive programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 473A of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/673b">42 U.S.C. 673b</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFB717182343144AB8FE77826CB467345"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(4), by striking <quote>2013 through 2015</quote> and inserting <quote>2016 through 2020</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4DC9767F23C488CBC351545CF2CF7C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (h)(1)(D), by striking <quote>2016</quote> and inserting <quote>2021</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BB5DBB2F8B147B196D799D2171EBB1C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (h)(2), by striking <quote>2016</quote> and inserting <quote>2021</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section></title><title id="H4F18DCA6078549B8A9355D28290D7C22"><enum>V</enum><header>Technical Corrections</header> <section id="H7F42203660C64DF3BE61FA05A56152BD"><enum>501.</enum><header>Technical corrections to data exchange standards to improve program coordination</header> <subsection id="HDB6A36EB9FCF4D23B7A900FF216E8AC8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 440 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/629m">42 U.S.C. 629m</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E8200E2F9CC4705AD456B46ADEEA4D6" style="OLC">
						<section id="H065C78CEF0874D8B8B7412DE93EA5751"><enum>440.</enum><header>Data exchange standards for improved interoperability</header>
 <subsection id="HEAEBC41F6C634585A3ACD4817C0FC1A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, in consultation with an interagency work group established by the Office of Management and Budget and considering State government perspectives, by rule, designate data exchange standards to govern, under this part—</text>
 <paragraph id="H063F29F1F6254DD0B9529F1A613AEA1F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">necessary categories of information that State agencies operating programs under State plans approved under this part are required under applicable Federal law to electronically exchange with another State agency; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H37653DD7384844F681D005B52D2D7495"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Federal reporting and data exchange required under applicable Federal law.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H30C4BCD3428845758C9C432720A05FBC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The data exchange standards required by paragraph (1) shall, to the extent practicable—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE8AD0857B4D842B68492D2B0DE03AE73"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incorporate a widely accepted, non-proprietary, searchable, computer-readable format, such as the eXtensible Markup Language;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAEF6FA454DB2410888564C2F8BD4CB3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>contain interoperable standards developed and maintained by intergovernmental partnerships, such as the National Information Exchange Model;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01A6149978214F9EACE4720CBDEFD6A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>incorporate interoperable standards developed and maintained by Federal entities with authority over contracting and financial assistance;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCA169265328F4ADDAAB9712AEB9326B3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>be consistent with and implement applicable accounting principles;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H356CC8F5AD5B4E0E8E217B1BC1B27C9B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>be implemented in a manner that is cost-effective and improves program efficiency and effectiveness; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5BE88398F7C640B69CC769041F2531ED"><enum>(6)</enum><text>be capable of being continually upgraded as necessary.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1AAE38DB6A864C389EE4E5BC748C758F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require a change to existing data exchange standards found to be effective and efficient.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6FE8BE407CCC4E0297616ADB9A320A50"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the date that is 24 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue a proposed rule that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE518B95D25884BA78220AA34220227E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies federally required data exchanges, includes specification and timing of exchanges to be standardized, and addresses the factors used in determining whether and when to standardize data exchanges; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC762B35444DC44D3AD065E05F40DFF21"><enum>(2)</enum><text>specifies State implementation options and describes future milestones.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDEACD24C7BD8486E94ACDC9B98903172"><enum>502.</enum><header>Technical corrections to State requirement to address the developmental needs of young children</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 422(b)(18) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/622">42 U.S.C. 622(b)(18)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>such children</quote> and inserting <quote>all vulnerable children under 5 years of age</quote>.</text>
			</section></title><title id="H0D9D122EDFCD4F6AB03697B915629038"><enum>VI</enum><header>Ensuring States reinvest savings resulting from increase in adoption assistance</header>
 <section id="HC1539A25EDCB4B7799C01F72A589E989"><enum>601.</enum><header>Delay of adoption assistance phase-in</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 473(e)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/673">42 U.S.C. 673(e)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD736293D896248F6B1851905528BB583"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>fiscal year</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>period</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC43EDEEDD1A4CD7A397129ED6AB0C7D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <subparagraph id="H1D1F140FE160459093BA7926737865A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding the table, by striking <quote>fiscal year</quote> and inserting <quote>period</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FC5763839474D558ED9D784CA254066"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the table—</text> <clause id="H6539BA674A84402CB7C0D9F9E791F01C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of fiscal year:</quote> and inserting <quote>of:</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1F984AC833784BCE9DC4073149870C04"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2010</quote> and inserting <quote>Fiscal year 2010</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="HFF042761F8E641058AD1BCCA6A3DBF18"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2011</quote> and inserting <quote>Fiscal year 2011</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8DE3D115348B4189AD545C833206432D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2012</quote> and inserting <quote>Fiscal year 2012</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="HB4527332A27C437E862BC71B26F82B91"><enum>(v)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2013</quote> and inserting <quote>Fiscal year 2013</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9D284FCC970F46A38A9D04F0A203C076"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2014</quote> and inserting <quote>Fiscal year 2014</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="H5628DF927AA04A828BAADEA6E669E4ED"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2015</quote> and inserting <quote>Fiscal year 2015</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF51EA60EA27A43D1808B17B54A05DE6E"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2016</quote> and inserting <quote>October 1, 2015, through March 31, 2019</quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="HE2CBB651A4E8495C8147EB72D3B003C2"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>2017</quote> and inserting <quote>April 1, 2019, through March 31, 2020</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H523015A1B1E2441BA1184BEB507FA432"><enum>(x)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2018</quote> and inserting <quote>April 1, 2020,</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H20C97C0E8457482E8F4EB796695A24CF"><enum>602.</enum><header>GAO study and report on State reinvestment of savings resulting from increase in adoption assistance</header> <subsection id="HEE897441A46345BAB7A2A32E1A7B4444"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall study the extent to which States are complying with the requirements of section 473(a)(8) of the Social Security Act relating to the effects of phasing out the AFDC income eligibility requirements for adoption assistance payments under section 473 of the Social Security Act, as enacted by section 402 of the Fostering Connections to Success and Increasing Adoptions Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/351">Public Law 110–351</external-xref>; 122 Stat. 3975) and amended by section 206 of the Preventing Sex Trafficking and Strengthening Families Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/183">Public Law 113–183</external-xref>; 128 Stat. 1919). In particular, the Comptroller General shall analyze the extent to which States are complying with the following requirements under section 473(a)(8)(D) of the Social Security Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB553BDDB77804B57B62C007D4F0D5C90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The requirement to spend an amount equal to the amount of the savings (if any) in State expenditures under part E of title IV of the Social Security resulting from phasing out the AFDC income eligibility requirements for adoption assistance payments under section 473 of such Act to provide to children of families any service that may be provided under part B or E of title IV of such Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0751823D675C4F4CBFE5BDD6527BD57D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The requirement that a State shall spend not less than 30 percent of the amount of any savings described in subparagraph (A) on post-adoption services, post-guardianship services, and services to support and sustain positive permanent outcomes for children who otherwise might enter into foster care under the responsibility of the State, with at least <fraction>2/3</fraction> of the spending by the State to comply with the 30-percent requirement being spent on post-adoption and post-guardianship services.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE309CC6812C4A0DA2C237CEB47DFCF1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Finance of the Senate, the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services a report that contains the results of the study required by subsection (a), including recommendations to ensure compliance with laws referred to in subsection (a).</text>
				</subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill>


