<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H22B18C9202774FF789696FF163153657" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4625 IH: Fundamentally Understanding The Usability and Realistic Evolution of Artificial Intelligence Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4625</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171212">December 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="O000168">Mr. Olson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Commerce to establish the Federal Advisory Committee on the Development
			 and Implementation of Artificial Intelligence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC60D72FAD5EB4AD68DB177C567F5858C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H81B7338B2F4547A4A72425B65B0B2BF5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fundamentally Understanding The Usability and Realistic Evolution of Artificial Intelligence Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FUTURE of Artificial Intelligence Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text>
 </section><section id="HA35CE776760B48ECA56EE4A64DC686D9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H12EA4D879D254D8EB4CC5D27E0FB9DF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>understanding and preparing for the ongoing development of artificial intelligence is critical to the economic prosperity and social stability of the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H188F3F1E83C246E2BFC2F2C580BE7547"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as artificial intelligence evolves, it can greatly benefit society by powering the information economy, fostering better informed decisions and helping unlock answers to questions that, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, are unanswerable;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7BC0BEAAC2B4B3E83FEBC82F076D603"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for the reasons set forth in paragraph (2) it's beneficial to better understand artificial intelligence and foster the development of artificial intelligence in a manner that maximizes its benefit to society; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H702C98080AF047F0B8C0324E3B23865A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>it is critical that the priorities of the advisory committee established under section 4(a)(1) include developing guidance or recommendations—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HDDDC2C3EB22C4743AEC1ECF21AF9A0AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to promote a climate of investment and innovation to ensure the global competitiveness of the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD99474F79DF45E2A789A0ABEDEE3C26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to optimize the development of artificial intelligence to address the potential growth, restructuring, or other changes in the United States workforce that results from the development of artificial intelligence;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF540C9C8462B41F79FCFC17F0D7B4712"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to promote and support the unbiased development and application of artificial intelligence; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5AF92F5DEDB4A86ADF9764933DB8F30"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to protect the privacy rights of individuals.</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H77CE4BA98209404F94ABACC18CBFA585"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header>
 <subsection id="HFAA9C17FF1844815A950A096050955B2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), in this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H1955D7BDF84E4C0AB13E426F20427245"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> includes the following:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC0FA4DF451E479699EBA960DC7BEB64"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any artificial systems that perform tasks under varying and unpredictable circumstances, without significant human oversight, or that can learn from their experience and improve their performance. Such systems may be developed in computer software, physical hardware, or other contexts not yet contemplated. They may solve tasks requiring human-like perception, cognition, planning, learning, communication, or physical action. In general, the more human-like the system within the context of its tasks, the more it can be said to use artificial intelligence.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9828C29E32C24CC19407E07D91977646"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Systems that think like humans, such as cognitive architectures and neural networks.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97BCEF546A744EE89A8CCD1127A34794"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Systems that act like humans, such as systems that can pass the Turing test or other comparable test via natural language processing, knowledge representation, automated reasoning, and learning.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H054CE92BB6E242BD88188CB08633F6CB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A set of techniques, including machine learning, that seek to approximate some cognitive task.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H288485674E1A4415BE8E0CB73BA37A81"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Systems that act rationally, such as intelligent software agents and embodied robots that achieve goals via perception, planning, reasoning, learning, communicating, decision making, and acting.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FFB89D921D642F19470396F25020151"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artificial general intelligence</header><text>The term <term>artificial general intelligence</term> means a notional future artificial intelligence system that exhibits apparently intelligent behavior at least as advanced as a person across the range of cognitive, emotional, and social behaviors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8A37636432644B1EA082B3E9EBEF7983"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Narrow artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <term>narrow artificial intelligence</term> means an artificial intelligence system that addresses specific application areas such as playing strategic games, language translation, self-driving vehicles, and image recognition.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE744710016914EEEAA7BB9E1D874E85B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modifications</header><text>The Federal Advisory Committee on the Development and Implementation of Artificial Intelligence established under section 4(a) may revise such definitions under subsection (a) of this section as the advisory committee considers appropriate.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H6C9A8FA5D58D48EE993CFFFD9089E15E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of Federal Advisory Committee on the Development and Implementation of Artificial
			 Intelligence</header>
			<subsection id="H6BA631650BA841DDA0315D3D43A15A4F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
 <paragraph id="H74B6BFC5518F4DA397B5911476CD0EB0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce shall establish a Federal advisory committee to advise the Secretary on matters relating to the development of artificial intelligence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70C15D6DB7644DDD834828680C11DB9F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The Federal advisory committee established under paragraph (1) shall be known as the <quote>Federal Advisory Committee on the Development and Implementation of Artificial Intelligence</quote> (in this section the <quote>Advisory Committee</quote>).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBBDAB15F40E04E73B167F1F57A427580"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes of the Advisory Committee</header> <paragraph id="H3E3BA8E75963445AA02456C4C7080BCF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advice</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall provide advice to the Secretary on matters relating to the development of artificial general intelligence and narrow artificial intelligence, including on the following as they relate to artificial intelligence:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H75CF9DC0C6A54F4EAC77C6DBC6F5A9C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The competitiveness of the United States, including matters relating to the promotion of public and private sector investment and innovation into the development of artificial intelligence.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86539B49FE5E43438E4B2E5396508EF5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Workforce, including matters relating to the potential for using artificial intelligence for rapid retraining of workers, due to the possible effect of technological displacement.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10C9770D9FDD4ABAA0ADE510E3EA72BD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Education, including matters relating to science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education to prepare the United States workforce as the needs of employers change.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35126CA6739C410FA2FA79890AC091F6"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ethics training and development for technologists working on artificial intelligence.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D4059C1284E49208799EF61EBCD43D8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Matters relating to open sharing of data and the open sharing of research on artificial intelligence.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C7269C97A7E4E05A47922FA2BACB875"><enum>(F)</enum><text>International cooperation and competitiveness, including matters relating to the competitive international landscape for artificial intelligence-related industries.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11F8B44BAB844BA7837F0F49A248203D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Accountability and legal rights, including matters relating to the responsibility for any violations of laws by an artificial intelligence system and the compatibility of international regulations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H612B96B32286420AAA551686E472E776"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Matters relating to machine learning bias through core cultural and societal norms.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CFB56E68BA94112BDAEE5335006371E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Matters relating to how artificial intelligence can serve or enhance opportunities in rural communities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EBD8B9F5D714B6ABD7E431B2C81478F"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Government efficiency, including matters relating to how to promote cost saving and streamline operations.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5AA44FF5D8E4416966DEF63E30C4C46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall study and assess the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HDE90C87788864D47B4D7110EFF1A4C2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>How to create a climate for public and private sector investment and innovation in artificial intelligence.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BB47F5F34D44339B48432C4C288116A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The possible benefits and effects that the development of artificial intelligence may have on the economy, workforce, and competitiveness of the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4047935F6E54D4396E399A287103805"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Whether and how networked, automated, artificial intelligence applications and robotic devices will displace or create jobs and how any job related gains relating to artificial intelligence can be maximized.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81E134E3CF5940C7A56589ABDBB86B02"><enum>(D)</enum><text>How bias can be identified and eliminated in the development of artificial intelligence and in the algorithms that support them, including with respect to the following:</text>
 <clause id="H2E72A48711B94F1E9532E2664238B29C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The selection and processing of data used to train artificial intelligence.</text> </clause><clause id="HCF6F62F11B5A4ADABCBEA6C2545B8075"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Diversity in the development of artificial intelligence.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC3FC363CA64D4FC386474198FD924E37"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The ways and places the systems are deployed and the potential harmful outcomes.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1313A8E312F4DDEA34368C43DFD56BD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Whether and how to incorporate ethical standards in the development and implementation of artificial intelligence.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H312261394DD04598A7D0D4349BCD0550"><enum>(F)</enum><text>How the Federal Government can encourage technological progress in implementation of artificial intelligence that benefits the full spectrum of social and economic classes.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA19E3D7E238F4F67A258288E8B3D20EB"><enum>(G)</enum><text>How the privacy rights of individuals are or will be affected by technological innovation relating to artificial intelligence.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BA226D9EB4E40FDBBFAB0A20001070A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Whether technological advancements in artificial intelligence have or will outpace the legal and regulatory regimes implemented to protect consumers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H971BCB1B947945ABA0A219F962BC1E51"><enum>(I)</enum><text>How existing laws, including those concerning data access and privacy, should be modernized to enable the potential of artificial intelligence.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB6B8668EAE14DC8A7D2A3DA14C0C4B6"><enum>(J)</enum><text>How the Federal Government utilizes artificial intelligence to handle large or complex data sets.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD7B5DCF641A44B18E11F3E3DB2E9DF0"><enum>(K)</enum><text>How ongoing dialogues and consultations with multi-stakeholder groups can maximize the potential of artificial intelligence and further development of artificial intelligence technologies that can benefit everyone inclusively.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8035474E9E046869FC49571EF83EBB7"><enum>(L)</enum><text>How the development of artificial intelligence can affect cost savings and streamline operations in various areas of government operations, including health care, cybersecurity, infrastructure, and disaster recovery.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9897076AEE0C4808984C5F8CC627F7F7"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Such other matters as the Advisory Committee considers appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H214DC4EC5BE347D3A620FC950221515A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports and recommendations</header> <subparagraph id="HBBC502C2FAE2402E9D4248E2DF7A7AA3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Report by Advisory Committee</header><text>Not later than 540 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Advisory Committee shall submit to the Secretary and to Congress a report on the findings of the Advisory Committee and such recommendations as the Advisory Committee may have for administrative or legislative action relating to artificial intelligence.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9354D239E1B04B7F93FC2CA34D779F0E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Recommendations of Secretary</header><text>Not later than 90 days after receiving the report submitted under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall review the report and submit to Congress such recommendations as the Secretary may have with respect to the matters contained in the report submitted under subparagraph (A).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF021D3511820413B82815CE19BB5A332"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header>
				<paragraph id="HDE119817AC8B4D8494B70FA0182C055F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Voting members</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9CC136AB4F9D4FAC9F3AC9B0984EC860"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall be composed of 19 voting members who shall be appointed by the Secretary of Commerce, with advisement from the Chair and Ranking Member of the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Chair and Ranking Member of the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, for purposes of the Advisory Committee from among individuals with expertise in matters relating to workforce development, ethics, privacy, artificial intelligence, or computer science.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5650874BD17D4AEA8B424831530EEAF5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Representation</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall ensure that voting members are appointed as follows:</text>
 <clause id="H5F3C1124F53844698ADFBFC7043D1685"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Five members from academic or research community.</text> </clause><clause id="H274383C796FC48E5AA63EDEC052BCA25"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Six members from private industry, at least one of whom shall be from a small business concern.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1D39FEDEA6B541448CDAC4E3069D0BE4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Six from civil society, at least two of whom shall be from groups that advocate for civil liberties or civil rights.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9D220360D22042E390BB66AC7E5C5DFD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Two from labor organizations or groups.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CF997F1DA6142578CE9170258071F43"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Geographical diversity</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall ensure that the voting members of the Advisory Committee come from diverse geographical locations within the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H01CCEB34A72E472EB6E865FC02CFA10B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonvoting members</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall also be composed of such nonvoting members as the Secretary considers appropriate, except that the Secretary shall appoint at least one such member from each of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H55D00945B4FD435DB6526717F6EF8707"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Department of Education.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76E99A2EE5A045A4A73DB008AC7E6FCD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Department of Justice.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6391BDAC05A45399026D6D803798584"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Department of Labor.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA335A0A1266B4961891B66877E89BAE2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Department of Transportation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3407DBB114E847B087A90A7170A0745E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Federal Trade Commission.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CE8BBA02C7E481BB1E89BD6EF5C0529"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00E5DA6263DF4ACB967175183662F454"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The National Science Foundation.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED5288E17C2A4DAAB5940DE1BC9C1DD9"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The National Science and Technology Council.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8897B34D51564CC497CB275BCE969400"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Such other nonvoting members as the voting members of the Advisory Committee consider appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B377BCAC2D34039B7FD9F32030EC942"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Secretary shall appoint a chairperson for the Advisory Committee from among the members appointed under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4A1918E76CA6441096D485A773383CF0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall meet—</text> <paragraph id="H84889ADD87D04A5D9CCDFF15DBBBAED6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in person no less frequently than twice each year; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H912A889DD35C4392BB3631BA85FD9613"><enum>(2)</enum><text>via telepresence no less frequently than once every two months.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H73C62DFDB99B45D682BEE9FF42C4AB80"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Powers</header><text>In order to carry out its duties under subsection (b), the Advisory Committee may—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF6DD995AB0EA489C9BE4242F05107C99"><enum>(1)</enum><text>hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Advisory Committee considers appropriate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB54D483D14A044A5946A3D5B2558C945"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to Congress such recommendations as the Advisory Committee considers appropriate;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC4E7A54149C449DAAC387ECECD5165D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>submit to Federal agencies such recommendations as the Advisory Committee considers appropriate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC4E005ED4B414969B4F916649ED290B7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>issue reports, guidelines, and memoranda;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBEBEF3EE11F84EECBD86A13286EFE2B0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>hold or host conferences and symposia;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD8C80DCD5104B32BE562DFA5132D159"><enum>(6)</enum><text>enter into cooperative agreements with third-party experts to obtain relevant advice or expertise, and oversee staff;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08BAD16D03AC48A693D8C16A4075F1B2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>establish subcommittees; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA3D3B9FE29A4C7E85B485AA66BEAEE0"><enum>(8)</enum><text>establish rules of procedure.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H93F64B0A0A5E433989F3C5253434C513"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>The members of the Advisory Committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Advisory Committee.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H78584CA921EC47359D560F6F40D6336B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Funding</header>
 <paragraph id="HF3A08CB967B84DD6A939776A5EC1B6D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), amounts to carry out this section shall be derived from amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to the Secretary of Commerce.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H1C631DF00CA646BC925FF7632501FF52"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Donations</header>
 <subparagraph id="H050ABA613F244C91B6FED43C0F0BD56A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>The Advisory Committee may solicit and accept donations from private persons and non-Federal entities to carry out this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55B806A3D60C44EDBB0EC78D069DD0A2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Of the amounts expended by the Advisory Committee in a fiscal year to carry out this section, not more than half may be derived from amounts received under subparagraph (A).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


