<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9E0E243CA9D64D478773AA8B77970263" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2903 IH: Rural Reasonable and Comparable Wireless Access Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2903</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170615">June 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Federal Communications Commission to promulgate regulations that establish a national standard for determining whether mobile and broadband services available in rural areas are reasonably comparable to those services provided in urban areas.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4EFA70D171824B74849708575D04DAEA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9611F9647EA94464B4A6BC75D29B770F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Reasonable and Comparable Wireless Access Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6A0282E962D24AB69A3A3D1BC56744B9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Availability of mobile and broadband services in underserved rural areas</header> <subsection id="H4DA3B666E8D140F0808D1FCC1157395C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall promulgate regulations that establish a national standard for determining, for purposes of rural, insular, and high cost universal service support pursuant to subsection (b)(3) of section 254 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/254">47 U.S.C. 254</external-xref>), whether commercial mobile service, commercial mobile data service, and broadband internet access service available in rural areas are reasonably comparable to those services provided in urban areas.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H475734CC94F44D57A019534C3C043045"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Underserved rural areas</header><text>The standard established under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H4C08BF41466F4DD1A66A79C680AAE70E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>define a <quote>rural area</quote> as any area that is either—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5EF20BFBA0CD407CB2434E91395A9E44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a rural area (as defined in paragraph (1) of section 54.600(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H44C5E695F766463DA61838190CA4B341"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a service area (as defined in section 214(e) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/214">47 U.S.C. 214(e)</external-xref>)) served by a rural telephone company (as defined in section 3 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/153">47 U.S.C. 153</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8C419D70F31B4728A5B47C11C97C993A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>define a rural area as <quote>underserved</quote>, with respect to a service described in subsection (a), if service that meets or exceeds the standard established under such subsection is not available in the area; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65EC74EEE5FA4143957BCB72D45D21B7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide that a rural area will be considered <quote>underserved</quote>, with respect to a service described in subsection (a), if tests show that the service available in the area does not meet or exceed the applicable averages determined under subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD9287938C9E54729A7EA3F38D1F7EF0F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data from urban areas</header><text>The Commission shall—</text> <paragraph id="H95C8A0A1E6844E2B94B976EF2BA5D775"><enum>(1)</enum><text>gather data on average signal strengths and average speeds of commercial mobile service and commercial mobile data service, and on average speeds of broadband internet access service, provided in the 20 most populous metropolitan statistical areas; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3D99A5267AC040E69ADA9D67E8E50774"><enum>(2)</enum><text>specify in the standard established under subsection (a) that—</text> <subparagraph id="H763682F8D3254557BFA6F3EB51A178BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>commercial mobile service or commercial mobile data service available in rural areas is reasonably comparable to that service provided in urban areas only if the average signal strengths and average speeds meet or exceed the averages determined under paragraph (1) for such service; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBC372FE721374368B5661A9C806A608E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">broadband internet access service available in rural areas is reasonably comparable to that service provided in urban areas only if the average speeds meet or exceed the averages determined under paragraph (1) for such service.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H59B49BCA4DA44A89A7C3C8287F64DC1F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Periodic updating of data</header><text>The Commission shall periodically update the data gathered under subsection (c)(1).</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H88820BD2753A45CDB22721D78A370A4E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HA2E6EF177C164C22848CA60F2C693A55" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Broadband internet access service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>broadband internet access service</quote> means a mass-market retail service by wire or radio that provides the capability to transmit data to and receive data from all or substantially all internet endpoints, including any capabilities that are incidental to and enable the operation of the communications service, but excluding dial-up internet access service. Such term includes any service that the Commission finds to be providing a functional equivalent of the service described in the previous sentence.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD154C56B3C0F47BBA7FC8452782758FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commercial mobile service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>commercial mobile service</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 332 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/332">47 U.S.C. 332</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF06FB154BBB4CD5BA8F16C3720A7BA3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commercial mobile data service</header><text>The term <quote>commercial mobile data service</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 6001 of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1401">47 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H760D9575506B4607B70EFD4BDF1748D9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <quote>Commission</quote> means the Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

