<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H35DEE6EE80E24D4F9789AD1846CAE3DD" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2538 IH: Intern Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2538</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170518">May 18, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide certain workplace protections to interns relating to discriminatory practices.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H90D26F4FF5B3482492EF229E1492B974" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3147A0D5E9524EE38DD10A6568C17E68" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Intern Protection Act</short-title></quote> .</text> </section><section commented="no" id="HBC862993FC26435BAC3FF0020A3BA7D3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">As used in this Act—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HB2E43E097AEF417FB07BE7B496DCD9A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE48F17CFC5EF4DC3B38F8632487E0AAA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employer</header><text>The term <term>employer</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB2DECBB487BC4C88A37E29BAA1249072"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a person engaged in an industry affecting commerce (as defined in section 701(h) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e(h)</external-xref>)) who has 15 or more employees (as defined in subparagraphs (A)(i) and (B) of paragraph (3)) for each working day in each of 20 or more calendar weeks in the current or preceding calendar year, and any agent of such a person, but does not include a bona fide private membership club (other than a labor organization) that is exempt from taxation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H32F58BA120B242F1892E1344EB599079"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an employing authority to which section 302(a)(1) of the Government Employee Rights Act of 1991 applies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA18DE25182EC45E68E536F4781DA056A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an employing office, as defined in section 101 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 or section 411(c) of title 3, United States Code; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H37863CCEF17047BDB537189A172C2918"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an entity to which section 717(a) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 applies.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD46E3C2BA62436BA1A6802638CF66B6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disability</header><text>The term <term>disability</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCDB944482DE044B7B3E371D81EA8E5F8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Gender identity</header><text>The term <term>gender identity</term> means the gender-related identity, appearance, or mannerisms or other gender-related characteristics of an individual, with or without regard to the individual’s designated sex at birth.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52C363D346BD4A6E91D7FAB1AAE501D0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Intern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>intern</term> means an individual who performs work for an employer, whether paid or unpaid for the purpose of training under the following circumstances:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1639CC8021C044BE98979CE4AC4D8F54"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The employer is not committed to hire the individual performing the work at the conclusion of the training period.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AE7F61BBA7C42F18218B70A5A59C1D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The work performed—</text> <clause id="H80D0692436174165A06ABD7545D0337D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides or supplements training that may enhance the employability of the intern;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD83C1BD36A6E40EA89F39FA6566FD2CF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides experience for the benefit of the individual performing the work;</text> </clause><clause id="H8AF5F6A1877B48BDBAE32C7871C8598F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>does not displace regular employees; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA9B4855BFC434933AE77C71FFCB504A6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is performed under the close supervision of existing staff.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2ED81127C8A34BC9831C17CC45DA1896"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Internship</header><text>The term <term>internship</term> means a position or job with an employer that is filled by an intern.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D97BE6CC55F4E4F97240691D940EF03"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Military status</header><text>The term <term>military status</term> means an individual’s status as a member of the Armed Forces or a veteran.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H668F02DB0A2B4705A5FF329576445CD0"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Predisposing genetic characteristics</header><text>The term <term>predisposing genetic characteristics</term> means, with respect to an individual, any information revealed by a genetic test of the individual or a family member of the individual, or the manifestation of a disease or disorder in any family member of the individual.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5D375B94E524609ADEC2822F35BE920"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Religion</header><text>The term <term>religion</term> has the meaning given such term in section 701(j) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e(j)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8DEE9D3F2554106AFC9714A185C1AC5"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Sex</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>sex</term> includes all of the aspects related to sex described in the term <term>because of sex</term> defined in section 701(k) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e(k)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCDC6C265712942C7A4541C1256DCA69B"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Sexual orientation</header><text>The term <term>sexual orientation</term> means homosexuality, heterosexuality, or bisexuality.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H85A90DB665344C30A413CA64F62D26D5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Unlawful discriminatory practices relating to interns</header>
 <subsection id="H1BAD5F33BE00405DB9E095095992A617"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Terms and conditions of employment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be an unlawful employment practice for an employer to—</text> <paragraph id="HC4FD0BCBD1A944E6BA545D8BC904C1E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>refuse to hire or employ or to bar or to discharge from internship an intern or to discriminate against such intern in the terms, conditions, or privileges of employment as an intern because of the intern’s age, race, religion, color, national origin, sex, sexual orientation, military status, disability, gender identity, predisposing genetic characteristics, marital status, or status as a victim of domestic violence;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H32F685CC2C284B09B969180B1E0B266B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">discriminate against an intern in terms of receiving, classifying, disposing, or otherwise acting upon applications for internships because of the intern’s age, race, religion, color, national origin, sex, sexual orientation, military status, disability, gender identity, predisposing genetic characteristics, marital status, or status as a victim of domestic violence;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H12A03926F2E245D383045B4FD5037C46"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">print or circulate or cause to be printed or circulated any statement, advertisement, or publication, or to use any form of application for employment as an intern or to make any inquiry in connection with prospective employment as an intern, which expresses directly or indirectly, any limitation, specification, or discrimination as to age, race, religion, color, national origin, sex, sexual orientation, military status, disability, gender identity, predisposing genetic characteristics, marital status, or status as a victim of domestic violence;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB3206E5BB7F475B9505B8F7F83FD655"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to compel an intern who is pregnant to take a leave of absence, unless the intern is prevented by such pregnancy from performing the activities involved in the internship in a reasonable manner; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEC4BBED132F7460083D51CBAA0521D0A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to discharge, expel, or otherwise discriminate against any person because he or she has opposed any practices forbidden under this Act or because he or she has filed a complaint, testified, or assisted in any proceeding under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDE453FC9980741F4BFA47C142E39C527"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sexual or other harassment</header><text>It shall be an unlawful employment practice for an employer to—</text> <paragraph id="HBECEFBAAEC224918A5815A19D5A06FCC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>engage in unwelcome sexual advances, requests for sexual favors, or other verbal or physical conduct of a sexual nature to an intern when—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H37AC38CCC9D047488D815A8575B80778"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submission to such conduct is made either explicitly or implicitly a term or condition of the intern’s continued position as an intern;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C46376BA0E54713ADB591B6819FD5EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submission to or rejection of such conduct by the intern is used as the basis for employment decisions affecting such intern; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1ED8F5BDF9D04FE9AB3E404FF94BBB2B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such conduct has the purpose or effect of unreasonably interfering with the intern’s work performance by creating an intimidating, hostile, or offensive working environment; or</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H033CCE3B29384DE5BFF7E88FBB337EFD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject an intern to unwelcome harassment based on age, race, religion, color, national origin, sex, sexual orientation, military status, disability, gender identity, predisposing genetic characteristics, marital status, or status as a victim of domestic violence, where such harassment has the purpose or effect of unreasonably interfering with the intern’s work performance by creating an intimidating, hostile, or offensive working environment.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF33F31B51E8D45A5A2BF9AB782D682E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Age limitation</header><text>The prohibitions in this section relating to discrimination based on age shall be limited to individuals who are at least 40 years of age.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H088C361FFA864C59AD2B523F85F76599"><enum>4.</enum><header>Enforcement</header>
 <subsection id="HC6BECB2FCA724586801F638E9F3D73CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enforcement powers</header><text>With respect to the administration and enforcement of this Act, in the case of a claim alleged by an individual for a violation of this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDE7B072C6FC84E6FA15DFDEFE0162DC3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Commission shall have the same powers as the Commission has to administer and enforce—</text> <subparagraph id="H2EEDEF25CE854887B468FEBA5C8F9E9A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e</external-xref> et seq.); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB65D7BF1C1A147DF80FBC110BA59466C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sections 302 and 304 of the Government Employee Rights Act of 1991 (42 U.S.C. 2000e–16b and 2000e–16c),</text>
					</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">in the case of a claim alleged by such individual for a violation of such title, or of section
			 302(a)(1) of the Government Employee Rights Act of 1991 (42 U.S.C.
 2000e–16b(a)(1)), respectively;</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AE5D200A074487FA3F0ECE87AD9030B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Librarian of Congress shall have the same powers as the Librarian of Congress has to administer and enforce title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e</external-xref> et seq.) in the case of a claim alleged by such individual for a violation of such title;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H02E1339DCE6F456D991A174F88E5EAC9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Board (as defined in section 101 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1301">2 U.S.C. 1301</external-xref>)) shall have the same powers as the Board has to administer and enforce the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1301">2 U.S.C. 1301</external-xref> et seq.) in the case of a claim alleged by such individual for a violation of section 201(a)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1311">2 U.S.C. 1311(a)(1)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DCA5F6C6D9441228B1D59CC96A3CB8B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Attorney General shall have the same powers as the Attorney General has to administer and enforce—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA6FAB034C4C341BBA9FB5DEB474D2124"><enum>(A)</enum><text>title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e</external-xref> et seq.); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78C629C235F047F6A07F717861ED28DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sections 302 and 304 of the Government Employee Rights Act of 1991 (42 U.S.C. 2000e–16b and 2000e–16c);</text>
					</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">in the case of a claim alleged by such individual for a violation of such title, or of section
			 302(a)(1) of the Government Employee Rights Act of 1991 (42 U.S.C.
 2000e–16b(a)(1)), respectively;</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0321DB29F97B46BF8C313A5DE8A199F7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the President, the Commission, and the Merit Systems Protection Board shall have the same powers as the President, the Commission, and the Board, respectively, have to administer and enforce <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/3/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 3, United States Code, in the case of a claim alleged by such individual for a violation of section 411 of such title; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7EDD8506A86C4B58899FB2ACD898BACE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a court of the United States shall have the same jurisdiction and powers as the court has to enforce—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4E1C0AB3D5B04F55B3F3614CCE7030AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e</external-xref> et seq.) in the case of a claim alleged by such individual for a violation of such title;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD04CDFD6447C454AAC35C1FA72C23CE3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sections 302 and 304 of the Government Employee Rights Act of 1991 (42 U.S.C. 2000e–16b and 2000e–16c) in the case of a claim alleged by such individual for a violation of section 302(a)(1) of such Act (42 U.S.C. 2000e–16b(a)(1));</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEACC66621C304DE4BE1EB65DE5677607"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1301">2 U.S.C. 1301</external-xref> et seq.) in the case of a claim alleged by such individual for a violation of section 201(a)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1311">2 U.S.C. 1311(a)(1)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3726E1E9213B475CBE143C6B664C14D5"><enum>(D)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/3/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 3, United States Code, in the case of a claim alleged by such individual for a violation of section 411 of such title.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE85FDB93F784E1596E2746525DA2140"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procedures and remedies</header><text>The procedures and remedies applicable to a claim alleged by an individual for a violation of this Act are—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0C5629AA93F7457DB85235A380D221F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the procedures and remedies applicable for a violation of title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e</external-xref> et seq.) in the case of a claim alleged by such individual for a violation of such title;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H855288063C6D4C4796D2B184981CEF56"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the procedures and remedies applicable for a violation of section 302(a)(1) of the Government Employee Rights Act of 1991 (42 U.S.C. 2000e–16b(a)(1)) in the case of a claim alleged by such individual for a violation of such section;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE51F6A8CA5E49A2ABECCFBED1615E5D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the procedures and remedies applicable for a violation of section 201(a)(1) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1311">2 U.S.C. 1311(a)(1)</external-xref>) in the case of a claim alleged by such individual for a violation of such section; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E272D3F88DC434199150954D4915274"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the procedures and remedies applicable for a violation of section 411 of title 3, United States Code, in the case of a claim alleged by such individual for a violation of such section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H87AB042340264F67A5CB11EE2072EFF9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other applicable provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a claim alleged by an individual for a violation of this Act, title III of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1381">2 U.S.C. 1381</external-xref> et seq.) shall apply in the same manner as such title applies with respect to a claim alleged by a covered employee (as defined in section 101 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1301">2 U.S.C. 1301</external-xref>)) for a violation of section 201(a)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1311">2 U.S.C. 1311(a)(1)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HC91F47A31BC74EE1A275780E950DD7B7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Attorneys’ fees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, in an action or administrative proceeding for a violation of this Act, an entity described in section 4(a) (other than paragraph (4) of such section), in the discretion of the entity, may allow the prevailing party, other than the Commission or the United States, a reasonable attorney’s fee (including expert fees) as part of the costs. The Commission and the United States shall be liable for the costs to the same extent as a private person.</text>
		</section><section commented="no" id="HCA1549723C864C9B8F908B940756261B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Regulations</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HCE646EFFF8E04497A77144635B299939"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsections (b), (c), and (d), the Commission shall have authority to issue regulations to carry out this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB7D8F0A79F0B4F6B8DFDD4AA33CC341E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Librarian of Congress</header><text>The Librarian of Congress shall have authority to issue regulations to carry out this Act with respect to employees and applicants for employment of the Library of Congress.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE275B32B42004F0BA0206475219BA6FF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Board</header><text>The Board referred to in section 10(a)(3) shall have authority to issue regulations to carry out this Act, in accordance with section 304 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1384">2 U.S.C. 1384</external-xref>), with respect to covered employees, as defined in section 101 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1301">2 U.S.C. 1301</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD326C4C869984C43B07E2A3C2A2300F4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>President</header><text>The President shall have authority to issue regulations to carry out this Act with respect to covered employees, as defined in section 411(c) of title 3, United States Code, and applicants for employment as such employees.</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H6CA1AC8F28104B8B851D493A0E1B09A4"><enum>7.</enum><header>Relationship to other laws</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall not invalidate or limit the rights, remedies, or procedures available to an individual claiming discrimination prohibited under any other Federal law or regulation or any law or regulation of a State or political subdivision of a State.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


