<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5BC02235AF2F47FD9BC58A23F199E91A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4682 IH: Open Internet Preservation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4682</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171219">December 19, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001243">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000567">Mr. Lance</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001092">Mr. Collins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000461">Mr. Flores</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001114">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000387">Mr. Knight</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to ensure internet openness, to prohibit blocking of lawful
			 content, applications, services, and non-harmful devices, to prohibit
			 impairment or degradation of lawful internet traffic, to limit the
			 authority of the Federal Communications Commission and to preempt State
			 law with respect to internet openness obligations, to provide that
			 broadband internet access service shall be considered to be an information
			 service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H730FFD51DBD94F2A9D44B3707BF588D1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H310E894CBB71413CAA11BBCE3D9FF002" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Open Internet Preservation Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H75F8482F76C642F5B47803DBF34D891B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Internet Openness</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF845317B07FA4E3589815CF523C735A8" style="OLC">
				<section id="H77D8B5763D14413C86215FFBFDA53F0E"><enum>13.</enum><header>Internet Openness</header>
 <subsection id="H986C9F046CFC4758BCD4091B6A3E616E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Obligations of broadband internet access service providers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person engaged in the provision of broadband internet access service, insofar as such person is so engaged—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2553994128114967BE16D878E5B94C1D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not block lawful content, applications, services, or non-harmful devices, subject to reasonable network management; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H34BD439B3A5848B9A07F831BFB5B807C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not impair or degrade lawful internet traffic on the basis of internet content, application, or service, or use of a non-harmful device, subject to reasonable network management.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDFE6CACD462E4EBDBFBE5A4B9C8AF9B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Commission authority</header>
 <paragraph id="H38EF14A27A2A4CD888A22142221EFD2A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall enforce the obligations established in subsection (a) and the obligations established in subsection (e)(2) through adjudication of complaints alleging violations of such respective subsection but may not, under any provision of law, whether by rulemaking or otherwise—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB31560F2FD3445F1BC3C94E15EAFCF6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>expand the internet openness obligations for provision of broadband internet access service beyond the obligations established in subsection (a); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BFE11E497FC4DB1A44E90871297736C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>expand the internet openness obligations for the offering or provision of specialized services beyond the obligations established in subsection (e)(2).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H711BB23AE2904FA1A138DE416BE9908C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Formal complaint procedures</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Commission shall adopt formal complaint procedures to address alleged violations of subsection (a) and alleged violations of subsection (e)(2). Such procedures shall include a deadline (relative to the date of filing of a complaint under such procedures) for the disposition of such complaint.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8DECF3E8B7704733B353BEC45847ABA2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Preemption of State law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No State or political subdivision of a State shall adopt, maintain, enforce, or impose or continue in effect any law, rule, regulation, duty, requirement, standard, or other provision having the force and effect of law relating to or with respect to internet openness obligations for provision of broadband internet access service.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H65991340C8014D8696EAEC79E8B34104"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Other laws and considerations</header><text>Nothing in this section—</text> <paragraph id="HF9312EDDAB904C0DB2984EBD1A186533"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supersedes any obligation or authorization a provider of broadband internet access service may have to address the needs of emergency communications or law enforcement, public safety, or national security authorities, consistent with or as permitted by applicable law, or limits the provider’s ability to do so; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF052A9A969144C7A8EC433B4F66B9173"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibits reasonable efforts by a provider of broadband internet access service to address copyright infringement or other unlawful activity.</text>
						</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F305EA7A07F488583A06409E5BF7889"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Specialized services</header>
 <paragraph id="HA95E2F209A6F4420BD28293D3F0A0438"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the ability of broadband internet access service providers to offer specialized services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H85A240DD2FD44F0D949A515DE44ED43C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on certain practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Specialized services may not be offered or provided in ways that threaten the meaningful availability of broadband internet access service or that have been devised or promoted in a manner designed to evade the purposes of this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HCB73DBA63CAD47CEB5A7C72B7B363AB4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Broadband To be considered information service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the provision of broadband internet access service or any other mass-market retail service providing advanced telecommunications capability (as defined in section 706 of the Telecommunications Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1302">47 U.S.C. 1302</external-xref>)) shall be considered to be an information service.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H13728EE52FAA4A5582F76EF5C30189AF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reasonable network management</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a), a network management practice is reasonable if it is primarily used for and tailored to achieving a legitimate network management purpose, taking into account the particular network architecture and technology of the broadband internet access service.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1F1412E93FBD475A8F3DD5E75DFC761D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H6A10FFDFF3A94997B8BB390BA6119F95"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Broadband internet access service</header> <subparagraph id="H3E05390A53064563B5A7DDC3F3E832A8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>broadband internet access service</quote> means a mass-market retail service by wire or radio that provides the capability to transmit data to and receive data from all or substantially all internet endpoints, including any capabilities that are incidental to and enable the operation of the communications service, but excluding dial-up internet access service.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DCCA31594F544C9A1B6EB2BF1FD9E3D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Functional equivalent; evasion</header><text>Such term includes any service that—</text> <clause id="HB83CBC7BFC064635A913A1ED62195C57"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Commission finds to be providing a functional equivalent of the service described in subparagraph (A); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF9C5AAF09C1948AA9F369AA35007F3B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is used to evade the obligations set forth in subsection (a).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCA242EFD4957409D897D72C8B2683369"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Network management practice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>network management practice</quote> means a practice that has a primarily technical network management justification. Such term does not include other business practices.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F8080DE3C504173A4DBDFEF072F039D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Specialized services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>specialized services</quote> means services other than broadband internet access service that are offered over the same network as, and that may share network capacity with, broadband internet access service.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section commented="no" id="HB1BBBA7AEB104B2F9744D3B6792A1862"><enum>3.</enum><header>Eligibility of broadband internet access services for universal service funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 254 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/254">47 U.S.C. 254</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H5869408765AD42B38EBE0E64D7507043"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDF85DD0476554F4CA5E5026D27D6E173" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H83513080AD8C4536B4A4A0FCB4BF36B6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Broadband internet access services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Broadband internet access services (as defined in section 13) shall be eligible to receive funding from Federal universal service support mechanisms authorized by this section.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCDD214DC018C48DB8C926CFABEEDACE8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text> <subparagraph id="H0A0153A36AB441AB8513E7A17231F300"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>or a provider of broadband internet access service (as defined in section 13)</quote> after <quote>section 214(e)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H700B970D13CC46338E045CA9697A519E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by inserting <quote>or provider</quote> after <quote>carrier</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

