<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H61882AF1FF5140A58376539559B7A8E4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3407 IH: To amend chapter 301 of subtitle VI of title 49, United States Code, to require a cybersecurity plan for highly automated vehicles, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3407</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170726">July 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend chapter 301 of subtitle VI of title 49, United States Code, to require a cybersecurity plan for highly automated vehicles, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBCB5045C21B541C8915B32BE1F45EF9F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9A239E3B83634B389049359C98E10B48" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Cybersecurity of automated driving systems</header> 
<subsection id="H84D45C6632D340B5A333347FA1C8A319"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 301 of subtitle VI of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after section 30129 (as added by section 4) the following new section: </text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HD7ED3255EAB248A49FAB925DC14D747C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H84663562655F48429C36D2E815BBB577"><enum>30130.</enum><header>Cybersecurity of automated driving systems</header> <subsection id="H23C5726E54384B52B91AC7D98D260DBF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cybersecurity plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A manufacturer may not sell, offer for sale, introduce or deliver for introduction into commerce, or import into the United States, any highly automated vehicle, vehicle that performs partial driving automation, or automated driving system unless such manufacturer has developed a cybersecurity plan that includes the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H80EBDDC4945B454BB0EF72CC7AB7512F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A written cybersecurity policy with respect to the practices of the manufacturer for detecting and responding to cyber attacks, unauthorized intrusions, and false and spurious messages or vehicle control commands. This policy shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H2A7C9DB3028D4B4DB00D48FDE0298CF2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a process for identifying, assessing, and mitigating reasonably foreseeable vulnerabilities from cyber attacks or unauthorized intrusions, including false and spurious messages and malicious vehicle control commands; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H926F0D52F3CF4BE399E1D8AEED703C1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a process for taking preventive and corrective action to mitigate against vulnerabilities in a highly automated vehicle or a vehicle that performs partial driving automation, including incident response plans, intrusion detection and prevention systems that safeguard key controls, systems, and procedures through testing or monitoring, and updates to such process based on changed circumstances.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC844EDC3FF734E1CBE5ABE7D124E4DC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The identification of an officer or other individual of the manufacturer as the point of contact with responsibility for the management of cybersecurity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCB9E18669322419A81A27DB56DFB08AF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A process for limiting access to automated driving systems.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H75C60F747067421BAC098B0DE00B694D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A process for employee training and supervision for implementation and maintenance of the policies and procedures required by this section, including controls on employee access to automated driving systems.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0A6696E02DEE431C8E615869296C34C4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect 180 days after the date of enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H634998070AA6462B89706A7A42DD5EA9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 30165(a)(1) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>30130,</quote> after <quote>30127,</quote>. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAC25B6E35BBA4D17B345F66802DC4920"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The analysis for chapter 301 of subtitle VI of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 30129 (as added by section 4) the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H8EF9D68B705A44EAB856E0658F85794C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">30130. Cybersecurity of automated driving systems.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H1D9778E01FF943C3A058A6DDB7BEC8E8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 30102 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6925A445B0A3422A9E3FC9D60509E78F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H09E3C1F2E46647548F9167C1C28B8238"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (13) as paragraphs (2), (3), (4), (5), (8), (9), (10), (11), (12), (13), (15), (16), and (17), respectively;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8F3AEBCA4E1941D9A5EF4D889D4BC5EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (2) (as so redesignated) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HC3FC4507C0F34AC393575791BA8F87F4" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H6C62EC9E37EF405495E53787486AB49F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><quote>automated driving system</quote> means the hardware and software that are collectively capable of performing the entire dynamic driving task on a sustained basis, regardless of whether such system is limited to a specific operational design domain.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H787E5BA0FBE24999856FF0CE1EC1561A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (5) (as so redesignated) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H9E15F1DD5EFB4285951FF2B7F44B27CC" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HE4F1C259D62144599045DE00A7713475"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><quote>dynamic driving task</quote> means all of the real time operational and tactical functions required to operate a vehicle in on-road traffic, excluding the strategic functions such as trip scheduling and selection of destinations and waypoints, and including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFD1D764602BF41388ED5FD077C437E0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>lateral vehicle motion control via steering;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6A4EE6D77B8040DBA79323C6E87D1564"><enum>(B)</enum><text>longitudinal vehicle motion control via acceleration and deceleration;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBC484063244C45AAB5B7C116E8ED6A39"><enum>(C)</enum><text>monitoring the driving environment via object and event detection, recognition, classification, and response preparation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H282AC866B08F4BD9B261EEF39408D2CB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>object and event response execution;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0DBC86D10A09481C8A1AA6B8CC585F63"><enum>(E)</enum><text>maneuver planning; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC1AF66F339C74DA4A9683FD0B48B1E0F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>enhancing conspicuity via lighting, signaling, and gesturing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE94BD9999DEC4960A06BD0E9BFE60686"><enum>(7)</enum><text><quote>highly automated vehicle</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="H66AF4BCA8A0046C7A7AB52851D7CBC9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a motor vehicle equipped with an automated driving system; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H97CC2CE1ECB44C8C8BF590E321F0D153"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include a commercial motor vehicle (as defined in section 31101).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE546959A216B46018A7669348EE3FB7D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (13) (as so redesignated) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HFFA4B4277F7342FA93BDB8FF89EABBEC" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H8C13EB91F59D46A2BB2BC5CB8732F296"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><quote>operational design domain</quote> means the specific conditions under which a given driving automation system or feature thereof is designed to function. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC2DFCE312B1A4540BF72C848F4B84F35"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H70B019149E0446B08463505AE6E0788B"> 
<paragraph id="H35D89FDF5E7A4B4DA1E4514A6C403D06"><enum>(18)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><quote>vehicle that performs partial driving automation</quote> does not include a commercial motor vehicle (as defined in section 31101).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF6B5D23FD7D426F814522F734F99456"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H3ED8EF57CDFD491FBB6D20820C6B9964" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HBF2A68BCCF0C4B378C4E56DFE88030FA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Revisions to certain definitions</header> 
<paragraph id="HEE590D0327EF4D66958962BB3B33ED1B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If SAE International (or its successor organization) revises the definition of any of the terms defined in paragraph (1), (6), or (14) of subsection (a) in Recommended Practice Report J3016, it shall notify the Secretary of the revision. The Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register to inform the public of the new definition unless, within 90 days after receiving notice of the new definition and after opening a period for public comment on the new definition, the Secretary notifies SAE International (or its successor organization) that the Secretary has determined that the new definition does not meet the need for motor vehicle safety, or is otherwise inconsistent with the purposes of this chapter. If the Secretary so notifies SAE International (or its successor organization), the existing definition in subsection (a) shall remain in effect. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H212ACCB11F7B4C3FA3287B5628E84261"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary does not reject a <italic></italic>definition revised by SAE International (or its successor organization) as described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall promptly make any conforming amendments to the regulations and standards of the Secretary that are necessary. The revised definition shall apply for purposes of this chapter. The requirements of section 553 of title 5 shall not apply to the making of any such conforming amendments.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD3D3C7667A2440FF91BECAFBB9363B39"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Pursuant to section 553 of title 5, the Secretary may update any of the definitions in paragraph (1), (6), or (14) of subsection (a) if <italic></italic>the Secretary determines that materially changed circumstances regarding highly automated vehicles have impacted motor vehicle safety such that the definitions need to be updated to reflect such circumstances.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

