<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4DC9ADD9F5F34663B2D8A13E58F97D09" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2713 IH: Miners Pension Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2713</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170525">May 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000297">Mr. Jenkins of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney of West Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to transfer certain funds to the
			 1974 United Mine Workers of America Pension Plan, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1990A775155446A89110D5679534866A" style="OLC">
 <section id="HCEF3B4D63291435BAF04BA9F494820DD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Miners Pension Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1A60320127B4707B773C3245EF73652" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transfers to 1974 UMWA Pension Plan</header> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE1E5C9F7E2547E0BEB9DC837D7DAF25"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (i) of section 402 of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1232">30 U.S.C. 1232</external-xref>), as amended by the Further Continuing and Security Assistance Appropriations Act, 2017, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB57314F58DC34FBB89D280348F627343"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C135B36AA704BF7BC822ADBE2B3F49B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H703E83C42B3C44FBA37A4F518F0948F4" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="H8E186561B3CD4771A710DA81A15479D5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additional amounts</header>
 <subparagraph id="H912709F31F144D61B1A8CBED4113A03A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Calculation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the dollar limitation specified in paragraph (3)(A) exceeds the aggregate amount required to be transferred under paragraphs (1) and (2) for a fiscal year, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer an additional amount equal to the difference between such dollar limitation and such aggregate amount to the trustees of the 1974 UMWA Pension Plan to pay benefits required under that plan.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2A84DE084EF4F8EAFC232AB1B4EA3CC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Cessation of transfers</header><text>The transfers described in subparagraph (A) shall cease as of the first fiscal year beginning after the first plan year for which the funded percentage (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/432">section 432(j)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) of the 1974 UMWA Pension Plan is at least 100 percent.</text>
							</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC18F3EF7552C4DD784E4C5A6EA0E2867"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Enhanced annual reporting</header>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6760D0B0292B4A81B83DB57F8F65F048"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than the 90th day of each plan year beginning after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Miners Pension Protection Act</short-title>, the trustees of the 1974 UMWA Pension Plan shall file with the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary's delegate and the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation a report (including appropriate documentation and actuarial certifications from the plan actuary, as required by the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary's delegate) that contains—</text>
 <subclause id="HECBCBAAC470F4403A539D0AEEAF6071C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>whether the plan is in endangered or critical status under section 305 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/432">section 432</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 as of the first day of such plan year;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8331C412AB9D414FB0212C5AAAEA9ADE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the funded percentage (as defined in section 432(j)(2) of such Code) as of the first day of such plan year, and the underlying actuarial value of assets and liabilities taken into account in determining such percentage;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3656A9A8393545768732FC507538161F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the market value of the assets of the plan as of the last day of the plan year preceding such plan year;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB8E3A6BC26444777B897AEF48AE90325"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the total value of all contributions made during the plan year preceding such plan year;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H57D650C414584ED7975AC1EEAC37C365"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the total value of all benefits paid during the plan year preceding such plan year;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5E734F69F62A4EA2BD7542AAD8A55BF8"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>cash flow projections for such plan year and either the 6 or 10 succeeding plan years, at the election of the trustees, and the assumptions relied upon in making such projections;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H202BF267A8F94D7DA11538C2997AEB99"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>funding standard account projections for such plan year and the 9 succeeding plan years, and the assumptions relied upon in making such projections;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H80D6255757DD4A419C2693C10764FDE1"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>the total value of all investment gains or losses during the plan year preceding such plan year;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H3877DF2B12FD41A7AABB225927F9A0CB"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>any significant reduction in the number of active participants during the plan year preceding such plan year, and the reason for such reduction;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD13E85A1211C4145A71B7F3DB7105616"><enum>(X)</enum><text>a list of employers that withdrew from the plan in the plan year preceding such plan year, and the resulting reduction in contributions;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H33E5AD376DE64C3FA2D070ED7FBE508A"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>a list of employers that paid withdrawal liability to the plan during the plan year preceding such plan year and, for each employer, a total assessment of the withdrawal liability paid, the annual payment amount, and the number of years remaining in the payment schedule with respect to such withdrawal liability;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8EA115F59D534729BD4A2A49E9783D68"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>any material changes to benefits, accrual rates, or contribution rates during the plan year preceding such plan year;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H893EAA5912364D6099E79E17F5F7D2CB"><enum>(XIII)</enum><text>any scheduled benefit increase or decrease in the plan year preceding such plan year having a material effect on liabilities of the plan;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5809F88F345D45318B4C89C3CBB82E74"><enum>(XIV)</enum><text>details regarding any funding improvement plan or rehabilitation plan and updates to such plan;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HF136F0BEB9B04ABFA9F29CF00709BAF4"><enum>(XV)</enum><text>the number of participants and beneficiaries during the plan year preceding such plan year who are active participants, the number of participants and beneficiaries in pay status, and the number of terminated vested participants and beneficiaries;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H735B314E0C4E422B96C1686B9689E991"><enum>(XVI)</enum><text>the information contained on the most recent annual funding notice submitted by the plan under section 101(f) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HBA277CFD3A394EC5A2735DA339DEFA87"><enum>(XVII)</enum><text>the information contained on the most recent Department of Labor Form 5500 of the plan; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H815C690C276F46498F116D63EB8836E6"><enum>(XVIII)</enum><text>copies of the plan document and amendments, other retirement benefit or ancillary benefit plans relating to the plan and contribution obligations under such plans, a breakdown of administrative expenses of the plan, participant census data and distribution of benefits, the most recent actuarial valuation report as of the plan year, copies of collective bargaining agreements, and financial reports, and such other information as the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary's delegate, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor and the Director of the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation, may require.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H9083EAAA5A894F9E838177642322ECFA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Electronic submission</header><text>The report required under clause (i) shall be submitted electronically.</text> </clause><clause id="H60145D325A3E415295B8B3732F667EB7"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Information sharing</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary's delegate shall share the information in the report under clause (i) with the Secretary of Labor.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H96D81FBA7C814B55B5560F8869ADA9AE"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Any failure to file the report required under clause (i) on or before the date described in such clause shall be treated as a failure to file a report required to be filed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6058">section 6058(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, except that section 6652(e) of such Code shall be applied with respect to any such failure by substituting <quote>$100</quote> for <quote>$25</quote>. The preceding sentence shall not apply if the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary's delegate determines that reasonable diligence has been exercised by the trustees of such plan in attempting to timely file such report.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4506D940A2B461AA7C84AD6A0BA8F71"><enum>(D)</enum><header>1974 UMWA Pension Plan defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>1974 UMWA Pension Plan</term> has the meaning given the term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9701">section 9701(a)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, but without regard to the limitation on participation to individuals who retired in 1976 and thereafter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6937AC3168694563AA17EDF096ED3FF4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective dates</header>
 <paragraph id="H21811BB39CA449018487C0FB019A2579"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to fiscal years beginning after September 30, 2016.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7D5CEF337F994FD2BB7209A0C2D885E6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text>Section 402(i)(4)(F) of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1232">30 U.S.C. 1232(i)(4)(F)</external-xref>), as added by this section, shall apply to plan years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H78152731E32540F9A896556B4BFB1374"><enum>3.</enum><header>Customs user fees</header>
 <subsection id="H12CF246293004B50838EBD2A2BA503C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 13031(j)(3)(A) of the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/58c">19 U.S.C. 58c(j)(3)(A)</external-xref>), as amended by section 105(a) of the Health Benefits for Miners Act of 2017, is amended by striking <quote>January 14, 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>May 13, 2026</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCAA5638AFA054D778D61D993D0E4B550"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rate for merchandise processing fees</header><text>Section 503 of the United States–Korea Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/41">Public Law 112–41</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3805">19 U.S.C. 3805</external-xref> note), as amended by section 105(b) of the Health Benefits for Miners Act of 2017, is amended by striking <quote>January 14, 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>May 13, 2026</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


