<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1700AE73916645B9A75466254F351BB2" key="H" public-private="public">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4270 IH: Monetary Policy Transparency and Accountability Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4270</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20171107">November 7, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Reserve Act to ensure transparency in the conduct of monetary policy, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form> 
<legis-body id="H5A6FEA695A614A489768EFE2884BAF3E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA24B24B02E0C4113AAE1131ED0AB3551" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Monetary Policy Transparency and Accountability Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HC10D5498932843F6898258AEA4A622BC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Monetary policy transparency and accountability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12A of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/263">12 U.S.C. 263</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFEC7CB55097C44469861B5F1444D8D35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) and (c) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H50EF38A9A7C54B7A95E21FC5953E6767"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsections:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H8848EAFE55F24D7A9E7B22353F34D71D" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H1457E8FBED5141AE98074208AA3C41EA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Policy transparency</header> 
<paragraph id="H11C9D299483A4EE79BCC37278C2C31A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Monetary policy strategy</header> 
<subparagraph id="H1CEEF68BF6E7478D8E748451E7F1726B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Committee shall annually establish exactly 1 monetary policy strategy, which shall serve as a non-technical public communication of the Committee’s consensus expectation for the conduct of monetary policy during that calendar year.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA3059F49D5F1488EAA7C1424E3B0D678"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Each monetary policy strategy of the Committee shall include the following:</text> 
<clause id="H16F2B6519C1E4FF5916E88757867640F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A plain English description of how the Committee would adjust each of the following monetary policy instruments in reaction to changes in a small and well-defined set of publicly available economic indicators:</text> <subclause id="H9BD9130F65FE40EDBE59931EF7A4BD26"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Short-term interest rate targets established by the Committee.</text> </subclause>
<subclause id="HDF212D1691654F25ACE2E8941ADC5253"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Open-market operations authorized under section 14.</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H1862D3487E4D4A2D9BB4AD6E0196CC24"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Earnings on balances maintained at a Federal reserve bank by or on behalf of a depository institution under section 19(b)(12).</text> </subclause></clause>
<clause id="H123DDB0452E1428DB0765BEC83DE9623"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An identification of 1 monetary policy instrument from the list in clause (i) that the Committee expects to use as the primary instrument for implementing the monetary policy strategy described under subparagraph (A).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6FEEB4480E4410A83BDE2FD3EE5A7BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reference monetary policy rules</header><text>In addition to the monetary policy strategy required under paragraph (1), the Committee shall annually adopt at least 1 and not more than 3 reference monetary policy rules, each of which shall mathematically express how the primary monetary policy instrument identified under paragraph (1)(B)(ii) reacts to changes in a small and well-defined set of publicly available economic indicators.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0F49EDF89DEB48B5839BB4D43E1DB592"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deviations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prevent the Committee from setting short-term interest rate targets, conducting open-market operations, or paying earnings on balances pursuant to section 19(b)(12) in a manner that deviates from a monetary policy strategy or any reference monetary policy rules established under this subsection.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5A7FC4073EFF4F2FBBF3D2276D34F67B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Testimony and reports of the Chairman</header><text>The Chairman shall, concurrent with each semi-annual hearing required under section 2B, submit a report to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Banking and Financial Services of the House of Representatives, containing—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7ECBB581BF8249F4A82072EC384109D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a statement as to whether the monetary policy strategy established under subsection (b)(1) qualitatively differs from any of the reference monetary policy rules required under subsection (b)(2) and, if applicable, a full and non-technical explanation of any such difference;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H4F8E1969C85548ABB99BA27FE22F0FA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a statement as to whether the Committee’s conduct of monetary policy since the previous report quantitatively differs from any reference monetary policy rule and, if applicable, a full and non-technical explanation of any such differences; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H51E8D37E0469481B8AD38F2A1617DF59"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of—</text> <subparagraph id="H1B7688B7552D41A9AFE7DC8531118CED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the circumstances under which the Committee’s monetary policy strategy may be amended from year to year; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H73CF2328D9C641C9A8D753D1B0346FEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a full and non-technical explanation of any such actual amendment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

