<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD038B6B0C5444E8C876C3266121BDB6B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3747 IH: Freezing Assets of Suspected Terrorists and Enemy Recruits Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3747</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170912">September 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require financial institutions to freeze the assets of individuals arrested under suspicion of
			 participating in domestic terrorism or providing material support to
			 terrorists, to establish a national clearinghouse for information on
			 incidents of homegrown <quote>lone wolf</quote> terrorism, domestic terrorism, and persons providing material support to terrorists, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1B63E852C51A46AD9EF4D469C211820B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H001108E9B5514B14A0FD252AECA09190" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Freezing Assets of Suspected Terrorists and Enemy Recruits Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FASTER Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7EC3487B4AAB456DA1519473FDFD0D1D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Freezing of assets of domestic terror suspects</header> <subsection id="H89FD371B7AA44739BD2F467C04B049C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual is arrested by a Federal law enforcement agency (or by a State or local law enforcement agency and subsequently turned over to a Federal law enforcement agency) under suspicion of participating in domestic terrorism or providing material support to terrorists, such Federal law enforcement agency shall notify FinCEN of such arrest and, upon such notification, FinCEN shall order each financial institution holding assets of the individual to freeze such assets.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H350CE6B31C57489F82A6B551BD3E3CF2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disposition of assets</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H141585B0161C4FA29B8082F7D9866C0B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of freezing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">FinCEN shall, as soon as practicable, but not later than 60 days after ordering a financial institution to freeze an individual’s assets under subsection (a), notify such individual of such asset freezing.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HC79DB622B7694F5C96B132322EDDFAFC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Right to contest</header>
 <subparagraph id="H99A27227A65C48B4AD0BC5987D8F8005"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A Federal district court of competent jurisdiction shall, on motion by an individual whose assets have been frozen under this section, order the individual’s assets unfrozen unless the Government establishes by probable cause that such assets are subject to seizure under this section.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14B0DF8077024EDF828D004BF16D3302"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Representation</header>
 <clause id="HC30DA0FD3838450095802C73786EDCA6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If an individual whose assets have been frozen under this section is financially unable to obtain representation by counsel with respect to the motion described under subparagraph (A), the court may order the individual’s assets unfrozen in an amount necessary to pay for such counsel, and such unfrozen funds may only be used to pay for such counsel.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC14BEF89DB9A40A19A2D420FDD531F9E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Factors to consider</header><text>In determining whether to order the unfreezing of funds under clause (i), a court shall take into account the individual’s standing to bring such a motion and whether the motion appears to be made in good faith.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD909AE6A7EFA473E833934B8C377B7CF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Unfreezing of property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">FinCEN shall order an individual’s assets unfrozen if—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H091E69BA6E7742CC9573852ACC350AF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">FinCEN does not provide the notice described under paragraph (1) within 60 days of ordering the assets frozen;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H722231CF6D594D53880F41176D03B0E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a criminal indictment is not filed against the individual with respect to participation in domestic terrorism or providing material support to terrorists within 90 days after FinCEN orders the assets frozen; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7403509CD6784E308EF8E80C526F4E89"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the individual is tried for domestic terrorism or providing material support to terrorists and is not convicted.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE5451272DB945D99E12B46DF1E91AAA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Confiscation upon conviction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual whose assets have been frozen under this section is convicted of domestic terrorism or providing material support to terrorists, FinCEN shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H43DB7E5841B942B39CAB3010EF9A7A9A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">confiscate all such assets that were involved in such crime, or that constitute or derive from proceeds traceable to such crime, and may—</text>
 <clause id="HA683444079EB4D91946D2EAED65AFA10"><enum>(i)</enum><text>distribute assets to victims of the individual;</text> </clause><clause id="HA1687665D37544B2A8CFC19D2CD53558"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>transfer assets to the Attorney General for distribution to law enforcement for counterterrorism purposes; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H400F14C435E34C5DAD3CDDE747DB196B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use assets for such other purpose as FinCEN determines appropriate; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F209134D4D74669845A256DB9C8C3A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>order all other such assets unfrozen.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF27EA7C2BC264919A2022214D83F486F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person violating the requirements of this section shall be subject to the same civil penalties provided for under section 5321 of title 31, United States Code, for violations of subchapter II of chapter 53 of such title (commonly known as the <quote>Bank Secrecy Act</quote>).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H12FEFBF3DE094ECDA7A6015A8171B0B3"><enum>3.</enum><header>National Homegrown Terrorism Incident Clearinghouse</header>
 <subsection id="HE82E090782F84323A592145DAA3927B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (hereinafter in this section referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>) shall establish and maintain a national clearinghouse for information on incidents of homegrown <quote>lone wolf</quote> terrorism, domestic terrorism, and a person providing material support to terrorists.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HECF74D947F9E4157AED2D5739823E868"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clearinghouse</header><text>The clearinghouse established under subsection (a) shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC48086F02B5040DEBE7B61ACEE0125AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>accept, collect, and maintain information on incidents described in subsection (a) that is submitted to the clearinghouse by Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies, by law enforcement agencies of foreign countries, and by victims of such incidents;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C4DE829C9D94A108EBE53497328702D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collate and index such information for purposes of cross-referencing;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5AE402B0AC8642E0A1F85868F5C42C62"><enum>(3)</enum><text>upon request from a Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency or from a law enforcement agency of a foreign country, provide such information to assist in the investigation of an incident described in subsection (a); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E8690F668DE428AB52D9994C26AD9A4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide all-source integrated analysis to other Federal agencies and State and local law enforcement agencies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E9256C7C9254D5C85E3803528B4794C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scope of information</header><text>The information maintained by the clearinghouse for each incident shall, to the extent practicable, include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFD43D30F9108425A87B88B15A7FD2BB2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date, time, and place of the incident;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H28F8F3C220A94C2B8B7FD307EEFAEA02"><enum>(2)</enum><text>details of the incident;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA32ABDDCC0D4399B119F19D66D57A69"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any available information on suspects or perpetrators of the incident; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DA79FDEC6EC4EEBA16C91CC5FDE7F67"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other relevant information.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H37CAD33B9F5E4C87BEB3A7AD4FE511F5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Design of clearinghouse</header><text>The clearinghouse shall be designed for maximum ease of use by participating law enforcement agencies.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H54907CE234224815812DCF3E7FE6BDFA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Publicity</header><text>The Director shall publicize the existence of the clearinghouse to law enforcement agencies by appropriate means.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEA1508DB47284D2DB9F39D7B50723578"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Resources</header><text>In establishing and maintaining the clearinghouse, the Director may—</text> <paragraph id="H319C63E9777D411DA83A7B5555D384FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>through the Attorney General, utilize the resources of any other department or agency of the Federal Government; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H12BFA31175C34C18A6C5CB770C279A19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>accept assistance and information from private organizations or individuals.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE62593865914418A2CB0907846D404D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Director shall carry out the Director's responsibilities under this section in cooperation with the Department of Homeland Security, and such other agencies as may be necessary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5C9678659D44461E9212FBEE8E0BD851"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2022 such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H06CB8C01D6C14FA18F1BB45484F790FD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H22C959051DF34E8D85B31940E70E92C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Domestic terrorism</header><text>The term <quote>domestic terrorism</quote> has the meaning given that term under section 2331 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8FC88E27F05F45BDAD7A2944B9130058"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Financial institution</header><text>The term <quote>financial institution</quote> has the meaning given that term under section 5312 of title 31, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A23ED4D939149E4B4940D9113975236"><enum>(3)</enum><header>FinCEN</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>FinCEN</quote> means the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network of the Department of the Treasury.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H521CDE7516C242A981FC8E44421B5BAB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Providing material support to terrorists</header><text>The term <quote>providing material support to terrorists</quote> means the offense described under section 2339A(a) of title 18, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

