<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2279C213C5BD460A9F08F0E07100BE61" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4390 IH: Hometown Heroes Relief Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4390</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171114">November 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000584">Mr. Gianforte</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000614">Mr. Duffy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reauthorize the rural emergency medical service training and equipment assistance program under
			 section 330J of the Public Health Service Act.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HCF433FD2E8AC454C9AEF75E24291A3A1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9B751560F09E453ABDF542FC49B6CE39" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hometown Heroes Relief Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1EE892BEC92F492A9A78CA6A4E109613"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reauthorization of rural emergency medical service training and equipment assistance program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 330J of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254c-15">42 U.S.C. 254c–15</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsections (c) through (g) and inserting the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68D403CC1336426ABAE29F46DF41AFE8" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HCC7B734FAC65408DAED6C684800BF70A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An entity shall use amounts received under a grant made under subsection (a) of this section, either directly or through grants to emergency medical service squads that are located in, or that serve residents of, a nonmetropolitan statistical area, an area designated as a rural area by any law or regulation of a State, or a rural census tract of a metropolitan statistical area (as determined under the most recent Goldsmith Modification, originally published in a notice of availability of funds in the Federal Register on February 27, 1992, 57 Fed. Reg. 6725), to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDC0B93F70344435F865CA3BDDA2E6402"><enum>(1)</enum><text>train emergency medical service personnel in emergency response, injury prevention, safety awareness, and other topics relevant to the delivery of emergency medical services;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B4532F231A64147879A36E0EAA7BE3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>fund specific training to meet Federal or State certification requirements;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H58437261D4D940C68EAA9D1DD3C34FC4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop new ways to educate emergency health care providers through the use of technology-enhanced educational methods (such as distance learning);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H69312756601243E1873DCDC0B2BCA5BD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>acquire emergency medical services equipment; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H66A9CFD4A9EC43568F742AAC1A465FFE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>acquire personal protective equipment for emergency medical services personnel as required by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2CED7DAC81304F4499AE83E6B7E80D36"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Emergency medical services</header><text>In this section, the term <term>emergency medical services</term>—</text> <paragraph id="HEA456D6A19994499BD9868BC7318249B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>means resources used by a qualified public or private nonprofit entity, or by any other entity recognized as qualified by the State involved, to deliver medical care outside of a medical facility under emergency conditions that occur as a result of the condition of the patient; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H382084DA356046969CCB9C9B801B7015"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes services delivered by an emergency medical services provider (either compensated or volunteer) or other provider recognized by the State involved that is licensed or certified by the State as an emergency medical technician or its equivalent (as determined by the State), a registered nurse, a physician assistant, or a physician that provides services similar to services provided by such an emergency medical services provider.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCC2377A4C2854DAD8F019A20FC624119"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="H67B3F9691B03454F8A446F069A59768E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3A782455C534E11AACB1EE28259626B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>The Secretary may use not more than 10 percent of the amount appropriated under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year for the administrative expenses of carrying out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


