<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB538CA5C03184151ADEFCCDACFC5733E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1609 IH: Department of Defense Cyber Scholarship Program Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1609</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170317">March 17, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000601">Mr. Ratcliffe</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to support meeting the increasing needs of the United States
			 for a cybersecurity and information assurance workforce by reinvigorating
			 and modifying the Information Assurance Scholarship Program of the
			 Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H79AF45F421F44D0AABC28899AAB95A42" style="OLC">
 <section id="H3B29302F664446F7BEC5A001056E8E0E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Defense Cyber Scholarship Program Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1B3C9944B1D74795875844423F6067D1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reinvigorating and modifying the Information Assurance Scholarship Program</header> <subsection id="H136DCC52E61C4262971A357E57A7DAE4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings and sense of Congress</header> <paragraph id="H669017D55B814AD7BCA88650BE351EEE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9212C3B7B297476AA8BFAA542B57DA9B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Cyber threats to United States interests posed by state and non-state actors are growing as the United States becomes increasingly reliant on the Internet and cyberspace for critical services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C256F473EDE4B55A9465BCE55A7A3E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A well-trained workforce is essential to meeting the increasing cybersecurity needs of the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A19422B416E44E38DEAC8DF63905649"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Department of Defense Cyber Strategy, issued in April 2015, cites building the cyber workforce among its objectives for achieving the essential strategic goal of building and maintaining ready forces and capabilities to conduct cyberspace operations.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C35FC7B9D7E46A49841DCC930DC6A7C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Specifically, the strategy stresses the importance of improving civilian recruitment and retention for fulfilling the cyber missions of the Department of Defense.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0B8E0695AE940A9B3471FE96B43C6AE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Many community colleges offer degrees or industry-recognized credentials in cybersecurity and related fields that prepare students to fill high demand cybersecurity jobs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA335F76A786244ECBBD20FCA4504B0D0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Information Assurance Scholarship Program of the Department of Defense and the National Security Agency promotes recruitment, education, and retention of cybersecurity professionals.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3323D70A5EBC4649BDB2F364BE33753A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Since 2001, the Information Assurance Scholarship Program has supported individuals pursuing cybersecurity education and training in exchange for government service.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0316CAFB0A8483A9A0DDFC69F3DEFB2"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Since 2013, budgetary considerations have resulted in reductions to funding for Information Assurance Scholarship Program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B04EE7C76BF45C2BAF3843C44B9BAD6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The efforts of the Department of Defense to build a cybersecurity workforce capable of defending against and responding to cyber threats should include reinvigorating the Information Assurance Scholarship Program and supporting cybersecurity degree programs at United States educational institutions.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CD8911FABB143BBB03B962D32974025"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Defense should—</text> <subparagraph id="HECD038BD1E0F4979ADF03FFEC76E40A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider the Information Assurance Scholarship Program to be a critical cybersecurity effort of the Chief Information Officer of the Department of Defense;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7F28755854C4D11BDC7CD63CC726B17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>continue to support programs at 2-year institutions of higher education that help students develop skills necessary to support the cybersecurity missions of the United States; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CDF7F04E66949B1AAE1915C5E29A6E4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>restore funding to the program to recruit and retain new scholarship recipients and build capacity at institutions of higher education.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC02BFB33DD734E8289FBC96A00F127B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modification of Information Assurance Scholarship Program</header>
 <paragraph id="H96C607A936204FC9AE156B08FA56D253"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation of program</header><text>Section 2200a of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3CE10BDCFE114A52A13994D954C1AD33" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HB06268BD42784E80AA2621CB4B6044F0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Designation of program</header><text>A program under which the Secretary provides financial assistance under subsection (a) of this section and grants under section 2200b of this title shall be known as the <quote>Department of Defense Cyber Scholarship Program</quote>.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB8F763ACE601473C9AEA54D7BF79240E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocation of funding</header><text>Subsection (f) of such section is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HA6C927A8FA1F441FA94A42B45B98E184"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(1)</quote> before <quote>Not less</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B6E3856D4D04F62ACEA45979385F7D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91FEB771B0304B55BB3366B7D5E7CAE5" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HC8B6FE34C34F43CD8779FE0D8B9AC39A" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Not less than five percent of the amount available for financial assistance under this section for a fiscal year shall be available for providing financial assistance for the pursuit of an associate degree.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE666494868A748B0973445677E4DC0AD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Defense to provide financial assistance under section 2200a of such title, as amended by subsection (b), and grants under section 2200b of such title, $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2018.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H555A8AF10E6E4D8C95D3052F2A0DDFE6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reinvigoration plan required</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2018, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees (as defined in section 101(a) of such title) a plan for reinvigorating the Department of Defense Cyber Scholarship Program, as designated by section 2200a(h) of such title, as added by subsection (b)(1) of this section.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


