<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4BB96DE3E429485C90FF6E2492CD0C2C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3473 IH: Native American Suicide Prevention Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3473</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170727">July 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000184">Mrs. Noem</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend section 520E of the Public Health Service Act to require States and their designees
			 receiving grants for development and implementation of statewide suicide
			 early intervention and prevention strategies to collaborate with each
			 Federally recognized Indian tribe, tribal organization, and urban Indian
			 organization in the State.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H51696534885C4BA0B9A390F988BCF62B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H41C82D6432974E9590B415742F6AD7C8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Native American Suicide Prevention Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE40BAB06733248E282514A91E6AA09C8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Collaboration with Federally recognized Indian tribes, tribal organizations, and urban Indian organizations in development and implementation of statewide suicide early intervention and prevention strategies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (e) of section 520E of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-36">42 U.S.C. 290bb–36</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H914E725C28B54F8BA10217FDFDBD61C8" style="OLC">
				<paragraph id="HF26C885C7D0B41919599D9472071D132"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Collaboration with Federally recognized Indian tribes, tribal organizations, and urban Indian
 organizations</header><text>As a condition on the receipt of a grant or cooperative agreement under this section for development and implementation of a statewide early intervention and prevention strategy, a State or an eligible entity designated by a State pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(B) shall agree to collaborate with each Federally recognized Indian tribe and tribal organization (as defined in the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act) and each urban Indian organization (as defined in the Indian Health Care Improvement Act) in the State regarding such development and implementation.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


