<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB3B5210B8A3D4E7784753E8F8C5FBF62" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2009 IH: Fostering Innovation in Medical Imaging Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2009</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide clarity with respect to the regulation
			 of diagnostic imaging devices intended for use with contrast agents.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H16259A12A8DE4A76BE6E8125BFEDF5AF" style="OLC">
 <section id="H194A2862574A408D9C13230DE88F76AD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fostering Innovation in Medical Imaging Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HCDA00C72B35F4E58B471C13072A6B375"><enum>2.</enum><header>Approval of applications for certain diagnostic medical imaging devices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 520 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/360j">42 U.S.C. 360j</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H17D90664614847EFA7615D2A773C1036" other-style="archaic" style="other">
 <subsection id="H23037D4F885A439FAB94151A79F55697"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Diagnostic imaging devices intended for use with contrast agents</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H726E81F746784F30B0A0081A65808EA9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary may, subject to the succeeding provisions of this subsection, approve an application (or supplement to such an application) submitted under section 515 with respect to an applicable medical imaging device, or, in the case of an applicable medical imaging device for which a notification was submitted under section 510(k) (or a supplement to such a notification), may make a substantial equivalence determination with respect to such applicable medical imaging device, if the indications and conditions of use proposed in such application or notification do not involve the use of a contrast agent—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE82ACBBC0CF744E4AE03C8CAEC1C57FA" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a concentration, rate of administration, or route of administration that is different from those described in the approved labeling of the contrast agent;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A369B6B79B847328AFE887CEEE41CD2" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a region, organ, or system of the body that is different from those described in the approved labeling of the contrast agent, unless the Secretary determines, based on information contained in the application or notification involved, that the difference does not reduce the safety of the contrast agent when used with the device;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE7FB81AC34C4793AC68F67CC171DEEE" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in a new patient population for which the contrast agent is determined by the Secretary to pose an increased risk; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D5B145AF90143518A1D6989FE37B3AD" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in an imaging modality (such as an ultrasonic, ionizing radiation, or magnetic resonance imagine modality) that is different from those described in the approved labeling of the contrast agent.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H991A54551BE34E7E8193E4140853CC3F" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The agency center charged with premarket review of devices shall have primary jurisdiction with respect to the review of an application or notification described in paragraph (1). In conducting such review, such agency center may—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H95FA700C99DB4777AD256B7A87F671D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consult with the agency center charged with the premarket review of drugs and biological products; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BADD3A851984CED95A14BF5FBF2221B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>review information and data provided to the Secretary by the sponsor of a contrast agent in an application submitted under section 505, so long as the sponsor of such contrast agent has provided to the sponsor of the applicable medical imaging device that is the subject of such review a right of reference or use.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FFB85D17CB7404F889C927D926790BC" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An application submitted under section 515 or a notification submitted under section 510(k) with respect to an applicable medical imaging device shall be subject to the requirements of such respective section, and shall not be subject to subsection (d) or (e) of section 505 (including the substantial evidence standard specified in such subsections).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H580D10A8A0924787B9C01935A0121E3F" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An application submitted under section 515 or a notification submitted under section 510(k) with respect to an applicable medical imaging device intended for use in conjunction with a contrast agent to which clause (ii) or (iii) of section 505(c)(3)(E) applies shall refer to such contrast agent by trade or brand name, rather than to a class of drugs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9398CD070C2489FAE17D0A93B719E4F" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection and section 505(y)—</text> <subparagraph id="H0CE0C3D125C24F17B8C90CAABA7C2750"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <quote>applicable medical imaging device</quote> means a device intended to be used in conjunction with a contrast agent (or class of contrast agents) for a use that is not described in the indications and usage section of the approved labeling of such contrast agent (or the approved labeling of any contrast agent in the same class as such contrast agent); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF47588E5A516441DB7E4CCBF673A5171"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <quote>contrast agent</quote> means a drug that—</text> <clause id="H021FEAC04595401A803FA2AAE5165FFF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a radioactive drug (as defined in section 310.3(n) of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations); or</text>
							</clause><clause id="H920BDB44F07B41B3BAED1644CB8D59FF"><enum>(ii)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H049F33FFC12A4EEA89756522ED1763E0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is approved under section 505;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H41B1CC47F9174CF18E832C8BF270D170" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is intended for use in conjunction with a diagnostic imaging device; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H42076DC4272244D189E55586625DEA6D" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>achieves its intended use by enhancing the contrast between a target tissue, structure, or fluid and the surrounding tissues or structures within the body.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HB3A83B3F36564DA280F8AE973D4BC491"><enum>3.</enum><header>Applications for approval of contrast agents intended for use with certain diagnostic medical
 imaging devices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/355">42 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HD903908CE8AA4B0AADEDA3E222E603A6" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H70AB808DE1074214BB7BC0C887FDE788"><enum>(y)</enum><header>Contrast agents intended for use with applicable medical imaging devices</header>
 <paragraph id="HDA6ED02AA6954EB1A621C27D35D763D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The sponsor of a contrast agent for which an application has been approved under this section may submit a supplement to the application seeking approval for the use of the contrast agent for a new contrast indication.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H32E46E7E03FE4024A1460BE75A35F992"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In reviewing a supplement submitted under this subsection, the agency center charged with the premarket review of drugs may—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAEA5DC6430F24527A7B0C31C84771CA5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consult with the center charged with the premarket review of devices; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB783ACC1861415A82FA16EB3866D698"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review information and data submitted to the Secretary by the sponsor of an applicable medical imaging device pursuant to section 515 or 510(k), so long as the sponsor of such applicable medical imaging device has provided to the sponsor of the contrast agent a right of reference or use.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BBDE3A40F704541AB74121B64AAD5A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="HB3C8B05AF5A64FD8B90D952B6684FE9E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <quote>new contrast indication</quote> means a use of a contrast agent that is described in the approved labeling of an applicable medical imaging device described in section 520(p), but that is not described in the indications and usage section of the approved labeling of the contrast agent; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CC52718B060492E993B456355C8D047"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <quote>applicable medical imaging device</quote> and <quote>contrast agent</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 520(p).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section></legis-body></bill> 

