<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HED122F43FDFC46EA9E4B35C24E5066A1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2481 IH: Protecting Our Ability to Counter Hacking Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2481</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170517">May 17, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Vulnerability Equities Review Board, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC4B20066CDD64812942695250D2EE18C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1B20F0DAD57F4296AC16F05F06E36D8D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Our Ability to Counter Hacking Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or <quote><short-title>PATCH Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H02373CC307414920AD6BB7046C1C7AA1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Vulnerability Equities Review Board</header> <subsection id="H436858053BFB48409100F813B5C75F2F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H138EDA0B4082462BB1640926C0BB29BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3285A74B7FD742E8A76A80536145FA3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publicly known</header> <subparagraph id="HDAD7F2ED4C5F4CF8ADE78546286E8E62"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>publicly known</term>, with respect to information regarding a vulnerability, means information that—</text>
 <clause id="H84B3290C5D964718832EDE4D8591F0BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is—</text> <subclause id="H6D469345BE61457C9E8AA85EFB5A4023"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a verbal or electronic presentation or discussion in a publicly accessible domain; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0D6A39E6A2E0436F9DF5CAF6B7FA566F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in a paper or other published documentation in the public domain; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H39D558C80B38416AA2CDB6026C7B97AE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that specifically discusses the vulnerability and how the vulnerability could be exploited.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H555194277D874959B60FC438D5C5A234"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Classified material</header><text>Information about a vulnerability shall not be considered <quote>publicly known</quote> if the information is currently protected as classified and has been inappropriately released to the public.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H392237197C1A402C96691B2803A9390D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Vendor</header><text>The term <term>vendor</term>, with respect to a technology, product, system, service, or application, means the person who—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2FEC7C10289B480BA64FBC68556838B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>developed the technology, product, system, service, or application; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51D92B7D34504B01B9F0EEA49034E5AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is responsible for maintaining the technology, product, system, service, or application.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE34DD19EE404558A616AD1968D7BA0B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Vulnerability</header><text>The term <term>vulnerability</term> means a design, configuration, or implementation weakness in a technology, product, system, service, or application that can be exploited or triggered to cause unexpected or unintended behavior.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C633E544A5D4A5F843E7B378847ABB4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established the Vulnerability Equities Review Board (in this section the <quote>Board</quote>).</text> </subsection><subsection id="HCD9F57F1CE3B4C0DA4DAA651657BA8FB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header> <paragraph id="HF6F192C044E34FE3B1347C1B8B182A6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Permanent members</header><text>The permanent members of the Board consist of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8EEC3B1109964689A9D907F0FB49A991"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, or the designee of the Secretary, who shall be the chair of the Board.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF7BC39371B74B0080E9B39CEBE0CAF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or the designee of the Director.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF71F7EEB657E41B8AA6DAE896B947DF5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Director of National Intelligence, or the designee of the Director.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FCBBEE6C5F94456AAEB18BB70E5D04C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, or the designee of the Director.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB69F814ACCA4CEE973F293007FDB0D5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Director of the National Security Agency, or the designee of the Director.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DD126E490DD4864AA71671B5AA7CA53"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Secretary of Commerce, or the designee of the Secretary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF1C493946D84831AC6CAC8948C58B56"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ad hoc members</header><text>The Board shall include as members, on an ad hoc basis, the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4E3A9FAD60B94870843E768A76B0CACE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, or the designee of the Secretary, when the Board considers matters under the jurisdiction of the secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFE83C8D4C0B4003BD92D7CE85E8D4A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury, or the designee of the Secretary, when the Board considers matters under the jurisdiction of the secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC55D03AC58648B29F09D9C517F3F6AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy, or the designee of the Secretary, when the Board considers matters under the jurisdiction of the secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B617FB700784335A37EAD3FD1451951"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Trade Commission, or the designee of the Commission, when the Board considers matters relating to the Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H80C85929488D46C586A5C156C1E992CD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other participants</header><text>Any member of the National Security Council under section 101 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3021">50 U.S.C. 3021</external-xref>) who is not a permanent or ad hoc member of the Board may, with the approval of the President, participate in activities of the Board when requested by the Board.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H728CE2945AB54DDC9198DB064393E81A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header>
				<paragraph id="HE1E7347476574D7FB8C223D2D1113D60"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Policies</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC60B8E70FEA7496E8C8528C8E8C5F58B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board shall establish policies on matters relating to whether, when, how, to whom, and to what degree information about a vulnerability that is not publicly known should be shared or released by the Federal Government to a non-Federal entity.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81547F88AFC344DFA32D08CCA3CC3D5E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability to the public</header><text>To the degree that the policies established under subparagraph (A) are unclassified, the Board shall make such policies available to the public.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F1C698D9D0A46E9830AA52281F79F5A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Draft policies</header>
						<clause id="HBF80AAB0A9CF4D7E91169C06B1A766DF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Submittal to Congress</header>
 <subclause id="H20F15925B4604E96BCAF8E36C8F70AC6"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Board shall submit to Congress and the President a draft of the policies required by subparagraph (A), along with a description of any challenges or impediments that may require legislative or administrative action.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H922F87D3FD324334A168403966D9BFA6"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The draft submitted under subclause (I) shall be in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H077AE657DC65400EA922B8B84B258DFE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not later than 240 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Board shall make available to the public a draft of the policies required by subparagraph (A), to the degree that such policies are unclassified.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1A20B5C4E0843738D77F45BA4979BFB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The head of each Federal agency shall, upon obtaining information about a vulnerability that is not publicly known, subject such information to the process established under paragraph (3)(A).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HBD7D944D4EB045D0BD0CFF58F7594C11"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Process</header>
 <subparagraph id="H4628D1D8C05749D1B9D498FD6A4B757A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board shall establish the process by which the Board determines whether, when, how, to whom, and to what degree the Federal Government shares or releases information to a non-Federal entity about a vulnerability that is not publicly known.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FE755F1ACF24AA0966CFA3BD77ACEBF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The process established under subparagraph (A) shall include, with respect to a vulnerability, consideration of the following:</text>
 <clause id="HEF85E4749ADF46178444EFC7A6E265A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Which technologies, products, systems, services, or applications are subject to the vulnerability, including whether the products or systems are used in core Internet infrastructure, in other critical infrastructure systems, in the United States economy, or in national security systems.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB2FF38D7F6D648F1A81A6375FE5C5CBB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The potential risks of leaving the vulnerability unpatched or unmitigated.</text> </clause><clause id="HBDCD6640E8F64A268371AB54B0598E17"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The harm that could occur if an actor, such as an adversary of the United States or a criminal organization, were to obtain information about the vulnerability.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6A4C5472932143159BF16A8820BC309A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>How likely it is that the Federal Government would know if someone external to the Federal Government were exploiting the vulnerability.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBBF5920AF90140FAB8FC973D5D74E805"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The need of the Federal Government to exploit the vulnerability.</text> </clause><clause id="HDAF1FAF15B1D419388ED0F31C1AABE0E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Whether the vulnerability i­s needed for a specific ongoing intelligence or national security operation.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE40E08F5D70F4923A351304DEF934C93"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>If a Federal entity would like to exploit the vulnerability to obtain information, whether there are other means available to the Federal entity to obtain such information.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0A2ABA3666514AAD950B0E5C190AB0F5"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The likelihood that a non-Federal entity will discover the vulnerability.</text> </clause><clause id="HE46FD7FC64094E6B8B05C562D11128F0"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>The risks to foreign countries and the people of foreign countries of not sharing or releasing information about the vulnerability.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9255CB17058A453BB4DAA767199335BA"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Whether the vulnerability can be patched or otherwise mitigated.</text> </clause><clause id="H3DEB55D03499493197A33B5AAE4FC843"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>Whether the affected non-Federal entity has a publicly disclosed policy for reporting and disclosing vulnerabilities.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AD2556C0F6A4FAEB59596BD361AB8D0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exclusion from process of vulnerabilities presumptively shareable or releasable</header>
 <subparagraph id="HBF3BA9A335B849D4B0DC698A69205CD5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under guidelines established by the Board, a Federal agency may share or release information to a non-Federal entity about a vulnerability without subjecting such information to the process under paragraph (3)(A) if the agency determines that such information is presumptively shareable or releasable. The guidelines shall specify the standards to be used to determine whether or not information is presumptively shareable or releasable for purposes of this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65AA4BB87C3A48ED98AE683EC0A38DE4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not be construed to imply that information which is determined under such subparagraph to be presumptively shareable or releasable is exempt from the requirements of subparagraph (A) of paragraph (5) or the sharing process established under subparagraph (B) of such paragraph.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF589D28B7DF40D9945ED19A27DCB073"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Dissemination of information on vulnerabilities</header>
					<subparagraph id="H0116709D7FDB4E42A03630C977C0F4C1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Sharing through Secretary of Homeland Security</header>
 <clause id="HDE578A08F85F45ED924C3117B50BA57D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any case in which the Board determines under paragraph (3)(A) that information about a vulnerability not otherwise publicly known should be shared with or released to an appropriate vendor, the Board shall provide the information to the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary shall, on behalf of the Federal Government, share or release the information as directed by the Board.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5F8A8AE8071F481AA9919FA95A25FB5A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Presumptively shareable or releasable information</header><text>In any case in which a Federal agency determines under paragraph (4)(A) that information about a vulnerability is presumptively shareable or releasable, the Federal agency shall provide such information to the Secretary and the Secretary shall, on behalf of the Federal Government, share or release the information.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1BABCBC535D411AAB4D50C11EE92456"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Sharing process</header>
 <clause id="HE43DC97C0CDB4A0193889C59585FF45C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce, shall establish the process by which the Secretary of Homeland Security shares or releases information pursuant to subparagraph (A).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFBBA67F6171F4288AF05EE32BBF574F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Use of voluntary consensus standards</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that—</text> <subclause id="H993739C9C89D467E9850695C101AF7CB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any sharing or release of information under subparagraph (A) is made in accordance with voluntary consensus standards for disclosure of vulnerabilities; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB4F14222C195445B88D46422F0EB4A5C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the process established under clause (i) is consistent with such standards.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBEC8D4D0E604012966BF7537EED0556"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Information not determined to be shareable or releasable</header> <clause id="HF28E10DD046B441BBF7C9304DB271DBF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The policies under paragraph (1) shall provide for—</text>
 <subclause id="H10043B4024694506A54947A5A0B03D41"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the periodic review of vul­ner­a­bil­i­ties that are determined by the Board, pursuant to the process established under paragraph (3)(A), not to be shareable or releasable, in order to determine whether such vul­ner­a­bil­i­ties may be shared or released in a manner consistent with the national security interests of the United States; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H1F5C475805CC4A848B9562870C64192A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the sharing with or releasing to appropriate non-Federal entities of information about vulnerabilities that may be shared or released in a manner consistent with the national security interests of the United States following review under subclause (I).</text>
							</subclause></clause><clause id="HFF41DC11082743A4AF32D98D11C83AEA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>In case of later becoming publicly known</header>
 <subclause id="H5F46542CDF5D43469362FAC087955773"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a vulnerability that was not publicly known and determined not to be shareable or releasable pursuant to clause (i)(I) and then subsequently becomes publicly known, the vulnerability shall not be subject to the process established under paragraph (3)(A) and shall be subject to such other Federal procedures and inter-agency operation processes as may be applicable, such as procedures and processes established to carry out the Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/1501">6 U.S.C. 1501</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H01F7C7561F8745F698AD4FF6A625E850"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Applicability to classified material</header><text>In this clause, subparagraph (B) of subsection (a)(2) shall not apply.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB1EB4EFFCA794D37B0FB40ADC38CF170"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>Each head of a Federal agency shall ensure that the agency complies with the policies issued by the Board under this section.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H8E6BD8362D994CD09FC321D20279DA19"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Oversight</header>
				<paragraph id="HC15A8E5C36A2426CADC83C9FB55A0FE4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual reports by Board</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0C95D0259F3B475E848E16FD57F0B976"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not less frequently than once each year, the Board shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the activities of the Board and the policies issued under subsection (d).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB279AA3248BD45E79E7D905158155241"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In addition to information about the activities and policies described in subparagraph (A), the report required by such subparagraph shall also include the following:</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H7ADFFF2B36044194A30954CB77E3F732"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The frequency of meetings held by the Board.</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H143BF96A5FC8445BBE7CDD7AD0E2AA36"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The aggregate number of vul­ner­a­bil­i­ties reviewed by the Board.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H599E1B342E77453AA2197CC1F0FAF69F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The number of vulnerabilities determined by the Board to be shareable or releasable.</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HD2973CCE3EB344C89A764AE1D22FFBE8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The number of vulnerabilities determined by the Board not to be shareable or releasable.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HC63A031D5CFF432B8523B6C21FDFB874"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Such other matters as the Board considers appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD409F7CFE1CD4C38AB49181992019AE0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Availability to the public</header><text>For each report submitted under subparagraph (A), the Board shall make an unclassified version of the report available to the public.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H91C7DE3DA60444A49494C46DFB6C6FB4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual reports on activities of IGs</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3BF01C381A024AD189345A9E89FCE26A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not less frequently than once each year, the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security shall, in consultation with the Inspectors General of other Federal agencies whose work is affected by activities of the Board, submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the activities of all such Inspectors General during the preceding year in connection with the activities of the Board, the policies issued under subsection (d), and the sharing and releasing of information about vulnerabilities pursuant to such policies.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF81851CD53874E4685D68567739A4B8E"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Availability to the public</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each report submitted under subparagraph (A), the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security shall make an unclassified version of the report available to the public.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CD7223CEA7B40229752C6657821AB98"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each report under paragraphs (1) and (2) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H3686B4C2BD094717BB2DAE3EA7ACE1A9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Review by Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board</header>
 <subparagraph id="H6EE528481CC0404194AD18815B34287E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board shall review each report submitted under paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75D60103880D4D3BB17A184705FAD998"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Vulnerability Equities Review Board may consult with the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board as the Vulnerability Equities Review Board considers appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BCA3AD9A0D74362A7D02EA3DDD7164E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H9C36484AE0764EEBB5EB5D920E22CBAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53325BA11B9948F19A81381263E1C468"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security, the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


