<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HEA1EE09974904AF496BEE3B226D2C175" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3342 IH: Sanctioning Hizballah’s Illicit Use of Civilians as Defenseless Shields Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3342</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170720">July 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000580">Mr. Roskam</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions on foreign persons that are responsible for gross violations of internationally
			 recognized human rights by reason of the use by Hizballah of civilians as
			 human shields, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5681FDCC59F940C3A5BA403C3478A241" style="OLC">
 <section id="H13472B27613C4272A3BEEE9A21426342" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sanctioning Hizballah’s Illicit Use of Civilians as Defenseless Shields Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H787D20EE71CA47699CB81CECBFA0EC3B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H397AA6521129430BBA0AF66CA0C95228"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Human shields are civilians, prisoners of war, and other noncombatants whose presence is designed to protect combatants and military objects from attack, and the use of human shields violates international law.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7320722B467041AAB9A8EADBB70018E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Throughout the 2006 conflict with the State of Israel, Hizballah forces utilized human shields to protect themselves from counterattacks by Israeli forces, including storing weapons inside civilian homes and firing rockets from inside populated civilian areas.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB6D0F87C8A744F6AB812F893A523687"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hizballah has rearmed to include an arsenal of over 150,000 missiles, and other destabilizing weapons provided by the Syrian and Iranian governments, which are concealed in Shiite villages in southern Lebanon, often beneath civilian infrastructure.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5076C942A88B442A976866BFCFDA8671"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Hizballah is legally required to disarm under both United Nations Security Council Resolution 1701 (2006) and the Taif Agreement (1989).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB303F67135DC4D89A5A4B40B6B679B30"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hizballah maintains an armed military force within Lebanon’s sovereign territory in direct violation of United Nations Security Council Resolutions 1559 (2004) and 1680 (2006), thus preventing Lebanon from exerting its lawful control over its internationally recognized borders.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H1468CBAFFB4A4D57AE633D7FE3E47E19"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It shall be the policy of the United States to consider the use of human shields by Hizballah as a gross violation of internationally recognized human rights, to officially and publicly condemn the use of innocent civilians as human shields by Hizballah, and to take effective action against those that engage in the grave breach of international law through the use of human shields.</text>
 </section><section id="HA6C922B73C8B448DADD22F567EAFA39A"><enum>4.</enum><header>United Nations Security Council</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President should direct the United States Permanent Representative to the United Nations to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States at the United Nations Security Council to secure support for a resolution that would impose multilateral sanctions against Hizballah for its use of civilians as human shields.</text>
		</section><section id="HF2D5988E372E421A979AF763BCB2E3A2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Identification of foreign persons that are responsible for gross violations of internationally
			 recognized human rights by reason of use by Hizballah of civilians as
			 human shields</header>
 <subsection id="H5D3312451F1D4BC5B252CE9217EDD2E0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall impose sanctions described in subsection (c) with respect to each person on the list required under subsection (b).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HC790855DE8F54F1887CEC5A922E72D80"><enum>(b)</enum><header>List</header>
 <paragraph id="H97BC85B49F6044D1B3BBF7BC748D3D7D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a list of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6B1B9B8AB2BE4C2F8002FB8A2A443D1E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Each foreign person that the President determines, based on credible evidence, is a member of Hizballah, or acting on behalf of Hizballah, that is responsible for or complicit in, or responsible for ordering, controlling, or otherwise directing, the use of civilians as human shields.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4E6166D9BA094C528D20F466581CDCD0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Each foreign person, or agency or instrumentality of a foreign state, that the President determines has provided, attempted to provide, or significantly facilitated the provision of, material support to a person described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H58D5DE5810A34751934C7751AD5C9435"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees an update of the list required under paragraph (1) as new information becomes available.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H46DB48AA3D7943F5AD9C423DA543793F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions to be imposed on a foreign person or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state on the list required under subsection (b) are the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF0F0900E861E4045BAF140C0E35F0878"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of the foreign person or of such agency or instrumentality of a foreign state if such property or interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HAB89B4DDDC1C490B90BD277D3743E303"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aliens ineligible for visas, admission, or parole</header>
 <subparagraph id="H8F15EE98F889461E910B6DDBB0B66B0B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien who the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) who is a foreign person on the list required under subsection (b) is—</text>
 <clause id="H9E0A7A73989342518359A6E1DAFA0638"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text> </clause><clause id="HF60EB828714A46AAA8C316BEC2B8C142"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3E8FEFDB7BEB46049D1633861BDF2351"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6D5D7FF35F546A4B75F6FA90C43726B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header>
 <clause id="HE29808A5348840E5933B4E4C83798533"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) shall revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien who is a foreign person on the list required under subsection (b) regardless of when such visa or other entry documentation was issued.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H43A5A72184B742AF99D3C98372B1BAAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under clause (i)—</text> <subclause id="HA589AC9AB0654911B44C2B1530E18E4A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall take effect immediately; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC87B1858E10F4E4B94830541B603EAD4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the possession of the alien who is the subject of such revocation.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DD964A145594E9D97B8E3A5BD3E5C77"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that knowingly violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations promulgated to carry out this section to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that knowingly commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of such Act.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HA80DDF8BF0974043900CD316122E85F2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header>
 <subparagraph id="H3A7CE240DDDD4845A22028829787BD37"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1702">50 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref> and 1704) for purposes of carrying out this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A1BDC0789674276A0FE1535A7FD7ABF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Issuance of regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall, promulgate regulations as necessary for the implementation of this section and the amendments made by this section.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE04EFD906F234084A7339803EF320EBA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notification to congress</header><text>Not later than ten days before the promulgation of regulations under subparagraph (B), the President shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on the proposed regulations and the provisions of this section that the regulations are implementing.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4486FAE30B24882B29C087F4EC4E311"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit the authority of the President pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) or any other relevant provision of law.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2629398D41C84B2AA4154D96C54D26FB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under this section for periods not to exceed 120 days with respect to a foreign person, or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state, if the President reports to the appropriate congressional committees that such waiver is vital to the national security interests of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9AABF1BB27474E69B2D980A7F694A4E1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text>Any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091</external-xref> et seq.), or to any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HC870886EEF3045E087AE78A67C490E9E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report</header>
 <subsection id="H2DD41E5F3F3C424F815ED7EDCC11FF69"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report containing a determination on whether each person described in subsection (b) meets the criteria described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 5(b)(1).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD1E213604216485B891DAD4226C944C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Persons described</header><text>The persons described in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph id="HCF747F82787A409EBEBE34061E75C114"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary General of Hizballah.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF56C8EFE2A4542588A956C29AE3B36D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Members of the Hizballah Politburo.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE263B41D6349490E8AC4946BFC811071"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any other senior members of Hizballah or other associated entities that the President determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4CE76CCAE64643C0AA6E2AD7321B83AB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person, or agency or instrumentality of a foreign state that the President determines provides material support to Hizballah that supports its use of civilians as human shields.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF533E259AA7847AF8F4BC87157A96197"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form of report; public availability</header>
 <paragraph id="HEB891249119D4478AC128591EAB6AC01"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B4CABF67AA14789A825378E6C8077F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The unclassified portion of such report shall be made available to the public and posted on the internet website of the Department of State—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H72C465BC9DB243F4A04B18DC582D783B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in English, Farsi, Arabic, and Azeri; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D56C28C9A63434E9014B8094CFBD6C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in pre-compressed, easily downloadable versions that are made available in all appropriate formats.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCEE59456038B4B039047A716909F86CF"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H8F2548F0EBE14D32B1EA64515B7AE39D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admitted; alien</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>admitted</term> and <term>alien</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDBFEEF6F460840BF99B009156537AFF3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency or instrumentality of a foreign state</header><text>The term <term>agency or instrumentality of a foreign state</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1603(b) of title 28, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H45FEA6ED7CB24806A27A6E2F6D9320D7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H205CBFB0849E48549E9CF414D3498307"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Financial Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88744B32594C4B18801913993FFE4CCF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B703FADCB0A4B37BD8BB689EC888A05"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means any citizen or national of a foreign country, or any entity not organized solely under the laws of the United States or existing solely in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86F430657F414516B6CDE51EC1A6A4C8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Foreign state</header><text>The term <term>foreign state</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1603(a) of title 28, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A2433E2330C45C1B6237D2673AD32BF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means any United States citizen, permanent resident alien, entity organized under the laws of the United States (including foreign branches), or any person in the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7739755825AC4A20AE48A55317A1D26C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Hizballah</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Hizballah</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H907A6BFE46394940B9D03C65C6C6AE62"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the entity known as Hizballah and designated by the Secretary of State as a foreign terrorist organization pursuant to section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE41173B2CA524AFFA94A1E9396DDC744"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any person—</text> <clause id="H7D86511F7AB14737AF6A11A2E5BF9555"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the property or interests in property of which are blocked pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8752F341EF4E47D89C2937246C47C3E9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>who is identified on the list of specially designated nationals and blocked persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury as an agent, instrumentality, or affiliate of Hizballah.</text>
					</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


