<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4EB539E1573D467EB64D3A64E38FD7E4" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2596 IH: Castner Range National Monument Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2596</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170523">May 23, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O'Rourke</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000132">Mr. Vela</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate the Castner Range in the State of Texas, to establish the Castner Range National
			 Monument, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9BB6C8784012421593181EC1E25CB254" style="OLC">
		<section id="H707B76610EF8412EA5BFF68048331895" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H3F8BF9984D244190BBCE0DBC6951ECFA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Castner Range National Monument Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HFFBAE6676AE346E29A7B456EA2133E0F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H707B76610EF8412EA5BFF68048331895" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5F221EA9B8AD45BDBDF4A5AF3A9992A0" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H34C975C7AC5E4F4A87D7DB54D6D8BF90" level="section">Sec. 3. Establishment of Castner Range National Monument, Texas.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA63293F70E5045C4AD56602C67D022EF" level="section">Sec. 4. Access and buffer zones.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H45B3B4E7E48F450A9C65A5CDC135FFC3" level="section">Sec. 5. Management of Federal lands within the National Monument.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H1E031AB929254AD29A44215F0CD21419" level="section">Sec. 6. Water.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4EC62239029C47B0918CDDFD349D2931" level="section">Sec. 7. Border security.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD91B172339C54554AB69D70B457CDCEA" level="section">Sec. 8. Department of Army responsibility and authority.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H18E93A59935942299441423A8C181A78" level="section">Sec. 9. Castner Range National Monument Advisory Council.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H6FA0CB24D5D247308F0976D81DFDEEBD" level="section">Sec. 10. Land conveyance, Castner Range, Fort Bliss, Texas.</toc-entry></toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="H5F221EA9B8AD45BDBDF4A5AF3A9992A0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H0A415FFE9BC14B41A62A68EB0B9E3ABA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advisory council</header><text>The term <term>advisory council</term> means the Castner Range National Monument Advisory Council.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H639134D0AB9D400CAD65D0AAEA4ED36A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National monument</header><text>The term <term>National Monument</term> means the Castner Range National Monument.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE8DBA7DD5A264AF4AC34D2127540D4F7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H85E903DB2F5D484BABD8CF35DB9737D9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Texas.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H34C975C7AC5E4F4A87D7DB54D6D8BF90"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of Castner Range National Monument, Texas</header> <subsection id="H2C3E5A4440CC4A418553DAAAF2BB6C1B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, there is hereby established the Castner Range National Monument in the State.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HAA8D23D12C02419E8210E7DF3243B704"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Area included</header><text>The National Monument consists of Federal land and interests in Federal land within El Paso County, Texas, as depicted on the map entitled <quote>Castner Range National Monument</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAD66307B2DE148818001EC504EC68BA1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exclusion of non-Federal land</header><text>The National Monument includes only Federal land and interests in Federal land and does not include or apply to private property or other non-Federal land and interests in land within the exterior boundaries of the National Monument.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HFA12259DA69F40AFA2E6BA02FBD4D246"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the National Monument is to conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the ecological, scenic, wildlife, recreational, cultural, historical, natural, educational, and scientific resources of the lands included in the National Monument, including Castner Range and its—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HC2B358079FF14EB1A7DCCFDB89CAFBD3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>relationship to the Department of the Army;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD545721C175B4FB2B491688847DD248E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>role as a water conservation sanctuary through a dozen natural canyons, arroyos (<quote>gullies, washes</quote>) and alluvial fans which efficiently transport run-off from the heights through seepage into the large underground Hueco Bolsón (<quote>aquifer</quote>, which along with the West Side Mesilla Bolsón supplies much of El Paso’s water);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H52EB87F9CF5843FD992A5FDC1FFD0A4A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>historical significance, as it contains numerous archaeological and historical resources that date as far back as the Paleo-Indian, Archaic and historic Indian groups, lasted from about 8000 B.C. to 4000 B.C. and was initially characterized by big-game hunting;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF9E4FDFE57A54286875AD5E5C6BC346C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>significance as a habitat for an extremely diverse aggregation of wildlife and plant species of special concern that are thought to inhabit Castner Range, including the sand prickly pear, the Texas lyre snake, and the western burrowing owl; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAC8EA1DD6BE74350A292946FC779165B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>significance as a one-of-a-kind vegetation region that includes a mountainous area, cactus lechuguilla region, and draw-yucca grassland region.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA63293F70E5045C4AD56602C67D022EF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Access and buffer zones</header>
 <subsection id="H54E969BB482E4EB4B678113A8C366385"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Access</header><text>The Secretary shall continue to provide historical and adequate access to private inholdings within the exterior boundaries of the National Monument.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H852269E540594EE2A3E81D2B910523B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Buffer zones</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act creates a protective perimeter or buffer zone around the National Monument. The fact that any activities or uses outside of areas designated by this Act can be seen or heard within the National Monument shall not preclude the activities or uses outside of the National Monument.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8048016F90994B26A4D9628BFFB95CEE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of easements</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall affect currently used easements located within the National Monument, including the use of Trans Mountain Highway, the National Border Patrol Museum, El Paso Museum of Archaeology, and the El Paso Water Utilities.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H45B3B4E7E48F450A9C65A5CDC135FFC3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Management of Federal lands within the National Monument</header>
			<subsection commented="no" id="HBAEF2F1431E847649D536FD4D064C4FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Basis of management</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HAEAF3635C04E4C088DCACFFD05CFFBAC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable laws</header><text>The Secretary shall manage the National Monument in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances the natural resources and values of the National Monument, in accordance with—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0E4177AC04C24363970FB71EF61F24F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this Act;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0612CC077D624C8181EE3ECD1AADD0FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H036FA211785F46108BC16F2DDC2E8F83"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Act of June 17, 1902 (commonly known as the Reclamation Act of 1902; 32 Stat. 388), and Acts amendatory thereof and supplemental thereto.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2BBBED6CAFA0410CA077FFFCC04498AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Resolution of conflicts</header><text>If there is a conflict between a provision of this Act and a provision of one of the other laws specified in paragraph (1), the more restrictive provision shall control.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H159E9778B3D04751A8AF0A698C948617"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tribal cultural uses</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to enlarge or diminish the rights of any Indian Tribe.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H26C23895905649318654B9E495F5261F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management plan</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H2684A987721D456A80A270025648398B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall develop a comprehensive plan for the protection and management of the National Monument that fulfills the purposes specified in section 3. In implementing the management plan and in considering any recommendations from the advisory council, the Secretary shall consult with the advisory council on a regular basis.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDAA7EB7AF33B47ED823671EF1D14C6DE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The management plan shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE03FD9D863BF4E0D8D882C131BEBD6BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describe the appropriate uses and management of the National Monument;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H30EC124112914D6AACA76C40F5E1A92B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify short-term and long-term management actions and prioritize management actions based on projected availability of resources;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6D087942D3834F61AA135581658E0A68"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include a habitat restoration opportunities component;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H46B34C768AA84DF386C5464C4AB6CE6A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>include a recreational opportunity enhancement component; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H555375C615B94E6DA7CA12CF5E17927B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>include a component that addresses the Secretary of Army’s remediation of hazardous substances or munitions and explosives of concern within the National Monument.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6657ED87E27E412CB788AB09FD2C2923"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public participation and special considerations</header><text>In developing the management plan, and to the extent consistent with this section, the Secretary—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE5F29C4D9947402BA01E774B6980F5B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall solicit extensive public input;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAE30C07CA028474DA69A055FAC6E3186"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall take into consideration any information developed in studies of the land within the National Monument;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC67D585733D5496B8D974CC1682268B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall assess available climate change information pertinent to the National Monument;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2C9A816C59649A58E9CA8C52BC8D030"><enum>(D)</enum><text>shall include standards and practices to ensure the preservation of wildlife corridors and facilitate species migration; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB3BFEAEA9DA146CBB514A0662589F022"><enum>(E)</enum><text>may incorporate any provision from a resource management plan, land and resource management plan, or any other plan applicable to the National Monument.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H92527820B9B14761809A5DAD897551BF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>In carrying out this Act, the Secretary may make grants to, or enter into cooperative agreements with, State, Tribal, and local governmental entities and private entities to conduct research, develop scientific analyses, and carry out any other initiative relating to the restoration or conservation of the National Monument.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H7632FF99B40F4F10861B4C93A600CAF4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Motorized and mechanized vehicles</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except where needed for administrative purposes or to respond to an emergency, the use of motorized and mechanized vehicles on lands within the National Monument shall be permitted only on roads and trails designated for their use.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF3C4B2FFD035489781EF609AAD492623"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Acquisition and incorporation of lands and interests</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HD15044ACB4BA437C9367DDD589EFBF44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Secretary may acquire non-Federal land within the exterior boundaries of the National Monument only through exchange, donation, or purchase from a willing seller.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HADCDA96843654E7FAFBB1840D3350B70"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management</header><text>Any land or interest in land that is located within the National Monument that is acquired by the United States shall—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H3331A79598FC4F94982F8C8AE674332E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>become part of the National Monument; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H68B39D0257FF429F8B629E9A45A97A6E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be managed in accordance with this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HA4026EA10416476A946A46C88FA34B99"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, all Federal land within the National Monument is withdrawn from—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HD73C79F8882C45539587E9A5CDEC05D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H97BC56D4965D45FD96CAB43489485106"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H37D17453C9C6417893EC74DCF084720F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>leasing or disposition under all laws relating to operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9E1B63480D024B4BA792EF58EE2FAD99"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Limited Conveyance Authority</header><text>The Secretary may authorize the conveyance of Federal land within the National Monument if—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H639E427B4AB041428360CB0C17680361"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the purpose for which the land is to be conveyed is consistent with the purposes specified in section 3;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8566060EC4B74DC9BDF51029EB651A90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the conveyance would benefit the National Monument and is in the public interest, as determined by the Secretary; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAA13C4EDFEED4809BCDBD0587AC1BD2E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the conveyance is made in accordance with applicable laws (including regulations).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H244B3C0145CC4E5EB65B1BD09582C3FD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Wildland fire operations</header><text>Nothing in this section prohibits the Secretary, in cooperation with other Federal, State, and local agencies, as appropriate, from conducting wildland fire operations in the National Monument consistent with the purposes specified in section 3.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H1E031AB929254AD29A44215F0CD21419"><enum>6.</enum><header>Water</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H1FF6980D84594A80B11540A2CD6A5265"><enum>(1)</enum><text>affects the use or allocation, in existence on the date of enactment of this Act, of any water, water right, or interest in water;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF06250D84614F029A90978D71A9CB1A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affects any vested absolute or decreed conditional water right in existence on the date of enactment of this Act, including any water right held by the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E0ECA1F7D7D478AB22C66F26C30B4EB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affects any interstate water compact in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC9501E661C84183817A80CCC8FF5706"><enum>(4)</enum><text>authorizes or imposes any new reserved Federal water rights; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBEEFDD73A2D446B7A97202EB75DF3D63"><enum>(5)</enum><text>relinquishes or reduces any water rights reserved or appropriated by the United States in the State on or before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H4EC62239029C47B0918CDDFD349D2931"><enum>7.</enum><header>Border security</header>
 <subsection id="H74A99FFE2C5548A6A10C48C4D9740EE0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this Act—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H2BA19597F1E743FCB0071DD5F2576428"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prevents the Secretary of Homeland Security from conducting—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H3492267CD0794FB394237C8FFC380825"><enum>(A)</enum><text>undertaking law enforcement and border security activities, in accordance with section 4(c) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(c)</external-xref>), including the ability to use motorized access within an area while in pursuit of a suspect; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE4AD4FAF86A54E27A15FCB8377001BB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any low-level flights over the area that may be necessary for law enforcement and border security purposes; or</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE61A18C323B2471DA9F3559EFCEF8884"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affects the 2006 Memorandum of Understanding among the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of the Interior, and the Department of Agriculture regarding cooperative national security and counterterrorism efforts on Federal lands along the borders of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4C6CEA47F18742CFAD0028C0C5E77B95"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Withdrawal and administration of certain area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section precludes the Secretary from allowing within the area described in subsection (a)(1)(A) the installation and maintenance of communication or surveillance infrastructure necessary for law enforcement or border security activities.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HD91B172339C54554AB69D70B457CDCEA"><enum>8.</enum><header>Department of Army responsibility and authority</header>
 <subsection id="H67FF4DE3B95C4422A0DF57C3636266A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Responsibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall affect—</text> <paragraph id="H4474E8DC40FB4869875DE2075459FE11"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the responsibility of the Department of the Army under applicable environmental laws, including the remediation of hazardous substances or munitions and explosives of concern within the National Monument boundaries;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7D59542FF774F1597C79EE1DC39B424"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the statutory authority of the Department of the Army to control public access or statutory responsibility to make other measures for environmental remediation, monitoring, security, safety, or emergency preparedness purposes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CF16A9909DA48A684A4763EF3B4AB2D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the activities of the Department of the Army on lands not included within the National Monument; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA805AD172E99499292E79688B5AB788C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the responsibility of the Department of the Army, in consultation with the Secretary (acting through the Bureau of Land Management), to continue to manage the lands and interests in lands under the Secretary’s jurisdiction within the National Monument boundaries until the Army transfers administrative jurisdiction of those lands and interests in lands to the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E3BFB66E8974C2ABDDE3283D6BA7C1C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Army and the Secretary may enter into a memorandum of understanding whereby the Secretary of the Army—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5D9895D7DF1C44D0A4EC26768CF47951"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may relinquish administrative jurisdiction over the Castner Range, Fort Bliss, Texas, to the Secretary of the Interior; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H13830D8965C54FC7BB891551A8DDB92D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may not relinquish or diminish the responsibility of the Secretary of the Army of responsibilities referred to in subsection (a).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H18E93A59935942299441423A8C181A78"><enum>9.</enum><header>Castner Range National Monument Advisory Council</header>
 <subsection id="HE9B9DF60E26D433780E2ED6E29E711E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not less than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish an advisory council to be known as the <quote>Castner Range National Monument Advisory Council</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H72FA45C932344739AEC8D53FABD0A703"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The advisory council shall advise the Secretary with respect to the preparation and implementation of the management plan for the National Monument.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE72DF19A24C4409599FD6E84290B7BEB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text>The advisory council shall be subject to—</text> <paragraph id="H226C4E9BE2114DD3BF2AB6152ADAADAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H14EDC94CC85541AEADF1CE010134304A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE89DB2869B59451E8F4882764FB50513"><enum>(3)</enum><text>all other applicable law.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H625EE595BDD24B34A06C364ECA59140E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The advisory council shall include 11 members, to be appointed by the Secretary, of whom, to the extent practicable—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE258B710225B4311B0D80B6782E7F6C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>one member shall be appointed after considering the recommendations of the El Paso County Commissioners Court;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4A1C67B5794844D8AB5340D8EA162CEA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>one member shall be appointed after considering the recommendations of the head of the Texas Parks and Wildlife Department;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25F5B0F136934F3FB9177CCD3714181A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>one member shall be appointed to represent Native American Tribes;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E2135AD26A0464BB79AB2FAFECA9C78"><enum>(4)</enum><text>one member shall be appointed to represent Fort Bliss; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7676B1931C19404394B1C4CF44DFF6E4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>seven members shall reside in, or within reasonable proximity to, the county specified in paragraphs (1) through (4) with backgrounds that reflect—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8203BC5FBA4549A9A5BE0515BAE3AF20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the purposes specified in section 3; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H784BE8C9479E47249224A44DA421B907"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the interest of persons affected by the planning and management of the National Monument, including persons representing the agricultural, private land-ownership, environmental, recreational, tourism, or other non-Federal land interests.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H60E62D9A34FB4FA39E69C38F4ABEAD48"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Representation</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the membership of the advisory council is fairly balanced in terms of the points of view represented and the functions to be performed by the advisory council.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H3A6E0AAC3A3843FCA4C3FB1D42ED3203"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Terms</header>
 <paragraph id="H5610CB3231DD4233BC6E0A27D0537E02"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Staggered terms</header><text>Members of the advisory council shall be appointed for terms of 3 years, except that, of the members first appointed, 5 of the members shall be appointed for a term of one year and 5 of the members shall be appointed for a term of 2 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H290F9928198A4EACA0C261AD01A256B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reappointment</header><text>A member may be reappointed to serve on the advisory council upon the expiration of the member’s current term.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H181FD79678C64629AAD92BAEEFF5BFAB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text>A vacancy on the advisory council shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF905D6B540CD43F2A11920B81BA01446"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A quorum shall be 7 members of the advisory council. The operations of the advisory council shall not be impaired by the fact that a member has not yet been appointed as long as a quorum has been attained.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB8DA49EE1F0A4EB0BB08B6B681F1D6B0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Chairperson and procedures</header><text>The advisory council shall elect a chairperson and establish such rules and procedures as it deems necessary or desirable.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBAEC61CE01CE4CB2BB5D0D6D1C2F4658"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Service without compensation</header><text>Members of the advisory council shall serve without pay.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HB47CC69612674F31BA5DEF23580EBFA2"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The advisory committee shall cease to exist—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0D81C5A271CD4C759B6A2A8779C18B10"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on the date that is 5 years after the date on which the management plan is officially adopted by the Secretary; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8C99EE37762456FB7E1199B775505E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on such later date as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6FA0CB24D5D247308F0976D81DFDEEBD"><enum>10.</enum><header>Land conveyance, Castner Range, Fort Bliss, Texas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2844 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 is repealed.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


