<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H237989AEFAA840EDB4B953451D7F0A23" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3898 RH: Impeding North Korea’s Access to Finance Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 265</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3898</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–361]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20171002">October 2, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001074">Mr. Hollingsworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>October 23, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001189">Mr. Messer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000598">Mr. Rothfus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000584">Mrs. Love</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000611">Mr. Poliquin</cosponsor></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>October 23, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported with amendments, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union,
			 and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on October 2, 2017</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to place conditions on certain accounts at United States
			 financial institutions with respect to North Korea, and for other
			 purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HFC85E2F53B4D48DFADAFCFC082B38BF1" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="H646D18BA9147413EA9CE365EAF2EBC35" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Impeding North Korea’s Access to Finance Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD5EAC74A9021466F809AF9773C2EF4D4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7A90EE0D8DE54E8DA4DD04F198A0754F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On June 1, 2016, the Department of the Treasury’s Financial Crimes Enforcement Network announced a Notice of Finding that the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea is a jurisdiction of primary money laundering concern due to its use of state-controlled financial institutions and front companies to support the proliferation and development of weapons of mass destruction (WMD) and ballistic missiles.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAAAB108F46E0447DAD6B66C1D2E3FA47"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Financial Action Task Force (FATF) has expressed serious concerns with the threat posed by North Korea’s proliferation and financing of WMD, and has called on FATF members to apply effective counter-measures to protect their financial sectors from North Korean money laundering, WMD proliferation financing, and the financing of terrorism.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5387644807FA40439EFF5C70789D180C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In its February 2017 report, the U.N. Panel of Experts concluded that—</text> <subparagraph id="H1570BC6380FB4A81BF1B4C95F9679533"><enum>(A)</enum><text>North Korea continued to access the international financial system in support of illicit activities despite sanctions imposed by U.N. Security Council Resolutions 2270 (2016) and 2321 (2016);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB98943BE2AD64B4B860DA2354D663A9D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>during the reporting period, no member state had reported taking actions to freeze North Korean assets; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4ED9710C474B4F53B126BB4FD078DDA9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>sanctions evasion by North Korea, combined with inadequate compliance by member states, had significantly negated the impact of U.N. Security Council resolutions.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3084F69928F94D168568CEF18B75B780"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In its September 2017 report, the U.N. Panel of Experts found that—</text> <subparagraph id="HD4F9332FB7684ECB9E3FA07C2B9F19CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>North Korea continued to violate financial sanctions by using agents acting abroad on the country’s behalf;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9FA914D0AF74F358208C78ABD3DDB53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>foreign financial institutions provided correspondent banking services to North Korean persons and front companies for illicit purposes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9261D249149543F7A41EDD9E85FAA80D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>foreign companies violated sanctions by maintaining links with North Korean financial institutions; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC24AAA75C3524EF29EEE2D7DE1C42AD6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>North Korea generated at least $270 million during the reporting period through the violation of sectoral sanctions.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3AD99C72CE04BF6A16D9E0B9D8688C4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>North Korean entities engage in significant financial transactions through foreign bank accounts that are maintained by non-North Korean nationals, thereby masking account users’ identity in order to access financial services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H039DEF109853416D9783A7D048972200"><enum>(6)</enum><text>North Korea’s sixth nuclear test on September 3, 2017, demonstrated an estimated explosive power more than 100 times greater than that generated by its first nuclear test in 2006.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2CD79E33D6C445A912658C3F9EF0E17"><enum>(7)</enum><text>North Korea has successfully tested submarine-launched and intercontinental ballistic missiles, and is rapidly progressing in its development of a nuclear-armed missile that is capable of reaching United States territory.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H2D4D92F7939A4648A35B76AB88C4C477"><enum>3.</enum><header>Conditions with respect to certain accounts and transactions at United States financial
			 institutions</header>
			<subsection id="H96AB058B3CD34587AA9D18598D50BA8B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Correspondent and payable-Through accounts held by foreign financial institutions</header>
 <paragraph id="HB8010D840C1F4B9B8EC08BB26ECDAFB8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 45 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe regulations to prohibit, or impose strict conditions on, the opening or maintaining in the United States of a correspondent account or a payable-through account by a foreign financial institution that the Secretary finds knowingly facilitates a significant transaction or transactions or provides significant financial services for a covered person.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H88C93270A3454B54B53E3AAA93AC5670"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H861795C41DE346C88A7ADF76C0E0309E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations prescribed under this subsection shall be subject to a civil penalty in an amount not to exceed the greater of—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H98FF5407F60944F5B0AEF333188C68AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$250,000; or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H9C7C5AD285444B24AC34D1856DFD634B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount that is twice the amount of the transaction that is the basis of the violation with respect to which the penalty is imposed.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCA14A8504DC44C9E96C826393DF9B2CC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Criminal penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who willfully commits, willfully attempts to commit, or willfully conspires to commit, or aids or abets in the commission of, a violation of regulations prescribed under this subsection shall, upon conviction, be fined not more than $1,000,000, or if a natural person, may be imprisoned for not more than 20 years, or both.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC1BF16FE3C1D4FD29A6142CD4DCBFE7F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restrictions on certain transactions by United States financial institutions</header>
 <paragraph id="HF591165E866342C28AA7707E802A1208"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe regulations to prohibit a United States financial institution, and any person owned or controlled by a United States financial institution, from knowingly engaging in a significant transaction or transactions with or benefitting any person that the Secretary finds to be a covered person.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBC2B6ED080E0452FAE1963C1B4299BC3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations prescribed under this subsection shall be subject to a civil penalty in an amount not to exceed the greater of—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HF2269C5812CE422DA4F032B769807321"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$250,000; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0045ACC44EE0439DB33C7BFEC2989D07"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount that is twice the amount of the transaction that is the basis of the violation with respect to which the penalty is imposed.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5FEE6F5F7C3F4ACF89B1522B6F4C7667"><enum>4.</enum><header>Opposition to assistance by the international financial institutions and the Export-Import Bank</header>
 <subsection id="H63487877A4E04397AFE8FD23F0B78741"><enum>(a)</enum><header>International financial institutions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bretton Woods Agreements Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/286">22 U.S.C. 286</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE23970860AEF4FC485876D0AE5AD7D94" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
					<section id="H519CF85A3D7843B0944915C98D49C9A4"><enum>73.</enum><header>Opposition to assistance for any government that fails to implement sanctions on North Korea</header>
 <subsection id="HD4D62C27FEEB4EE9B37A5BBF984AA968"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Director at the international financial institutions (as defined under section 1701(c) of the International Financial Institutions Act) to use the voice and vote of the United States to oppose the provision of financial assistance to a foreign government, other than assistance to support basic human needs, if the President determines that, in the year preceding consideration of approval of such assistance, the government has knowingly failed to prevent the provision of financial services to, or freeze the funds, financial assets, and economic resources of, a person described under subparagraphs (A) through (E) of section 7(2) of the Impeding North Korea’s Access to Finance Act of 2017.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB7A30AB92ECB4AD6A461DBE34C17907F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may waive subsection (a) for up to 180 days at a time with respect to a foreign government if the President reports to Congress that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2DE2AC06BD604A2DB801F071B612AE90"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the foreign government’s failure described under (a) is due exclusively to a lack of foreign government capacity;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H19C03582777948D694B67E52FA10F2BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the foreign government is taking effective steps to prevent recurrence of such failure; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC40A26F711254179BB26EC8F95BE84EF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such waiver is vital to the national security interests of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0BC9AF9BD96247B18887B87E50255AB0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Export-Import Bank</header><text>Section 2(b) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/635">12 U.S.C. 635(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E129720A6194B3A8EFAD3AF14C8E254" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H35E0CFC1B98445C4965F24337B3144EA"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Prohibition on support involving persons connected with North Korea</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bank may not guarantee, insure, or extend credit, or participate in the extension of credit in connection with the export of a good or service to a covered person (as defined under section 7 of the Impeding North Korea’s Access to Finance Act of 2017).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H9101ADE2E02E4D78B3BF2D1CA1C66D4C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Treasury reports on compliance, penalties, and technical assistance</header>
			<subsection id="H3F1961063B724A2A9CF8FA7BF2BF8354"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Quarterly report</header>
 <paragraph id="HEC56E11EC0544623B6D5C022CEBFA83A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days following the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 90 days thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate that includes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBEC26643E5734D88AB747F9629DE1DB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of financial institutions that, in the period since the preceding report, knowingly facilitated a significant transaction or transactions or provided significant financial services for a covered person, or failed to apply appropriate due diligence to prevent such activities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H187051F2B3E24F739FC48F633073FC05"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a list of any penalties imposed under section 3 in the period since the preceding report; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A548094133645FCB632E5D1FFC9245A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of efforts by the Department of the Treasury in the period since the preceding report, through consultations, technical assistance, or other appropriate activities, to strengthen the capacity of financial institutions and foreign governments to prevent the provision of financial services benefitting any covered person.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2785177932E34D28B05E8EBB888F2BF9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form of report; public availability</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9EAF6C57FC264ED89448895E6CC51DE8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61984169D4D549DE80AFD88BED77A1AC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The unclassified portion of such report shall be made available to the public and posted on the website of the Department of the Treasury.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H84B11283A14541F591069EBA5BCD5326"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Testimony required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon request of the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives or the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, the Under Secretary of the Treasury for Terrorism and Financial Intelligence shall testify to explain the effects of this Act, and the amendments made by this Act, on North Korea’s access to finance.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2444D620CC424FCBAD647A4630AA7FAB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>International Monetary Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title XVI of the International Financial Institutions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/262p">22 U.S.C. 262p</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7EB36183223043659755D968FF4B86C5" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
					<section id="HB50BED1BCEAF411EB8E66CE3ACE4DB4A"><enum>1629.</enum><header>Support for capacity of the International Monetary Fund to prevent money laundering and financing
 of terrorism</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Director at the International Monetary Fund to support the use of the administrative budget of the Fund for technical assistance that strengthens the capacity of Fund members to prevent money laundering and the financing of terrorism.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H860CD1871765407EB85CDFC05F72CA80"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National Advisory Council report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairman of the National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Policies shall include in the report required by section 1701 of the International Financial Institutions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/262r">22 U.S.C. 262r</external-xref>) for the fiscal year following the date of the enactment of this Act a description of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC51DAA9E5FB449198340EBD7D727A794"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the activities of the International Monetary Fund in the most recently completed fiscal year to provide technical assistance that strengthens the capacity of Fund members to prevent money laundering and the financing of terrorism, and the effectiveness of the assistance; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33D798D512DD4EE1B0459FDC95570B54"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the efficacy of efforts by the United States to support such technical assistance through the use of the Fund’s administrative budget.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFCC0920F87BE4810BEDD8B178EE46935"><enum>6.</enum><header>Suspension and termination of prohibitions and penalties</header>
 <subsection id="H9AAF0638A1CA4320A45A28F88344E233"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Suspension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may suspend, on a case-by-case basis, the application of any provision of this Act, or provision in an amendment made by this Act, for a period of not more than 180 days at a time if the President certifies to Congress that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H125B856AC4274DFA9BF78437C1E338D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Government of North Korea has—</text> <subparagraph id="H70FBBED960DC40DE981C88FD69D85C2A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>committed to the verifiable suspension of North Korea’s proliferation and testing of WMD, including systems designed in whole or in part for the delivery of such weapons; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91FDABBC4E4E46FA95D20087931BDAC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has agreed to multilateral talks including the Government of the United States, with the goal of permanently and verifiably limiting North Korea’s WMD and ballistic missile programs; or</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC5F8E02A45E42AE853D6B19A9E2C92A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such suspension is vital to the national security interests of the United States, with an explanation of the reasons therefor.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H201C3113FAD345F0B6EC608BCFE355A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination</header>
 <paragraph id="HDD84AA6577FF49FFB746C58A9B245246"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On the date that is 30 days after the date on which the President makes the certification described under paragraph (2)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD69B2F289738444FA69DEC3CE8D634B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 3, subsections (a) and (b) of section 5, and section 6(a) of this Act shall cease to have any force or effect;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5842A566F0E54168829166977A5DFD63"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 73 of the Bretton Woods Agreements Act, as added by section 4(a), shall be repealed; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86FFFE93813144C5B59A9A301729183F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 2(b)(14) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945, as added by section 4(b), shall be repealed.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7669DD0EAB847E8841A170248ACAF2F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The certification described under this paragraph is a certification by the President to the Congress that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H30A5A4D8D6FC487881B5429F2F7F7CC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Government of North Korea—</text> <clause id="HFA8F8BA41DD74577898DE91B7E9AE0C1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has ceased to pose a significant threat to national security, with an explanation of the reasons therefor; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9DF0A77D245F4F2CB199ED9928506BDE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is committed to, and is taking effective steps to achieving, the goal of permanently and verifiably limiting North Korea’s WMD and ballistic missile programs; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H513F58B5E72C46829099119A41672785"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such termination is vital to the national security interests of the United States, with an explanation of the reasons therefor.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H758EFC102528468698EC3138B7D9FCB0"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HE17E97A7DA544E00BCDD007CC7A9E5A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Terms related to North Korea</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>applicable Executive order</quote>, <quote>Government of North Korea</quote>, <quote>North Korea</quote>, <quote>North Korean person</quote>, and <quote>significant activities undermining cybersecurity</quote> have the meanings given those terms, respectively, in section 3 of the North Korea Sanctions and Policy Enhancement Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9202">22 U.S.C. 9202</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CE31D96C7854DEEA8D61552AA6317AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered person</header><text>The term <quote>covered person</quote> means the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H94EF65548B484866A580DD9BD52E8D74"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any designated person under an applicable Executive order.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B46630F86E6463EBC9328A2EF46E692"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any North Korean person that facilitates the transfer of bulk cash or covered goods (as defined under section 1027.100 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H437618DE0F1649BA9D41EF9E844080BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any North Korean financial institution.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EBEEE55B3C64C5BA8BC288B0C2E3B0E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any North Korean person employed outside of North Korea, except that the Secretary of the Treasury may waive the application of this subparagraph for a North Korean person that is not otherwise a covered person and—</text>
 <clause id="H8CFDFF7C5D914E5789BF2C8B64EE31A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has been granted asylum or refugee status by the country of employment; or</text> </clause><clause id="H06A2B0A5BF88437B8142C8CF9B4C789E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is employed as essential diplomatic personnel for the Government of North Korea.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CA70A8D977E4C2982E81C19F23BBE4D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any person acting on behalf of, or at the direction of, a person described under subparagraphs (A) through (D).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC77170C7801341C8AE8CE3A146294FFD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any person that knowingly employs a person described under subparagraph (D).</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC779A48F2D5E4DDCBBCBE979FC510FE7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any person that facilitates the import of goods, services, technology, or natural resources, including energy imports and minerals, or their derivatives, from North Korea.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C9DBBC93EE54D32AFFBF9B4495518AD"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person that facilitates the export of goods, services, technology, or natural resources, including energy exports and minerals, or their derivatives, to North Korea, except for food, medicine, or medical supplies required for civilian humanitarian needs.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73F9023E693F4C4DA55FA60DB7D929D9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person that invests in, or participates in a joint venture with, an entity in which the Government of North Korea participates or an entity that is created or organized under North Korean law.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2ED57118358342FDA70DA4387948A4F7"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Any person that provides financial services, including through a subsidiary or joint venture, in North Korea.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34B8EB11D05A4D3D85ECB79FF95E842D"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Any person that insures, registers, facilitates the registration of, or maintains insurance or a registration for, a vessel owned, controlled, commanded, or operated by a North Korean person.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E506EE9C26340A79129B036AFC16D17"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person providing specialized teaching, training, or information or providing material or technological support to a North Korean person that—</text>
 <clause id="H4CC873435D4843548ACD31856F409D2F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may contribute to North Korea’s development and proliferation of WMD, including systems designed in whole or in part for the delivery of such weapons; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3381C79CE0D14718BD146529D4D9FB17"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may contribute to significant activities undermining cybersecurity.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC8D836394024A9A8142F62217D96A11"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Financial institution definitions</header> <subparagraph id="H1682FECAE2374D38B1F7C7880EB87FE0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Financial institution</header><text>The term <quote>financial institution</quote> means a United States financial institution or a foreign financial institution.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F1E3231421940CDA8C2C296156B1F5D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Foreign financial institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>foreign financial institution</quote> has the meaning given that term under section 1010.605 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAD109CB0EE540B98CD6915DBFF1B33D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>North Korean financial institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>North Korean financial institution</quote> includes—</text>
 <clause id="HC02672B0754D4D3FA685C4BCFA2FDFBE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any North Korean financial institution, as defined in section 3 of the North Korea Sanctions and Policy Enhancement Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9202">22 U.S.C. 9202</external-xref>);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8E6CB38ADF424CDC98F215E51D2EE233"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any financial agency, as defined in section 5312 of title 31, United States Code, that is owned or controlled by the Government of North Korea;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFC40FF7B0B5A4397828967EFBAE5DE4B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any money transmitting business, as defined in section 5330(d) of title 31, United States Code, that is owned or controlled by the Government of North Korea;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7F4B0B7CA53F41C2AA0038D39E32903E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any financial institution that is a joint venture between any person and the Government of North Korea; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4B3C2BF3B9004E038D4BBD95ADC4F991"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any joint venture involving a North Korean financial institution.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3904B95F3B4A40E1BAAA38ACFE0006FA"><enum>(D)</enum><header>United States financial institution</header><text>The term <quote>United States financial institution</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>U.S. financial institution</quote> under section 510.310 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F54854D4035448EB4341EBFFD2D3255"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>knowingly</quote> with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body><official-title-amendment>Amend the title so as to read: <quote>A bill to impose secondary sanctions with respect to North Korea, strengthen international efforts
			 to improve sanctions enforcement, and for other purposes.</quote>.</official-title-amendment>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>October 23, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported with amendments, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union,
			 and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


