<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB0F561E2F03E47DCB2B0FB53B11A1AAC" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2067 IH: Cents and Sensibility Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2067</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001187">Mr. Stivers</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000462">Mr. Tiberi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 31, United States Code, to save the American taxpayers money by immediately altering
			 the metallic composition of the one-cent, five-cent, dime, and quarter
			 dollar coins, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF3E31563D0514BF589021D79AD2FC0AC" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9226CEA94AF04EA1B29C8E71FB3F2024" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cents and Sensibility Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE84B001351A0413AA31851257630F6DB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Composition of circulating coins</header> <subsection id="H26FB856F41FE48C68859623E5561FCF1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Steel coins required</header><text>Section 5112 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H3C55FB87207546C28E11C9E12403BA5B" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H7549545A4E344E4F8AA7EE213D4A2FFE"><enum>(w)</enum><header>Composition of circulating coins</header>
 <paragraph id="H017225D82B894C2C9D340A1DDFA40171"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the one-cent, five-cent, dime, and quarter dollar coins produced for circulation and issue shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4A141755E40C4EFC80438E79AE8CB8CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be produced primarily of steel; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC13A283508974B01B9D7AD61E1E1EDB5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>meet such other specifications as the Secretary may determine to be appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFD1D79517F447DDA4F00124AD0E8C2D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The one-cent, five-cent, dime, and quarter dollar coins produced for circulation and issue shall be treated in such a manner that the appearance of the coins, both when new and after they have been in circulation, is similar to the one-cent, five-cent, dime, and quarter dollar coins, respectively, produced before the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text>
						</paragraph><paragraph id="H58BD8FF76B85457CBEBE6BDB6AFF95B4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Buy American steel requirement</header>
 <subparagraph id="H72BB309DACF04637BDDA88FA9E15F49B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall, in minting one-cent, five-cent, dime, and quarter dollar coins produced for circulation and issue, only use steel produced in the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D21038D70664929AFE5551A09299012"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply if the Secretary finds, and publishes in the Federal Register the basis of such finding, that—</text>
 <clause id="H0DB4D6F9F49E4B29BDA21C4413DAB385"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applying subparagraph (A) would be inconsistent with the public interest; or</text> </clause><clause id="HF30316C7DB1F47E99F050F714B87DD7F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an adequate supply of an appropriate grade of steel is not produced in the United States in sufficient and reasonably available quantities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H129098B048684DABB5ADDAF1DB8D13C9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conversion to new coin specifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In setting specifications under section 5112(w) of title 31, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury shall not set specifications that would—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1466DBEC7FB04AF1938B26DF7DBC1208"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require more than 1 change to coin-accepting and coin-handling equipment to accommodate all coins produced pursuant to such subsection;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0AEBAB66DDA8474CB1905A26E14314AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>facilitate or allow the use of a coin with a lesser value produced by another country, or the use of any token or other easily or regularly produced metal device of minimal value, in the place of a circulating coin produced by the Secretary; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD1FE211CBB5C4005BE2EFF3D6698FA1D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require non-trivial changes to coin-accepting or coin handling equipment to easily accommodate continued co-circulation of both coins produced with the new specifications under such subsection and coins produced on or before the date that is the end of the 90-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A538D0A22FE4942902953E2B998D3BE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="HEBFDCB34991B4FDABD958DC050C9EFE4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to all one-cent, five-cent, dime, and quarter dollar coins produced for circulation and issued after the end of the 90-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8035B9B4B64456795FD0B9DF1E9E305"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury may produce numismatic versions of the one-cent, five-cent, dime, and quarter dollar coins either in the composition specified in section 5112(w) of title 31, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), or in forms and materials similar to those the Secretary produced before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB2B4BB4759204691B4E9F17EE264A01D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5112 of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HFAACD15B51CA404D9ADFCCAC432EB349"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking the first, second, third, fourth, sixth, seventh, eighth, and tenth sentences; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCCC1C4337E1749D8BB5A04B6DA6894A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subsection (c) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H27F89E78F129438B838F937939F09EA7" style="USC"> <subsection id="HE51E1310997E44E89372C30857F8CB71"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Weight of the one-Cent coin</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may prescribe the weight of the one-cent coin that the Secretary determines is necessary to ensure an adequate supply of one-cent coins to meet the needs of the United States.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


