<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H6A3A65B2DDA44D789E5621E3BE77E6DE" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2770 IH: Health Care Options for All Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2770</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170602">June 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To allow individuals living in areas without qualified health plans offered through an Exchange to
			 have similar access to health insurance coverage as Members of Congress
			 and congressional staff.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H71AA8569A167469A9FC47BC27E03FCCA" style="OLC">
 <section id="H35005186724A45CA817389531FF3ABF7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Care Options for All Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H34318C1D6D784B7DADA8B5DE202F1B71"><enum>2.</enum><header>Access to coverage for individuals in areas without any available Exchange plans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part 2 of subtitle D of title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18031">42 U.S.C. 18031</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H632B969A8BBA4893B573AEC70883D669" style="OLC">
				<section id="HC4318EEFFF874665926167874A5CCA6E"><enum>1314.</enum><header>Access to coverage for individuals in areas without any available Exchange plans</header>
					<subsection id="HCC6C4E86677541BB8413FEC94FBB13DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="H0DFC601B0FE84A4EBB18A1AD3119F0FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coverage through DC SHOP Exchange</header><text>Not later than 3 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, shall establish a mechanism to ensure that, for any plan year beginning on or after the date described in subsection (c), any individual described in paragraph (2) may enroll in health insurance coverage in the small group market through the Exchange operating in the District of Columbia, including the health insurance coverage that is available to Members of Congress and congressional staff (as defined in section 1312(d)(3)(D)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1475B8547719494CA848F1228642F957"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individual described</header><text>An individual described in this paragraph is any individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="HAB3C3F0796474F7D869CAD48DA643EED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is eligible to purchase health insurance coverage through the Exchange operating in the State of residence of the individual; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FFB59422BB14612B7269062AEF856DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>resides in a rating area or county in which the Secretary certifies that no qualified health plan is offered through an Exchange established under this title.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9EF4B442E2DF410F9EC0C87FB2E69B22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Premium assistance tax credits and cost-Sharing</header><text>Any individual described in subsection (a)(2) who enrolls in health insurance coverage through the Exchange operating in the District of Columbia pursuant to subsection (a)(1) shall be eligible for any premium tax credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, or reduced cost-sharing under section 1402, that the individual would otherwise be eligible for if enrolling in health insurance coverage in the individual market through the Exchange operating in the State of the individual.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA78A1B75EDA1453799680A82D6616418"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Date described</header><text>The date described in this subsection is the date on which the Secretary establishes the mechanism under subsection (a)(1).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


