<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H855590C4FE0F4998B670B379D46BAEDB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3103 IH: To direct the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security to jointly conduct a study and submit a report on deported veterans.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3103</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170628">June 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Guti&#233;rrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000132">Mr. Vela</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security to jointly conduct a study and submit a report on deported veterans.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF45A3063158F4088B39BB38E6D222AE1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7A863775D44B4E3FADB3A08EA4A9F711" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Study and report on deported veterans</header> 
<subsection id="HFB73A466B9584BF8A2C460E50253C148"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">By not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall jointly carry out a study on aliens—</text> <paragraph id="H769341239B204506894FE13243E393CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>who are or were veterans; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C6208175ABE419CA4EBE60D36B383E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>who were removed from the United States during the period beginning on January 1, 1990, and ending on January 1, 2017.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H64174D695BFD425887718A869C687ED9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the completion of the study required under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall jointly submit to the Committees on Armed Services and the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on the study. Such report shall include each of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H141AB8F6604E4C37ADE9B918710531A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of aliens removed by Immigration and Customs Enforcement during the period covered by the report who served on active duty in the United States Armed Forces or in a reserve component of the United States Armed Forces for a period of more than 180 days.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D181D68433545B98D9316C65FA64C67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The country of origin for each alien described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H243C2194D09C46D89E7217C7E16B9289"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of aliens described in paragraph (1) who were discharged or released from service in the Armed Forces under honorable conditions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H145E165B4160450981D7D7709F7E36C3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The grounds for removal under section 237(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1227">8 U.S.C. 1227</external-xref>) or section 212(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</external-xref>), as applicable, for each alien described in paragraph (1) during the period covered by the report.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H79E5F1EFF6074AC9A407E413BC524BA6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>For each removed alien described in paragraph (1), whether the alien appealed the removal order.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC41CC01604364491A605B4DF8897404A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>For each such removed alien, the length of time the alien served as a member of the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA072FF5949804F26968893D73796C6AC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The number of such removed aliens who were deployed overseas as members of the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFD6BE17402042DB8716511FA8EA8967"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The number of such removed aliens who served on active duty in a combat theater of operations as members of the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB351387E4328426082F830A951EB25DF"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The number of such removed aliens who were awarded service medals on the basis of service in the Armed Forces.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill> 

