<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1CAA8FB6E8A645A29DCB6468EEE88492" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4348 IH: Keeping Russian Entrapments Minimal and Limiting Intelligence Networks Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4348</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171109">November 9, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of National Intelligence to produce a National Intelligence Estimate on
			 Russian political intentions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2EC4D5C9EC344969B20CDAB4D2E8C7DB" style="OLC">
 <section id="H20AB0A17976C451498685961BE251E36" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Keeping Russian Entrapments Minimal and Limiting Intelligence Networks Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>KREMLIN Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HEE87EFDC9FE640D4883014D969FD2B22"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD38B7ABD90EB401182D82E4729FB9ACA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Russia continues to engage in information warfare and political interference in the West, including by undermining democratic systems and exploiting economic and ethnic tensions within member countries of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDEA306B7EC5B4C4C861379000FCB9B86"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Such activities constitute a threat to the United States and to its allies.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H26AF38B8E2BC40E6920A772809E3C742"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The intelligence community of the United States, while aware of such activities, does not have a complete understanding of the political intentions underlying these activities, which is critical to effectively calibrate a United States response to Russian aggression and prevent escalation.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HD654BA65F0EA4C72A55308374E705E25"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HF20A55C79222475F863F423DA157106B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/44">Public Law 115–44</external-xref>) was an appropriate response to Russia’s—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H86FFD1BD1AD14331B833401D2864567A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meddling in the 2016 United States presidential election;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H386C032D1842465790ED83DF9933F242"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">continued aggression in the Ukraine and the Crimea region; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15458F5855564C46AC266EAC631B9EDC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support for the Assad regime in Syria;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F9FF4C8ABA1487A862E296E6251878E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States should sustain its newly deployed enhanced forward presence in Poland, Lithuania, and Estonia and urge Canada, the United Kingdom, and Germany to quickly deploy and sustain parallel commitments in those countries;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD2B23459EFB141808E2BDFEF1B74F6FF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States has defensive intentions in pursuing such sanctions and such enhanced military posture in Europe, and does not seek to threaten Russian territory; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H07125FA73ACF4C65AF6A729B2FAD0244"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States does not seek to be an enemy of the Russian people and propaganda directed against the United States by President Vladimir Putin misrepresents the intentions of the United States for the purposes of preserving his power.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HC3DF9640664D4B3AAD792B7CF9D15406"><enum>4.</enum><header>Requirement for National Intelligence Estimate</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall produce a National Intelligence Estimate on the political intentions of Russia, including with respect to each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HEF73AF13370C4A7D9249967410B0F3B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Russian leadership intentions in pursuing military scenarios against members of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, including conduct of an exercise on the border with Moldova of more than 100,000 Russian forces in August 2017.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA054A5CB801047198CCA6B61658BAE86"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Russian leadership reactions to the European Reassurance Initiative.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H867D5B9664A34D6ABFADD55957198229"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Areas of possible joint cooperation with Russia.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


