<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0D1A1D6D3EBB4F17AAF10971B281C931" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2259 IH: Sam Farr Peace Corps Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2259</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170501">May 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Peace Corps Act to expand services and benefits for volunteers, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H367EF0D6AB0544F98BA1E000C7EBFE86" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD5A50F2A62E84C218F5B452140928B47" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sam Farr Peace Corps Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H468D0E38F0E3499A857C1BA65DF36E6C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Provisions for current and former volunteers of the peace corps</header> <subsection id="H08782F8A48DA4339A88DDCB49B46E2AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enhanced compensation benefits</header> <paragraph id="HFBE6756A829B4779BB2FD5F6F018DB83"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 8142 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB6D99322264144C3A8219668F4722A30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <clause id="H2873186AF6E84EF2A20E6FAEA829C17B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>GS–7</quote> and inserting <quote>GS–11</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2302B0D2362F49F9B804192A0576FDA2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2) and redesignating paragraphs (3) and (4) as paragraphs (2) and (3), respectively; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6725AE4C91D485481CFEE3186C39BC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7470533D81B47178EA6C5D262096FAA" style="USC"> <subsection id="HA8FC8B606C454C5BA5F4251B89E89FB3"><enum>(d)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9AAB35807A4346298D361363AF67775B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Director of the Peace Corps shall provide the initial furnishing of medical and other benefits under section 8103(b) of this title to any former volunteer for the 180-day period beginning on the date of termination of the service of such volunteer, to the extent that the Director determines that such benefits are given with respect to an injury that is probably compensable under this section (as such term is defined for purposes of section 8103(b)). The provision of such benefits may be authorized directly or by the certification of vouchers, in accordance with section 8103(b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H04F0D562566B4A9A8794CB361794549E" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A volunteer may not be provided medical or other benefits pursuant to paragraph (1) unless the injury with respect to which such benefits would be provided was proximately caused by the employment of such volunteer under subsection (c)(2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA857731254DD466F931E4FA4F1E9C873" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the 180-day limitation period under paragraph (1), a volunteer may receive medical or other benefits provided pursuant to such paragraph with respect to an injury until the date on which the Secretary of Labor makes a final determination with respect to compensation for such injury under this section, if the volunteer applied for such compensation before the last day of such limitation period.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7F491CDD6E44EB2A03B7FB21DA6213B" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall consult with health experts outside the Peace Corps, including experts licensed in the field of mental health, in order to provide the best standard of care.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB67F9B5A54184F6484CF6B6E06F71278" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of section 8116(c) of this title regarding liability shall apply with respect to benefits provided to a former volunteer under this section in the same manner and to the same extent as such provisions apply with respect to benefits provided to an employee of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H32DD5FC9781A406093E15CF30DBD291D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendments made by <internal-xref idref="HB6D99322264144C3A8219668F4722A30" legis-path="2.(a)(1)(A)">paragraph (1)(A)</internal-xref> shall apply with respect to any compensation paid pursuant to section 8142 of title 5, United States Code, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8123958F647644ACAE5BDB72A5D04B51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Health care for volunteers; criminal liability for acts against volunteers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5 of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2504">22 U.S.C. 2504</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HEBD7E5076EA04BE3A0155F40D2E12474"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (e), by striking <quote>receive such immunization and dental care preparatory to their service</quote> and inserting <quote>receive, preparatory to their service, such immunization and dental care, and (in accordance with subsection (o)) such trial prescriptions</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0DCDEB973C734858973A64DB936647C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (h), by striking <quote>section, and</quote> and inserting <quote>section), and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B93AE0EBB414B369DAFACB6E6085FC6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8BE5EAB3259E4E868FE8A77C433E194E" style="traditional">
 <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H05B89544ABC847FAA549F95B9E004C72"><enum>(o)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Peace Corps may only prescribe mefloquine to a volunteer, including as a trial prescription to a volunteer who chooses to use such medication before departing the United States to a post, on an individual basis and in accordance with relevant recommendations or guidelines issued by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention or the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, after counseling such volunteer about the benefits, risks, and side effects of each available medication for the prophylaxis of malaria. The Director shall monitor the volunteer during the course of such prescription for the development of any side effects (or determine that the volunteer has been so monitored), evaluate the volunteer at the completion of such course for evidence of neuropsychiatric symptoms (or determine that the volunteer has been so evaluated), and report to the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the Commissioner of Food and Drugs any such side effects or symptoms. A volunteer may only switch to the use of mefloquine from another drug for the prophylaxis of malaria while serving at a post if another medication for the prophylaxis of malaria is simultaneously provided to such volunteer in a manner that ensures continuous protection against malaria.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H88134E51FC6A40FEB14DAEC3E88115D4"><enum>(p)</enum><text>It is the policy of the United States to recognize the importance of Peace Corps volunteers and the core function that such volunteers play within the agency. The President should therefore prioritize the provision of health care services and necessary safety and security support for all volunteers.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H2ED0C4AAC05E4F90A7865E236E913D3D"><enum>(q)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H03E0D81EEB9B417CBB6659F7225F12F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever engages in conduct outside the United States against a volunteer that would constitute an offense under any section listed in paragraph (2) if the conduct had been engaged in within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States (as defined in section 7 of title 18, United States Code) shall be punished as provided for that offense.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H02C693A5EAD14C5E9CD7E2DF5B088DBD" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The sections listed in this paragraph are sections 113, 1111, 1112, 1113, 1117 (to the extent that such section applies to section 1111), 1201, 2241, 2242, 2244, and 2261A of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3C306ECA76E64232A9C042D5112C3E0E" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, paragraph (9)(B) (regarding residences in foreign countries) of section 7 of title 18, United States Code, shall include the residences used by volunteers in foreign countries and the land appurtenant or ancillary thereto, irrespective of ownership.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H03555CA5EEAE462FB0DEE57CC0C59301"><enum>3.</enum><header>Provisions regarding employees of the peace corps</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7 of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2506">22 U.S.C. 2506</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H88F4C670938C4E0A833ABDE8353541A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAC118E4112E14AF990B9AAA7DADB46BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by inserting <quote>or paragraph (8)</quote> after <quote>paragraph (6)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EA7C32608AA4D04971E9E5A295D984D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA615A03AF8A42DAAECC151F59862C66" style="traditional">
						<paragraph id="H0A737CF32A604BAA9CE390E454FE8903" indent="up1"><enum>(8)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H304D69E470AA4E64BFC8897F7A8E58CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Peace Corps may designate a position as a <quote>critical management position</quote> or a <quote>critical management support position</quote> if the position requires specialized technical or professional skills and knowledge of Peace Corps operations, such as positions that involve volunteer health services, financial management, information technology, procurement, personnel, legal services, or safety or security.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9281C540944245D39F594C0D4045D895" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any limitation set forth in paragraph (2) and subject to subparagraph (C), an appointment or assignment to a critical management position or a critical management support position designated under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph and any extension of such appointment or assignment shall be for a term of not more than five years.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BFD6CFF3FFA4A0EAD8D6148F085F9F9" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Director shall ensure that any decision regarding an appointment, assignment, or extension of such appointment or assignment to a critical management position or a critical management support position shall be consistent with Peace Corps policies and based on operational and programmatic factors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5188663BA8848FAA20A7717FA456BB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H14F8BA1D8D234ABAA77AB0E709D0C334" style="traditional"> <subsection id="HA3EE4A3384EE4FE7AD51EC64F9C38857"><enum>(d)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAAB4FAA8930B43C5997DB77F2430ABE0"><enum>(1)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF2C3DC0ED18449D484E469068B88DEE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall ensure that each overseas post has the services of a medical office that is consistent in size and scope with the needs of the Peace Corps at such post, including, if necessary, by detailing to any such post the licensed medical staff of other United States departments, agencies, or establishments.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28772A4B6A754E6CBD1486DF3DEC9D85" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual may be hired as a Peace Corps Medical Officer after consideration of the following criteria:</text>
 <clause id="HA53F2F3EA9B94332BD541751B03F1DF2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Medical training, experience, accreditations, and other qualifications.</text> </clause><clause id="H97B5934359E44F4381433AED8D587181"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Administrative capabilities.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCAB0C0AC07EF4DFB93A9AA4487341E1D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Understanding of the local language and culture.</text> </clause><clause id="H8524A0BEDE574CBC957BEA1917ABB10F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Ability to work in the English language.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEC461348D7F945AA9CCACE9F13E80FD2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Interpersonal skills.</text> </clause><clause id="H02E77C27400C40929B9840D2F44471CC"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Record of performance.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFAC875E82A25460EA349584C39C45162"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Any other factors the Director of the Peace Corps determines appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H24E6DE06CF444143A3C10E59206ABD7B" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Director of the Peace Corps shall ensure that each Peace Corps Medical Officer serving in a malaria-endemic country receives training in the recognition of the side effects caused by the use of mefloquine and the data supporting the patient information handouts required by the Food and Drug Administration regarding mefloquine, including the potential capacity of the drug to cause permanent neuropsychiatric effects.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HBA59AFFA42524341A666B063BA34D0E1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Monitoring training records</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8 of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2507">22 U.S.C. 2507</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF5021F5C0ED24BAEB483A20B604AD9EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following new sentences: <quote>As a part of such training, the President, in coordination with the Inspector General of the Peace Corps, shall provide each volunteer with information regarding the mandate of the Inspector General and the availability (including contact information) of the Inspector General as a resource for volunteers. The President shall provide such information at least once during training that occurs prior to enrollment and at least once during each significant instance of training after enrollment.</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDCC22760F8B74B899D5EF49B15CFD3D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A3D3693F5154ED68E815223B3CEA525" style="traditional"> <subsection id="HE6B9007C50064D05A86A59D0D889AD73"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall implement procedures to maintain a written record verifying the attendance of each individual completing training provided to meet each requirement in this section and sections 8A, 8B, 8F, and 8G(b).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H102CBC765A8B45DC8402321CD3E6532D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Additional disclosures to applicants for enrollment as volunteers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8A of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2507a">22 U.S.C. 2507a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB3EFD85DEE044525BD0850D5C43C6B36"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subsection (d) to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HFA32D6344FE045E484F45C106537BA5D">
 <subsection id="HA5B232320E644EAF83C2A9EBA94BA928"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Information regarding crimes and risks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each applicant for enrollment as a volunteer shall be provided, with respect to the country in which the applicant has been invited to serve, with information regarding crimes against and risks to volunteers, including an overview of past crimes against volunteers in such country, the current early termination rate of volunteers serving in such country, any health risks prevalent in such country, and the level of satisfaction reported by volunteers serving in such country. Upon receiving such information, the applicant shall have the option to timely decline the invitation without retaliation and with priority to be invited to serve in a different country.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA179B53BA2704A849A1CFAAD9CE9FC03"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (f)(2)(B), in clause (iii), by striking <quote>victim advocates</quote> and inserting <quote>Victim’s Advocates,</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H05A7C2E4CACA4342AAF9521AA8470F9D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reporting requirements with respect to victims of sexual assault</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (3) of section 8B(a) of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2507b">22 U.S.C. 2507b(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF429C96CFACA475C81968E0975EDE2B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>SARLs</quote> and inserting <quote>any employee of the Peace Corps</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBFE074133096438B84F43A2BE5212B9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Victim Advocate</quote> and inserting <quote>Victim’s Advocate</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H15946B4055364ED29B05740B471E86D5"><enum>7.</enum><header>Office of victim advocacy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8C of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2507c">22 U.S.C. 2507c</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H502AC968DFB645F7A2B74E1E35CC8E58"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>victim advocate</quote> in each place it appears and inserting <quote>Victim’s Advocate</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H612C5C27B8024544AF7AA7ECB170193E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>victim advocates</quote> in each place it appears and inserting <quote>Victim’s Advocates</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4319B190DBFA41ECABABFA6B63C63F8F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsection (e).</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HFEBA3B594048466E8C72DEF8730E292B"><enum>8.</enum><header>Reform and extension of the sexual assault advisory council</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8D of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2507d">22 U.S.C. 2507d</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H70E95A2CA7A74A03B16CE9900C0B2E7A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H60326ACB47314455A5BFF5E6CAFEBFE5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>not less than 8 individuals</quote> and inserting <quote>not fewer than 8 and not more than 14 individuals</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE12491B52BF54EE5A87678094B58EDE3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after the first sentence the following new sentence: <quote>At least one member shall also be licensed in the field of mental health.</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43CA8D7CDD8A4DB4A0DC1869243CF0F0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>There shall be no limit to the number of terms an individual may serve as a member of the Council.</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9914F5878AB44DE8A6C154B215B70F3A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0D8E657512434088848FE9D23E1F49E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and the implementation of such policy</quote> after <quote>section 8B</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0709A8C1D75B445D90DD1E3FDAAFAFDE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>To carry out the functions in this subsection, the Council shall conduct case reviews and shall have access, including through interviews or visits, to volunteers and staff in the field, to volunteer surveys under section 8E, to all data collected from restricted reporting, and to any other information necessary to conduct case reviews, except that the Council may not have access to any personally identifying information associated with such surveys or data.</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E87585F0E534451AAD122A92C76257E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by striking <quote>2018</quote> and inserting <quote>2023</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4030407EED65463898EC8192C6B04D0D"><enum>9.</enum><header>Publication requirement for volunteer surveys</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8E of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2507e">22 U.S.C. 2507e</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD29932A787D94B288127ADAD2C560230"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="H6E9B6D4C7A4D4344A9937E47D920754F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the first sentence, by striking <quote>2018</quote> and inserting <quote>2023</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDF2F2669779240A7A2D0BF6401D0E4AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the third sentence, by striking <quote>subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (b)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D88304DB69F466F9DF3B2E6ED75EB82"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new sentences: <quote>The President shall publish on a publicly available website of the Peace Corps the results of each survey related to volunteer satisfaction in each country in which volunteers serve, and the early termination rate of volunteers serving in each such country. The information published shall be posted in an easily accessible place near the description of the appropriate country and shall be written in an easily understood manner.</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HA6D076B384544844847B63794389D710"><enum>10.</enum><header>Experts and consultants for the inspector general</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 13 of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2512">22 U.S.C. 2512</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8F66C29A04164D8E93CA8198246525CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>Section</quote> and inserting <quote>section</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9F62A62F0CB44EDB761F397C0C5B6EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB17E122CE58748BAA6E3120D188CB7D5" style="traditional"> <subsection id="H36C0B6AD232C4D54AA99EE53D146B71B"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An expert, consultant, or organization thereof employed pursuant to subsection (a) by the Inspector General of the Peace Corps may be compensated without regard to the daily equivalent of the highest rate payable under section 5332 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HE3F8F0D1A37B41208933421DD45D64B0"><enum>11.</enum><header>Report and survey on volunteer access to health care benefits</header>
 <subsection id="H21262BE9848F4ED2994EDA3457B8FA3D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter for four years, the Director of the Peace Corps shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report including each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H39D2B66AB42E43F78ED644B5F10C7D51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of Peace Corps volunteers who returned to the United States in the prior year and whom the Director assisted in resolving difficulties in securing health care benefits through the Department of Labor (including difficulties in receiving health care services or reimbursement for such services).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4653D4C47C3E4EAE897F7FD0B7F5BFA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The date on which the Director was contacted by each such volunteer to request such assistance.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD90A911A10AE42CC827EC94B355F9F27"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If such difficulties were successfully resolved by the Director, the date of each such resolution.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H505975ED2BA944AA8A1832FA6886F15B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The average period of time that such resolution was pending, with respect to requests for such assistance in the prior year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7D480074F4143BDBB62E5E93FFEA81E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The rate of satisfaction of such returned volunteers with the quality of such assistance.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF91F2004DE0B482E893F52C71B396A66"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Survey</header> <paragraph id="H4522C2EDFACB447DB396CD3CD691025D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Director shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report including the results of the survey described in <internal-xref idref="H3BE475A98F6044D2B8687D183C7E51E0" legis-path="10.(b)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BE475A98F6044D2B8687D183C7E51E0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope of survey</header><text>The survey described in this paragraph is an annual survey, provided to each former Peace Corps volunteer who accessed post-service health care provided by the Peace Corps, that assesses, with respect to such volunteers, each of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC98396E5AF07454988406CDEFA7DC460"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The level of awareness of the existence of the Federal Employees’ Compensation program and knowledge of the specific health care benefits associated with Peace Corps service that are available under the program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2682383A403F47A186FD2EEB998D189F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The level of awareness of the application requirements of the program, including eligibility requirements and the documentation that the Department of Labor requires before making a decision regarding benefits under the program.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38CD7973261C4020AA3F02E7FB629F1C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The level of satisfaction with the program, including the timeliness of processing applications and providing reimbursement for health and other benefits.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFBEE25914F448288002E89626E09C62"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The average time taken by the Secretary of Labor—</text> <clause id="HBD264C9531904F85A40AF7FCD97C9844"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to review and to approve or deny an application for benefits under the program; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDA7F56B4CC3D43699A0F37D27032DA78"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide a reimbursement for submitted medical claims.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H317B355AF5B3474F9BCFA573F0604E75"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The ability to access medical providers using the benefits provided by the program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4637AC778955458398574C881E7D2F78"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Paperwork reduction act exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The collection of data for purposes of a report submitted under <internal-xref idref="H4522C2EDFACB447DB396CD3CD691025D" legis-path="10.(b)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> is not subject to the requirements of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H345C46E393424F39B8D600EECCE95304"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="HC21548C4BBC54C2BAA70AC182E4F85D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9BFFF5A6D6D4E2DB9396867BE69DA04"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

