<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H44E86B6E5BB6490EB90E7D7149E3D5CE" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4021 IH: Leveraging Performance-Based Transportation Services Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4021</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171011">October 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to provide funding for public transportation services
			 offered by high-performing public and private systems, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H41DB9C66B822473FA3093D6AA9EB1FA9" style="OLC">
 <section id="H177ED24AFF194F6CBF4A1250FD84D574" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Leveraging Performance-Based Transportation Services Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H474C07D2D2004F0F914939758275AEE1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Funding for capital projects of leveraged systems</header> <subsection id="H2188A30AA6434EE7B7CB2EEA0EE35287"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National Transit Database</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5335 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HFD43E40E2F0E472FB7124F0FDB985600" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HD6CAA95A43454CAAA845E959D45FEAEB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Direct reporting by leveraged systems</header>
 <paragraph id="HA95D796B17D240B5A034F8394BB30852"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An owner or operator of a leveraged system may submit directly to the National Transit Database data regarding the public transportation service provided by the system.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B9382C5EE2E437A81B51E948D374841"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice to designated recipient</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the date of a submission under paragraph (1), the owner or operator of a leveraged system shall provide to the appropriate designated recipient under section 5307, 5311, or 5339 and metropolitan planning organization a copy of the submission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H18B3A947E9D0474E828E9AF50C29D38C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Leveraged system defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>leveraged system</quote> means a provider of public transportation services, whether public or private, including commuter bus services and including services provided by a private provider of public transportation by vanpool (as defined in section 5323(i)(2)(C)), that the Secretary determines—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8FB67752A1984141A4D37E150F12F586"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is able to recover, through fare revenue or payments made directly by the provider, all operating costs associated with the services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E3C5F799EAF474589605C367BE03C9B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>meets the requirements of the Federal Transit Administration with respect to the provision of the services; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA722D51B0C1E48BAA0F7FD322C650910"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not, through the provision of the services, negatively impact other publicly subsidized or privately provided public transportation services.</text>
							</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H083137422F1B456391A0E9AEDD533C53"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Leveraging transit services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5315 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC41BC99E436C4D7DB3795D2B00411450"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (e); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FDFF4A6D1544F31AD061B8943B91DDF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD88884F2BB6C4BE7A961A64A38A260B5" style="USC"> <subsection id="H8481BF4742784A2FB1AA13D39561B020"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Leveraging transit services</header> <paragraph id="H9C8CEC500C694DC5833C097979A161DE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Passthrough</header> <subparagraph id="H4225779E85C94222A0157F6207F49E5B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Apportionments</header><text>The data submitted by the owner or operator of a leveraged system to the National Transit Database under section 5335(d) shall be used by the Secretary in calculating apportionments for capital payments under each of sections 5307, 5311, and 5339.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AB6340F457B42A2A4C7CB39AEC2E889"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A designated recipient that receives additional amounts in apportionments for a fiscal year as a result of data submitted to the National Transit Database by the owner or operator of a leveraged system under section 5335(d) shall enter into an agreement with the owner or operator that includes assurances that not less than 90 percent of the additional amounts will be transferred to the owner or operator if the owner or operator demonstrates that the transferred amounts will be used for capital expenditures to expand public transportation services meeting the requirements of paragraph (2) in the geographic area represented by the designated recipient.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FE887A29A57441693E884B180A4DD33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Services</header><text>A public transportation service meets the requirements of this paragraph unless—</text> <subparagraph id="H928DEF2997B74EAB9E2D136513AD608D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the service—</text>
 <clause id="H666490D6C7F5467C9D1A7B2711D46E8B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>overlaps or directly competes with a service provided by the designated recipient concerned; and</text> </clause><clause id="HA1B38C9A110D40CFADA3FDA4F2666FCE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a direct effect on such service, including a projected ridership reduction of more than 3 percent along a corridor served by the designated recipient; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99F156867A874947BED5870DAC00C47C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the service is provided by a service provider that has less than 10 vehicles serving the recipient’s designated area.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H860B120EB74C4016A851E25D0A7B106D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Local consent</header>
 <subparagraph id="H30D5FFF11093492283D4C4F62F799384"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Opportunity to object</header><text>During the 30-day period beginning on the date the owner or operator of a leveraged system submits data to the National Transit Database under section 5335(d), the metropolitan planning organization representing the geographic area in which the owner or operator proposes to provide expanded public transportation services using amounts made available under this subsection may submit to the Secretary a letter that—</text>
 <clause id="H791377F5E76F470C9BC5481A896D774B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">objects to such use of funds based on a determination by the metropolitan planning organization that the expanded public transportation services do not meet the requirements of paragraph (2); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H85ADCB70911F4E95AF97998493E615E4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">objects to the use of the data in calculating apportionments based on a determination by the metropolitan planning organization that the owner or operator has not met the requirements of section 5335(d).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE662A739EC9491D874FBE7FFBBD1821"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect of objection</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall take into account any letter received from a metropolitan planning organization under this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7FB2E0DA30A453EA2EC354DDE7E6D93"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Statutory construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed—</text> <subparagraph id="H6CEB156472FB47FF8557A7013488C85F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to allow a designated recipient to dictate the service provided by the owner or operator of a leveraged system; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H316999BD29CA442DBAE2FB307BC8401A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to authorize the use of funds in a manner that is inconsistent with this chapter.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H20884A95C75749B6B4B7EDE2FD91BCA4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Leveraged system defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>leveraged system</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 5335(d).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


