<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H0582F2BC9C58402FB4DB210E391EB983" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1259 EH: VA Accountability First Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no"> I</distribution-code> 
<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress> <session>1st Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 1259</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for the removal or demotion of employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs based on performance or misconduct, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HFCDB23BCB95B49DBA08E137C03CD548E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5CAA7C94538A4314AED3DD8285D1221F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="H7A0EABACB1F94EE38B4C84D2BDEFB9B9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>VA Accountability First Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7331822F428D403F851A997010EBBB83"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry idref="H5CAA7C94538A4314AED3DD8285D1221F" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H50EE1C3599C7480EAA64B0415B6896EA" level="section">Sec. 2. References to title 38, United States Code.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HCBBC8393D5A144348BBA59F5BFFA7CAC" level="section">Sec. 3. Removal, demotion, and suspension of employees based on performance or misconduct.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H71FD4B8B234A4305B3D9D10CD6C50657" level="section">Sec. 4. Reduction of benefits for Department of Veterans Affairs employees convicted of certain crimes.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H5EA9C18E510E46CFB20DCEEAD5A2A4CA" level="section">Sec. 5. Authority to recoup bonuses or awards paid to employees of Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HCC24D9702CD449E5BAF64030663BFDB5" level="section">Sec. 6. Authority to recoup relocation expenses paid to or on behalf of employees of Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H8EB43B9254DB49FDB4207CF1F56B4295" level="section">Sec. 7. Time period for response to notice of adverse actions against supervisory employees who commit prohibited personnel actions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H73F7860671824F518FFEDCE5B2D560C7" level="section">Sec. 8. Direct hiring authority for medical center directors and VISN directors.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H51F6ECB8E7F741F9B0E7470B9645CC4E" level="section">Sec. 9. Time periods for review of adverse actions with respect to certain employees.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H0CD976A6ADE74E4F869BFBE628957186" level="section">Sec. 10. Annual report on performance awards and bonuses awarded to certain high-level employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE24FB659066A40D99CBD151E407B62C0" level="section">Sec. 11. Accountability of supervisors at Department of Veterans Affairs for addressing performance of employees.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H232552048BA545E4806845BACCC4C0F4" level="section">Sec. 12. Improvement of training for supervisors.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="H50EE1C3599C7480EAA64B0415B6896EA"><enum>2.</enum><header>References to title 38, United States Code</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided, whenever in this Act an amendment or repeal is expressed in terms of an amendment to, or repeal of, a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision of title 38, United States Code.</text></section> <section commented="no" id="HCBBC8393D5A144348BBA59F5BFFA7CAC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Removal, demotion, and suspension of employees based on performance or misconduct</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H317D07C656814993B05742B5A0739788"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/7">chapter 7</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D7D8A8F708B438E9E9A2A8A17F4B069" style="USC"> 
<section commented="no" id="HC97277D21E5D4483B84F43963E063D1C"><enum>719.</enum><header>Employees: removal, demotion, or suspension based on performance or misconduct</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C4137A4EF9244ADB89A6B292CCAB5EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may remove, demote, or suspend an individual who is an employee of the Department if the Secretary determines the performance or misconduct of the individual warrants such removal, demotion, or suspension. If the Secretary so removes, demotes, or suspends such an individual, the Secretary may—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1429253AA9D44F05AFC0A0DBD4E38E90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>remove the individual from the civil service (as defined in section 2101 of title 5);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H01F6E19E87B54B70928912A0E23CAF0B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demote the individual by means of a reduction in grade for which the individual is qualified, that the Secretary determines is appropriate, and that reduces the annual rate of pay of the individual; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H29EBD1771DCC454DA6FC4CAD100CAD5E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>suspend the individual.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H7A12DA9839D74DC7856900CF117C3B97"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pay of certain demoted individuals</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H971396F7895A4504AEBF7D5B29162309"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any individual subject to a demotion under subsection (a)(2) shall, beginning on the date of such demotion, receive the annual rate of pay applicable to such grade.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HB426B1F6A73348BEAC5EFCD7A50ECD9B" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An individual so demoted may not be placed on administrative leave during the period during which an appeal (if any) under this section is ongoing, and may only receive pay if the individual reports for duty or is approved to use accrued unused annual, sick, family medical, military, or court leave. If an individual so demoted does not report for duty or receive approval to use accrued unused leave, such individual shall not receive pay or other benefits pursuant to subsection (e)(5).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H154A98BA87014805B66D0AF88C721175"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice to Congress</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H28B80060B77E4F829A68F9B1C4827EA2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than 30 days after removing, demoting, or suspending an individual employed in a senior executive position under subsection (a) or after removing, demoting, or suspending an individual under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/74">chapter 74</external-xref> of this title, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives and to each Member of Congress representing a district in the State or territory where the facility where the individual was employed immediately before being removed, demoted, or suspended is located notice in writing of such removal, demotion, or suspension. Such notice shall include the job title of the individual, the location where the individual was employed immediately before being removed, demoted, or suspended, the proposed action, and the reason for such removal, demotion, or suspension.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9945124FFD0489D9106C7D1C1472319" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the last day of a fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report listing all removals, demotions, and suspensions under this section or under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/74">chapter 74</external-xref> of this title during such fiscal year. Each such report shall include the job title of each individual removed, demoted, or suspended, the location where the individual was employed immediately before being so removed, demoted or suspended, the proposed action, and the reason for such removal, demotion, or suspension.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8DB676897D5344679F7CFF2F08DD5A85" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>senior executive position</quote> means, with respect to a career appointee (as that term is defined in section 3132(a)(4) of title 5), a Senior Executive Service position (as such term is defined in section 3132(a)(2) of title 5).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HC6E7DAD13DFF478BB38084B89B879418"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Procedure</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2EDB423C8B764DF1BEFC996680CF35F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subsection (b) of section 7513 of title 5 shall apply with respect to a removal, demotion, or suspension under this section, except that the period for notice and response, which includes the advance notice period required by paragraph (1) of such subsection and the response period required by paragraph (2) of such subsection, shall not exceed a total of 10 business days. Subsection (c) of such section and <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7121">section 7121</external-xref> of such title shall not apply with respect to such a removal, demotion, or suspension.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H59956B1E1D794B39A2CA6E7A0511E7EE" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall issue a final decision with respect to a removal, demotion, or suspension under this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H2DC712FC85FB4F0CA4AE35CFB9857DD3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a proposed removal, demotion, or suspension to which an individual responds under paragraph (1), not later than five business days after receiving the response of the individual; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H92BBDB3D17A84D5CA1FD6DB0DAA3AD8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a proposed removal, demotion, or suspension to which an individual does not respond, not later than 15 business days after the Secretary provides notice to the individual under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF17C6FFD7AF452C80A3072532EB658B" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The procedures under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/43">chapter 43</external-xref> of title 5 shall not apply to a removal, demotion, or suspension under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H435A88DDB9604C939D6B4358367AE66B" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE99E5BD687844A8096E60E54A92D27B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Subject to subparagraph (B) and subsection (e), any removal, demotion, or suspension under subsection (a) may be appealed to the Merit Systems Protection Board, which shall refer such appeal to an administrative judge pursuant to section 7701(b)(1) of title 5.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0BC5459471174E249AEEBEF6EB223AE0" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An appeal under subparagraph (A) of a removal, demotion, or suspension may only be made if such appeal is made not later than 7 days after the date of such removal, demotion, or suspension.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H714AC62DE89D4136B703AD193CCE647D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Expedited Review</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4F2CF59BF38649B79E1B17D2A3825E48"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Upon receipt of an appeal under subsection (d)(4)(A), the administrative judge shall expedite any such appeal under such section and, in any such case, shall issue a final and complete decision not later than 45 business days after the date of the appeal.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H1DF9499D751E40F1AD602C3DDE206170" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 7701(c)(1)(B) of title 5, the administrative judge shall uphold the decision of the Secretary to remove, demote, or suspend an employee under subsection (a) if the decision is supported by substantial evidence. If the decision of the Secretary is supported by substantial evidence, the administrative judge shall not mitigate the penalty prescribed by the Secretary.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H19DCE7EE2FBC47B88986BB4C541EC8FA" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H106CB7C2162149158DF4A2CC7B45D27B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The decision of the administrative judge under paragraph (1) may be appealed to the Merit Systems Protection Board.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD19A6F635E92453783611F927A806EDA" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An appeal under subparagraph (A) of a decision of an administrative judge may only be made if such appeal is made not later than 7 business days after the date of the decision of the administrative judge.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HC2E121BAED7248FD827067035FA7C69B" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In any case in which the administrative judge cannot issue a decision in accordance with the 45-day requirement under paragraph (1), the Merit Systems Protection Board shall, not later than 14 business days after the expiration of the 45-day period, submit to the Committees on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report that explains the reasons why a decision was not issued in accordance with such requirement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H8CD45EC8F63E46EFB9C4F3C84EB4DF6D" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD8F157C821674551837D90DD82EAE69C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A decision of the Merit Systems Protection Board under paragraph (3) may be appealed to the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit pursuant to section 7703 of title 5.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H8CE032344B774C89BCAAC95932F19F12" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An appeal under subparagraph (A) of a decision of the Merit Systems Protection Board may only be made if such appeal is made not later than 7 business days after the date of the decision of the Board.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HDD26B8CBE2454B8FB38A8BECBBA2A956" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any decision by such Court shall be in compliance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7462">section 7462(f)(2)</external-xref> of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HA4B75D501A28465DA1A3B9F8DD767924" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Merit Systems Protection Board may not stay any removal, demotion, under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H0BFD299A757C4F4497A509A557ED2F81" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period beginning on the date on which an individual appeals a removal from the civil service under subsection (d) and ending on the date that the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit issues a final decision on such appeal, such individual may not receive any pay, awards, bonuses, incentives, allowances, differentials, student loan repayments, special payments, or benefits related to the employment of the individual by the Department.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H0AA786BFA1824A278F03877C889E3756" indent="up1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall provide to the Merit Systems Protection Board such information and assistance as may be necessary to ensure an appeal under this subsection is expedited.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H73EA4F17350B411AB1D128E89C6E7CB6" indent="up1"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an employee prevails on appeal under this section, the employee shall be entitled to backpay (as provided in section 5596 of title 5).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0B9D644E9D6A46C1A7EB9FBF2BB2915E" indent="up1"><enum>(10)</enum><text>This subsection shall supercede any collective bargaining agreement to the extent that such an agreement conflicts with this subsection.<italic></italic></text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HD1DA5A01FA1D495C97247C33BAE454A7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Whistleblower protection</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3744257A041243098DE3F9F37A9ADE74"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual seeking corrective action (or on behalf of whom corrective action is sought) from the Office of Special Counsel based on an alleged prohibited personnel practice described in section 2302(b) of title 5 or <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/733">section 733(c)</external-xref> of this title, the Secretary may not remove, demote, or suspend such individual under subsection (a) without the approval of the Special Counsel under section 1214(f) of title 5.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H98C9B0BB35864E84AE79185CB933D1F2" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In the case of an individual who has filed a whistleblower complaint, as such term is defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/731">section 731</external-xref> of this title, the Secretary may not remove, demote, or suspend such individual under subsection (a) until a final decision with respect to the whistleblower complaint has been made.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H1D7BFA3566A64A4C9718DC634D5C2B3B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination of investigations by Office of Special Counsel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Special Counsel (established by section 1211 of title 5) may terminate an investigation of a prohibited personnel practice alleged by an employee or former employee of the Department after the Special Counsel provides to the employee or former employee a written statement of the reasons for the termination of the investigation. Such statement may not be admissible as evidence in any judicial or administrative proceeding without the consent of such employee or former employee.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8BA5C29F37A24B0EA78AA4B981A55C0A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual who is removed or demoted under subsection (a), to the maximum extent feasible, the Secretary shall fill the vacancy arising as a result of such removal or demotion.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAAAB9D0A5B4045C68A0DEF6693B6F1DA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Semi-Annual report on transferred employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives semi-annual reports on senior executive employees who are transferred within the Department. Each such report shall include, for each such senior executive employee transferred during the period covered by the report, the reason for the transfer and any costs associated with the transfer. </text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H3FBFDBCB336948E2B8B416EE94C30443"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H6C3752EBDCC64390B8D67589D3D56A0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>individual</term> means an individual occupying a position at the Department but does not include—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H796427F975E9436C9E031539EA0920A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual appointed pursuant to section 7306, 7401(1), or 7405 of this title;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H1DC5F05B785A454D806D26B06422D54C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual who has not completed a probationary or trial period; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE2B76FB19B2E4DB98212ECC5384F7360"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a political appointee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D3D2AF2F8854AEB871042D4A129AE9D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>suspend</term> means the placing of an employee, for disciplinary reasons, in a temporary status without duties and pay for a period in excess of 14 days.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H611878E6773F42E29C470106471639B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>grade</term> has the meaning given such term in section 7511(a) of title 5.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H3572B077C82B4614B6D7C01B1D100E51"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>misconduct</term> includes neglect of duty, malfeasance, or failure to accept a directed reassignment or to accompany a position in a transfer of function.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HDC5E121064B84AD980FCD9A8A81DC656"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>political appointee</term> means an individual who is—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HEEDC7BBF7F7546C19B068AD5B275C6B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employed in a position described under sections 5312 through 5316 of title 5 (relating to the Executive Schedule);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HBAD7EF5F33B34584AA0171E7998CE535"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a limited term appointee, limited emergency appointee, or noncareer appointee in the Senior Executive Service, as defined under paragraphs (5), (6), and (7), respectively, of section 3132(a) of title 5; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC357E19EDD514EAA977AB15D83CDD170"><enum>(C)</enum><text>employed in a position of a confidential or policy-determining character under schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5 of the Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB906BC71A8A540C6AAE6011CD27D8CB7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal of superceded provision of law</header> 
<paragraph id="HC98111E40EA54F60BDB63AD22FC9C87A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 713 of title 38, United States Code, is hereby repealed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6BEA4C91EF09455B96D89D45020C414D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/7">chapter 7</external-xref> is amended by striking the item relating to section 713.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H7B933D38779348C3BE028FB94E299B44"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical and conforming amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="H44E2311222AB439CB5D7368A3B8DCC02"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Clerical</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/7">chapter 7</external-xref> is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 717 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB8B1756AAE8B40758DB91F2104AE0563" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">719. Employees: removal, demotion, or suspension based on performance or misconduct.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B98A860504045D7A4FC4EE37DF6DCA2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming</header><text>Section 4303(f) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2E151A3B45AC48A7BD478F6F7E7CC054"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA8CA63DACEFE41F2A76FF2392D151219"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (3) and inserting <quote>, or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFC11623F262F48DB92BD79CC5FA41058"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2BAADA7C2354987A81A31518345A382" style="USC"> <paragraph id="HB572D5743FC94B228511B0C9FD7E0C57"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any removal or demotion under section 719 of title 38.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H67FBDB673DCC446283DAFF3FE0DA05F8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Temporary exemption from certain limitation on initiation from removal from Senior Executive Service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 120-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, an action to remove an individual from the Senior Executive Service at the Department of Veterans Affairs pursuant to this section may be initiated, notwithstanding section 3592(b) of title 5, United States Code, or any other provision of law.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H71FD4B8B234A4305B3D9D10CD6C50657" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reduction of benefits for Department of Veterans Affairs employees convicted of certain crimes</header> <subsection id="H6DE7B3E77CD04A0987E225B0469DED65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reduction of benefits</header> <paragraph id="H15B056C243324112919C9218B813FB0D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter I of chapter 7 is further amended by inserting after section 719, as added by section 3, the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7001FD90924A40F3A3985FCF67ECE212" style="USC"> 
<section id="HA8E3E83CD71B4CEEBDB53FFFC36F3812"><enum>721.</enum><header>Reduction of benefits of employees convicted of certain crimes</header> 
<subsection id="HD81BD457D6E644A08688354849F9B895"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reduction of annuity for removed employee</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE735B903CB80400DA0F5D0FC57DD75BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall order that the covered service of an employee of the Department removed from a position for performance or misconduct under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/719">section 719</external-xref> or <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7461">7461</external-xref> of this title or any other provision of law shall not be taken into account for purposes of calculating an annuity with respect to such individual under chapter 83 or <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/84">chapter 84</external-xref> of title 5, if—</text> <subparagraph id="H8B232130082C4B36AA83EF6F96C1FADE" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that the individual is convicted of a felony that influenced the individual’s performance while employed in the position;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8C3FFA568509428CB7C4823A24534163" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>before such order is made, the individual is afforded—</text> <clause id="H1A38CEFE572448889AF0053AD6433E0D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>notice of the proposed order; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6EF5E07EAF5346D09B854593C27579AA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an opportunity to respond to the proposed order by not later than ten business days following receipt of such notice; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8DB3BC56B8CE43E38DC7A08EA7B3FA8C" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary issues the order—</text> 
<clause id="H8B25DFE95A8540C1904889B0E67EE29C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a proposed order to which an individual responds under subparagraph (B)(ii), not later than five business days after receiving the response of the individual; or</text></clause> <clause id="HF4233D53639D4E87806E8DDE2B8E863B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a proposed order to which an individual does not respond, not later than 15 business days after the Secretary provides notice to the individual under subparagraph (B)(i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H61CF918DFC5444DF9328A2A6F22D292D" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Upon the issuance of an order by the Secretary under paragraph (1), the individual shall have an opportunity to appeal the order to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management before the date that is seven business days after the date of such issuance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5398A6B938054F7DA34A783D99618550" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall make a final decision with respect to an appeal under paragraph (2) within 30 business days of receiving the appeal.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6F38C11181724C3BA70D531BA95A8CBD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reduction of annuity for retired employee</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA86AEF21351F465BB06282C9F746A07A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may order that the covered service of an individual who is removed for performance or misconduct under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/719">section 719</external-xref> or <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7461">7461</external-xref> of this title or any other provision of law but who leaves employment at the Department prior to the issuance of a final decision with respect to such action shall not be taken into account for purposes of calculating an annuity with respect to such individual under chapter 83 or <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/84">chapter 84</external-xref> of title 5, if—</text> <subparagraph id="H718BCDFAA7F04C5AA9B5C7B51911229E" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that the individual is convicted of a felony that influenced the individual’s performance while employed in the position;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HECADAB02AFF449459C5C42A617051EE2" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">before such order is made, the individual is afforded—</text> <clause id="H8F821B56E46D413BA76B99DE2E460DF1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notice of the proposed order; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H85BDE7612C394F6DB9E2E30D8E928F54"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>opportunity to respond to the proposed order by not later than ten business days following receipt of such notice; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9ADC6156EA2F48BBA346FBA5E6FCFB55" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary issues the order—</text> 
<clause id="H8F3816CF17894189A948C6AD6DC9B499"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a proposed order to which an individual responds under subparagraph (B)(ii), not later than five business days after receiving the response of the individual; or</text></clause> <clause id="HEB78B011DB4246B98B7B598B5F7E9593"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a proposed order to which an individual does not respond, not later than 15 business days after the Secretary provides notice to the individual under subparagraph (B)(i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F3214459DD841AA8AC273D9017C9E2E" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Upon the issuance of an order by the Secretary under paragraph (1), the individual shall have an opportunity to appeal the order to the Director of the Office of Personnel Management before the date that is seven business days after the date of such issuance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA229D7FA77C4A52A780CA4BB82B8208" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall make a final decision with respect to an appeal under paragraph (2) within 30 business days of receiving the appeal.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA974D097A22F4A80892C00D57E77BC41"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administrative requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 37 business days after the Secretary issues a final order under subsection (a) or (b), the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall recalculate the annuity of the individual.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD98BDF54D6D14E08A4E71D05CD1385D9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Lump-Sum Annuity Credit</header><text>Any individual with respect to whom an annuity is reduced under subsection (a) or (b) shall be entitled to be paid so much of such individual’s lump-sum credit as is attributable to the period of covered service.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9D1475E950B641BC9970474030651BFD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Spouse or children exception</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Office of Personnel Management, shall prescribe regulations that may provide for the payment to the spouse or children of any individual referred to in subsection (a) or (b) of any amounts which (but for this subsection) would otherwise have been nonpayable by reason of such subsections. Any such regulations shall be consistent with the requirements of sections 8332(o)(5) and 8411(l)(5) of title 5, as the case may be.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3D54C5FB40054A599B19EBDDE5F74D5C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB7F81F9531404F0F8536E575324ADB9C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered service</quote> means, with respect to an individual subject to a removal for performance or misconduct under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/719">section 719</external-xref> or <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7461">7461</external-xref> of this title or any other provision of law, the period of service beginning on the date that the Secretary determines under such applicable provision that the individual engaged in activity that gave rise to such action and ending on the date that the individual is removed from or leaves a position of employment at the Department prior to the issuance of a final decision with respect to such action.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H5CCFA90B9EB144CEB2B1433AB5BF632C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>lump-sum credit</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 8331(8) or section 8401(19) of title 5, as the case may be.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC4AD994272434D53B9998135DCC9411A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>service</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 8331(12) or section 8401(26) of title 5, as the case may be.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H591FCD5FD56645CC9090ABC06D4CB17E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/7">chapter 7</external-xref> is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 719, as added by section 3, the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C5531D793914CBA9CF0C7D6B53554ED" style="USC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">721. Reduction of benefits of employees convicted of certain crimes.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H109AAFB54BCB42C4A60C524E0DB4E778"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 721 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(1), shall apply to any action of removal of an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/719">section 719</external-xref> or <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7461">7461</external-xref> of this title or any other provision of law, commencing on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H5EA9C18E510E46CFB20DCEEAD5A2A4CA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authority to recoup bonuses or awards paid to employees of Department of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="HD9BC733C964848319F5B4B22CA0AAB55"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter I of chapter 7 is further amended by inserting after section 721, as added by section 4, the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF6784AD9B3E48BB8318EFA3EE803BB3" style="USC"> 
<section id="H71DB9E54E9934E3381FCD910B01F504F"><enum>723.</enum><header>Recoupment of bonuses or awards paid to employees of Department</header> 
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2BC3D8C36574D56A445F5962DEA6B01"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may issue an order directing an employee of the Department to repay the amount, or a portion of the amount, of any award or bonus paid to the employee under title 5, including under chapter 45 or 53 of such title, or this title if—</text> <paragraph id="HE65B4B445291484B9FABD70296C9987F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary determines that the individual engaged in misconduct or poor performance prior to payment of the award or bonus, and that such award or bonus would not have been paid, in whole or in part, had the misconduct or poor performance been known prior to payment;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C84D1698A9D43EB882BA173EE24ABF0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>before such repayment, the employee is afforded—</text> <subparagraph id="H3277F6525CAD4B68ABBC5695388D2B68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notice of the proposed order; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H193C261E7E71424B93C5652262BA996D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an opportunity to respond to the proposed order by not later than ten business days after the receipt of such notice; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF7731AEED4F41FA890AC21E29A44435"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary issues the order—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6FF4689E165545C8BDE06C04B266DAE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a proposed order to which an individual responds under paragraph (2)(B), not later than five business days after receiving the response of the individual; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1934536BEA9840DCB75A6734353EFCF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a proposed order to which an individual does not respond, not later than 15 business days after the Secretary provides notice to the individual under paragraph (2)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H33722C0943734F85BED7A1413FDF1470"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text>Upon the issuance of an order by the Secretary under subsection (a), the individual shall have an opportunity to appeal the order to another department or agency of the Federal Government before the date that is seven business days after the date of such issuance.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7B3F36B0C1C14837B221495583BA935E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Final decisions</header><text>The head of the applicable department or agency of the Federal Government shall make a final decision with respect to an appeal under subsection (b) within 30 business days after receiving such appeal.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H99E6E025BB7F4E1EA21C5E52203E983E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter, as amended by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/4">section 4,</external-xref> is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 721, as added by section 4(a)(2), the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12188645C5EF4D58A4228999E86848A8" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">723. Recoupment of bonuses or awards paid to employees of Department.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H04995DF1AA5040638A8450D68FBBB769"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Section 723 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall apply with respect to an award or bonus paid by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7F23B0C5D58940ADBBADD62E4DF48936"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act may be construed to modify the certification issued by the Office of Personnel Management and the Office of Management and Budget regarding the performance appraisal system of the Senior Executive Service of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subsection></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC24D9702CD449E5BAF64030663BFDB5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to recoup relocation expenses paid to or on behalf of employees of Department of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="H6756D871683D4C49A3830CF040625137"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter I of chapter 7 is further amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F80A815B3004E7F889CC735DE6FBFF7" style="USC"> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDFAA842430F541889020956D116B4253"><enum>725.</enum><header>Recoupment of relocation expenses paid to or on behalf of employees of Department</header> 
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83576C4515B8429CB3B22EFC8BDE073D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may issue an order directing an employee of the Department to repay the amount, or a portion of the amount, paid to or on behalf of the employee under title 5 for relocation expenses, including any expenses under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5724">section 5724</external-xref> or <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5724a">5724a</external-xref> of such title, or this title if—</text> <paragraph id="H0596ABF8C94A45F6894E3291A2DD923D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary determines that relocation expenses were not lawfully authorized or that the employee committed an act of fraud, waste, or malfeasance that influenced the authorization of the relocation expenses;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E1F45B26EDD4AF59B1EE35F274F0F51"><enum>(2)</enum><text>before such repayment, the employee is afforded—</text> <subparagraph id="H094AEEF7C1EA42D9B688AE49BEBC3F53"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notice of the proposed order; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H714FF4C9598A4282925EC1B8878CB085"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an opportunity to respond to the proposed order not later than ten business days following the receipt of such notice; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC9587E019E745C882A904BF5E9801D6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary issues the order—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H28C2C96E5C79444C9E6B97454164F22E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a proposed order to which an individual responds under paragraph (2)(B), not later than five business days after receiving the response of the individual; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDAA46B7A44C84D89956C9F80FB9275CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a proposed order to which an individual does not respond, not later than 15 business days after the Secretary provides notice to the individual under paragraph (2)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H20DE29D832D44D08A25AAAE258C8C42B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text>Upon the issuance of an order by the Secretary under subsection (a), the individual shall have an opportunity to appeal the order to another department or agency of the Federal Government before the date that is seven business days after the date of such issuance.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF2DAE1D7ABA243B09FF127BD26FFA623"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Final decisions</header><text>The head of the applicable department or agency of the Federal Government shall make a final decision with respect to an appeal under subsection (b) within 30 days after receiving such appeal.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE2A8B5D456064D7CA038ECB2DC3A0808"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is further amended by inserting after the item relating to section 723, as added by section 5(b), the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H145668F4408946C2BCFCE37FE8133FF0" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">725. Recoupment of relocation expenses paid to or on behalf of employees of Department.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HAB21AB71794E42108B72BEA32EEA6C0C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Section 725 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall apply with respect to an amount paid by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to or on behalf of an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs for relocation expenses on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8EB43B9254DB49FDB4207CF1F56B4295"><enum>7.</enum><header>Time period for response to notice of adverse actions against supervisory employees who commit prohibited personnel actions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/733">Section 733(a)(2)(B)</external-xref> is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HFD7FCC7BB5B748E59DDAD08FC8F7A0E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>14 days</quote> and inserting <quote>10 days</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF322380C25D4400A9F7D0BBB7408D281"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>14-day period</quote> and inserting <quote>10-day period</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H73F7860671824F518FFEDCE5B2D560C7"><enum>8.</enum><header>Direct hiring authority for medical center directors and VISN directors</header> <subsection id="H4ABC48C5EC48450581606977E5FAE13F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7401">Section 7401</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7CED6FEA39A45A69DA4F95D19489945" style="USC"> 
<paragraph id="H0B22FBDBC40B4137B72E805D459A8A39"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Medical center directors and directors of Veterans Integrated Service Networks with demonstrated ability in the medical profession, in health care administration, or in health care fiscal management.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H08C458D8A60943178AB9FD05B58C1F33"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7404">Section 7404(a)(1)</external-xref> is amended by inserting <quote>and 7401(4)</quote> after <quote>7306</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H51F6ECB8E7F741F9B0E7470B9645CC4E"><enum>9.</enum><header>Time periods for review of adverse actions with respect to certain employees</header> 
<subsection id="H8C5B82EC320D4E139B5A34AA157C2E9F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Physicians, dentists, podiatrists, chiropractors, optometrists, registered nurses, physician assistants, and expanded-Function dental auxiliaries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7461">Section 7461(b)(2)</external-xref> is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H786E3EF455B440FBAAD38119B3A8D828" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H295B1905BE194952BB5F0E8D9F5F4D0C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case other than a case described in paragraph (1) that involves or includes a question of professional conduct or competence in which a major adverse action was not taken, such an appeal shall be made through Department grievance procedures under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7463">section 7463</external-xref> of this title.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H72B4F17719514CAB9A093EFD72A727F1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Major adverse actions involving professional conduct or competence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7462">Section 7462</external-xref> is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HBF7E6EC15955489FA35BBAD3CFB9EABD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H10101667E0C14748B3A1AC2AAEEE92BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="H0107126A6D66436082825ACC9E779CFB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>At least 30</quote> and inserting <quote>Ten business</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5AE29D30951D486C84134F6DB15D692C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <subclause id="HFBDDCACFD5D442C09A7FE80FB078A486"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A reasonable time, but not less than seven days</quote> and inserting <quote>The opportunity, within the ten-day notice period</quote>; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB86B54DFEADE4E46A109F03EEC98D7CA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>orally and</quote>;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D62ECAD8ADA42428039BC813FFD8C34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> 
<clause id="H024A92D042AA42CCA97EDADF141097C0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(A) If a proposed adverse action covered by this section is not withdrawn</quote> and inserting <quote>After considering the employee’s answer, if any</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H95B00E0DD3C7474DB88089E929CE6714"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>21 days</quote> and inserting <quote>5 business days</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2B1F9F594A1C4FF9A14A920C43E7DB7D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>answer. The decision shall include a statement of</quote> and inserting <quote>answer stating</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H9B3B63FA1AB0427AAA35B866746BCD54"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B); and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCA782C2E467B4E7FAE8699D2B82199BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text> <clause id="H098909A967A54237930FD735016EC33C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(A) The Secretary</quote> and all that follows through <quote>(B) The Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>The Secretary</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H95D8B5BE93064C879F3AD36A290EF0D9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>30 days</quote> and inserting <quote>7 business days</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H04479BA40FBC480CB91CCCD9CB435184"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H00C76EE662C3428A8D35E5BCA438E5F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting <quote>the hearing must be concluded not later than 30 business days after the date on which the appeal is filed, and</quote> after <quote>If such a hearing is held,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H42511F05979F4EFB8B783B57B67C4FCF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text> 
<clause id="HB452345CFAD24B69A5937605AC818085"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>45 days</quote> and inserting <quote>15 business days</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF66CE701F83F4D0BB29B581F183C5F0F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>120 days</quote> and inserting <quote>45 business days</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6DD3645AFC1640C2B3C864FFCEE7C113"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1), by striking <quote>90 days</quote> and inserting <quote>15 business days</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB33C2E3855E84D2C91BE968B336A6A1A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other adverse actions</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7463">Section 7463</external-xref> is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H948843CFBE864AD1AD313394520986AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b) and redesignating subsections (c) through (e) as subsections (b) through (d), respectively; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B403DD2601A4C6DA38A103D9A1C65C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2), as so redesignated—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4EDB13E903A8448F9C944243243FB802"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>an advance</quote> and inserting <quote>ten business days</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAA825D00947B45A7BCC2D81DC43D1021"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> 
<clause id="HEE5056831D3442669FBA7CCAAC53A01E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>a reasonable time</quote> and inserting <quote>the opportunity, within the ten business day notice period,</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HEA192D7D40434B3BB65F4E5C6BB4B469"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>orally and</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CD976A6ADE74E4F869BFBE628957186" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>10.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Annual report on performance awards and bonuses awarded to certain high-level employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE28CD597E25A4B858F858D99BA1233C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/7">Chapter 7</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is further amended by inserting after section 723, as added by section 5, the following new section:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD915B6326FDD4DE4BD45F4656E00EF96" style="USC"> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45FF64277D82469E94AA07AE4629C81D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>724.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Annual report on performance awards and bonuses awarded to certain high-level employees</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFDD7F77B3A9F4D80AD79E5DCF84B6D5A"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that contains, for the most recent fiscal year ending before the submittal of the report, a description of the performance awards and bonuses awarded to Regional Office Directors of the Department, Directors of Medical Centers of the Department, Directors of Veterans Integrated Service Networks, and any other individual employed in a senior executive position.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4BC8AF486EE4763924629145FE990B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall include the following with respect to each performance award or bonus awarded to an individual described in such subsection:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5AE60A5D36B944EE8647578FBBF535A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of each award or bonus.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HADCC2197034944B7814AFF992A5F2EBC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The job title of the individual awarded the award or bonus.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE088485F1AF45539554F32B9A83BF95"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The location where the individual awarded the award or bonus works.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D798886E4EC4E2A921422BFFAB47E35"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HE114FBFADAEC4C95BABA566938A66E3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H17C19D6F5DA24790A0F3621522763F03" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H64F0A7AA57424D0F92522A9600E07295" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H149E3F91641D4C5BA3F3A3866CDBA725"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>individual</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H86A093B9A5284F98A47EB0C0C98C176C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a career appointee (as that term is defined in section 3132(a)(4) of title 5); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7E6451439D594BB6BE891B2E5772F6D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any individual who occupies an administrative or executive position and who was appointed under section 7306(a) or <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7401">section 7401(1)</external-xref> of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54D10D8B987D4D71AFA19FA5E04D861A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>senior executive position</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7ACC17EF3C1049A4ABF6F5A34C457E15"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a career appointee (as that term is defined in section 3132(a)(4) of title 5), a Senior Executive Service position (as such term is defined in section 3132(a)(2) of title 5); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD05CECECEAA94F6C90340BEF6FB29F2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to an individual appointed under section 7306(a) or <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7401">section 7401(1)</external-xref> of this title, an administrative or executive position.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07691A623A3542C28D44E3FABAC218A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 723, as added by section 5, the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H954895D8D05A49EE986F68414568597C" style="USC"> <toc> <toc-entry bold="off" idref="H45FF64277D82469E94AA07AE4629C81D" level="section">724. Annual report on performance awards and bonuses awarded to certain high-level employees.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE24FB659066A40D99CBD151E407B62C0"><enum>11.</enum><header>Accountability of supervisors at Department of Veterans Affairs for addressing performance of employees</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5061E15092B94671BCA381CFA869AF53"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that, as a part of the annual performance plan of a supervisor in the Department, the supervisor is evaluated on the following:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H567EE9DA6FD74F1A879DD9D67912F46F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Taking action to address poor performance and misconduct among the employees that report to the supervisor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC225309AADEA4BF0A27BCC7E07AF563D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Taking steps to improve or sustain high levels of employee engagement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H30AD38735BF142C3953722CB262C519B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Promoting a positive culture of service that—</text> <subparagraph id="H9DDB6A900A5A4CA9BBF1013A4485863A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reflects the mission of the Department and the values of integrity, commitment, advocacy, respect, and excellence; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2FBABFA67B84396A20E900F2E3651E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>emphasizes the greatest degree of performance and conduct.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07F205C1D8F74043B8AE9D07A329A32A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Supervisor defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>supervisor</term> has the meaning given such term in section 7103(a) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H232552048BA545E4806845BACCC4C0F4"><enum>12.</enum><header>Improvement of training for supervisors</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4FCC1543ABFB40B5B8335AFC2095E172"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall provide to each employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs who is employed as a supervisor periodic training on the following:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB21EF097F5A428B89D6578E3D314742"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The rights of whistleblowers and how to address a report by an employee of a hostile work environment, reprisal, or harassment.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0932B203D6344FDF95E43189ED51D65A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>How to effectively motivate, manage, and reward the employees who report to the supervisor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B1C24D0F6934E7AAE71FAA120E66DE2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>How to effectively manage employees who are performing at an unacceptable level and access assistance from the human resources office of the Department and the Office of the General Counsel of the Department with respect to those employees.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B11E21F7973440C99882C20FCADF03B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACC2A4B546F34046B5FABB2C890D0018"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Supervisor</header><text>The term <term>supervisor</term> has the meaning given such term in section 7103(a) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9892BF325F784EB8A6189499B0BB5579"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Whistleblower</header><text>The term <term>whistleblower</term> has the meaning given such term in section 323(g) of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 101.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20170316" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives March 16, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

