<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H82AD8642F10A4D8589C4CAB7E89A2F15" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 301 IH: NIST Plumbing Research Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 301</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170105">January 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the National Institute of Standards and Technology to establish a premise plumbing
			 research laboratory, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5B7F899758154DA29492CACE55B79244" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8E86FE68A8634FAE879087FAF4A1EE2F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>NIST Plumbing Research Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HEB59C76DCE7547F38314201CDCC8C728"><enum>2.</enum><header>Premise plumbing research</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (in this Act, referred to as <quote>NIST</quote>) shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB32AF198BA75464294CE920AA38FFD50"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish or designate a laboratory to conduct research on premise plumbing in relation to water safety, security, efficiency, sustainability, and resilience;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD3AC838914674A80967A85BFDEE6CEBA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conduct an organizational review of all research and other activities related to premise plumbing conducted by Federal entities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H14BD41B026DA442C908B4AA4D81C7F34"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appoint one or more officers or employees of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to liaise with non-Federal entities conducting research or other activities related to premise plumbing.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H5C82F74DFAF7443F8823DD2353E3146D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 4 years thereafter, the Director of NIST shall submit to Congress a report on the progress made by NIST regarding—</text>
 <paragraph id="H516FFCA4C4AD4E42BB0E42DB148E0CE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the status of the laboratory described in paragraph (1) of section 2, including any staff designated to work in such laboratory;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8ED513EA8E3E430DBEBAA7CD2AAAC18F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all projects of NIST related to premise plumbing, including completed projects, projects in progress, and projects planned for the future;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5214513244945C0AA03BEB2E91DB90C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">updates to data relevant to premise plumbing system structure, design, and construction; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D315C1AFF3A4C1189A8461482238C8F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any progress of private organizations in updating premise plumbing standards.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H39CF892E88AF400BBD9EEB3BAAA21A56"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>premise plumbing</quote> means the water distribution system located within the property lines of a property, including all buildings and permanent structures on such property. Such term includes building supply and distribution pipes, fixtures, fittings, water heaters, water-treating and water-using equipment, and all respective joints, connections, devices, and appurtenances.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


