<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H84E912E114AD40299B89E0443992CA79" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 910 : Fair Access to Investment Research Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 910</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20170502">May 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To direct the Securities and Exchange Commission to provide a safe harbor related to certain
			 investment fund research reports, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H783E2C7EED5649DEBAEDFC73CFB393D4" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7F7CBECBA19F4836879903BA444BB438" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Access to Investment Research Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HA5C694158F1C4DF3991861E4BC94A448"><enum>2.</enum><header>Safe harbor for investment fund research</header> <subsection id="HB58F34905996493FBD3AC20B9108927F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expansion of the safe harbor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Securities and Exchange Commission shall propose, and not later than the end of the 270-day period beginning on such date, the Commission shall adopt, upon such terms, conditions, or requirements as the Commission may determine necessary or appropriate in the public interest, for the protection of investors, and for the promotion of capital formation, revisions to section 230.139 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, to provide that a covered investment fund research report that is published or distributed by a broker or dealer—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7F1EA7E486634DDBAE47282CAB9E4DD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be deemed, for purposes of sections 2(a)(10) and 5(c) of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77b">15 U.S.C. 77b(a)(10)</external-xref>, 77e(c)), not to constitute an offer for sale or an offer to sell a security that is the subject of an offering pursuant to a registration statement that is effective, even if the broker or dealer is participating or will participate in the registered offering of the covered investment fund’s securities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC7AEDD11AF148388C5D1D90C181315B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be deemed to satisfy the conditions of subsection (a)(1) or (a)(2) of section 230.139 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor provisions, for purposes of the Commission’s rules and regulations under the Federal securities laws and the rules of any self-regulatory organization.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D0130C4CD01452A9252E22DA56A52E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation of safe harbor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In implementing the safe harbor pursuant to subsection (a), the Commission shall—</text> <paragraph id="HC39FCCFA8D18470FB12D63E8D6300BED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not, in the case of a covered investment fund with a class of securities in substantially continuous distribution, condition the safe harbor on whether the broker’s or dealer’s publication or distribution of a covered investment fund research report constitutes such broker’s or dealer’s initiation or reinitiation of research coverage on such covered investment fund or its securities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA197B35D56144085BB90C63EE9C238D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not—</text> <subparagraph id="HC46A175F19114F7BAD1A860E7BADCFBE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require the covered investment fund to have been registered as an investment company under the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-1">15 U.S.C. 80a–1</external-xref> et seq.) or subject to the reporting requirements of section 13 or 15(d) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78m">15 U.S.C. 78m</external-xref>, 78o(d)) for any period exceeding the period of time referenced under paragraph (a)(1)(i)(A)(1) of section 230.139 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4AF3D2731464A82BE730FD96C86B6D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>impose a minimum float provision exceeding that referenced in paragraph (a)(1)(i)(A)(1)(i) of section 230.139 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC669DF8D33B541A6B463AB60C6B34794"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide that a self-regulatory organization may not maintain or enforce any rule that would—</text> <subparagraph id="H01381980913E414B93CB110F8C63D160"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prohibit the ability of a member to publish or distribute a covered investment fund research report solely because the member is also participating in a registered offering or other distribution of any securities of such covered investment fund; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H122B2F189B44450C95F7C0D19F48C7B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prohibit the ability of a member to participate in a registered offering or other distribution of securities of a covered investment fund solely because the member has published or distributed a covered investment fund research report about such covered investment fund or its securities; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H395CBA8FC2AD4717BA90AD58578B42DD"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide that a covered investment fund research report shall not be subject to section 24(b) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-24">15 U.S.C. 80a–24(b)</external-xref>) or the rules and regulations thereunder, except that such report may still be subject to such section and the rules and regulations thereunder to the extent that it is otherwise not subject to the content standards in the rules of any self-regulatory organization related to research reports, including those contained in the rules governing communications with the public regarding investment companies or substantially similar standards.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H053571DA7D1643898621B8CECD3AE0C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed as in any way limiting—</text> <paragraph id="H22731684ED9446538D4B58333FAAF0E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicability of the antifraud or antimanipulation provisions of the Federal securities laws and rules adopted thereunder to a covered investment fund research report, including section 17 of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77q">15 U.S.C. 77q</external-xref>), section 34(b) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-33">15 U.S.C. 80a–33</external-xref>), and sections 9 and 10 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78i">15 U.S.C. 78i</external-xref>, 78j); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59D829918B8242A4BF22DBF830A3FE68"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the authority of any self-regulatory organization to examine or supervise a member’s practices in connection with such member’s publication or distribution of a covered investment fund research report for compliance with applicable provisions of the Federal securities laws or self-regulatory organization rules related to research reports, including those contained in rules governing communications with the public, or to require the filing of communications with the public the purpose of which is not to provide research and analysis of covered investment funds.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4ADDFEA991E34FF185CA1503D099D668"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interim effectiveness of safe harbor</header>
 <paragraph id="H6FBBF4601E43415291EAA239F941FA97"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From and after the 270-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, if the Commission has not adopted revisions to section 230.139 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, as required by subsection (a), and until such time as the Commission has done so, a broker or dealer distributing or publishing a covered investment fund research report after such date shall be able to rely on the provisions of section 230.139 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, and the broker or dealer’s publication of such report shall be deemed to satisfy the conditions of subsection (a)(1) or (a)(2) of section 230.139 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, if the covered investment fund that is the subject of such report satisfies the reporting history requirements (without regard to Form S–3 or Form F–3 eligibility) and minimum float provisions of such subsections for purposes of the Commission’s rules and regulations under the Federal securities laws and the rules of any self-regulatory organization, as if revised and implemented in accordance with subsections (a) and (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H30FE5132E68045EE9F09B2F8537DF8EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Status of covered investment fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After such period and until the Commission has adopted revisions to section 230.139 and FINRA has revised rule 2210, for purposes of subsection (c)(7)(O) of such rule, a covered investment fund shall be deemed to be a security that is listed on a national securities exchange and that is not subject to section 24(b) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-24">15 U.S.C. 80a–24(b)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H8A2F222481E848A697668C4D986C8B45"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered investment funds communications</header>
 <subparagraph id="H111B0A50A5ED4FF7A3100C4374651045"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), communications that concern only covered investment funds that fall within the scope of section 24(b) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-24">15 U.S.C. 80a–24(b)</external-xref>) shall not be required to be filed with FINRA.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC14392F662BC4DD491789D87E0382D49"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>FINRA may require the filing of communications with the public if the purpose of those communications is not to provide research and analysis of covered investment funds.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H300CF2BAFA874C7E9486F9798CB99DAE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HD70905B56CEF4228A6D81FBCDE06B24C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered investment fund research report</term> means a research report published or distributed by a broker or dealer about a covered investment fund or any securities issued by the covered investment fund, but not including a research report to the extent that it is published or distributed by the covered investment fund or any affiliate of the covered investment fund.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H44B16162A608470A8F2115E5C48E2CB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>covered investment fund</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H42463DAFD7AE4C11934F88BC8155D362"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an investment company registered under, or that has filed an election to be treated as a business development company under, the Investment Company Act of 1940 and that has filed a registration statement under the Securities Act of 1933 for the public offering of a class of its securities, which registration statement has been declared effective by the Commission; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62A7890309574931A3972644A32CCED4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a trust or other person—</text> <clause id="HA2993082E30E43CBB58233CD8EC26C8E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>issuing securities in an offering registered under the Securities Act of 1933 and which class of securities is listed for trading on a national securities exchange;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3DD98A0FF328476FA92202D86FED9CA3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the assets of which consist primarily of commodities, currencies, or derivative instruments that reference commodities or currencies, or interests in the foregoing; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H15F73A65F9914695A40D3EE08FACC0DA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that provides in its registration statement under the Securities Act of 1933 that a class of its securities are purchased or redeemed, subject to conditions or limitations, for a ratable share of its assets.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB020DD0A0DE4789BD1ED44578EC5803"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>FINRA</term> means the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H057A5BD4995C46CEA67FAD8293699E91"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>research report</term> has the meaning given that term under section 2(a)(3) of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77b">15 U.S.C. 77b(a)(3)</external-xref>), except that such term shall not include an oral communication.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAABB54B7F11247CD95A58EE6494D618F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>self-regulatory organization</term> has the meaning given to that term under section 3(a)(26) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)(26)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
	<attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170501">Passed the House of Representatives May 1, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


