<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5E8686F643334184AF7916D904D6D70A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2346 IH: Support and Defend Our Military Personnel and Their Families Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2346</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170503">May 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000435">Ms. Ros-Lehtinen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to protect the well-being of soldiers and their
			 families, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HD0D513C26DCC41FA8AECC97F2FAE45A5" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB3EDD1502B7E457FA4996CD4FB495C88" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Support and Defend Our Military Personnel and Their Families Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7E5A7D079802428B81A45890083C7F5C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Facilitating naturalization for military personnel</header> <subsection id="HB295ABCA5BD9433680B1542EA2A57F10"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person who has served honorably as a member of the Armed Forces of the United States in support of a contingency operation (as defined in section 101(a)(13) of title 10, United States Code), and who, if separated from the Armed Forces, was separated under honorable conditions, may be naturalized as provided in section 329 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1440">8 U.S.C. 1440</external-xref>) as though the person had served during a period designated by the President under such section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H10568E6EB39644B5B8E54F91C4135199"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Naturalization through service in the Armed Forces of the United States</header><text>Section 328 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1439">8 U.S.C. 1439</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H53FC8C6CEFE34266B85C83972B27BF29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>six months</quote> and inserting <quote>one year</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4586DA8BC9034A9FB34AF6BEBBA9D82C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by striking <quote>six months</quote> and inserting <quote>one year</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8176F220A45645EB89EE50E44F890D92"><enum>3.</enum><header>Timely reunification of military personnel and their nuclear families</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 201(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H6129C817E9B94791ABEADE243639343D" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HA21B98AE67934B2EAA3B8234EB4993ED" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Aliens who are eligible for an immigrant visa under paragraph (2) of section 203(a) and are the spouse, child, son, or daughter of an alien who is serving in the Armed Forces of the United States.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HF84EB046EC4F4599B9311DD537EBB06F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Relief for immediate family members of active duty personnel</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 245 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1255">8 U.S.C. 1255</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9173F902DD334F5CBC9763315748D478" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="HC0DB53B2C58D46FBAF0919AFA3BDCE35"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Relief for immediate family members of active duty personnel</header>
 <paragraph id="H546E82BCC7674DD0966271F517CE73E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may adjust the status of an alien described in paragraph (2) to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0B44B2D6DFA64F27A5BC0836B9ACF812"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the alien makes an application for such adjustment, and is physically present in the United States on the date the application is filed;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB74B99412C2A483F8552F483B0BC6478"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the alien is eligible to receive an immigrant visa and is admissible under section 212(a) (except that paragraphs (4), (6)(A), (7)(A), and (9)(B) of such section shall not apply for purposes of this subsection);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H234C7A0FDBB8449A9F2602D6790136A9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an immigrant visa is immediately available to the alien at the time the application is filed; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6196B424943D422A88415D914CFB2BBD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the alien pays a fee, as determined by the Secretary, for the processing of such application.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H229D586815DC43DCBBC7DCCE3886E192"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible aliens</header>
 <subparagraph id="H9D42FBDD396747CAA9128CA6E0C43E70"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The benefits provided in paragraph (1) shall apply only to an alien who is a parent, spouse, child, son, daughter, or minor sibling of an eligible member of the Armed Forces.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46732EE220AE44C1A729265B0AEB8937"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Posthumous benefits</header><text>An alien described in subparagraph (A) shall continue to be eligible for adjustment under this subsection for 2 years after the death of an eligible member of the Armed Forces whose death was the result of injury or disease incurred in or aggravated by his or her service in the Armed Forces or, if such death occurred prior to the date of enactment of this paragraph, for 2 years after such date of enactment.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H627B59A75C0C4410B7C3FEF61AA59472"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible members of the Armed Forces</header><text>In this subsection, <quote>eligible member of the Armed Forces</quote> means any person who—</text> <subparagraph id="H4E470EC554F24CC297AA1376978B817E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has served honorably in an active duty status in the Armed Forces of the United States; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03034E373C5140C18860AFE9EE77A11A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if separated from the service described in subparagraph (A), was separated under honorable conditions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HA229BD344B0147C0AE7E0DFD673AC998"><enum>5.</enum><header>Factors to consider in initiating removal proceedings against active duty military personnel and
 veterans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 239 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1229">8 U.S.C. 1229</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="H1BD999F33C72431E88A1E2D09FA7CFB2" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H38E93C0D707745338B2791DE4F78199C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Considerations for active duty military personnel and veterans</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E281DBCF96E4BB195E3E5BC28F66F44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A notice to appear shall not be issued against an alien who has served honorably at any time in the Armed Forces of the United States, and who, if separated from the Armed Forces, separated under honorable conditions, without prior approval from the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H70AB80E5F1F44232BA743C28DAF5A5C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Factors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether to issue a notice to appear against such an alien, the Secretary shall consider the alien’s eligibility for naturalization under section 328 or 329, as well as the alien’s record of military service, grounds of deportability applicable to the alien, and any hardship to the Armed Forces, the alien, and his or her family if the alien were to be placed in removal proceedings.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE08DCA6FB8274F48B1F18B7B94961C22"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alien who has served honorably in the Armed Forces of the United States, and who, if separated from the Armed Forces, separated under honorable conditions, shall not be removed from the United States under subparagraph (A)(i) or (B)(iii) of section 235(b)(1), section 238, or section 241(a)(5).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


