<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE6122217C98D4089AF5795A048BC822A" key="H" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2989 RH: Frederick Douglass Bicentennial Commission Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code> 
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 245</calendar> 
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2989</legis-num> 
<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–340]</associated-doc> 
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20170621">June 21, 2017</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HGO00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<action>
<action-date>October 5, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="R000576">Mr. Ruppersberger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000604">Mr. Russell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001199">Mr. Smucker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001293">Mr. Bishop of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000604">Mr. Dent</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney of West Virginia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor></action-desc>
</action>
<action> 
<action-date>October 5, 2017</action-date> 
<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc> 
<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction> 
<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on June 21, 2017</action-instruction> 
</action> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak/></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To establish the Frederick Douglass Bicentennial Commission.<pagebreak/></official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HGO00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HB57019D3A11B458A9E4F6E4FE3F285D3" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H599AF2B2FBD540628EC8DF6EDED2B208" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Frederick Douglass Bicentennial Commission Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H566EC99BED9448598A13F1A9E0454494"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4B20875021824501B48B434658212068"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Born into slavery on the Eastern Shore of Maryland in 1818 and given the name Frederick Augustus Washington Bailey after his mother Harriet Bailey, Frederick Douglass has been called the father of the civil rights movement.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HACD6D7EBC900462A92F554EE1E3BD6DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Douglass rose through determination, brilliance, and eloquence to shape the American Nation. He was an abolitionist, human rights and women’s rights activist, orator, author, journalist, publisher, and social reformer.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H283C039511334973976B5183E701BA32"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Taught basic reading skills by his mistress until she was forced to stop, Douglass continued to teach himself to read and write and taught other slaves to read despite risks including death.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HB66C8B4A5C694E08AD962C49045B5B22"><enum>(4)</enum><text>During the course of his remarkable life Frederick Douglass escaped from slavery, became internationally renowned for his eloquence in the cause of liberty, and went on to serve the national government in several official capacities.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9681228F2A184982B9ECB437D785040B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Forced to leave the country to avoid arrest as an escaped slave, he returned to become a staunch advocate of the Union cause and helped recruit African-American troops for the Union Army, including two of his sons, Charles and Lewis Douglass. His personal relationship with Abraham Lincoln helped persuade the President to make emancipation a cause of the Civil War.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H42D4A496F23D45CC9D6E71E9D34E644C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>With the abolition of slavery at the close of the Civil War, Douglass then turned his attention to the full integration of African-Americans into the political and economic life of the United States. Committed to freedom, Douglass dedicated his life to achieving justice for all Americans, in particular African-Americans, women, and minority groups. He envisioned America as an inclusive Nation strengthened by diversity and free of discrimination.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7D91DFE97E23484B825D7DFE1E2BB158"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Douglass served as an advisor to Presidents. Abraham Lincoln referred to him as the most meritorious man of the nineteenth century. Douglass was appointed to several offices. He served as the United States Marshal of the District of Columbia under Rutherford B. Hayes’ administration; President James Garfield appointed Douglass the District of Columbia Recorder of Deeds. In 1889, President Benjamin Harrison appointed Frederick Douglass to be the United States minister to Haiti. He was also appointed by President Grant to serve as Assistant Secretary of the Commission of Inquiry to Santo Domingo.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D3781D51D85495EA9B0F54991ECEB85"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Douglass lived in the District of Columbia for 23 of his 57 years as a free man, and in recognition of his leadership and continuous fight for justice and freedom, his home, Cedar Hill, was established as a National Historic Site in Anacostia, in Southeast Washington, DC.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1CC84BBCAB984A4588246CF983BA8B83"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The statue of Frederick Douglass in the United States Capitol is a gift from the almost 700,000 residents of the District of Columbia.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H6516269CC72A470BB8105A973E5BE0DA"><enum>(10)</enum><text>All Americans could benefit from studying the life of Frederick Douglass, for Douglass dedicated his own life to ensuring freedom and equality for future generations of Americans. This Nation should ensure that his tireless struggle, transformative words, and inclusive vision of humanity continue to inspire and sustain us.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H151EA37ABBCE4BCE838D80CB3230B767"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The year 2018 marks the bicentennial anniversary of the birth of Frederick Douglass, and a commission should be established to plan, develop, and carry out, and to recommend to Congress, programs and activities that are fitting and proper to celebrate that anniversary in a manner that appropriately honors Frederick Douglass.</text> </paragraph></section> <section id="H9FD2C4AD5894463AB9FFB3C1C1E2E5F1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is established a commission to be known as the Frederick Douglass Bicentennial Commission (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text> </section>
<section id="H7F64805DC1374C9D94F0597E41D87938"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall have the following duties:</text> <paragraph id="H5A6551A8A83B4D65A0DEB1A1A93BA572"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To plan, develop, and carry out programs and activities that are fitting and proper to honor Frederick Douglass on the occasion of the bicentennial anniversary of Douglass’ birth.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB8B2BEA9F3924754B8419C17A509436F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To recommend to Congress programs and activities that the Commission considers fitting and proper to honor Frederick Douglass on such occasion, and the entity or entities in the Federal Government that the Commission considers most appropriate to carry out such programs and activities.</text> </paragraph></section> <section id="H39B160BA263D44F5BB8A45FB53E09605"><enum>5.</enum><header>Membership</header> <subsection id="H96AD56F6E706449EB90688D38406A20E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Number and appointment</header><text>The Commission shall be composed of 16 members appointed as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2A54FC61D69E4F499E1FB52188CADD7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Two members, each of whom shall be a qualified citizen described in subsection (b), appointed by the President.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D666628A64842E7B68CE9DE584F65D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>One member, who shall be a qualified citizen described in subsection (b), appointed by the President on the recommendation of the Governor of Maryland.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H395E89A75345424994CDED2FF010557B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>One member, who shall be a qualified citizen described in subsection (b), appointed by the President on the recommendation of the Governor of Massachusetts.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HCCD1A62E23FC42019B1F638E8E972849"><enum>(4)</enum><text>One member, who shall be a qualified citizen described in subsection (b), appointed by the President on the recommendation of the Governor of New York.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H14C192D37F464A7B8E303C9958D0292C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>One member, who shall be a qualified citizen described in subsection (b), appointed by the President on the recommendation of the Mayor of the District of Columbia.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H69A1806B48BD488CA4CC763B88C056CF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Three members, at least one of whom shall be a Member of the House of Representatives, appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3FA54983894F41B1BBFF1CA8403744CB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Three members, at least one of whom shall be a Senator, appointed by the majority leader of the Senate.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H364C4016668448D795727B1A489EC0ED"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Two members, at least one of whom shall be a Member of the House of Representatives, appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1FD709141F7E451DAB39D726C0FBF296"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Two members, at least one of whom shall be a Senator, appointed by the minority leader of the Senate.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFF225A9E23244CB48BEA79F5D9D361DF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified citizen</header><text>A qualified citizen described in this subsection is a private citizen of the United States with—</text> 
<paragraph id="H576C14CD2D0A488BBCC44532180F22D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a demonstrated dedication to educating others about the importance of historical figures and events; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H52306B8F809140718C922D837F8BA5AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>substantial knowledge and appreciation of Frederick Douglass.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H4FDE3EE1BFDE4B89B252F0747CC7D788"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Time of appointment</header><text>Each initial appointment of a member of the Commission shall be made before the expiration of the 60-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HB7C7138BCF62449C9FEBB8E67B3EDCAF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Continuation of membership</header><text>If a member of the Commission was appointed to the Commission as a Member of Congress, and ceases to be a Member of Congress, that member may continue to serve on the Commission for not longer than the 30-day period beginning on the date that member ceases to be a Member of Congress.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H4D5459A49FC449E3B93CE7B064D5E5DF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>Each member shall be appointed for the life of the Commission.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HB9F176F8196443B596BE64E40C7B3D9F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>A vacancy in the Commission shall not affect the powers of the Commission but shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H42681ECF6D9B48AAA51C701BAF9907DC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Basic pay</header><text>Members shall serve on the Commission without pay.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H02A20E69AED84E67A5EAB238E1E22858"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>Each member shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with sections 5702 and 5703 of title 5, United States Code.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H664AF65E57E6413DB4D4E17A6C746D18"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>Six members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum but a lesser number may hold hearings.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H871533EE68864BCD84C91F4A25253CDE"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The Commission shall select a Chair from among the members of the Commission.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H2B8794053DD04BCAB2B7B135EE1A433A"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Commission shall meet at the call of the Chair. Periodically, the Commission shall hold a meeting in Rochester, New York.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H369475614B5542AF81EF1F90CD735094"><enum>6.</enum><header>Director and staff</header> <subsection id="H0025E6C902E04F1B8A27E417227EE348"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The Commission may appoint and fix the pay of a Director and such additional personnel as the Commission considers to be appropriate.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HD0B1764D9164446F9AB0DE6E053EB461"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability of certain civil service laws</header> 
<paragraph id="HAC69C5889F3343409E4A307CAD1FDD15"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The Director of the Commission may be appointed without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, and may be paid without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of that title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H33C71E72BC7F45C691EACA901A557580"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Staff</header><text>The staff of the Commission shall be appointed subject to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, and shall be paid in accordance with the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of that title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H25976CF593CC4C5FADA07D87CB9D3DA5"><enum>7.</enum><header>Powers</header> 
<subsection id="HFCE1CBAEEA734BF3AD85CD7230BC9B91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Hearings and sessions</header><text>The Commission may, for the purpose of carrying out this Act, hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Commission considers to be appropriate.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H2AD6D939CF574D22A50DA6E52A323C06"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Powers of members and agents</header><text>Any member or agent of the Commission may, if authorized by the Commission, take any action that the Commission is authorized to take by this Act.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H89FEA476EA864E91A9617350190F64A7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Obtaining official data</header><text>The Commission may secure directly from any department or agency of the United States information necessary to enable the Commission to carry out this Act. Upon request of the Chair of the Commission, the head of that department or agency shall furnish that information to the Commission.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HDB4A90B1953A48178E8B5CCC1904EDE0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Mails</header><text>The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the United States.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H612EF02EADEF4D01BD13F5D347108468"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administrative support services</header><text>Upon the request of the Commission, the Administrator of General Services shall provide to the Commission, on a reimbursable basis, the administrative support services necessary for the Commission to carry out its responsibilities under this Act.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HB0DCF5E6EA8C45169F59BEF0481050A7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Gifts</header><text>The Commission may solicit, accept, use, and dispose of gifts, bequests, or devises of money or other property for carrying out its duties.</text> </subsection></section>
<section id="HB36B314AC70F41C5B988A218648A832E"><enum>8.</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<subsection id="H7D3948B602DA442D8D7D392C781846A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than August 1, 2018, the Commission shall submit to Congress an initial report containing its recommendations under section 4(2).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HBA164765DB494D42A83C8442BCB6144C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than June 1, 2019, the Commission shall submit a final report to Congress, and shall include in the final report—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFCE7B2C929FC4AA889F102C9B765B63B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of its activities and programs;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HEDE8E8E4BE324B9FB52BEDFE256CC19F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a final accounting of the funds the Commission received and expended; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF0363225E8D24402BA33D913331E0444"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other information that the Commission considers to be appropriate.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H3D4B0E496F454ED0AF9375F7F09B9708"><enum>9.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall terminate 30 days after submitting the final report pursuant to section 8(b).</text> </section>
</legis-body> 
<endorsement display="yes"> 
<action-date>October 5, 2017</action-date> 
<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement> 
</bill> 


