<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9C6F2CCE78EA434BA7E0CBB07A93FA83" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2189 IH: Trade Protection Not Troll Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2189</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170427">April 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. C&#225;rdenas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend section 337 of the Tariff Act of 1930 with respect to requirements for domestic industries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDB2D0B28CCA14086BFEFAB3C296E519E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H387DD68BF77246628A0F699D5C392ADC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Trade Protection Not Troll Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7104774FCC0D430BB143DB3D9F0AFBC1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to ensure that the resources of the United States International Trade Commission are focused on protecting genuine domestic industries, to restore confidence with the trading partners of the United States that the Commission will not be a duplicative forum for enforcing intellectual property rights when United States district courts are already available, and to safeguard the public health and welfare and the United States economy (including competitive conditions).</text></section>
<section id="H6035F8DEDEE344958BFD5F69A572CA6D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Unfair practices in import trade</header>
<subsection id="HED117324061B42639EB8B6572C20DADE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 337 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1337">19 U.S.C. 1337</external-xref>) is amended as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HA63D09C2AFD54F3ABD480CF7BE7BF6EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subsection (a) is amended—</text>
<subparagraph id="H60005A3F54B645A1B073CB0B034C61F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <clause id="H383D635B8A7944509D79B0669E34A701"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (B);</text></clause>
<clause id="H0710495877C9454782B7D285CC166759"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>engineering, research and development, or licensing.</quote> and inserting <quote>engineering and research and development; or</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8DCF26ECA9AB4D0FA78766C59D6C81C2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding after subparagraph (C) the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C3DA2CE10574A39A91FB130AB8F346D" style="OLC">
<subparagraph id="HC55FE65C2E98493096492657DEA36AA0" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">substantial investment in licensing activities that leads to the adoption and development of articles that incorporate the patent, copyright, trademark, mask work, or design.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7E02D78EAA2E47DF926EB758EBBEE2BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4F37355AFB02430CB87E1A7676C2E1AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71CC4C5BA5134822A692DC0508F36F6B" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H28C5808F205F40BAB733BB70F5E676D6" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (3), the complainant may not rely upon activities by its licensees unless the license leads to the adoption and development of articles that incorporate the claimed patent, copyright, trademark, mask work, or design for sale in the United States.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCB725D5BD410498A9C45263BD3A4DA4D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Subsection (b) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HE96AC562CCA3482B84D613F5404F4223"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting after the first sentence the following: <quote>For a complaint under oath, a person may be relied upon to qualify as an industry under subsection (a)(2) only if the person joins the complaint under oath, except that nothing in this sentence shall be construed to compel such a person to join the complaint.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA2B82E422ECE4C7B9F60E5B29BE315CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H41F0F59AA1004C54A003B182C249DBD2" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H4D0D433363284FCB9C0F993BDF7EA285" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5C92C313867F486880ACD3162B99594D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall identify, at the beginning of an investigation, whether the investigation presents a dispositive issue appropriate for an expedited fact finding and an abbreviated hearing limited to that issue, and shall direct the assigned administrative law judge to rule on such issue early in the investigation. The Commission, in its notice of instituting the investigation, shall set out specific timeframes for such expedited fact finding and hearing.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5ACA2AA6860F4C3095BB2F7B03154E80" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If the Commission identifies a domestic industry as the dispositive issue in question, the Commission shall direct the assigned administrative law judge to expedite fact finding in the investigation on the domestic industry requirement, including an early evidentiary hearing, and to issue an initial determination on this matter within 100 days after the investigation is instituted.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H04349117797F40A2B335562DF058913D" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any initial determination by the assigned administrative law judge under subparagraph (A) or (B) shall stay the investigation pending Commission action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD7613D2AF6344BA3A1B2646A33EE7152"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Subsection (c) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HCE810D9B3E28472F9E3BB6D7238EF6B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking the first sentence and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H529CFD988EF04600BC00A00B683C8208" style="OLC"><text>(1) The Commission shall determine, with respect to each investigation conducted by it under this section, whether or not there is a violation of this section, except that the Commission—</text> <subparagraph id="HBAAE856F802146D4950E98EA491C553E" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may, by issuing a consent order or on the basis of an agreement between the private parties to the investigation, including an agreement to present the matter for arbitration, terminate any such investigation, in whole or in part, without making such a determination; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5570AE6960BA4F079B878BF2034BAACD" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may determine during the course of the investigation that the exclusion of the articles under investigation would not be in the interest of the public, after considering the nature of the articles concerned and the effect of such exclusion upon the public health and welfare, the United States economy (including competitive conditions), the production of like or directly competitive articles by the complainant and its licensees, United States consumers, and any other relevant considerations, and terminate any such investigation, in whole or in part, without making any further determination.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3ADCED910EB84ED0A2A97949C1DF83B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>Each determination</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28AE1C69D3C043BC97E5E8DF2DA6E317" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="HB6BC649F37294092AE2274F7DD81963B" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each determination</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H40CB749955784E21A1E62A6E1E65D165"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>the Federal Circuit for review in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</quote> the following: <quote>In addition, any person adversely affected by a ruling of the Commission under subsection (b)(4) may appeal such ruling, within 60 days after all administrative remedies are exhausted, to the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit for review in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code. In the event that the Commission’s ruling is appealed under this subsection and upon motion by the adversely affected party, the Commission shall stay all further proceedings in the investigation until all appeals are final.</quote>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF5581D47A8804B6999D797191730D342"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking <quote>its findings on the public health and welfare, competitive conditions in the United States economy,</quote> and inserting <quote>its findings on the public health and welfare, the United States economy (including competitive conditions),</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H372030CE54544AE390F2221C2AD6E774"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>by the complainant and its licensees</quote> after <quote>the production of like or directly competitive articles</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF4CCD111AB174F9FB7AE5DAF28EC26C0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (d)(1) is amended by striking the first sentence and inserting the following: <quote>If the Commission determines, as a result of an investigation under this section, that there is a violation of this section and that exclusion of the articles concerned would be in the interest of the public, after considering the nature of the articles concerned and the effect of such exclusion upon the public health and welfare, the United States economy (including competitive conditions), the production of like or directly competitive articles by the complainant and its licensees, United States consumers, and any other relevant considerations, the Commission shall direct that the articles concerned that are imported by any person violating the provision of this section be excluded from entry into the United States.</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H452E0865FD254903B069EC2A677D4412"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Subsection (e)(1) is amended by striking the first sentence and inserting the following: <quote>If, during the course of an investigation under this section, the Commission determines that there is reason to believe that there is a violation of this section and that exclusion of the articles concerned would be in the interest of the public, the Commission may direct that the articles concerned that are imported by any person with respect to whom there is reason to believe that such person is violating this section be excluded from entry into the United States, after considering the nature of the articles concerned and the effect of such exclusion upon the public health and welfare, the United States economy (including competitive conditions), the production of like or directly competitive articles by the complainant and its licensees, United States consumers, and any other relevant considerations.</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA018449AB222445A9E29BB370C26D565"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (f)(1) is amended by striking the first sentence and inserting the following: <quote>In addition to, or in lieu of, taking action under subsection (d) or (e), the Commission may issue and cause to be served on any person violating this section, or believed to be violating this section, as the case may be, an order directing such person to cease and desist from engaging in the unfair methods or acts involved, after considering the nature of the articles concerned and the effect of such exclusion upon the public health and welfare, the United States economy (including competitive conditions), the production of like or directly competitive articles by the complainant and its licensee, United States consumers, and any other relevant considerations.</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC4991C8DC65C4C36BFAB7684996F744B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Subsection (g)(1) is amended by amending the matter following subparagraph (E) to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A0CCC8C18034DA08C5C98241D5C1381" style="OLC">
<quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="section">the Commission shall presume the facts alleged in the complaint to be true and shall, upon request, issue an exclusion from entry or a cease and desist order, or both, limited to that person, after considering the nature of the articles concerned and the effect of such exclusion upon the public health and welfare, the United States economy (including competitive conditions), the production of like or directly competitive articles by the complainant and its licensees, United States consumers, and any other relevant considerations.</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H3EC19178D1F743F0A83E9A5F19578324"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply to complaints filed under section 337 of the Tariff Act of 1930 on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

