<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAE263305464F4A21BC98E52AA05DB892" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2296 IH: Advancing CCUS Technology Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2296</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170502">May 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To increase accountability with respect to Department of Energy carbon capture, utilization, and
			 sequestration projects, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H733BE817541D44E388DF0E0C7CDA3BE6" style="OLC">
 <section id="H324C25613DA544A2942544E59E2B8C65" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advancing CCUS Technology Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H81C7A034755D4143819612510181F92B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Carbon capture, utilization, and sequestration technologies</header> <subsection id="HD82E4E04AF554DCEA4EC234D7B18AC45"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments to the Energy Policy Act of 2005</header> <paragraph id="H2A2C10745BA54878A7BBE22F2CEC46E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fossil energy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 961(a) of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16291">42 U.S.C. 16291(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDAB448B0C2B249CDADD2E7EC40B4736F" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H3DC5D542EAC14B9F976C209D2C1E8F84"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Improving the conversion, use, and storage of carbon dioxide produced from fossil fuels.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDDAB82C3A97149479F9EE6F9CCB9C3C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coal and related technologies program</header><text>Section 962(b)(1) of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16292">42 U.S.C. 16292(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBBA715DE61A34C9C8D5C423BA75F6AE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>during each of calendar years 2008, 2010, 2012, and 2016, and during each fiscal year beginning after September 30, 2021,</quote> and inserting <quote>during each fiscal year beginning after September 30, 2017,</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDFEE0CADBB645A48C5F4A58294AE1A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>allow for large scale demonstration and</quote> after <quote>technologies that would</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H474DD7667AEE4ED092738533B8C0FB3B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>commercial use,</quote> after <quote>use of coal for</quote>.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA3A38AC3E7594E48827A3E44314DF27C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Increased accountability with respect to carbon capture, utilization, and sequestration projects</header>
				<paragraph id="HB494CF6ECF16469587A5CFC8599871CF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>DOE evaluation</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB8583D48D931465BBD7CF2E41341D840"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Energy (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall, in accordance with this subsection, annually conduct an evaluation, and make recommendations, with respect to each project conducted by the Secretary for research, development, demonstration, or deployment of carbon capture, utilization, and sequestration technologies (also known as carbon capture and storage and utilization technologies).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15B19F23FAB04D4586852E33DF6C76A8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Scope</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, a project includes any contract, lease, cooperative agreement, or other similar transaction with a public agency or private organization or person, entered into or performed, or any payment made, by the Secretary for research, development, demonstration, or deployment of carbon capture, utilization, and sequestration technologies.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7DA8CFCD19B4A42949E12AEEADB91F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements for evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting an evaluation of a project under this subsection, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H47C2FFCB836148A081F34E1DF277050A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examine if the project will allow a carbon capture, utilization, and sequestration technology to advance and achieve any specific goal of the project; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8305B11BC45842959EA240FCA9E363DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate and determine if the project has made significant progress in advancing a carbon capture, utilization, and sequestration technology.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DF4BCEADB58447AB1A9DD09185CACFA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each evaluation of a project conducted under this subsection, if the Secretary determines that—</text> <subparagraph id="H287D06C09E3F4A36A7366A8755DA76BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">significant progress in advancing a carbon capture, utilization, and sequestration technology has been made, the Secretary shall assess the funding of the project and make a recommendation as to whether increased funding is necessary to advance the project; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0166EF9C2084569AF3DE5FE6F6A55A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>significant progress in advancing a carbon capture, utilization, and sequestration technology has not been made, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="H27BF1B22088A4FD2AC0C5671C6BFFEA2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assess the funding of the project and make a recommendation as to whether increased funding is necessary to advance the project;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2DF8BF5A259B4E08AB69DA4AA941945B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assess and determine if the project has reached its full potential; and</text> </clause><clause id="H8CC1E05C5965485D94480D0CD5BF727C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>make a recommendation as to whether the project should continue.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1165AAF44724F7E88FFDCC60FB9E44E"><enum>(4)</enum><header> Reports</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7624C6BBC44047F08863EB239DC7E543"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Report on evaluations and recommendations</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="H3425B2F01049421A8AD5F6C9DECDA4FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>issue a report on the evaluations conducted and recommendations made during the previous year pursuant to this subsection; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9B8019828030484EA02ACB38CD167271"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>make each such report available on the Internet Web site of the Department of Energy.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E1715B8FC8845F8891FCBD0618721A9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 3 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Subcommittee on Energy of the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report on—</text>
 <clause id="HB4995DF79CDF473F8373FFB3D0A77D53"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the evaluations conducted and recommendations made during the previous 3 years pursuant to this subsection; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2FBFBEBAD2F3491ABA3AF5C6DF724D4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the progress of the Department of Energy in advancing carbon capture, utilization, and sequestration technologies, including progress in achieving the Department of Energy’s goal of having an array of advanced carbon capture and sequestration technologies ready by 2020 for large-scale demonstration.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


