<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8CDE469A6F1F4329900F910E2B44C9CF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4423 IH: North Texas Water Supply Security Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4423</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171116">November 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000174">Mr. Sam Johnson of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000601">Mr. Ratcliffe</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001036">Mr. Hensarling</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To limit claims under Federal law seeking judicial review of any environmental impact statement,
			 environmental review, or authorization for the Lower Bois d’Arc Creek
			 Reservoir Project in Fannin County, Texas, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H753B49E898154C44BEE8A86815382614" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9E8115BE56EF4EEF9C7D27811994AB81" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>North Texas Water Supply Security Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H080C4D0EA4AA489DAF356B18C3F77F5C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitations on claims under Federal law seeking judicial review of any environmental impact statement, environmental review, and/or authorization for the Lower Bois d’Arc Creek Reservoir Project in Fannin County, Texas</header> <subsection id="H42AF9534F1714DE2A2CF05C6D53DC561"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header> <paragraph id="HBAFD7CF6D6EE484F9FBB8FD36E63ADCC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <quote>agency</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1246AD90232046CABDDC2BC9D4C41609"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>The term <quote>authorization</quote> means any license, permit, approval, finding, determination, certification, or other administrative decision issued by an agency or a State agency acting under delegated or other Federal authority that is required or authorized under Federal law in order to site, construct, reconstruct, or commence operations of the reservoir project.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5D8D30D7348A4F56B4541D3AE9512DDB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Environmental impact statement</header><text>The term <quote>environmental impact statement</quote> means the detailed statement required under section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8781576B263241F9B3CF373DEDE499E3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Environmental review</header><text>The term <quote>environmental review</quote> means procedures and processes conducted to comply with section 102 of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8CA81B8773D4F1388EB19885FAD5C13"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Project sponsor</header><text>The term <quote>project sponsor</quote> means the North Texas Municipal Water District.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0006176C5AB478D982CC18BC1C17D35"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reservoir project</header><text>The term <quote>reservoir project</quote> means the Lower Bois d’Arc Creek Reservoir Project located in Fannin County, Texas, proposed for construction by the North Texas Municipal Water District.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H74213E6625CB4B0FA2AF54088558218B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a claim arising under Federal law seeking judicial review of any environmental impact statement, environmental review, and/or authorization issued by an agency or a State agency acting under delegated or other Federal authority for the reservoir project shall be barred unless—</text>
 <paragraph id="H65B54071456A41B8BD35865EB9F4884A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the action is filed not later than 60 days after the date of publication in the Federal Register of the final record of decision or approval or, unless a shorter time is specified in Federal law under which judicial review is allowed; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE403D90F37E94CF5B83BE74082EB8B4E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of an action pertaining to an environmental impact statement for, environmental review of, or authorization for the reservoir project, the action is filed by a party that submitted a comment during the public comment period on the revised draft environmental impact statement for the reservoir project.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H37A7FCEE18C1441B8FE26EE9C9F8C425"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Separate action</header><text>The final agency action that follows preparation of a supplemental environmental impact statement, if required, shall be considered a separate final agency action, and the deadline for filing a claim for judicial review shall be 60 days after the date of the Federal Register notice of the final agency action.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H81B8D9AD3750461BB79F84A757CF5F4D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>District court venue and deadline</header><text>All actions related to the reservoir project—</text> <paragraph id="H260A6F53D7C84BB69CE301636780C898"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be brought in the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Texas; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H30E45F9A362C4C17B401F4ACFC0B2F57"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be resolved as expeditiously as possible.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEE2CAF2523904566A96ABBA174A677C6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Injunctive relief</header> <paragraph id="H8999ABBDEC984912A3EB58B902478709"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to considering any other applicable equitable factors, in any motion for a temporary restraining order or any injunction against an agency, a State agency acting under delegated or other Federal authority or the project sponsor in connection with review or authorization of the reservoir project, the court shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB7500869EAFC48478C9D53A6B32E8543"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider the potential effects on public health, safety, and the environment, and the potential for significant negative economic effects resulting from an order or injunction;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEE8D86689ED4E9991CCFB3E886D3BF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not presume that the harms described in subparagraph (A) are reparable;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H546358A6910E4A03B52EBBFBDA0AF1CE"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not waive or limit the requirements of Federal Rule of Civil Procedure 65(c) as to any movant for a temporary restraining order or injunction; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC42E8C5ECA8548E996361B52354409DC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>determine the amount of security described in subparagraph (C) in the same proceeding in which the court considers the temporary restraining order or any injunction.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H659550BF96EA4C51BB57498EB9789076"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Security</header><text>With respect to the security described in paragraph (1)(C)—</text> <subparagraph id="H757C8A0EE8D2450D9DDBB56125ACA1D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an order granting injunctive relief shall not be effective unless and until such security has been posted by the movant;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0278C849A1F040678002F6A7E411CB11"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an order granting injunctive relief shall require such security to be posted within 15 calendar days or less from the issuance of the order; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55F6153738EB4C8E8EEFEF95FB1D0A50"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if the movant fails to post such security within the time provided in an order granting injunctive relief, the order granting injunctive relief automatically terminates.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB22159CA8F2D4B36AB0391E1A0202070"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this section—</text> <paragraph id="HDF958118A624483FB8EB5200A88A9FAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>creates a right to judicial review;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4C53DABD1A84FF1B0D951BAFBB595A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supersedes, amends, or modifies any Federal statute or affects the responsibility of any State or Federal officer to comply with or enforce any statute;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7B4880E874D4E5F9BB61C9631CC6FB6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>creates a presumption that the reservoir project will be approved or favorably reviewed by any agency or a State agency acting under delegated or other Federal authority; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5FB7CF1B7A554232B8FB8646C60F52A7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>places any limit on filing a claim that a person has violated the terms or conditions of a permit, license, approval, or certification.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


