<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H91E94D3E42F24457B0E73AB9B7130408" key="H" public-private="public">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4395 IH: Geospatial Data Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4395</legis-num>
<current-chamber></current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20171115">November 15, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To improve the coordination and use of geospatial data.</official-title>
</form> 
<legis-body id="HB72978C9DB144C928FEC81905188971F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H203011730EE544A49A5DAD6D726C3EA7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Geospatial Data Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H0B4CE58502AA4DD88F3CC387894C7FCF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA6B63D8101364EF89BA33E741919F6E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Advisory Committee</term> means the National Geospatial Advisory Committee described in section 4(a);</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE231EDAE3F34116A071E745837AAA96"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Committee</term> means the Federal Geographic Data Committee established under section 3(a);</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA1EE4D6D2BDE4A45AD7F8131D7D064B0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>covered agency</term> means an agency, as defined in section 551 of title 5, United States Code, that collects, produces, acquires, maintains, distributes, uses, or preserves geospatial data on paper or in electronic form to fulfill the mission of the agency, either directly or through a relationship with another organization, including a State, local government, Indian tribe, institution of higher education, business partner or contractor of the Federal Government, and the public;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HD29C89999A724E02B991F9DFB5EB6233"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>GeoPlatform</term> means the GeoPlatform described in section 8(a);</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5BA7B2DE78B646A2901AB00F0C2852FC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>geospatial data</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HDA16678DA6794F5D956EB434B61CBF4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means information that is tied to a location on the Earth, including by identifying the geographic location and characteristics of natural or constructed features and boundaries on the Earth, and that is generally represented by points (for example a well), lines (for example a road), polygons (for example a forest), or other complex geographic features or phenomena (for example a forest fire, the spread of West Nile virus, or the infestation of pine-bark beetles);</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD9B9159598CB45499335C95DA0511D81"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be derived from, among other things, remote sensing, mapping, and surveying technologies;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5DAC98EB2B614B9A806C44305935DB12"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes images and raster datasets, aerial photographs, and other forms of geospatial data or datasets in digitized or non-digitized form; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7A1B46A315EF4604BABDD8271107901D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>does not include—</text> <clause id="HB0222AE891C14C6BAE3C2B8C05FBBD32"><enum>(i)</enum><text>geospatial data activities of an Indian tribe not carried out, in whole or in part, using Federal funds, as determined by the tribal government;</text> </clause>
<clause id="H981CF03C18874589A5C78F2473486079"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>classified national security-related geospatial data activities of the Department of Defense, unless declassified under Executive Order 12951, as determined by the Secretary of Defense;</text> </clause> <clause id="H86E6A1E625AD40ABB41289692955607D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>classified national security-related geospatial data activities of the Department of Energy, unless declassified under Executive Order 12951, as determined by the Secretary of Energy; or</text> </clause>
<clause id="H4092D507B6854F67AF4B73429694633D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>intelligence geospatial data activities, as determined by the Director of National Intelligence;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C6D82AC345F4E09A5D866BB52BAB310"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the meaning given that term under section 4 of the <act-name parsable-cite="ISDA">Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/450b">25 U.S.C. 450b</external-xref>);</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0984AE83B64845D4B29F916265D5784D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given that term under section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>);</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF1F3420A619A4A749DE7910A942D46FF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the term <term>lead covered agency</term> means a lead covered agency for an NGDA data theme designated under section 6(b)(1);</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3D1C9733EE3B4588A895255F2E7604BD"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the term <term>local government</term> means any city, county, township, town, borough, parish, village, or other general purpose political subdivision of a State;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD5DF20E78CE4C0E95B93F32EEEDE834"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the term <term>metadata for geospatial data</term> means information about geospatial data, including the content, source, vintage, accuracy, condition, projection, responsible party, contact phone number, method of collection, and other characteristics or descriptions of the geospatial data;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE929A9C20FAC4B46BD42D895621922E7"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the term <term>NGDA data theme</term> means the National Geospatial Data Asset core geospatial datasets (including electronic records and coordinates) relating to a topic or subject designated under section 6;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0CC450929F546478A1173F4869ADAF8"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the term <term>National Spatial Data Infrastructure</term> means the technology, policies, criteria, standards, and employees necessary to promote geospatial data sharing throughout the Federal Government, State, tribal, and local governments, and the private sector (including nonprofit organizations and institutions of higher education); and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC41B27BED4D64964B8D8154E4772FB5D"><enum>(13)</enum><text>the term <term>proven practices</term> means methods and activities that advance the use of geospatial data for the benefit of society.</text> </paragraph></section> <section id="H26183180A10B48A7B950E6317E1E3423"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal Geographic Data Committee</header> <subsection id="H172B5E579B5F48CC865C307A7817E168"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Office of Management and Budget an interagency committee to be known as the Federal Geographic Data Committee, which shall act as the lead entity in the executive branch for the development, implementation, and review of policies, practices, and standards relating to geospatial data.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H819F862D7EC14904832E8BB67AEF894A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header> 
<paragraph id="HC4F4448C94774177935A9E496C6DF519"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chairperson and Vice Chairperson</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget and the Secretary of the Interior shall serve as Chairperson of the Committee and Vice Chairperson of the Committee, respectively.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6ADBEC590CF45ECA3EE194FBF8B0938"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other members</header><text>The President shall appoint the other members of the Committee from among the officers and employees of covered agencies.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H4167EF2F83E0421A94A242AC34338823"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Committee shall—</text> <paragraph id="H6ACA90793A8541569543B9E52098AA3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>lead the development and management of and operational decision making for the National Spatial Data Infrastructure strategic plan and geospatial data policy in accordance with section 5;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC6E156DAA4DF4835BA07A84FF205E84F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>designate NGDA data themes and oversee the coordinated management of the NGDA data themes in accordance with section 6;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H7CD227A10582485986401B8300D9A4CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish and maintain geospatial data standards in accordance with section 7;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD0A4E0B413A14316A62F42C510CAB6F9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>periodically review and determine the extent to which covered agencies comply with geospatial data standards;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H765CE5A0A3294BE592FE52C9C1814C47"><enum>(5)</enum><text>ensure that the GeoPlatform operates in accordance with section 8;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF672CAE0676A4665B464E77A483F68AB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>direct and facilitate national implementation of the system of NGDA data themes;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H599857074B5B4683B1AB9575188764E2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>communicate with and foster communication among covered agencies and other entities and individuals relating to geospatial data technology development, transfer, and exchange in order to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1A9BDE72A443451FBEAB0578ADA4CB13"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify and meet the needs of users of geospatial data;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA7A405B32D614980A9DB3F2F491FBA63"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promote cost-effective data collection, documentation, maintenance, distribution, and preservation strategies; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7C41E3D49EEA46CDB06ED68AAB67004E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>leverage Federal and non-Federal resources;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEFF4197BB47C4BA8B48663879FF0788B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>define roles and responsibilities and promote and guide cooperation and coordination among agencies of the Federal Government, State, tribal, and local governments, institutions of higher education, and the private sector in the collection, production, sharing, and use of geospatial information, the implementation of the National Spatial Data Infrastructure, and the identification of proven practices;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4DDD38B4959B429E9A54BD13D112B3C2"><enum>(9)</enum><text>coordinate with international organizations having an interest in the National Spatial Data Infrastructure or global spatial data infrastructures;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HC355B9B8698D4D3CA697AC75EFB8A5C1"><enum>(10)</enum><text>make available online and update at least annually—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCF292CBE96A5403D8839B76A69D55459"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of the status for each NGDA data theme, based on the report submitted by the applicable lead covered agency under section 6(b)(3)(E)(ii)(I), which shall include—</text> <clause id="H9329059D65124CE9B659412440D5AEBE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an evaluation of the progress of each lead covered agency in achieving the requirements under subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (D) of section 6(b)(3); and</text> </clause>
<clause id="H7E2E2415DCC4404ABA0219843CCFF5FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a determination of whether, for each of subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (D) of section 6(b)(3), each lead covered agency meets expectations, has made progress toward expectations, or fails to meet expectations;</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6634C1345F4D45B5824D2F50FD6A8008"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a summary and evaluation of the achievements of each covered agency, based on the annual report submitted by the covered agency under section 9(b)(1), which shall include a determination of whether the covered agency meets expectations, has made progress toward expectations, or fails to meet expectations for each of paragraphs (1) through (14) of section 9(a);</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5A709440A1F84AEDAAA72F5371A4D359"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a collection of periodic technical publications, management articles, and reports related to the National Spatial Data Infrastructure; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFC20CC14D8494A9AAA907D1C3FD09DA1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a membership directory for the Committee, including identifying members of any subcommittee or working group of the Committee;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDD6312EB1E2F45D2862B73D6F929AF9E"><enum>(11)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H705D3BA7C8DC400C81AFFE77F0ED1724"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make available to and request comments from the Advisory Committee regarding the summaries and evaluations required under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (10);</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD05D0640691249CAA17B0A1133A36B5B" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if requested by the Advisory Committee, respond to any comments by the Advisory Committee; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3FBD9CEAD052410AA1339EB2C616E347" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not less than once every 2 years, submit to Congress a report that includes the summaries and evaluations required under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (10), the comments of the Advisory Committee, and the responses of the Committee to the comments;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H357550C35719457D86C1C13F8F4164DC"><enum>(12)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5A639579B18947C59A37BCFEB2397A54"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make available to and request comments from covered agencies regarding the summaries and evaluations required under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (10); and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H91B347624B444BE39E3D0ECAFF2974FB" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less than once every 2 years, submit to Congress a report that includes the comments of the covered agencies and the responses of the Committee to the comments; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3F69D0BE91474A0D98C0EF61D4646C42"><enum>(13)</enum><text>support and promote the infrastructure of networks, systems, services, and standards that provide a digital representation of the Earth to users for many applications.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H6180BE695562450E98B5754B92C82FBD"><enum>4.</enum><header>National Geospatial Advisory Committee</header> 
<subsection id="H03373F7333F44BB0B27A457E5BB28F83"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is in the Department of the Interior the National Geospatial Advisory Committee to provide advice and recommendations to the Chairperson of the Committee.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HECCDDF4199534EE89405CFA06DDF0F59"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header> <paragraph id="HB3F9C1D4DBBF4F0F9E752F5F97608841"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall be composed of 30 members who shall be—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4120ACDBFB00481B8EB951AFACE46091"><enum>(A)</enum><text>appointed by the Chairperson of the Committee;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7F74A2753285438AA584724610D97603"><enum>(B)</enum><text>selected—</text> 
<clause id="HEC93FF0666FF47E59AA3378198DBFDF5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to generally achieve a balanced representation of the viewpoints of various interested parties involved in national geospatial activities and the development of the National Spatial Data Infrastructure; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H12DAED749AC3496DA6D713382299E945"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with consideration of a geographic balance of residence of the members; and</text> </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4A1F4C5599A4405C93A2E074B2649523"><enum>(C)</enum><text>selected from among groups involved in the geospatial community, including—</text> <clause id="H6C21DADEE97C4B9FAFE73B307F8A8A2D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>States;</text> </clause>
<clause id="H8AE0184C00704217883E35C1AFE7CD76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>local governments;</text> </clause> <clause id="H25E765989EFF414FAE86F024D83249D5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>regional governments;</text> </clause>
<clause id="HE1BF6DBCA166472BA91F937B31EC2682"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>tribal governments;</text> </clause> <clause id="HA75E3D840A77444BA73DE95A07566A3F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>private sector entities;</text> </clause>
<clause id="H50963BB9432A4018A9EA3F3AB6368F49"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>geospatial information user industries;</text> </clause> <clause id="H290382CDEBD94D18B1F558D2EA724B5C"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>professional associations;</text> </clause>
<clause id="HBE5BAFB55F9E4A0DB3DD951F7A75DD25"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>scholarly associations;</text> </clause> <clause id="HA7CC9513B9ED430B978B2F2EF96FB50E"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>nonprofit organizations;</text> </clause>
<clause id="H3FB5432AB91D41ABBE35CAE3E5B0A539"><enum>(x)</enum><text>academia; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H84165C8CE8E6442F93F7D149410C5F41"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>the Federal Government.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8663F242D30D49079505C92E13BA0D43"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Chairperson of the Committee shall appoint the Chairperson of the Advisory Committee.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF7C00EFBD1124B92AB211FFE828C2EC0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Period of appointment; vacancies</header> <subparagraph id="HDEFF14BF51404CF9830DCB8CC067EA3F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Members shall be appointed for a term of 3 years, with the term of <fraction>1/3</fraction> of the members expiring each year.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9AE509388460482785DE3E8766E8C688"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>Any vacancy in the Advisory Committee shall not affect its powers, but shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E305DF5F40247148F6DD9707CDF0A4F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limit on terms</header><text>An individual—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8192DB48BD8A4652B9D5E31AF03F8F49"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may not be appointed to more than 2 consecutive terms as a member of the Advisory Committee; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H29AE297ABFFF4E98A7319665117E7B82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after serving for 2 consecutive terms, is eligible to be appointed as a member of the Advisory Committee on and after the date that is 2 years after the end of the second consecutive term of the individual as a member of the Advisory Committee.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1BB79F8AD31E46959D47ABFBC6AD526B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Ethical requirements</header><text>A member of the Advisory Committee may not participate in any specific-party matter (including a lease, license, permit, contract, claim, agreement, or related litigation) with the Department of the Interior in which the member has a direct financial interest.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H086A420D1C2B458DB3BF00E76CC5E4E0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Incumbents</header> <subparagraph id="H3D3789996883421AA952EC35AD73CE41"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An individual serving on the day before the date of enactment of this Act as a member of the National Geospatial Advisory Committee established by the Secretary of the Interior may serve as a member of the Advisory Committee until the end of the term of the individual under the appointment.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6DFFC3F04BDC46E99425C58A7F5F28EB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limit on terms</header><text>Any period of service as a member of the National Geospatial Advisory Committee established by the Secretary of the Interior shall be considered a period of service as a member of the Advisory Committee for purposes of paragraph (4).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2404EDB14B074B9F8D81813A513B9A91"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Subcommittees</header><text>A subcommittee of the Advisory Committee—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6FFC4A45B88A494A8045AFF1FDC884F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may be formed for the purposes of compiling information or conducting research;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HFFEA13FF3EB94401A7EBD83FDABFA446"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be composed of members appointed by the Chairperson of the Advisory Committee;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H000CD00A4CC148EFACC228B6AF0879D2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall act only under the direction of the Chairperson of the Advisory Committee;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H446C54CECFFD45F4A4EB81683C93E672"><enum>(4)</enum><text>shall report the recommendations of the subcommittee to the Advisory Committee for consideration; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H24848E2F89F2494BB56EB9A78BFBF23B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>shall meet as necessary to accomplish the objectives of the subcommittee, subject to the approval of the Chairperson of the Advisory Committee and the availability of resources.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCD2CDBE4BF8A44E284D6E6FB8AF28FB1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header> <paragraph id="H9C43B48F5A754AE6A49D3786385F588B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall meet at the call of the Chairperson, not less than 1 time each year and not more than 4 times each year.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB26FB8EF35B742E6B97A601F71FACED2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members of the Advisory Committee shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number of members may hold meetings or hearings.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFBD65B9D23AB4D4B9AD96789A50C7292"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duties of the Advisory Committee</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE88146323E024690B2B066A64C57C375"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide advice and recommendations relating to—</text> <subparagraph id="HD33E4BBE5501423B8DEC7C0C5D260FF2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the management of Federal and national geospatial programs;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H46CCB83BD5E047538C3008B8E11C8E8B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the development of the National Spatial Data Infrastructure; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDEDFFE69C55645148308E7D9F204CB2F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>implementation of this Act;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H80F158FB2A72452398D5215BA1F035DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>review and comment on geospatial policy and management issues; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H9718F0D683C44AF1A66ABDB73C931BD7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure the views of representatives of non-Federal interested parties involved in national geospatial activities are conveyed to the Committee.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9929BB7B0940441787AACED0E8D16E0E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Powers of the Advisory Committee</header> 
<paragraph id="HDB6390757E7D4ED585A997386973AEFD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text>The Advisory Committee may hold such meetings or hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Advisory Committee considers advisable to carry out this Act.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H989F5A8D521942818E4E30E96EDF0953"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information from covered agencies</header> <subparagraph id="H0EDF921BD8B443A18F5C1E04472C522C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Advisory Committee may secure directly from any covered agency such information as the Advisory Committee considers necessary to carry out this Act. Upon request of the Chairperson of the Advisory Committee, the head of such agency shall furnish such information to the Advisory Committee.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7917FC7340174AC98B23AD3450D03B23"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Noncooperation</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall include in the comments of the Advisory Committee submitted under section 3(c)(11) a discussion of any failure by a covered agency to furnish information in response to a request under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9816F88AFDAD4D18A65FFC06A193AA66"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Postal services</header><text>The Advisory Committee may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other agencies of the Federal Government.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H95858584B72E4833B43051A124A614C0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Gifts</header><text>The Advisory Committee—</text> <subparagraph id="HBEA41B2BA0FC4274B113BA8B7AC59D57"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may accept, use, and dispose of gifts or donations of services or property; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H67AEFFC9BD2F44B2933B2C9862F45F2B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall establish rules for the acceptance, use, and disposition of gifts and donations that avoid any conflict of interest or appearance of a conflict of interest.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBE15B82FCCF64D3389E88646BAE191D1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Advisory Committee personnel matters</header> <paragraph id="HBC1534B950E34DD5856DE5335421438B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No compensation of members</header> <subparagraph id="H4822CBBD1D2849CCB86A261E0E1F5F53"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Non-federal employees</header><text>A member of the Advisory Committee who is not an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall serve without compensation.</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE1E5D4479DA344E2906D0903E5CACCF0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federal employees</header><text>A member of the Advisory Committee who is an officer or employee of the Federal Government shall serve without compensation in addition to the compensation received for the services of the member as an officer or employee of the Federal Government.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H21A1562049A944A2B9BB827AE4B6139F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>The members of the Advisory Committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Advisory Committee.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4D207FC62DD34AAEA61FA66C9242FD77"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Detail of government employees</header><text>Any Federal Government employee may be detailed to the Advisory Committee without reimbursement, and such detail shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H02F8C24EBD19459F9694C981B32D0650"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Applicability of FACA</header> <paragraph id="H2A5F74588C0B4D7C93F507502C4F42C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall apply to the Advisory Committee.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3A6F9F31FF6F45E0AB8109B6165610BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No termination</header><text>Section 14(a)(2) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall not apply to the Advisory Committee.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE0F5FDF078224185861EACE77EAF1700"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Termination</header> <paragraph id="H2A4E991C723C4A5ABB52BC1B24571DAE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Advisory Committee shall terminate 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB197CFEBEF254CAFA41E9E5201E0787B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continuation</header><text>The Advisory Committee may be continued for successive 10-year periods by action taken by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to renew the Advisory Committee before the date on which the Advisory Committee would otherwise terminate.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HFC959D3D6D94439AA07A8F1C09ABF805"><enum>5.</enum><header>National Spatial Data Infrastructure</header> <subsection id="H3E37E53BB51143598235E755E696E48A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The National Spatial Data Infrastructure shall ensure that geospatial data from multiple sources (including the Federal Government, State, local, and tribal governments, the private sector, and institutions of higher education) is available and easily integrated to enhance the understanding of the physical and cultural world.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="H6858005FC8BF41E6A6A1E3C178445183"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The goals of the National Spatial Data Infrastructure are to—</text> <paragraph id="HE0BA8D3E07FD47839F64BD58FF723AB6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H916DEE158396477EBA37BF2346B607C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the privacy and security of the personal data of individuals and accuracy of statistical information on individuals, both in raw form and in derived information products;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF149121898544D0BA7362B0A571FE7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>free access for the public to geospatial data, information, and interpretive products, in accordance with Office of Management and Budget Circular A–130, or any successor thereto;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2E0A6E9AC3034DBC8BAFB91AF6A35CA0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the protection of proprietary interests related to licensed information and data; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2BAB9EAA195424BA5A8131E360B8EF5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the interoperability of Federal information systems to enable the drawing of resources from covered agencies and partners of covered agencies; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H76DB69A385A044EEB64C5DD0A86E07DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support and advance the establishment of a Global Spatial Data Infrastructure, consistent with national security, national defense, national intelligence, and international trade requirements, including ensuring that covered agencies develop international geospatial data in accordance with international voluntary consensus standards, as defined in Office of Management and Budget Circular A–119, or any successor thereto.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H18DDCFE3C64E4B848F9002CAF277A616"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Strategic plan</header><text>The Committee shall prepare and maintain a strategic plan for the development and implementation of the National Spatial Data Infrastructure in a manner consistent with national security, national defense, and emergency preparedness program policies regarding data accessibility.</text> </subsection>
<subsection id="HA29F8B48F95A4F919789C2DE2FB4FD9C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Advisory role</header><text>The Committee shall advise Federal and non-Federal users of geospatial data on their responsibilities relating to implementation of the National Spatial Data Infrastructure.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H25C35E4339DA4D72A9698C4D29A823D2"><enum>6.</enum><header>NGDA data themes</header> <subsection id="H91E76F5C450D40B0A8E4B0686BAAF092"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Committee shall designate as NGDA data themes the primary topics and subjects for which the coordinated development, maintenance, and dissemination of geospatial data will benefit the Federal Government and the interests of the people of the United States, which shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1B650EBE64BF402198D351E86149CDCF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be representations of conceptual topics describing digital spatial information for the Nation; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D046D30B10F4D4CBBB5E3BDE354E999"><enum>(2)</enum><text>contain associated datasets (with attribute records and coordinates)—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF566C735824E439D9206DE0C612BDEA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that are documented, verifiable, and officially designated to meet recognized standards;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83581736352543F0B746825283F6A774"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that may be used in common; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC32B1C2A50CF44E2BA778B158697D737"><enum>(C)</enum><text>from which other datasets may be derived.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD61AF19D5C91429EBD5E9647DF44A6D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Lead covered agencies</header> <paragraph id="HA3CB96B4BA7444C694B5B6EF91F36DC4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For each NGDA data theme, the Committee shall designate one or more covered agencies as the lead covered agencies for the NGDA data theme.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC153F64B2B5E4B5D9E849452E03FD019"><enum>(2)</enum><header>General responsibility</header><text>The lead covered agencies for an NGDA data theme shall be responsible for ensuring the coordinated management of the data, supporting resources (including technology and personnel), and related services and products of the NGDA data theme.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H72FF8B5F08C848B5B5A4F6E4142F58C9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Specific responsibilities</header><text>To assist in fulfilling the responsibilities under paragraph (2) with respect to an NGDA data theme, the lead covered agencies shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5D6D0795F5A04B2EA43ACF37C6DDA455"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide leadership and facilitate the development and implementation of geospatial data standards for the NGDA data theme, with a particular emphasis on a data content standard for the NGDA data theme, including by—</text> <clause id="H10BC2D1DD68C4E19AF1AAB5FAE40A01A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assessing existing standards;</text> </clause>
<clause id="H08BC1CD927CC46AE85DA4ACCE66DE7C0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identifying anticipated or needed data standards; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H45D54C2667544308A4F415B871158AA1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>developing a plan to originate and implement needed standards with relevant community and international practices—</text> 
<subclause id="HC2FD9488E7F9465E89E9C783B9874492"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in accordance with Office of Management and Budget Circular A–119, or any successor thereto; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="HAFAA56574ADE43DB847ECE24F8A5A938"><enum>(II)</enum><text>consistent with or as a part of the plan described in subparagraph (B);</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCE32763AAF3E4BEBB76A5BCF1646B153"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide leadership and facilitate the development and implementation of a plan for nationwide population of the NGDA data theme, which shall—</text> <clause id="H7F63B91250A34F78B63258D35412DCE0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>include developing partnership programs with States, Indian tribes, institutions of higher education, private sector entities, other Federal agencies, and local governments;</text> </clause>
<clause id="H7E823129F2E24A4B87F448975156225C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meet the needs of users of geospatial data;</text> </clause> <clause id="H180A67F8883D4112B395697D7C5BF0B0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>address human and financial resource needs;</text> </clause>
<clause id="H6E60C584439B4C029FB9741D7E9BF1A9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>identify needs relating to standards, metadata for geospatial data within the NGDA data theme, and the GeoPlatform; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H7E5CC7C2FD264DC28DB7230041AAA0A4"><enum>(v)</enum><text>expedite the development of necessary NGDA data themes;</text> </clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1A998D1242B14B4291E5F694F01AFCBB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establish goals that support the strategic plan for the National Spatial Data Infrastructure prepared under section 5(c);</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1179CBD161734F63B52333FA04045A18"><enum>(D)</enum><text>as necessary, collect and analyze information from users of geospatial data within the NGDA data theme regarding the needs of the users for geospatial data and incorporate the needs of users in strategies relating to the NGDA data theme; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7654E40AF0FC46AAA4DF1C9CC048F23A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>as part of administering the NGDA data theme—</text> <clause id="H08D40263771C45E9A39EF8B662D5BDD8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>designate a point of contact within the lead covered agency who shall be responsible for developing, maintaining, coordination relating to, and disseminating data using the GeoPlatform;</text> </clause>
<clause id="HD7C9737E41FA44689CFA7C8D83A06734"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit to the Committee—</text> <subclause id="H24F6790F07424410A917E9CC7A8424A1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a performance report, at least annually, that documents the activities relating to and implementation of the NGDA data theme, including progress in achieving the requirements under subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (D); and</text> </subclause>
<subclause id="H71D065D9D44F43E99AFBBE139C724C0C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>comments, as appropriate, regarding the summary and evaluation of the performance report provided by the Committee under section 3(c)(12);</text> </subclause></clause> <clause id="H2C0C786B71BA49E798E0740D4486F854"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>publish maps or comparable graphics online (in accordance with the mapping conventions specified by the Committee) showing the extent and status of the NGDA data themes for which the covered agency is a lead covered agency;</text> </clause>
<clause id="H62A728F4B7F543ADAD1D0C8699E53373"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>encourage individuals and entities that are a source of geospatial data or metadata for geospatial data for the NGDA data theme to provide access to such data through the GeoPlatform;</text> </clause> <clause id="H3D8A0A49E3324A24BB862EE25C895E39"><enum>(v)</enum><text>coordinate with the GeoPlatform; and</text> </clause>
<clause id="HB39154CD83824DD6AD9C182C7A9BD129"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>identify and publish proven practices for the use and application of geospatial data of the lead covered agency.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HEE08BB5E2A0946968ED39735FEE45274"><enum>7.</enum><header>Geospatial data standards</header> <subsection id="HF358C678E4574822B63D2CC9C7431B15"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with section 216 of the E-Government Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/44/3501">44 U.S.C. 3501</external-xref> note), the Committee shall establish standards for each NGDA data theme, which—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA9FBEFA2BFAB497192A8DE0C1E775C6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HEA327EE162034767BE532E84D20E9E31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>rules, conditions, guidelines, and characteristics for the geospatial data within the NGDA data theme and related processes, technology, and organization; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6CDF5F6595BE4DDE8910064A1F0C8A80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>content standards for metadata for geospatial data within the NGDA data theme;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H015E0F14E42F4E028FF94FF5EB22AC72"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, shall be consistent international standards and protocols; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB21C593D430A4F8584FE0D05C051518B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Committee shall periodically review and update as necessary for the standards to remain current, relevant, and effective.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H66375A5282644DC0966BADA3514EFF8E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development of standards</header><text>The Committee shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF36DD7DB73774567B22C7A1B32471A9D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and promulgate standards under this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H9D2535EE70E54A91B913060D065BA9AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in accordance with Office of Management and Budget Circular A–119, or any successor thereto; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H72201507791F4F14BB07EC25060DA37D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after consultation with a broad range of data users and providers;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B14711F3BB248C1A9E682D02D46506E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the maximum extent possible, use national and international standards adopted by voluntary standards consensus bodies; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H66BC405744E64A9586DADD1E26DE8319"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish new standards only to the extent standards described in paragraph (2) do not exist.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0343DD8E0A1D4DAC9B46C5D20BE2546C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall withhold from public disclosure any information the disclosure of which reasonably could be expected to cause damage to the national interest, security, or defense of the United States, including information relating to geospatial intelligence data activities, as determined in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence.</text> </subsection></section>
<section id="H06250B8FCC3847589A0FDEFE0579ACD5"><enum>8.</enum><header>GeoPlatform</header> 
<subsection id="HB8A13A11CFBB426CB23CC86660F3F584"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Committee shall operate an electronic service that provides access to geospatial data and metadata for geospatial data, to be known as the GeoPlatform.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HC43E47EAE2734C9CB357ECE2C6B6DF5C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The GeoPlatform—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFD69476D42CF46C7B3818BD666B2353D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HB881A3D1487A47B7B94E71E13C94C5E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be available through the internet and other communications means;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7ACA6F5606984E998BB8AC81D69DFDE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be accessible through a common interface;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H757C5C42081B41598C0BCCC149F1AE04"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include all geospatial data collected by covered agencies, directly or indirectly; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H490F5DB9001B492993C702487196254A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>include a set of programming instructions and standards providing an automated means of accessing available geospatial data, which—</text> <clause id="H4C03D1FDDBD14942A7FDD1A270160D03"><enum>(i)</enum><text>harmonize sources and data standards associated with geospatial data, including metadata; and</text> </clause>
<clause id="H8B2C8D6770BB4426968E885C7B2BD5CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, as determined by the Chairperson of the Committee, shall be made publicly available;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C97EFE17CC14827B812D42B62056611"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may include geospatial data from a source other than a covered agency, if determined appropriate by the Committee; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0BF3653EBA394CEEAEFDBAD23BBEDCE4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall not include proprietary data acquired under a license by the Federal Government.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0C2DC54EA66D43E3A46954AC794A64EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>Although the GeoPlatform is intended to include all National Geospatial Data Asset and other Federal datasets, nothing in this Act shall be construed to prevent a covered agency from also presenting, providing, or disseminating data that is—</text> 
<paragraph id="H38A42BB615D8401DAB4941A40D0015F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>specific to the functions of the covered agency; or</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C04020DFFD149F7BF4AC08DF7922361"><enum>(2)</enum><text>targeted to information consumers that directly interface with the services, portals, or other mechanisms of the covered agency.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H3E1FF9ED25514DAEA680EE0D8B75E440"><enum>9.</enum><header>Covered agency responsibilities</header> 
<subsection id="H585F82C9B4A24145853B4EC8AE4A2940"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each covered agency shall—</text> <paragraph id="H3CD25AC3E2514FDEB573E21693F384D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prepare, maintain, publish, and implement a strategy for advancing geographic information and related geospatial data activities appropriate to the mission of the covered agency, in support of the strategic plan for the National Spatial Data Infrastructure prepared under section 5(c);</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H18CB15C4605C4CD29BDD4DCBCDED8CCF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collect, maintain, disseminate, and preserve geospatial data such that the resulting data, information, or products can be readily shared with other Federal agencies and non-Federal users;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC0815E4256A4AFB853E38DCAA537160"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promote the integration of geospatial data from all sources;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE3157662AF014302BFA262DEDAF2731D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensure that data information products and other records created in geospatial data activities are included on agency record schedules that have been approved by the National Archives and Records Administration;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H33B733A04D024FD5B2AAD40B1FC58325"><enum>(5)</enum><text>allocate resources to fulfill the responsibilities of effective geospatial data collection, production, and stewardship with regard to related activities of the covered agency, and as necessary to support the activities of the Committee;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA4ED46C69A1641A0BD5004EFFEF7EB36"><enum>(6)</enum><text>use the geospatial data standards, including the standards for metadata for geospatial data, and other appropriate standards, including documenting geospatial data with the relevant metadata and making metadata available through the GeoPlatform;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H30D9DB62552D412F8894313EABDBCEE5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>coordinate and work in partnership with other Federal agencies, agencies of State, tribal, and local governments, institutions of higher education, and the private sector to efficiently and cost-effectively collect, integrate, maintain, disseminate, and preserve geospatial data, building upon existing non-Federal geospatial data to the extent possible;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H58418CF282894E749A92349933397727"><enum>(8)</enum><text>use geospatial information to—</text> <subparagraph id="H39A5504C6A6445628BEE601C7FDC10AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make Federal geospatial information and services more useful to the public;</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H93840826960B4F4697823E1D21E0788C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enhance operations;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H07A1C0E7BC61485889FBFBA4B5AA815E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support decision making; and</text> </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA6EC37BA170645BAB4F019E0F611215C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>enhance reporting to the public and to Congress;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7F4050C6C0A47EDAB38DAA057FF6DC1"><enum>(9)</enum><text>protect personal privacy and maintain confidentiality in accordance with Federal policy and law;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5E8C34888076476484366F536E64D4C2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>support emergency response activities requiring geospatial data in accordance with the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.) and other governing law;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HA5F5DCF1A73648D6A4E5BCDEE3C2CE15"><enum>(11)</enum><text>participate in determining, when applicable, whether data declassified pursuant to Executive Order 12951 can contribute to and become a part of the National Spatial Data Infrastructure;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6FF521077B6D4CC093CD9B07E27329DD"><enum>(12)</enum><text>search all sources, including the GeoPlatform, to determine if existing Federal, State, local, or private geospatial data meets the needs of the covered agency before expending funds for geospatial data collection;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B89F58002164168809062D62712AEB2"><enum>(13)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, ensure that a person receiving Federal funds for geospatial data collection provides high-quality data; and</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H30880D8B4A50481385F3C6BDF064D3F3"><enum>(14)</enum><text>appoint a contact to coordinate with the lead covered agencies for collection, acquisition, maintenance, and dissemination of the NGDA data themes used by the covered agency.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H92323FC7C87945ECA3884ABDD3C21744"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting</header> <paragraph id="H7260D885083E4C2F8D29B8F17971E8A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each covered agency shall submit to the Committee an annual report regarding the achievements of the covered agency in preparing and implementing the strategy described in subsection (a)(1) and complying with the other requirements under subsection (a).</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFF27F1F1DBB64BD19FC49A1E2A5785CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Budget submission</header><text>Each covered agency shall include geospatial data as a capital asset for purposes of preparing the budget submission of the President under section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code (including for purposes of the information required under submissions under exhibits 53 and 300 of Office of Management and Budget Circular A–11, relating to planning, budgeting, acquisition, and management of major information technology capital investments, or any successor thereto).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H0C0C6F6B177D4752BE117CBDCBCB830D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>Each covered agency shall disclose each contract, cooperative agreement, grant, or other transaction that deals with geospatial data, which may include posting information relating to the contract, cooperative agreement, grant, or other transaction on www.USAspending.gov, or any successor thereto.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H531105BF06664E41ADAAADAEB9DFD6C5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>OMB review</header><text>In reviewing the annual budget justifications submitted by covered agencies, the Office of Management and Budget shall take into consideration the summary and evaluations required under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 3(c)(10), comments, and replies to comments as required under paragraphs (11) and (12) of section 3(c), in its annual evaluation of the budget justification of each covered agency.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8AA8327F310947A5B20E93E138BEFCFE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>The Office of Management and Budget shall include a discussion of the summaries and evaluation of the progress in establishing the National Spatial Data Infrastructure in each E-Government status report submitted under section 3606 of title 44, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H6D318BA06E7746F1BADCD25528022906"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Audits</header><text>Not less than once every 2 years, the Inspector General of a covered agency (or senior ethics official of the covered agency for a covered agency without an Inspector General) shall submit to Congress an audit of the collection, production, acquisition, maintenance, distribution, use, and preservation of geospatial data by the covered agency, which shall include a review of—</text> <paragraph id="H04419785B0B7481DA6E552D36F8607BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the compliance of the covered agency with the standards for geospatial data, including metadata for geospatial data, established under section 7;</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H99F06C352E7E4518B78145F00B9FE230"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the compliance of the covered agency with the requirements under subsection (a); and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H3763E77D181E4C4CAFEB01BFCE1321E0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the compliance of the covered agency on the limitation on the use of Federal funds under section 10.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H35E80B33E72D4027B72988AA50872F2F"><enum>10.</enum><header>Limitation on use of Federal funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">On and after the date that is 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, Federal funds shall not be available for the collection, production, acquisition, maintenance, or dissemination of geospatial data that does not comply with applicable standards established under section 7, as determined by the Committee.</text> </section> </legis-body> </bill> 

