<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H46CD2C62EF52489E97855DFBAD4831A5" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1518 IH: Maritime Washington National Heritage Area Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1518</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170313">March 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Maritime Washington National Heritage Area in the State of Washington, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H09E742E63DEC4F8181E7072999DF0CD6" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4C2589243F26463DBFF5FD5BAA901DC7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Maritime Washington National Heritage Area Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HACF326C171994EC78F08254E298E8CED"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H948A68181AF64F4EAB959B15E1FBF7B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local coordinating entity</header><text>The term <term>local coordinating entity</term> means the local coordinating entity for the National Heritage Area designated by section 3(d).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H19B4BF763BE94401A135677125DACF1F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management plan</header><text>The term <term>management plan</term> means the management plan for the National Heritage Area required under section 4.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC27913BA9D74D1B901E50D9E4A2D595"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Map</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>map</term> means the map entitled <term>Maritime Washington National Heritage Area Proposed Boundary</term>, numbered 584/125,484, and dated August 2014.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA2AEAAB829F44879CE332B6EAC3F51B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>National heritage area</header><text>The term <term>National Heritage Area</term> means the Maritime Washington National Heritage Area established by section 3(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0EAAC9E12DC9472589F31221D775ABA8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB8685CB2B2FA4938A5F040DF334B612C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Washington.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HD7A2564544434B869B7777AE2865452C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Maritime Washington National Heritage Area</header>
 <subsection id="H0D9CDEAA72A643DF856D1D267811E030"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the State the Maritime Washington National Heritage Area.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HB04CB7C21B444232A9F19695AA359DDE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Boundaries</header> <paragraph id="H25060F82D58547508633A65C281A1840"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Heritage Area shall consist of land located in the counties of Whatcom, Skagit, Snohomish, San Juan, Island, King, Pierce, Thurston, Mason, Kitsap, Jefferson, Clallam, and Grays Harbor in the State that is at least partially located within the area that is <fraction>1/4</fraction>-mile landward of the shoreline, as generally depicted on the map.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA605D6DA66CC4120A864782A8DE9A8E6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Revision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The boundaries of the National Heritage Area established under paragraph (1) may be revised if the revision is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H733974403A60472AB5D4E662ACF66EBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">proposed in the management plan;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D7C653C98FE41FCAA3B8C86A30BB642"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">approved by the Secretary in accordance with section 4; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3A937A183524E6A828EC33E60DCF2CD"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">placed on file in accordance with subsection (c).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF8A7FDBB7DC9486FA9ACC51CC7437957"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of map</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H337B6A8617314331B19A07D18160CF31"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Park Service; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8FF58966E701451BBBA5318E8BEF20A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the local coordinating entity.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H05FF63B4CA15402AA2749BB5FC1302EF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Local coordinating entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Washington Trust for Historic Preservation shall be the local coordinating entity for the National Heritage Area.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H3E61538060244C9587AF462562EFF896"><enum>4.</enum><header>Management plan</header>
 <subsection id="H11AF419FF2934AC89739E08F4ECE6D26"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the local coordinating entity shall submit to the Secretary for approval a proposed management plan for the National Heritage Area.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H84E2490D3057427CB0F4E3A7FB73E3D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The management plan shall—</text> <paragraph id="H8EF78057825749BE91413B3233511733"><enum>(1)</enum><text>incorporate an integrated and cooperative approach for the protection, enhancement, and interpretation of the natural, cultural, historical, scenic, and recreational resources of the National Heritage Area;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H98537C6B56A34196854A4DF5C33C5CBA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>take into consideration State and local plans;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H29D3738A3C68446588D654B74D25681C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAD21367154B546EB9B1F397513DC4E28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an inventory of—</text> <clause id="H039CEA9831884912AA98ABA8E8C0B484"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the resources located in the National Heritage Area; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9D39042EDC794A91B14F3C300B36E627"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other property in the National Heritage Area that—</text> <subclause id="HDEE3B460811A4052B8C3594C960104B0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is related to the themes of the National Heritage Area; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD4D5F6D04C9D4460821A79BB24B66625"><enum>(II)</enum><text>should be preserved, restored, managed, or maintained because of the significance of the property;</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34922BCB064744E784793D9E003B5487"><enum>(B)</enum><text>comprehensive policies, strategies and recommendations for the conservation, funding, management, and development of the National Heritage Area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2AB90AA742D464E864A7D6681A839D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of actions that governments, private organizations, and individuals have agreed to take to protect the natural, cultural, and historical resources of the National Heritage Area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7F7D37ABE204E66B410051220BE0368"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a program of implementation for the management plan by the local coordinating entity that includes a description of—</text>
 <clause id="H0EF66352D3A3473089DB8962DCBFB7E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>actions to facilitate ongoing collaboration among partners to promote plans for resource protection, restoration, and construction; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H45021CB732D44021BF45FFDC4E9A48F2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>specific commitments for implementation that have been made by the local coordinating entity or any government, organization, or individual for the first 5 years of operation of the National Heritage Area;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64D475606CC64C33B20D6FDEAA60FDB7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the identification of sources of funding for carrying out the management plan;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9C09AD1772A4526A2CB7107F3800CE2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>analysis and recommendations for means by which Federal, State, and local programs may best be coordinated to carry out this section, including a description of the role of the National Park Service in the National Heritage Area; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8977695F2CEC40139799949134F66C82"><enum>(G)</enum><text>an interpretive plan for the National Heritage Area; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6539338CCD1D494A94BD324D2538C543"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommend policies and strategies for resource management that consider and detail the application of appropriate land and water management techniques, including the development of intergovernmental and interagency cooperative agreements to protect the natural, cultural, historical, scenic, recreational, and educational resources of the National Heritage Area.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H014CDA7F31024595B2F91571305EA29F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>If a proposed management plan is not submitted to the Secretary by the date that is 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the local coordinating entity shall be ineligible to receive additional funding under this Act until the date on which the Secretary receives and approves the management plan.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H4B83CD80867A480CA378A3EABC9AA27D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Approval or disapproval of management plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H6FC28224463946FAADE13BBD500DAA48"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of receipt of the management plan under subsection (a), the Secretary, in consultation with the State, shall approve or disapprove the management plan.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H866B71C0FF444E849F734B4DA8D8C009"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria for approval</header><text>In determining whether to approve the management plan, the Secretary shall consider whether—</text> <subparagraph id="HEE03C6E9E74D4A6BA9B5AF9FCBAD4801"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the local coordinating entity is representative of the diverse interests of the National Heritage Area, including governments, natural and historical resource protection organizations, educational institutions, businesses, and recreational organizations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B28CA851D084792ADD94382F659D5A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the local coordinating entity has afforded adequate opportunity, including public hearings, for public and governmental involvement in the preparation of the management plan; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D032F94EDDB46358C475FD90AD4B3AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the resource protection and interpretation strategies contained in the management plan, if implemented, would adequately protect the natural, cultural, and historical resources of the National Heritage Area.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE53E669DE330457C915B50AFD0C1844B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Action following disapproval</header><text>If the Secretary disapproves the management plan under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H4FFE7F2B12AF412ABE9E1F1A0DADC3A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advise the local coordinating entity in writing of the reasons for the disapproval;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03DB867662614F27A720075FBFD3F6FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make recommendations for revisions to the management plan; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F423A58404643DB87AC4E69EA901E07"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the receipt of any proposed revision of the management plan from the local coordinating entity, approve or disapprove the proposed revision.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H95D41C3801E14FF7889D2EA247A18AB4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Amendments</header>
 <subparagraph id="H81F650B7A36E461BA0142C060F36E151"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall approve or disapprove each amendment to the management plan that makes a substantial change to the management plan, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70925F55FFE8422497A23F8A055F8FD2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>The local coordinating entity shall not use Federal funds authorized by this section to carry out any amendments to the management plan until the date on which the Secretary has approved the amendments.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H67E42F1B7B3D412BB6EE58492804E3E3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Administration</header>
 <subsection id="H42AF553B4ED44D2ABD906386A2D1F8ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorities</header><text>For purposes of implementing the management plan, the Secretary, acting through the local coordinating entity, may use amounts made available under section 9—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7F0FCF7720B34B4D9CAAA0992CD113AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to make grants to the State or a political subdivision of the State, nonprofit organizations, and other persons;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCBAC84295439492C8580EEC4B6532F4F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to enter into cooperative agreements with, or provide technical assistance to, the State or a political subdivision of the State, nonprofit organizations, and other interested parties;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE708F0E2962F4174A0D9B5A383392229"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to hire and compensate staff, which shall include individuals with expertise in natural, cultural, and historical resources protection and heritage programming;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE392357407C413782971BBE0CC42DCE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to obtain money or services from any source, including any money or services that are provided under any other Federal law or program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71C76F45DCE547E7A85D1E747ED3DA14"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to contract for goods or services; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F8830DB919B490C88B97186B49FA53C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to undertake to be a catalyst for any other activity that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H55CECFC80DCF4179894C49C7A8FB57DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>furthers the purposes of the National Heritage Area; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H196B3ABB17DC49C39529821EC6503D81"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is consistent with the approved management plan.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H728D6F3B9E3347B19C72FF776F7F3B2B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The local coordinating entity shall—</text> <paragraph id="H3C8E59B606AA4286942D8BA11662E64F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in accordance with section 4, prepare and submit a management plan to the Secretary;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5AE8EE40FAAC44629D11322FFE5E6B1A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assist units of local government, regional planning organizations, and nonprofit organizations in carrying out the approved management plan by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC5E5A1C1170840FD8B9D45B6F51EC0B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carrying out programs and projects that recognize, protect, and enhance important resource values in the National Heritage Area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49AC4AADD66B43D48E376482AC471CE3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing and maintaining interpretive exhibits and programs in the National Heritage Area;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09AE8E70F70143B9AA8EE557276BEDB0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>developing recreational and educational opportunities in the National Heritage Area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DFC36225B264763AE92F8ACEDE474CC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>increasing public awareness of, and appreciation for, natural, cultural, historical, and scenic resources of the National Heritage Area;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E70261F3FEA43CF8B2F6C9E4761DA2A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>identifying and restoring historic sites and buildings in the National Heritage Area that are consistent with National Heritage Area themes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DA2F02709F2485DA4FA88D359CA5A4E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>ensuring that clear, consistent, and appropriate signs identifying points of public access and sites of interest are posted throughout the National Heritage Area; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4181AA14879A47978F29BF7C13C0AF58"><enum>(G)</enum><text>promoting a wide range of partnerships among governments, organizations, and individuals to further the National Heritage Area;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H190E2FEB387B43579F68132D26CA644E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consider the interests of diverse units of government, businesses, organizations, and individuals in the National Heritage Area in the preparation and implementation of the management plan;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A220A9D094B473C82A6486E1DD5C895"><enum>(4)</enum><text>conduct meetings open to the public at least semiannually regarding the development and implementation of the management plan;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7936FD7FD9A246BDBCE52116479C7C7A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>for any year for which Federal funds have been received under this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H17F01829314B45FF987B4FC5CF678FA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary an annual report that describes the activities, expenses, and income of the local coordinating entity (including grants from the local coordinating entity to any other entities during the year that the report is made);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE9C24CC561C4AF690FEF9BB2C6C01B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make available to the Secretary for audit all records relating to the expenditure of the funds and any matching funds; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7518F1EE156F4F4798AF3ED10E5B815F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>require, with respect to all agreements authorizing the expenditure of Federal funds by other organizations, that the organizations receiving the funds make available to the Secretary for audit all records concerning the expenditure of the funds; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H52F1684DED114A1CAFE204A4202CEFAE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>encourage, by appropriate means, economic viability that is consistent with the National Heritage Area.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B6FC46876F44749B546418FD220D608"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on the acquisition of real property</header><text>The local coordinating entity shall not use Federal funds made available under section 9 to acquire real property or any interest in real property.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H724D8A120E904FFF8283E0A9F8A37F8D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Relationship to other Federal agencies</header>
 <subsection id="H5FE547D258F5417A8099809EA4B6A55B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects the authority of a Federal agency to provide technical or financial assistance under any other law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3E0015565161425794BA47AF2DD46A51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation and coordination</header><text>The head of any Federal agency planning to conduct activities that may have an impact on the National Heritage Area is encouraged to consult and coordinate the activities with the Secretary and the local coordinating entity, to the maximum extent practicable.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1F54362CD8B0447DA0BCF4F0F33FDCE1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other Federal agencies</header><text>Nothing in this Act—</text> <paragraph id="HE0AE5B4C811348968F40B688BAAAD291"><enum>(1)</enum><text>modifies, alters, or amends any law or regulation authorizing a Federal agency to manage Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Federal agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE1429DCA5DF4326AA162F6671F7BB70"><enum>(2)</enum><text>limits the discretion of a Federal land manager to implement an approved land use plan within the boundaries of the National Heritage Area; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A2D8B36E1F34C41913EA9615BECC77F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>modifies, alters, or amends any authorized use of Federal land under the jurisdiction of a Federal agency.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H50528ECF45A9410C904A72F9679F8BCD"><enum>7.</enum><header>Private property and regulatory protections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act—</text> <paragraph id="HF953BBF0EBDD4A6E9A44831F3D180C39"><enum>(1)</enum><text>abridges the rights of any owner of public or private property, including the right to refrain from participating in any plan, project, program, or activity conducted within the National Heritage Area;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H483BD5F4C12646AA81A9C53A3B927CFC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>requires any property owner—</text> <subparagraph id="H4FF4C4714D824997B3030E196F201DCA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to permit public access (including access by Federal, State, or local agencies) to the property of the property owner; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30DBAA4D32A04B19A0E99462512E07DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to modify public access or use of property of the property owner under any other Federal, State, or local law;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8093273C71BD47BB82BED6B3AE461359"><enum>(3)</enum><text>alters any duly adopted land use regulation, approved land use plan, or other regulatory authority of any Federal, State, tribal, or local agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H90697B4C8A9145F6AD492BB273B3BC74"><enum>(4)</enum><text>conveys any land use or other regulatory authority to the local coordinating entity;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB1B2F6BB1F49452481E3C94C682626A7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>authorizes or implies the reservation or appropriation of water or water rights;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA41C443F4C7D4AE18B6F1307F2AE0B10"><enum>(6)</enum><text>diminishes the authority of the State to manage fish and wildlife, including the regulation of fishing and hunting within the National Heritage Area; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8AA8E898B72A4EA38516B2EB678A08D4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>creates any liability, or affects any liability under any other law, of any private property owner with respect to any person injured on the private property.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H0304C49231974F1196D11ACEC62551ED"><enum>8.</enum><header>Evaluation and report</header>
 <subsection id="H6D7C539893634C93A6CF14105D0D370E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years before the date on which authority for Federal funding terminates for the National Heritage Area, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7A3D443F6C3C4DFDA6F2448C3D8AD773"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct an evaluation of the accomplishments of the National Heritage Area; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0CD1E9433E16450FBAF0E7CA9DC1B583"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prepare a report in accordance with subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H216E710674204E0CA4C9840E324619CC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>An evaluation conducted under subsection (a)(1) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H318661686DF24C8D9C44F109D14EF4F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assess the progress of the local coordinating entity with respect to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF82A7771E3934060AB50D711511E9D33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accomplishing the purposes of the National Heritage Area; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1421D1AC34E4B40B4FD462AFC51AC3B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>achieving the goals and objectives of the management plan;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6C4CDA0BBCB4BF58A870ADACC6F19AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>analyze the investments of Federal, State, tribal, and local government and private entities in the National Heritage Area to determine the impact of the investments; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC53F27DC29FB4006ADF1704D23DA484D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>review the management structure, partnership relationships, and funding of the National Heritage Area for purposes of identifying the critical components for sustainability of the National Heritage Area.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC1E9BDF27D174DE8BEA44BB5EC0BC387"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Based on the evaluation conducted under subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report that includes recommendations for the future role of the National Park Service with respect to the National Heritage Area.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H57BC84DA85274597910271F58DE74C9D"><enum>9.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <subsection id="H7F6C120AC17C4F24AC01B671C46C3B87"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $10,000,000, of which not more than $1,000,000 may be made available in any fiscal year.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF44749DF633C49C9BF59C6C2142AC7EC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts made available under subsection (a) shall remain available until expended.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H106AC8F1CFC640E2985F0EB2528F0DBA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cost-Sharing requirement</header> <paragraph id="H171E733DEE9D4ED78133CB4A10DF1ADD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal share of the total cost of any activity carried out under this Act shall be not more than 50 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56345946D54C4093A0150343659C30FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The non-Federal share of the total cost of any activity carried out under this Act may be in the form of in-kind contributions of goods or services fairly valued.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A228564E7534808B11D52EC22B38451"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination of authority</header><text>The authority of the Secretary to provide assistance under this Act terminates on the date that is 15 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


