<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA1DD471D46A4411AA5390CC0C3152056" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2753 IH: Teacher Loan Repayment Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2753</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170526">May 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001284">Mrs. Brooks of Indiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for loan repayment for teachers in high-need schools.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC50FC3EE4D314BABB9635A585AAB4021" style="OLC">
 <section id="H209091D10BE1422B8B56DE251C070127" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Teacher Loan Repayment Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H36ADB696DB61443E8DD8F13BC4A9837A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Loan repayment for teachers</header> <subsection id="HEFAA720D2D7A4DBD9A2347428F34DF2F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sunsets</header><text>The Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1023175814F649E4822781E0B356B751"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 420O—</text> <subparagraph id="HC8FBB7CDEBD44532821B9EB65B619229"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Beginning</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In general.—</header-in-text>Beginning</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E589DD686744959B69BF382DFA36CDA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF209D93735EB45C28B208F4E7C29AF75" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HCAD9850263954F63AC281D3EC47317C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>Beginning on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Teacher Loan Repayment Act of 2017</short-title>, the Secretary shall not award funds under this subpart for new TEACH Grants.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H26E9A4358F95416DAA89D3C8A7D742CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 428J, by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA212652D7DEA45A8BC12E3539DE8F8D8" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HA81E16B23BA34A60B03C8C00055C9A05"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>Beginning on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Teacher Loan Repayment Act of 2017</short-title>, the Secretary shall not enter into a new agreement to assume the obligation to repay a qualified loan amount under this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD25DBFAD60AF4FFDB3A9EFABADEC304D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 428K—</text> <subparagraph id="H48FA3F3B5FE44334890452F19B6EC9F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (h) as subsection (i); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64B55DB8375047339E0FABC8D01F67AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (g) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD6C8ED6E9AD4DD7B83AB9057882A04E" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HA7EE4C3C082C4458B1841178B5C34C5C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>Beginning on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Teacher Loan Repayment Act of 2017</short-title>, the Secretary shall not enter into a new agreement to forgive a qualified loan amount under this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FCEF376089B4FF889E48BAEED5A1913"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 460, by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H442FFC0DBD5A45B5B39FEE441E484259" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H120AF16BE3C947318C64C32E73024A70"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>Beginning on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Teacher Loan Repayment Act of 2017</short-title>, the Secretary shall not enter into a new agreement to cancel the obligation to repay a qualified loan amount under this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H377C5E00DB294465A2DC6150AF045A37"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Loan repayment for teachers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC235A248FAA6479B99E549158F41B361" style="OLC">
					<part id="H9056198519274B90B017AC652A8259E4"><enum>J</enum><header>Loan repayment for teachers</header>
						<section id="HBDE3191E17E84C6691E4CCFBE2B3DC5C"><enum>499A.</enum><header>Loan repayment for teachers</header>
 <subsection id="H9F64520F32BA44999EF568EA01D8E768"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to encourage highly qualified individuals to enter and continue in the teaching profession, and to ensure qualified effective teachers are encouraged to work in high-need schools.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5F2C8B64D6DB401FBBE525BC2361661E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HB18DFE229E3142F8A26EAA20DE4DC168"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Child with a disability</header><text>The term <term>child with a disability</term> has the meaning given the term in section 602 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H73279D205D3F404799E79D4E75C9DEDE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Student loan</header><text>The term <term>student loan</term> means a loan—</text> <subparagraph id="H182912E5F12D400BBC47A71C9E1D40E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>made, insured, or guaranteed under part B, except as provided in subparagraph (C);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB407B8783727451C90FCBC5F113D1B48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>made under part D or E, except as provided in subparagraph (C); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3442B429CD3648E094C774240E8404B9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>made under section 428C or 455(g), to the extent that such loan was used to repay a Federal Direct Stafford Loan, a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan, or a loan made under section 428 or 428H.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1FF7F8FDFA0344B9B57A5378E76BAF0C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out a program under which the Department of Education shall assume the obligation to repay a student loan, by direct payments on behalf of a borrower to the holder of such loan, in accordance with subsection (e), for any borrower who—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB9AED3DF094E4C39BD0E22AF3A3547AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is not in default on a loan for which the borrower seeks forgiveness; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFAB23AA0C45844C6B6EE0BE8E05A716A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is employed as a full-time teacher for service in an academic year (including such a teacher employed by an educational service agency)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4FC12D1AF2A14B9CB460617A88DFE2EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a public elementary school or secondary school, which, for the purpose of this paragraph and for that year—</text>
 <clause id="H8DC579524CCE42B692B1E3FDA599D534"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has been determined by the Secretary (after consultation with the State educational agency of the State in which the school is located) to be a school in which the number of children meeting a measure of poverty under section 1113(a)(5) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, is not less than 40 percent of the total number of children enrolled in such school; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF72E2EA5BDAD4265B5472774F4544226"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is in a school district served by a local educational agency that is eligible in such year for assistance pursuant to part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB15FC81FBAD34CFEB119893A5FE172F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a public elementary school or secondary school or location operated by an educational service agency, which, for the purpose of this paragraph and for that year, has been determined by the Secretary (after consultation with the State educational agency of the State in which the educational service agency operates) to be a school or location in which the number of children taught who meet a measure of poverty under section 1113(a)(5) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, is not less than 40 percent of the total number of children taught at such school or location.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEFE705B841FC43F683E61ED83A0B9A8F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <paragraph id="H071D58914DA643449537868847E61DE2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>List</header><text>If the list of schools in which a teacher may perform service pursuant to subsection (c)(2) is not available before May 1 of any year, the Secretary may use the list for the year preceding the year for which the determination is made to make such service determination.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF1212448FC64D358615E7E422807188"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continuing eligibility</header><text>Any teacher who performs service in a school during which time their service meets the requirements of subsection (c)(2) in any year, and, in a subsequent year, fails to meet the requirements of such subsection, may continue to teach in such school and shall be eligible for loan cancellation pursuant to this section in subsequent years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C31022F32644C69B00B510B8B60735F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Choice of loan repayment program</header><text>An individual who, on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Teacher Loan Repayment Act of 2017</short-title>, is participating in a loan repayment program under section 428J, 428K, or 460, may choose to continue to participate in such program or may enter into participation in the program under this section if eligible to participate in the program under this section.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A18E3C495ED42F1839CF5E7C08900E0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Terms of loan repayment</header>
 <paragraph id="H1B133B0052524644AA0AD4179CFFB5D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Borrower agreement</header><text>The Secretary and an individual who desires to receive student loan repayment under this section shall enter into an agreement that includes a provision that to remain eligible to receive student loan repayment under this section, the individual shall remain employed in the school or location for which the individual gained eligibility for student loan repayment under this section.</text>
								</paragraph><paragraph id="HDA37423AC1BC470ABF76BA31EBAEA1E4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Student loan payment amount</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC12300478EC346EF9041F93E6FF2B5D0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the agreement described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall agree to make a student loan payment for such individual of $250 a month for the first and second year of teaching, $300 a month for the third year of teaching, $350 a month for the fourth year of teaching, and $400 a month for the fifth and sixth year of teaching.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F83816E533A430ABA68EACE3E545201"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Maximum total amount</header><text>The maximum total amount of student loan payments made by the Secretary for an individual under this section shall be $23,400.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAEBEE26E2194980A1382957E82AAF8A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Remaining balance</header><text>An individual shall enter repayment on any remaining principal and interest due on a student loan for which the Secretary has made payments under this section after the maximum total amount has been reached under subparagraph (B).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB32B062A8884435AAF3637474361EFF3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Beginning of payments</header><text>Nothing in this section shall authorize the Secretary to pay any amount to reimburse a borrower for any student loan payments made by such borrower prior to the date on which the Secretary entered into an agreement with the borrower under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


