<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCF6A783D73004B5F8590612AB8EC2A28" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 529</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170113">January 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make improvements in the rules related to qualified tuition programs and qualified ABLE programs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFF4DCE11EE7B453E9F68D1E91EE6DEA0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H701547B5B91F429B832E97161E55C771" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>529 and ABLE Account Improvement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3B3921331F654E0F8F180825BABFBD06" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Employer contributions to qualified tuition programs and qualified ABLE programs</header> <subsection id="H3D901032B5CE42ECA9C7CD66D0169F4E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/132">section 132</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of paragraph (7), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (8) and inserting <quote>, or</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H809DEFA047544AE09AB61090D47E6E7F" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H2688E2CD7A6548DC93CE78C04E1E9334"><enum>(9)</enum><text>qualified tuition program and qualified ABLE program contributions.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HA7383D232789490DAFC6B2756E4F10DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified tuition program and qualified ABLE program contributions defined</header><text>Section 132 of such Code is amended by redesignating subsection (o) as subsection (p) and inserting after subsection (n) the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A9364F623BA47CB9EB697265B9D90A8" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HC341957ABC344773832C79B7A23409A2"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Qualified tuition program and qualified ABLE program contributions defined</header> 
<paragraph id="H5DFD07121BF14D819C08FD59016D1B2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>qualified tuition and qualified ABLE program contributions</quote> means contributions (including matching contributions) made by an employer directly to a qualified tuition program (as described in section 529) or qualified ABLE program (as described in section 529A) designated by an employee if—</text> <subparagraph id="H3F809A2BF18340C886FEBEB74CBB3E22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such contribution is made to an account under such program for which the designated beneficiary is the employee or a member of the family of the employee (within the meaning of section 529(e)(2)), and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6B8840E1D3A0485A8CD02B8451F792D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such contribution is made in connection with a qualified payroll deduction contribution program established by the employer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC3037074AC5458B85DDF0AD09C9BE46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified payroll deduction contribution program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>qualified payroll deduction contribution program</quote> means a program established by an employer—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDD7589DA6AF44395AE46135FBE38EEDE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>under which employees may elect to make contributions to accounts described in paragraph (1)(A) which reduce the amount of wages received directly by such employee by the amount of such contribution, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H5B550A6CC98C45A297B5A844CB1307B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which is made available on substantially the same terms to each member of a group of employees which is defined under a reasonable classification set up by the employer which does not discriminate in favor of highly compensated employees (as defined in section 414(q)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4441DA90D30641EAA19BA25364DB2FE6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on exclusion</header><text>The amount of qualified tuition and qualified ABLE program contributions which may be excluded from gross income under subsection (a)(9) with respect to any employee shall not exceed $100 in any calendar year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H992EF2F676A2475C9623040EE24F6AE4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Nondiscrimination rule for employer contributions</header><text>Subsection (a)(9) shall only apply to contributions provided with respect to a highly compensated employee if such contributions meet the requirements of paragraph (2)(B).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H42DE6EF690044A28850154EC38D2B8F4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header> 
<subparagraph id="H38E58F31D8A245E6ACFD6D014840E532"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any taxable year beginning in a calendar year after 2017, the $100 amount contained in paragraph (3) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text> <clause id="HBEC8EB5191C94E8C8CCD63E866862334"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></clause> 
<clause id="H21977BD0BE884E019AC641E4D537B177"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> for <quote>calendar year 1992</quote> in subparagraph (B) thereof.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H80B003974A8C47148A06E5456A68D5FB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>Any increase determined under subparagraph (A) shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $25.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H85D911F199764F83A5D97B357D382B37"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to contributions made after December 31, 2016.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H966238406B5B4014AC302BA3A522E4AF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Tax credit for small employer costs of establishing direct payroll deduction into qualified tuition programs and qualified ABLE programs</header> <subsection id="H5E5E9F47B4AE469F826E8E347CB57EBF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45E">Section 45E</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E32D71A3DEA4B42A2A393BC1A4CF58F" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H21325B15C4324481BBBF2D36013259F3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Application to programs for payroll deduction contributions to qualified tuition programs and qualified ABLE programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a qualified payroll deduction contribution program (as defined in section 132(o)(2)) established by an employer—</text> <paragraph id="H58E4134C2B614A1D9265E067327AEBC7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such program shall be treated as an eligible employer plan for purposes of this section,</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFBB7B9A1971D43E0B58B3651A44FF8CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>this section (including the limitation of subsection (b)) shall be applied separately with respect to such programs and any other eligible employer plans of the employer, and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A0672970B6B4C91807ACC6134A204B5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>subsection (d)(1)(A)(ii) shall be applied by substituting <quote>education</quote> for <quote>retirement-related education</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAB3FCB45519C431A9F256EAEFB608DA3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="H3DE7BD30309C4E56B971E0EF582274BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The heading for section 45E of such Code is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">pension</header-in-text></quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H858A79F91C194255A60E3AC1DE618165"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by striking the item relating to section 45E and inserting the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3F5206ED03F4D9BB78F19EF877F4B5D" style="OLC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 45E. Small employer plan startup costs.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA32AB1AAE91047F7AA4FC060370C73C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to costs paid or incurred in taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HCFA2DC65D37E4974BC24B98064B9D0B5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Exemptions from additional tax for certain distributions from qualified tuition programs</header> <subsection id="H8DBF6012D9D14AC4BEFDADCE9DFE7218"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/529">Section 529(c)(6)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking the last sentence and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H46AF3B6230D24EA6A1268BD71DBD6E0A" style="OLC"><text>This paragraph shall not apply to the extent that—</text> <subparagraph id="H59EFDDD186F94C07ACED54FEABCDDE55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a payment or distribution is used (within 90 days of the payment or distribution) to make a payment of interest or principal on a qualified education loan (as defined in section 222(d)(1)) on behalf of the designated beneficiary or a member of the family of such designated beneficiary within the meaning of section 529(e)(2)), or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H058BB877A577451F98113A3C4D298EB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the recipient of a payment or distribution makes (within 90 days of the receipt of the payment or distribution) a contribution to an organization described in section 170(b)(1)(A) (other than any organization described in section 509(a)(3) or any fund or account described in section 4966(d)(2)), but only if—</text> <clause id="HDCC577D62C9D4E9E86E8E4D407AA21B3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a deduction for the entire payment or distribution is allowable under section 170, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA76FE5ED13F441309EA8A41E432EC178"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total payments and distributions taken into account under this subparagraph with respect to such recipient for any taxable year does not exceed $1,000.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H93A981D0A5004E43AECD7895FCE63CC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to distributions after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H33C3B51EBDF341C585685FBF513B0669"><enum>5.</enum><header>Clarification regarding investment direction in qualified tuition programs and qualified ABLE programs</header> 
<subsection id="H4E11640AD2EB474A9564179644BC5367"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Investment direction in qualified tuition programs</header><text>Paragraph (4) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/529">section 529(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>For purposes of this paragraph, rebalancing investments among broad-based investment strategies established under the program shall not be treated as investment direction by a contributor or designated beneficiary unless the specific investments within those broad-based strategies are directed by the contributor or designated beneficiary.</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8FE9DB7A76B54E339B8ADEFF8100229C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Investment direction in qualified ABLE programs</header><text>Paragraph (4) of section 529A(b) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>For purposes of this paragraph, rebalancing investments among broad-based investment strategies established under the program shall not be treated as investment direction by a designated beneficiary unless the specific investments within those broad-based strategies are directed by the designated beneficiary.</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4CA100EDA4264FD0BEC9D5C4447129F5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to calendar years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HF5EF2A3AEFB449E094674CAFF68825C8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rollovers between qualified tuition programs and qualified ABLE programs</header> <subsection id="H752159DF1DCD422AA822445FC10969FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rollovers from qualified tuition programs to qualified ABLE programs</header><text>Clause (i) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/529">section 529(c)(3)(C)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subclause (I), by striking the period at the end of subclause (II) and inserting <quote>, or</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HAC678C844E4347C6A1699145F9F0E066" style="OLC"> 
<subclause id="HC022E576CF564BBB8E70C40C53BB7D63"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to an ABLE account (as defined in section 529A(e)(6)) of the designated beneficiary or a member of the family of the designated beneficiary.</text></subclause> <quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="clause">Subclause (III) shall not apply to so much of a distribution which, when added to all other contributions made to the ABLE account for the taxable year, exceeds the limitation under section 529A(b)(2)(B).</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H62FA4B14AF414C0EBFCAC0A06BF9F54D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rollovers from qualified ABLE programs to qualified tuition programs</header><text>Clause (i) of section 529A(c)(1)(C) of such Code is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9AD2A30BEC9846C8B047184F7C2684CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>such payment or distribution, into another</quote> and inserting</text> <quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0910D626601A4A0C8F2D6693790067E4" style="OLC"><text>such payment or distribution—</text> 
<subclause id="H56C1AA2A2B0D43159CF03F48E5D5555F"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">into another</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8E88446E62644D58213659143C4726C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, or</quote>, and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1FB2E6B370B94D148BD3F00F83763675"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1EACAF85C7C4B029ED16369E43924CD" style="OLC"> <subclause id="HC4278E30C5FA44D5B276A02B02F4A69E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to a qualified tuition program (as described in section 529) for the benefit of the same designated beneficiary or a member of the family of such designated beneficiary.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H189306E7D20548B0A23CC296AF4636BC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to distributions after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

