<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9D7E4375D9A3482AA4FE5B60AD5FA691" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4250 IH: Buy Smarter and Save Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4250</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171103">November 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote category management principles within the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H622DE3BE25684B1BAE06B002172F2D65" style="OLC">
 <section id="H21AA675877AE4C109296700BC4329C0B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Buy Smarter and Save Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDD3058E1E4D241D2A269112494D278F7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of Federal procurement goals</header> <subsection id="HE500199F94764B6FB1F437E068500EC4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning with the first fiscal year following the date of the enactment of this Act, and for each succeeding fiscal year, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy, the Category Management Leadership Council, and a representative from each Executive agency that is not represented on the Category Management Leadership Council, shall provide the President with recommendations for the establishment of the following:</text>
 <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H994FDEF192634A689D7C5129A300E9C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An annual Governmentwide goal for Executive agencies to reduce the number of contracts for the procurement of common goods and services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H493B5E45FF3B413A90F59DEC4564DA67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An annual Governmentwide goal for Executive agencies to increase spend under management.</text> </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88036850EF1644E392336BE0C39AB892"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An annual Governmentwide goal for Executive agencies to use category management to produce savings.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65EB1E8FE7714B6DB6CCBD3A5BD0D471"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
 <paragraph id="HAFCD9273AF3F45A2B82C41E14005F912"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Governmentwide goals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall use the recommendations provided under subsection (a) to establish the annual Governmentwide goals described in such subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H20FD4BE85DEB432D8D63F6357044D242"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individualized goals</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the Director, in consultation with the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy and the Category Management Leadership Council, may establish specific annual goals for procurement and savings that are customized for an individual Executive agency, which may include goals relating to contract reduction and spend under management.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H58D9C8A492454474B573B364F42E3182"><enum>3.</enum><header>Guidance on implementation of Federal procurement goals</header>
 <subsection id="H677165D38FF74B58B42E0C29F5FD0A36"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall develop and issue guidance, in accordance with the requirements described in subsection (b) and the considerations described in subsection (c), for Executive agencies on the implementation of the goals established under section 2(b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9702381EFA60404590F955D6FA406697"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The guidance issued under subsection (a) shall provide, at a minimum, for the following:</text> <paragraph id="HC8ECF4C1AAAB44ADACF25C124E108431"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The maintenance of a category hierarchy for common goods and services to be procured using category management, consistent with the considerations described in subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H73AFA29D0E1F491F808CDE5AB9C0F878"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The implementation of Governmentwide standards, policies, and guidelines for category management for Executive agencies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCEEC673F1343428891703444B47C2D93"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The establishment of a single authoritative source for Governmentwide procurement data that enables category management analytics and reporting.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H928DB1AFBD6346658A441186F614AECF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The maintenance and regular update of a set of criteria for, and list of, preferred Governmentwide contract vehicles.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H808EC3230B7C42BB8EFD5B1685386609"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of the specific data required to be submitted by each Executive agency to the Director relating to the implementation of the goals established under section 2(b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5C29EA10C234D329629C3A16484583D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Guidance on calculating and verifying annual contract reduction, spend under management, and savings.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3DB23D70509D492286EC090E9EC653CE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The establishment of standards for Executive agencies to measure progress with respect to the implementation described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H35A91CDC34B3469280793FB294BACFB5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In developing guidance under subsection (a), the Director shall take into consideration the application of category management in a manner that—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCBAB6817AABD43D598EE3B819F8658D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>maintains a strong industrial and manufacturing base in the United States;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H52058A548DE340E8BC709605E4377C82"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promotes continuous effective competition;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD6572E4CA7C44CABA973BD48B05D9E76"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the greatest extent applicable, complies with the Governmentwide goals for procurement contracts established under section 15(g) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/644">15 U.S.C. 644(g)</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE5E040C5E9D43F795ADA2F57A99C296"><enum>(4)</enum><text>maintains regular consultation with and outreach to entities in the private sector;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H63AA828BD2644DBAB70DF0C0E7BE3980"><enum>(5)</enum><text>maintains consistency with international trade agreements;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35F7595A6DEF49B9B2B7DCD9997F4C59"><enum>(6)</enum><text>accounts for the benefits and costs of the procurement of common goods and services;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H214188ECF4644DF5A0CC2ADD8FE02702"><enum>(7)</enum><text>emphasizes the procurement of common goods and services that are procured routinely and in large amounts; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF27C176164B3413B9CEEA453B876AFE6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>facilitates the ability to conduct a spend analysis under section 4(b).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H595D488D577947869815B96829017F94"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Standards, policies, and guidelines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy, in consultation with the Category Management Leadership Council, shall prescribe regulations or issue guidance as necessary to implement the Governmentwide standards, policies, and guidelines described in subsection (b)(2).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4D8A8FF09FF9476F8C8F11F6357F7377"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the end of each fiscal year for which a goal is established under section 2(b), the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of this Act, which shall include, at a minimum, the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HCEBD4D5409FD4876AF6803C9BF783086"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The progress of the Federal Government in implementing the goals established under section 2(b).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H18218A7FCF8D4D5689298B363419C085"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the performance of each Executive agency in implementing the goals established under section 2(b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HECA4A738978B4AB4B1BA9B4017171C0B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The progress achieved by each Executive agency in implementing category management.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0934DA26174B456AAB3EEF318C8A625F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Small business participation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9CE5D09F15D34558A2C5F42C7E89005B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The state of Governmentwide procurement data in terms of accuracy, accessibility, and comprehensiveness in data systems such as the Federal Procurement Data System–Next Generation (FPDS–NG), the System for Award Management (SAM), the Contractor Performance Assessment Reports System (CPARS), and Acquisition Gateway.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD700A3A895F04EA09A1AAC4A9020E5D8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The list of preferred Governmentwide contract vehicles, as required under subsection (b)(4).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCFD295ABD45847C8B3323214465A19FB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Such findings and recommendations as the Administrator considers appropriate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H21512E383139487AA4DFB5F22324B6D3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Category management duties of Executive agencies</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H177552D1F88C4955A263618A79E91FAD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of an Executive agency shall take the following actions to support category management efforts in the agency:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HBA9D06A7B1FC4210978A7B0214195273"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Establish agencywide goals for category management efforts in support of the goals established under section 2(b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE640432CC46D450ABBF3E173F3BC2B8F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Designate a category management accountability official.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8AC20450DDC149838EAD0BA876457CE9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Issue a policy that outlines the role, authority, and responsibilities of the category management accountability official and category management practices for the agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1C9818DC208847A09DFC0C66DA139356"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Identify preferred multi-agency and agency-specific category management vehicles in use.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFCF72D93358A4CD29F2FB3B28FFDFD92"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Establish and regularly update utilization and spend under management goals for category management efforts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0C5DDE6A44224481A7A62E453DFE24AA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Develop standards to track and assess compliance with the goals established under section 2(b), consistent with the guidance issued under section 3(a).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14BE22789D734D039DD6EF39188D3912"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Spend analysis</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and in accordance with the guidance issued under section 3(a), the head of an Executive agency shall conduct a spend analysis of procurements by the agency during fiscal year 2017 to establish a baseline for spend under management.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H841DBEA2EF6A45F1A4183CBC6F08E0FD"><enum>5.</enum><header>Study by Comptroller General</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7C8FBD1264A84434BF50C33D7F8A85EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a study to assess the impact of the use of Governmentwide procurement contracts and Federal supply schedules on the taxpayer; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H679D5C7D91CA45EE9F91DA861D3F1672"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report on the results of such study.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H86FB8ACF3BE847BCA89EF30BC4E16B1C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H3F69700918824492B30B83592A7029C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Executive agency</header><text>The term <quote>Executive agency</quote> means the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HBA30AF2ACAEA4406B9AC0A3BA51C25C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An Executive department (as defined in section 105 of title 5, United States Code).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H862B5F4F7B0F4EA1BB0E58BE6AEE9DBA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Environmental Protection Agency.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC4EB6CD5E154C318241E0FC72887B7F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA887E30B39A14284ABACA2E317B375E7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Agency for International Development.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6306B4E4E5743DFBACF5AF043A36280"><enum>(E)</enum><text>General Services Administration.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB0F93BF7B4447DD8158C4395D3A58B8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>National Science Foundation.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B6BA468933440C5B0ED1D938B0ED2D2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3436519CB99B444EA77B595955780741"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Office of Personnel Management.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD99609166A254BAE9BEF47DAA369CDE0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Small Business Administration.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF29E244AA7A344309966F96F9B5FC932"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Social Security Administration.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBAD514B5EA049CCAEB94EF74895A346"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Category management</header><text>The term <quote>category management</quote> means a business practice for reducing duplication in contracting, more effectively leveraging the buying power of the Federal Government, and promoting the use of best-in-class solutions and practices throughout the Federal Government.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1790D272E02149E5A1DBB6CED5B0FC65"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Common</header><text>The term <quote>common</quote> means, when used with respect to a good or service, that such good or service is—</text> <subparagraph id="HEFC1681926584B6A86495ED903956A48"><enum>(A)</enum><text>procured by all or most Executive agencies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04BD4B1AC1624E05A3E256CC74EBFD2D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not unique to the mission of an individual Executive agency;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB71641434AC04A089340769781536D3E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>interchangeable between Executive agencies; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23532DDC96A4414893917A71484731C8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>generally available commercially.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD4C1D6C4BFB4276A22D9EAB550D3435"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H90685D2641F54B98AB34CEBA7366B40E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>spend under management</header><text>The term <quote>spend under management</quote> means the number equal to the quotient obtained by dividing—</text> <subparagraph id="HCB3818EA5B364AB39FA7689B4753492E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total spending on preferred Governmentwide contract vehicles; by</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81D6D48019084C2981BBD74DDFCAB72D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total spending on all Governmentwide contract vehicles.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

