<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5C38DF2382B64C78AC08DB3803D34518" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4252 IH: Geothermal Production Expansion Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4252</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171103">November 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To expand geothermal production, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB944A4B8538747B3A96BCD2FE8944D2C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H719E8BD2E47C48D09DB2A389BF095649" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Geothermal Production Expansion Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB6CB222510AC4BD5BE2B6328BE9B9A9D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Noncompetitive leasing of adjoining areas for development of geothermal resources</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4(b) of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1003">30 U.S.C. 1003(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD063E37A19144B69B0EF75BAED418F25" style="OLC">
				<paragraph id="H4D8DC30C3C0C4986908E4A4AD4336B25"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Adjoining land</header>
 <subparagraph id="H99DE9E2C8D4E4B6EBD57B066AADE653F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph:</text> <clause id="HB25ED86BE05140A6872099928D7DDD2F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Fair market value per acre</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fair market value per acre</term> means a dollar amount per acre that—</text>
 <subclause id="H7AB8256F6F9B4D68952C088C81818B6B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>except as provided in this clause, shall be equal to the market value per acre (taking into account the determination under subparagraph (B)(iii) regarding a valid discovery on the adjoining land) as determined by the Secretary under regulations issued under this paragraph;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7AA2C442EAF5415DB33B221EE2AD9AA3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall be determined by the Secretary with respect to a lease under this paragraph, by not later than the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date the Secretary receives an application for the lease; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H33430CC2F75643039FFAB547E2983B86"><enum>(III)</enum><text>shall be not less than the greater of—</text> <item id="H120578E46D5943B099795189E68A8606"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>4 times the median amount paid per acre for all land leased under this Act during the preceding year; or</text>
 </item><item id="HD84AB26CAB5240CF9371CB262F9FA3C0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>$50.</text> </item></subclause></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5EE6A586B324FCD8654496D3C62D658"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Industry standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>industry standards</term> means the standards by which a qualified geothermal professional assesses whether downhole or flowing temperature measurements with indications of permeability are sufficient to produce energy from geothermal resources, as determined through flow or injection testing or measurement of lost circulation while drilling.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4B07F76A4BF94321B02201D983CF4D30"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Qualified Federal land</header><text>The term <term>qualified Federal land</term> means land that is otherwise available for leasing under this Act.</text> </clause><clause id="H4F60B90B66394D7C9218CC2C16F05F6C"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Qualified geothermal professional</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified geothermal professional</term> means an individual who is an engineer or geoscientist in good professional standing with at least 5 years of experience in geothermal exploration, development, or project assessment.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8B592913BF1C4338AF88E3B8E2CBA30F"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Qualified lessee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified lessee</term> means a person that may hold a geothermal lease under this Act (including applicable regulations).</text> </clause><clause id="H1CEA10C7F38B4853B60B54E65A70F53D"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Valid discovery</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>valid discovery</term> means a discovery of a geothermal resource by a new or existing slim hole or production well, that exhibits downhole or flowing temperature measurements with indications of permeability that are sufficient to meet industry standards.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC8D98510F5A4CBA8805CA7BC793992A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>An area of qualified Federal land that adjoins other land for which a qualified lessee holds a legal right to develop geothermal resources may be available for a noncompetitive lease under this section to the qualified lessee at the fair market value per acre, if—</text>
 <clause id="H8CE8556209CD4A69BE1B2DEB16CC347C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the area of qualified Federal land—</text> <subclause id="HA1218189E66840E1BFD94A1B834CC8FB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>consists of not less than 1 acre and not more than 640 acres; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H529179A6272149D5B13CCF0ED6E08188"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is not already leased under this Act or nominated to be leased under subsection (a);</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HC30D7D7B9379461D8358A3775785F310"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the qualified lessee has not previously received a noncompetitive lease under this paragraph in connection with the valid discovery for which data has been submitted under clause (iii)(I); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9484FB3D49C84CC7AD368FE06B794AC0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>sufficient geological and other technical data prepared by a qualified geothermal professional has been submitted by the qualified lessee to the applicable Federal land management agency that would lead individuals who are experienced in the subject matter to believe that—</text>
 <subclause id="HE96363EBC37D4B47BE54E9CAA7CD5F84"><enum>(I)</enum><text>there is a valid discovery of geothermal resources on the land for which the qualified lessee holds the legal right to develop geothermal resources; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7BF43D42BD404D91BDA427AE47F0C5C1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that thermal feature extends into the adjoining areas.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EECCB68B51C429C8D5B3E4322863761"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Determination of fair market value</header> <clause id="HCE648CED5DA247B18233617A6A42A394"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text>
 <subclause id="HABE124E10EC346A480541C7589E2CFFA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>publish a notice of any request to lease land under this paragraph;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HB521D615C0DD478AAB07380197A760CB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>determine fair market value for purposes of this paragraph in accordance with procedures for making those determinations that are established by regulations issued by the Secretary;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HCF7BE7ADFF4F46A1B06FE0FC490EFAF8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>provide to a qualified lessee and publish, with an opportunity for public comment for a period of 30 days, any proposed determination under this subparagraph of the fair market value of an area that the qualified lessee seeks to lease under this paragraph; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB9C9C0E4FECF47E59B33A80E053DF439"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>provide to the qualified lessee and any adversely affected party the opportunity to appeal the final determination of fair market value in an administrative proceeding before the applicable Federal land management agency, in accordance with applicable law (including regulations).</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HBA3F3F3E0C4547B99DF31DCF844F048A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation on nomination</header><text>After publication of a notice of request to lease land under this paragraph, the Secretary may not accept under subsection (a) any nomination of the land for leasing unless the request has been denied or withdrawn.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7694D2E96EC4475D97E6C5798D11105F"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Annual rental</header><text>For purposes of section 5(a)(3), a lease awarded under this paragraph shall be considered a lease awarded in a competitive lease sale.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94EB21CB940B4CC88AE9AD2685A0B0E5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Geothermal Production Expansion Act of 2017</short-title>, the Secretary shall issue regulations to carry out this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section></legis-body></bill> 

