<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H567DD905EC814DD6BA0FD89609E2BC30" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2984 IH: High Risk Pool, No Reward Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2984</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170621">June 21, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to restrict Members of Congress who
			 represent a State with a waiver approved under the amendments made by the
			 American Health Care Act of 2017 to the same health insurance coverage as
			 is available under such waiver to their constituents.</official-title></form>
 <legis-body id="HDF159CCD31E04AF9AA93B2C2FB96876B" style="OLC"><section id="id8BDE9DF5C82546D787CA83C58375B7A1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>High Risk Pool, No Reward Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3C2F1E8D356F4F04A9429F5CB38B4628" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restricting access of certain Members of Congress, who represent a State with an AHCA approved waiver, to health insurance coverage available under such waiver to their constituents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1312(d)(3) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18032">42 U.S.C. 18032(d)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD3AD17A4777241C4899654DED1152CDF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)(i), by inserting <quote>except as provided in subparagraph (E),</quote> after <quote>Notwithstanding any other provision of law,</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H510E9DE041004CB088E53F0046CF4DFA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE42457C13CC5422D9AABDFFB5D5B05CF" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H692E95D9871F46948F14E725CD2AC458"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Coverage of Members of Congress consistent with AHCA State waivers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State that has a waiver approved and in effect under section 2701(b) of the Public Health Service Act, as added by section 136(a) of the American Health Care Act of 2017, for a purpose described in paragraph (1)(C) of such section 2701(b), a Member of Congress who represents such State or a district in the State—</text>
 <clause id="HD5192B4AC15A4171AB75309D98C5EDB7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not eligible to receive coverage under any health benefits plan (or to receive any Government contribution regarding coverage under such plan) under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, with respect to their service as a Member of Congress; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAB1C750DDF304EF3A4BA57B4917DA811"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is eligible to enroll in health insurance coverage in the individual market in the State under this Act and under such waiver (including, to the extent applicable, through a high-risk program that carries out the purpose described in paragraph (1) or (2) of section 2202(a) of the Social Security Act or a program established under section 2205 of such Act) in the same manner as the Member’s constituents who are eligible to enroll in such coverage.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


