<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC3681128D3E14FD484A7F02A1D7A3834" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4559 IH: Global Aviation System Security Reform Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4559</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171206">December 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000298">Mr. Estes of Kansas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To conduct a global aviation security review, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H03BEA52ED9A74D7E8C6D2A7027258E4D" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA4D88B9BA0154902A0997D36B61F0B40" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Global Aviation System Security Reform Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4BA20479EA0546D2A0BCD8C8E45E7B89"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7CF7876BC2504DE5BD1863A57A7A7516"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The term <quote>Administration</quote> means the Transportation Security Administration.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H228110B2DB964A67B2333334F30F3DEA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <quote>Administrator</quote> means the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B36F8247E8C4263A5FA0B37269A4DD0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H135BFA69EB0444EA8E98B896F9B9747C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Global aviation security review</header>
 <subsection id="HE53BB61D3B8F4898AE4B0FEACB6D464F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall conduct a global aviation security review to address improving aviation security standards across the global aviation system.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H06E888E62B0A49DEAB79BFDCBDFA666F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The global aviation security review established under subsection (a) shall include input from the following entities:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF44CD36E37864656967B307D8B1FD1DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Office of Global Strategies of the Administration.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H822E94D5A5434CA399EDF773DF3F13E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Office of Intelligence and Analysis of the Administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H20809C203F884670BFAB9E8D1999E4C4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Office of Security Policy and Industry Engagement of the Administration.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDEA2B97B9EEF40C2B1ACB4485D81D71C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall coordinate with the following entities on the global aviation security review:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7150F0D61C4745A8917ACAE2CC49D615"><enum>(1)</enum><text>U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H77017FFB63B843608A43A3D64B7F8B57"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Office of International Engagement of the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D4EF823BD4D4439A03B03F0A5C772DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Department of State.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC26EE24D2FD4168B1C8033B60C76C75"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any other relevant office or agency of the Federal Government, as determined by the Administrator.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFFE016A7F7A3474F93A7C0AF40100149"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>The global aviation security review shall establish best practices regarding the following:</text> <paragraph id="HC8FFF2BD36324A3E9E2AA0A03BFE81E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Collaborating with foreign partners to improve global aviation security capabilities and standards.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD077765AC5B74FA9A974B7BF514A3151"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Identifying foreign partners that have not successfully implemented security protocols from the International Civil Aviation Organization or the Department of Homeland Security and have not taken steps to implement such security protocols.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD80EF8DCAB04407D86682DEBE4FB7B8E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Improving the development, outreach, and implementation process for security directives or emergency amendments, as the case may be, issued to domestic and foreign air carriers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5004F13380C489A8B34C3C5AA7DE98C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Assessing the cybersecurity and cyber espionage risk of security screening equipment.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H59F48E2F42B2494488107739DE5BC561"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header> <subsection id="HBFF402D5AC7F4B698EA88FF5F1466A33"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Progress report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall report to the appropriate congressional committees on the organization, development, and progress of the global aviation security review required under section 3.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAF97FCA4B631401AB856E17A1D170888"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 240 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on best practices identified by the global aviation security review required under section 3 and the actions the Administrator has taken to implement such best practices.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


