<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2C2DE5CB19444C1BAF05500061EB0058" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3289 IH: To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to require identification and description on the website of the Federal Communications Commission of items to be decided on authority delegated by the Commission.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3289</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170718">July 18, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to require identification and description on the website of
			 the Federal Communications Commission of items to be decided on authority
			 delegated by the Commission.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H779979038E63449FBC4641A19361AC07" style="OLC">
		<section id="H947429C7BBD74AE1B303E329D2A2FB06" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Identification and description of items to be decided on authority delegated by the Commission</header>
 <subsection id="H79286BC6CD044A0EAA059B97E5FA9475"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5(c) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/155">47 U.S.C. 155(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD2BBA1FEF8094C56AD0938C485B541AA" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HCC325C76706B45E9BA4A7D386EF21D39" indent="up1"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 48 hours before the time when an order, decision, report, or action is made or taken pursuant to delegation under paragraph (1), such order, decision, report, or action shall be identified and briefly described on the Internet website of the Commission, unless the authority to which the delegation is made for good cause finds that such identification and description are likely to lead to a result described in a paragraph of section 552b(c) of title 5, United States Code. This paragraph shall not apply with respect to an order, decision, report, or action that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFEC8DA05C94B4309AAF7233C27C83110"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not receive a delegated authority number pursuant to the procedures of the Commission;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF964FBCAE7D54CFC95B7E6FF0D0BDBDD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is made or taken on authority delegated to an administrative law judge; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H952A851ACC324EE6AF7FDA77CFA7CC68"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is made or taken to address an immediate threat to health or safety that constitutes an emergency requiring an expedited response from the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7EDFBCB6E5184CB2B478B70F6A949698"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply with respect to an order, decision, report, or action made or taken after the date that is 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


