<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4A290E0C5BB2460483BDDCF898062436" key="H" public-private="public">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2025 IH: Abuse-Deterrent Opioids Plan for Tomorrow Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2025</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001106">Mr. Costello of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend section 505(c)(3)(E) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to prevent certain applications from being considered ineligible for approval under section 505(c) of such Act on the basis that the proposed labeling includes information describing abuse-deterrent properties that otherwise would be blocked by exclusivity under clause (iii) or (iv) of section 503(c)(3)(E) of such Act, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form> 
<legis-body id="H2E17B1C6DD4F4836B0817D733E4702F7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H47B41E8D8AAC41339016BF4CFED29BB2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Abuse-Deterrent Opioids Plan for Tomorrow Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H76FCC31473EF4935AECD15C9E7449A3D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Labeling information describing abuse-deterrent properties</header> <subsection id="H384343CA06CB4EAD943D19057AA27679"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (E) of section 505(c)(3) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(c)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4973DB539A8F4892A715325BE6EFA06A" style="OLC"> 
<clause id="HB0C6BD988A204880A7BFB708FC090F10" indent="up2"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A drug for which an application (or a supplement to an application) described in subsection (b)(2) is submitted shall not be considered ineligible for approval under this subsection on the basis that its labeling includes information describing the abuse-deterrent properties of the drug (including abuse-deterrent claims) that otherwise would be blocked by exclusivity under clause (iii) or (iv) of this subparagraph if—</text> <subclause id="H56D7D08E7784439DBF6E18D318DF8930"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the investigation or investigations relied upon by the applicant for approval of the labeling information were conducted by or for the applicant or the applicant has obtained a right of reference or use from the person by or for whom the investigation or investigations were conducted; and</text> </subclause>
<subclause id="H63E39E3A76D0461C91435AFEAA877A8B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the drug has meaningful technological differences compared to the drug otherwise protected by exclusivity under clause (iii) or (iv) of this subparagraph.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection id="H589A7309649648458005A74352EE43BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD4D6D6A9BEF54472A7B8AE955F3D375D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, issue draft guidance regarding the award and scope of exclusivity under clauses (iii) and (iv) of section 505(c)(3)(E) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(c)(3)(E)</external-xref>) for drugs with properties designed to deter abuse and the exception to such exclusivity described in clause (vi) of such section 505(c)(3)(E), as added by subsection (a); and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D213DC33803413AB10650CE1C3F65A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 18 months after the close of the period for receiving public comments on such draft guidance, publish final guidance on the topics described in paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HFCDF9ADB1570462D93314116710FA6FF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) applies with respect to applications, and supplements to applications, that are submitted or pending under section 505(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355(b)</external-xref>) on or after January 1, 2017.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

