<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H54071B58AD084233B61A73A566151F73" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1775 IH: Prescription Reduction in Costs for Everyone (PRICE) Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1775</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170329">March 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to direct the President to negotiate
			 prescription drug prices and establish a formulary on behalf of Medicare
			 beneficiaries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8C17D2AE0DD14FF39923ABB0C0B1F01E" style="OLC">
 <section id="H64510D30AB884E24BBC3224FDD5DB85A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prescription Reduction in Costs for Everyone (PRICE) Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HE04BB15C00044CF29C127C89E53CA3AE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H61882DA1C5634299B14E61B7893F5074"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The President has announced his intention to bring down prices of prescription drugs.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H659ABCB8D2B544F1AA7124B6062D85F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The President has touted his negotiating skills and referred to himself as a <quote>master negotiator</quote>.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HFBE3EEE7299E417DA20932807D5F7651"><enum>3.</enum><header>Presidential negotiation of prescription drug prices</header>
 <subsection id="H3411B8FEE7A24D94B71DD0CBED35929A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Negotiation by President</header><text>Section 1860D–11 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-111">42 U.S.C. 1395w–111</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (i) (relating to noninterference) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H99490011B67E4BBC8D0CD8049013FC5A" style="OLC">
					<clause id="H8F099157008243FEAE6B1B3347CECD0C" indent="up3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Negotiation of lower drug prices</header>
 </clause><paragraph id="H8A29372EB82944BAA23E197AB3BE038F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President shall negotiate with pharmaceutical manufacturers the prices (including discounts, rebates, and other price concessions) that may be charged to PDP sponsors and MA organizations for covered part D drugs for part D eligible individuals who are enrolled under a prescription drug plan or under an MA–PD plan.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HC045E5B21F804F9CA17D37F416248C15"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No change in rules for formularies</header>
 <subparagraph id="H90A5CB1F11694079B84B61707BA81599"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in paragraph (1) shall be construed to authorize the President to establish or require a particular formulary.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H771DA04CCB4749F99B661D225BAE9402"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not be construed as affecting the President’s authority to ensure appropriate and adequate access to covered part D drugs under prescription drug plans and under MA–PD plans, including compliance of such plans with formulary requirements under section 1860D–4(b)(3).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H84E9F66408FB4018B67430A86DBEAE93"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as preventing the sponsor of a prescription drug plan, or an organization offering an MA–PD plan, from obtaining a discount or reduction of the price for a covered part D drug below the price negotiated under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H683091374EB644E997C1A5180678DD2A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Semi-annual reports to congress</header><text>Not later than June 1, 2018, and every 6 months thereafter, the President shall submit to the Committees on Ways and Means, Energy and Commerce, and Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on negotiations conducted by the President to achieve lower prices for Medicare beneficiaries, and the prices and price discounts achieved by the President as a result of such negotiations.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H914818CE63FF4BDEAC921D0E94FF70F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall first apply to negotiations and prices for plan years beginning on January 1, 2018.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H53EC4AEC50414F02A705A6A9437D2767"><enum>4.</enum><header>Presidential establishment of Medicare operated prescription drug plan option</header>
 <subsection id="HDF5D264566FA45199C38C5F07ACE75ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart 2 of part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act is amended by inserting after section 1860D–11 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-111">42 U.S.C. 1395w–111</external-xref>) the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block act-name="Social Security Act" id="H9FF93826354146B18606479864C350CF" style="traditional">
 <section id="HA626F099F44F47DB81A4859C48C08161"><enum>1860D–11A.</enum><header>Medicare operated prescription drug plan option</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF2E3EEE16C9A4953B3BD2FEBD32F4A66"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this part, for each year (beginning with 2018), in addition to any plans offered under section 1860D–11, the President shall offer one or more Medicare operated prescription drug plans (as defined in subsection (c)) with a service area that consists of the entire United States and shall enter into negotiations in accordance with subsection (b) with pharmaceutical manufacturers to reduce the purchase cost of covered part D drugs for eligible part D individuals who enroll in such a plan.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBAC1528BF9964E99BEB5DF30BD726692"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Negotiations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of offering a Medicare operated prescription drug plan under this section, the President shall negotiate with pharmaceutical manufacturers with respect to the purchase price of covered part D drugs in a Medicare operated prescription drug plan and shall encourage the use of more affordable therapeutic equivalents to the extent such practices do not override medical necessity as determined by the prescribing physician. To the extent practicable and consistent with the previous sentence, the President shall implement strategies similar to those used by other Federal purchasers of prescription drugs, and other strategies, including the use of a formulary and formulary incentives in subsection (e), to reduce the purchase cost of covered part D drugs.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H98582BF2E5814484BDD82FD4D77ED3DC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Medicare operated prescription drug plan defined</header><text>For purposes of this part, the term <term>Medicare operated prescription drug plan</term> means a prescription drug plan that offers qualified prescription drug coverage and access to negotiated prices described in section 1860D–2(a)(1)(A). Such a plan may offer supplemental prescription drug coverage in the same manner as other qualified prescription drug coverage offered by other prescription drug plans.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="HF8CFCC6B90F749E2A0EB9D92372EB2B2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Monthly beneficiary premium</header>
 <paragraph id="HCFF805DFABF44862903A1F960684B472"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified prescription drug coverage</header><text>The monthly beneficiary premium for qualified prescription drug coverage and access to negotiated prices described in section 1860D–2(a)(1)(A) to be charged under a Medicare operated prescription drug plan shall be uniform nationally. Such premium for months in 2018 and each succeeding year shall be based on the average monthly per capita actuarial cost of offering the Medicare operated prescription drug plan for the year involved, including administrative expenses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H713C59C4E42240B2A57537874C85EC2C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Supplemental prescription drug coverage</header><text>Insofar as a Medicare operated prescription drug plan offers supplemental prescription drug coverage, the President may adjust the amount of the premium charged under paragraph (1).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9EE24EF576C5487EB1AFE5F8B2EAE6EB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of a formulary and formulary incentives</header>
 <paragraph id="H51D4305D544349D790EAE11F732B70C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the operation of a Medicare operated prescription drug plan, the President shall establish and apply a formulary (and may include formulary incentives described in paragraph (2)(C)(ii)) in accordance with this subsection in order to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5ADE013444804BCB8B8606DA6AB948CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increase patient safety;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27C637C6CAEF4B57BF62E0D6142BB66D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase appropriate use and reduce inappropriate use of drugs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4ECC05762944EDA9E32F836406F059C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reward value.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65BE878B926A4791BFDB629F5261CC9B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Development of initial formulary</header> <subparagraph id="H1F9D0CF315B94D8F946A16C7FBC69DF2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting covered part D drugs for inclusion in a formulary, the President shall consider clinical benefit and price.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DC221C43B1041E090A3DB7144AA830E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Role of AHRQ</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality shall be responsible for assessing the clinical benefit of covered part D drugs and making recommendations to the President regarding which drugs should be included in the formulary. In conducting such assessments and making such recommendations, the Director shall—</text>
 <clause id="HD6AE243C375A420EBA3FC3936C0FD806"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consider safety concerns including those identified by the Federal Food and Drug Administration;</text> </clause><clause id="HCE45409FDD6D4826BE78C7E6106B09A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use available data and evaluations, with priority given to randomized controlled trials, to examine clinical effectiveness, comparative effectiveness, safety, and enhanced compliance with a drug regimen;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC239F42270B34B6A8E69A3B105DB09EE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>use the same classes of drugs developed by United States Pharmacopeia for this part;</text> </clause><clause id="H23AF3E4F59BD4A2F9CC2782069E03ECE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>consider evaluations made by—</text>
 <subclause id="H2325F40E1B864849B6AD3D67FE77C3A2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Director under section 1013 of the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE5D0B3664E264E6EA949FB2DBF28A917"><enum>(II)</enum><text>other Federal entities, such as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H807C92CE965F495B8859A8830C45171E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>other private and public entities, such as the Drug Effectiveness Review Project and Medicaid programs; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HFC9B5801030D47FD9DCAC7B828A09EEE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>recommend to the President—</text> <subclause id="H373327BA8FE9465A87B1903511FA0827"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">those drugs in a class that provide a greater clinical benefit, including fewer safety concerns or less risk of side effects, than another drug in the same class that should be included in the formulary;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3EFC26616C6B4A5EA261B09E5203F136"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">those drugs in a class that provide less clinical benefit, including greater safety concerns or a greater risk of side effects, than another drug in the same class that should be excluded from the formulary; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB729DC1EADC44627A3A60495A8A41B1A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>drugs in a class with same or similar clinical benefit for which it would be appropriate for the Secretary to competitively bid (or negotiate) for placement on the formulary.</text>
										</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA59A21543414CE6853BA7D61B7C308A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consideration of AHRQ recommendations</header>
 <clause id="HAD0AB506524148BA8FB13C0763A9BA1D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President, after taking into consideration the recommendations under subparagraph (B)(v), shall establish a formulary, and formulary incentives, to encourage use of covered part D drugs that—</text>
 <subclause id="H588110A1F7E44C9B8543166FFC305B11"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have a lower cost and provide a greater clinical benefit than other drugs;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HD3BB1C9CD8CA4A24A2ABC7151C09DD38"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have a lower cost than other drugs with same or similar clinical benefit; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0DC2E20F4C774853AF2DD3ABD7C8059A"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have the same cost but provide greater clinical benefit than other drugs.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H570E5D4AA4A64ED29288FF472B630E6F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Formulary incentives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The formulary incentives under clause (i) may be in the form of one or more of the following:</text>
 <subclause id="HBF5F915BC5294567889D61535EA59016"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tiered copayments.</text> </subclause><subclause id="HAB336451FAA848E2B26A5986FF2E4152"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Reference pricing.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H069548A7FCAE423A9D3CEA6419E38158"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Prior authorization.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H652BBCBA9E144C60B18FA74F7EDE9C70"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Step therapy.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9A4A0BFBA2714EDCAE1A4F797D787B2A"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Medication therapy management.</text> </subclause><subclause id="HDD15EAF5DF034C7AA597E01A8148C806"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Generic drug substitution.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HDB11DE108A4E42D5B1218ED3F3FF8AB4"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Flexibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In applying such formulary incentives the President may decide not to impose any cost-sharing for a covered part D drug for which—</text>
 <subclause id="H3569E844A4AF46A5A23C9DE4D521C96A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the elimination of cost sharing would be expected to increase compliance with a drug regimen; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H20B4DD862E274707967BFF6B31BEBBB3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>compliance would be expected to produce savings under part A or B or both.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0305C558FD9141F693D2CEC5388AEF4F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations on formulary</header><text>In any formulary established under this subsection, the formulary may not be changed during a year, except—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2694D3B321024F2FBC3F2CDCBA65EFB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to add a generic version of a covered part D drug that entered the market;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99AF3D81F72B4CE0859FF70DA52DED7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to remove such a drug for which a safety problem is found; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA632A49D6BAD47DBA93AE0E1FE082E08"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to add a drug that the President identifies as a drug which treats a condition for which there has not previously been a treatment option or for which a clear and significant benefit has been demonstrated over other covered part D drugs.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF27B63AC53C1446D8D230B4591A9978D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Adding drugs to the initial formulary</header>
 <subparagraph id="H395F3B6335284CA985B0320B6B15A6B1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Use of advisory committee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall establish and appoint an advisory committee (in this paragraph referred to as the <term>advisory committee</term>)—</text>
 <clause id="HA93DD3B29EB84458B629B6DF69BF5D7F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to review petitions from drug manufacturers, health care provider organizations, patient groups, and other entities for inclusion of a drug in, or other changes to, such formulary; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H519E2B813EEC46A9BC9C3EAD5E6DCC9D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to recommend any changes to the formulary established under this subsection.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCD918A7C3F14B3D845FFD287828EC7D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Composition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The advisory committee shall be composed of 9 members and shall include representatives of physicians, pharmacists, and consumers and others with expertise in evaluating prescription drugs. The President shall select members based on their knowledge of pharmaceuticals and the Medicare population. Members shall be deemed to be special Government employees for purposes of applying the conflict of interest provisions under section 208 of title 18, United States Code, and no waiver of such provisions for such a member shall be permitted.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A6864985B5443CCB780077A6F4470B7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The advisory committee shall consult, as necessary, with physicians who are specialists in treating the disease for which a drug is being considered.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91942C723866481D822701FAA60B424E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Request for studies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The advisory committee may request the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality or an academic or research institution to study and make a report on a petition described in subparagraph (A)(ii) in order to assess—</text>
 <clause id="H72B09DBDD6EC455291380651B44AF9B9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>clinical effectiveness;</text> </clause><clause id="HD2581C1AB54B4D41873546A54CF582F5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>comparative effectiveness;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD54F27B06FB34D65AC1B4685AC3E9BAC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>safety; and</text> </clause><clause id="H3FD04A052ECA4872871A4CA0567ACBF3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>enhanced compliance with a drug regimen.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56ACD0B8C2A6401FAEF300B46E271A18"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>The advisory committee shall make recommendations to the President regarding—</text> <clause id="HDACE51C922B74926A2420AFA6BEFF4F2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether a covered part D drug is found to provide a greater clinical benefit, including fewer safety concerns or less risk of side effects, than another drug in the same class that is currently included in the formulary and should be included in the formulary;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB418CF75AE4A443A9A13E3C11D6CFC38"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether a covered part D drug is found to provide less clinical benefit, including greater safety concerns or a greater risk of side effects, than another drug in the same class that is currently included in the formulary and should not be included in the formulary; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H07D9D1CF27874D45A3423016D06455DB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whether a covered part D drug has the same or similar clinical benefit to a drug in the same class that is currently included in the formulary and whether the drug should be included in the formulary.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C1B010BC0964844BB5A866251324AE0"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Limitations on review of manufacturer petitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The advisory committee shall not review a petition of a drug manufacturer under subparagraph (A)(ii) with respect to a covered part D drug unless the petition is accompanied by the following:</text>
 <clause id="HE2794CB619A745BDA3508D1259E707AE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Raw data from clinical trials on the safety and effectiveness of the drug.</text> </clause><clause id="H5F59BE83C47143C3B2F6CD39F3B3B191"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Any data from clinical trials conducted using active controls on the drug or drugs that are the current standard of care.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDC90FDBBA99B4109A85009EA63D76B12"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any available data on comparative effectiveness of the drug.</text> </clause><clause id="H69CC523260A343AE932FB1B0FC85EDD8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Any other information the President requires for the advisory committee to complete its review.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DC3E6117A4A40B0B473657089EBBE19"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Response to recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall review the recommendations of the advisory committee and if the President accepts such recommendations the President shall modify the formulary established under this subsection accordingly. Nothing in this section shall preclude the President from adding to the formulary a drug for which the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality or the advisory committee has not made a recommendation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA83BD649C2A84AC5B46A8FE002A0C19D"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Notice of changes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall provide timely notice to beneficiaries and health professionals about changes to the formulary or formulary incentives.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H669A10DD857649A1827B080AC8A0B06E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Informing beneficiaries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall take steps to inform beneficiaries about the availability of a Medicare operated drug plan or plans including providing information in the annual handbook distributed to all beneficiaries and adding information to the official public Medicare Web site related to prescription drug coverage available through this part.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCD4285D24AA54D368A40C495C21F8E92"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Application of all other requirements for prescription drug plans</header><text>Except as specifically provided in this section, any Medicare operated drug plan shall meet the same requirements as apply to any other prescription drug plan, including the requirements of section 1860D–4(b)(1) relating to assuring pharmacy access.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H6C2536EEC16244F2AA4394141C572271"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="H31EE4B5992C94320AC62791C0428BB87"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 1860D–3(a) of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-103">42 U.S.C. 1395w–103(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block act-name="Social Security Act" id="H1CC8679D822A494B9560FDCD4536E483"> <paragraph id="H1061953FC24B42C6B776D4BD917315A1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Availability of the medicare operated prescription drug plan</header><text>A Medicare operated prescription drug plan (as defined in section 1860D–11A(c)) shall be offered nationally in accordance with section 1860D–11A.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2571C5B3BA0497CBA2079A31469E9FE"><enum>(2)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC82D24FB63A244AF9CADD5BE3627E138"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 1860D–3 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-103">42 U.S.C. 1395w–103</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H388EE59FD7F44B8087172087412115C3" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H41B5506DB1B84F3EAD32F64EBC2B1154"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Provisions only applicable in 2006 through 2017</header><text>The provisions of this section shall only apply with respect to 2006 through 2017.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56D76EFAEF62454EBE7676030B5DB431" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 1860D–11(g) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-111">42 U.S.C. 1395w–111(g)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H7481A45C918F4CBDB049C8D092738571" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HD5D0C79B7CAD4D6981D6B0C631D5EE61"><enum>(8)</enum><header>No authority for fallback plans after 2017</header><text>A fallback prescription drug plan shall not be available after December 31, 2017.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H62FD1EBF7E6C49D0A23553CCB5C3FF36"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 1860D–13(c)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-113">42 U.S.C. 1395w–113(c)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7902493415E1419BA342918B02418C4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">and Medicare operated prescription drug plans</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Fallback plans</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82041D71A06D42E9AF03DD6CDE28D59B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>or a Medicare operated prescription drug plan</quote> after <quote>a fallback prescription drug plan</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE43124FC842A4A84983056B729B48EAF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–16(b)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-116">42 U.S.C. 1395w–116(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H7A0C9A24A7184498AA346CF400D57DC1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD31F65D3586414CB90A7A864238AF29"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H408EE9F5D4464749AA51F3A5ED97CA93"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
						<quoted-block id="HA9394D4D205A44EE8384380F4B491743">
 <subparagraph id="HBCD0494F2DD5432AB646A642615F7027"><enum>(E)</enum><text>payments for expenses incurred with respect to the operation of Medicare operated prescription drug plans under section 1860D–11A.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87BB34BD40114321A5AEA44366A07551"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–41(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-151">42 U.S.C. 1395w–151(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H7DA4A084CD494D80BD21D527E280C06F">
 <paragraph id="H7E8310DDAA92440B855C7E2F9958B670"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Medicare operated prescription drug plan</header><text>The term <term>Medicare operated prescription drug plan</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1860D–11A(c).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

