<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1575CAA8308B48D0A99EBB41C5F3413D" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1800 RH: To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to transfer certain Federal land to facilitate scientific research supporting Federal space and defense programs.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 327</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1800</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–442]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170330">March 30, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001250">Mr. Bishop of Utah</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00" deleted-display-style="italic">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action>
			<action-date>December 6, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 30, 2017</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to transfer certain Federal land to facilitate scientific
			 research supporting Federal space and defense programs.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HII00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HFE0C6A6A96A54E36A238099F5F67CE33" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
		<section id="HB1C16CFE82194C5282407EA7E56AF537" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Land conveyance, Wasatch-Cache National Forest, Rich County, Utah</header>
 <subsection id="HAE2AD68070844C81BE73D5DC6B578555"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Land conveyance authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights, not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Agriculture shall convey, without consideration, to the Utah State University Research Foundation, (in this section referred to as the <quote>Foundation</quote>) all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to a parcel of real property consisting of approximately 80 acres, including improvements thereon, located outside of the boundaries of the Wasatch-Cache National Forest, Rich County, Utah, within Sections 19 and 30, Township 14 North, Range 5 East, Salt Lake Base and Meridian for the purpose of permitting the Foundation to use the property for scientific and educational purposes.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5D44554CB95D4033A56BB6FE417E5B9C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reversionary interest</header><text>If the Secretary of Agriculture determines at any time that the real property conveyed under subsection (a) is not being used in accordance with the purpose of the conveyance specified in such subsection, all right, title and interest in and to such real property, including any improvements thereto, shall, at the option of the Secretary, revert to and become the property of the United States, and the United States shall have the right of immediate entry onto such real property. A determination by the Secretary under this subsection shall be made on the record after an opportunity for a hearing.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H37B2B4E4162C44289BC0985D579F4AA3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Payment of costs of conveyance</header>
 <paragraph id="HA5F2F613FE84451090CFFCA8552E3ED5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payment required</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall require the Foundation to cover the costs (except any costs for environmental remediation of the property) to be incurred by the Secretary, or to reimburse the Secretary for such costs incurred by the Secretary, to carry out the conveyance under subsection (a), including survey costs, costs for environmental documentation, and any other administrative costs related to the conveyance. If amounts are collected from the Foundation in advance of the Secretary incurring the actual costs, and the amount collected exceeds the costs actually incurred by the Secretary to carry out the conveyance, the Secretary shall refund the excess amount to the Foundation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H99AFC8C4A4BC4DC58A627D4BDFC8336B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of amounts received</header><text>Amounts received as reimbursement under paragraph (1) shall be credited to the fund or account that was used to cover those costs incurred by the Secretary in carrying out the conveyance. Amounts so credited shall be merged with amounts in such fund or account, and shall be available for the same purposes, and subject to the same conditions and limitations, as amounts in such fund or account.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3145B1BDD1CD4A58B1AE8151009876D1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Description of property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exact acreage and legal description of the property to be conveyed under subsection (a) shall be determined by a survey satisfactory to the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2CD13025F460434E928F3C160A299745"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional terms and conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture may require such additional terms and conditions in connection with the conveyance under subsection (a) as the Secretary considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>December 6, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


