<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCAD7B815E46444C9BC33F5996219C562" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 179 IH: Miners Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 179</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170103">January 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000297">Mr. Jenkins of West Virginia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to transfer certain funds to the
			 Multiemployer Health Benefit Plan and the 1974 United Mine Workers of
			 America Pension Plan, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H65F825040631402F916D36BDE3220825" style="OLC">
 <section id="H57BA93A56F33489BBB1E5E337CD2100B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Miners Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HAA849AF7E32B41439820B0A8C6A8CBC1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reinstatement of Multiemployer Health Benefit Plan provisions of Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this Act, the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1201">30 U.S.C. 1201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended to read as if section 167 of the Continuing Appropriations Act, 2017, as amended by section 101(3) of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/254">Public Law 114–254</external-xref>, were not enacted.</text>
		</section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4871CBB633DB4F6F80C2348F70020EF1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Inclusion of certain retirees in the Multiemployer Health Benefit Plan</header>
 <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9ED90F7F1F5149B7A89DF36858D0D588"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 402 of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1232">30 U.S.C. 1232</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD87E8E21EB844B0491AA1530A9B93252"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(2)(C)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD6B3C8F0059E48AD9E196FC5CC656E53"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A transfer</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE530B5BD18AF432588469D713DC664C7" style="OLC"> <clause id="H82CB9E5C4028424A9503032F9C260496"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Transfer to the Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A transfer</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4161D959C5B94B608E5CFB46B62AE634"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (i) and (ii) as subclauses (I) and (II), respectively, and moving such subclauses 2 ems to the right; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81BADE559F3E410980C2E39F5B7776FB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking the matter following such subclause (II) (as so redesignated) and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE549D9A2C87044CA89D287451D5B1747" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H04E6A8F604EC4AF0BF793E2D9DFD01D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Calculation of excess</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The excess determined under clause (i) shall be calculated by taking into account only—</text> <subclause id="H37434F3322AB4B2798B79F2DCCC98890"><enum>(I)</enum><text>those beneficiaries actually enrolled in the Plan as of the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Miners Protection Act of 2017</short-title> who are eligible to receive health benefits under the Plan on the first day of the calendar year for which the transfer is made, other than those beneficiaries enrolled in the Plan under the terms of a participation agreement with the current or former employer of such beneficiaries; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD625645EA74D4391B0248CF8E2659A86"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">those beneficiaries whose health benefits, defined as those benefits payable directly following death or retirement or upon a finding of disability by an employer in the bituminous coal industry under a coal wage agreement (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9701">section 9701(b)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986), would be denied or reduced as a result of a bankruptcy proceeding commenced in 2012 or 2015.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H7E20CAA2FC684A9D9D5984023A51520E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Eligibility of certain retirees</header><text>Individuals referred to in clause (ii)(II) shall be treated as eligible to receive health benefits under the Plan.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H838B538FDBCC49F28B818B41C28563B0"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Requirements for transfer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of the transfer otherwise determined under this subparagraph for a fiscal year shall be reduced by any amount transferred for the fiscal year to the Plan, to pay benefits required under the Plan, from a voluntary employees' beneficiary association established as a result of a bankruptcy proceeding described in clause (ii).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBABD5E1DE0A5455CAD73137FAA110ABD"><enum>(v)</enum><header>VEBA transfer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The administrator of such voluntary employees’ beneficiary association shall transfer to the Plan any amounts received as a result of such bankruptcy proceeding, reduced by an amount for administrative costs of such association.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FD0ADD7C3B1402AB4AF32E57E592D72"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (i)—</text> <subparagraph id="H273FD2AD1A284E3A957AEEA5E680582A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8BED7E7BCCA4212B4EC48AD1A94162E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H50264A0A94DB4AAF875995C0D356820A" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H5F1B960A2B044ACD8C283BA7A924CE68"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additional amounts</header> <subparagraph id="HA19DB9B8FDB246D1AB3F5D7A59142A14"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Calculation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the dollar limitation specified in paragraph (3)(A) exceeds the aggregate amount required to be transferred under paragraphs (1) and (2) for a fiscal year, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer an additional amount equal to the difference between such dollar limitation and such aggregate amount to the trustees of the 1974 UMWA Pension Plan to pay benefits required under that plan.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DE76A00DF9549EAA44C422E0FBC7ECD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Cessation of transfers</header><text>The transfers described in subparagraph (A) shall cease as of the first fiscal year beginning after the first plan year for which the funded percentage (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/432">section 432(i)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) of the 1974 UMWA Pension Plan is at least 100 percent.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6362C1E6C766486CA92DFF403FB807F9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Prohibition on benefit increases, etc</header><text>During a fiscal year in which the 1974 UMWA Pension Plan is receiving transfers under subparagraph (A), no amendment of such plan which increases the liabilities of the plan by reason of any increase in benefits, any change in the accrual of benefits, or any change in the rate at which benefits become nonforfeitable under the plan may be adopted unless the amendment is required as a condition of qualification under part I of subchapter D of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D7EDFBF4ED64C53A7D3CABA466BF654"><enum>(D)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Treatment of transfers for purposes of withdrawal liability under ERISA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of any transfer made under subparagraph (A) (and any earnings attributable thereto) shall be disregarded in determining the unfunded vested benefits of the 1974 UMWA Pension Plan and the allocation of such unfunded vested benefits to an employer for purposes of determining the employer’s withdrawal liability under section 4201.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7B51CFC58DA4D65A03944C7AEC9ECEC"><enum>(E)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Requirement to maintain contribution rate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A transfer under subparagraph (A) shall not be made for a fiscal year unless the persons that are obligated to contribute to the 1974 UMWA Pension Plan on the date of the transfer are obligated to make the contributions at rates that are no less than those in effect on the date which is 30 days before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Miners Protection Act of 2017</short-title>.</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA8EEA118B8094AD6A1986D9C18E76A09"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Enhanced annual reporting</header>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30723625EC194CC982224C42332AA1CD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than the 90th day of each plan year beginning after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Miners Protection Act of 2017</short-title>, the trustees of the 1974 UMWA Pension Plan shall file with the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary's delegate and the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation a report (including appropriate documentation and actuarial certifications from the plan actuary, as required by the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary's delegate) that contains—</text>
 <subclause id="H5FEA1B520EAF4C67BA4387507C7F85D0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>whether the plan is in endangered or critical status under section 305 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/432">section 432</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 as of the first day of such plan year;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H37C3EC0A846D4D68BC5568F813DE9D97"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the funded percentage (as defined in section 432(i)(2) of such Code) as of the first day of such plan year, and the underlying actuarial value of assets and liabilities taken into account in determining such percentage;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HCEF5F77FDD7F416A809CA94726851C80"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the market value of the assets of the plan as of the last day of the plan year preceding such plan year;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H701D4C0722AE479AA9A84827795D59CB"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the total value of all contributions made during the plan year preceding such plan year;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HEA0D7A69279947248CCA53263A67B750"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the total value of all benefits paid during the plan year preceding such plan year;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HCFC9064602A4462295ECC9F7C4C9560D"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>cash flow projections for such plan year and either the 6 or 10 succeeding plan years, at the election of the trustees, and the assumptions relied upon in making such projections;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6A73CC243312446A87951314B8BC48A8"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>funding standard account projections for such plan year and the 9 succeeding plan years, and the assumptions relied upon in making such projections;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3FCAF5EF974A467AA16A538CDDCDC304"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>the total value of all investment gains or losses during the plan year preceding such plan year;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HEAA53CFE1A0B41659C798DB7A84ABC57"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>any significant reduction in the number of active participants during the plan year preceding such plan year, and the reason for such reduction;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB4F0C8C2C4734018A6DC3E03A7DE7D2C"><enum>(X)</enum><text>a list of employers that withdrew from the plan in the plan year preceding such plan year, and the resulting reduction in contributions;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC3FB7D6E1D094B47A71B9260E232059F"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>a list of employers that paid withdrawal liability to the plan during the plan year preceding such plan year and, for each employer, a total assessment of the withdrawal liability paid, the annual payment amount, and the number of years remaining in the payment schedule with respect to such withdrawal liability;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H617891D7F44448D6B476DB7566285449"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>any material changes to benefits, accrual rates, or contribution rates during the plan year preceding such plan year;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H39C70DCF0BFF4E11B592E17FB3CA3FD1"><enum>(XIII)</enum><text>any scheduled benefit increase or decrease in the plan year preceding such plan year having a material effect on liabilities of the plan;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5534766FE55B44CC9D15C5323EF0CF41"><enum>(XIV)</enum><text>details regarding any funding improvement plan or rehabilitation plan and updates to such plan;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H2E8B794D2DA04517A5D71BFB876AFD7F"><enum>(XV)</enum><text>the number of participants and beneficiaries during the plan year preceding such plan year who are active participants, the number of participants and beneficiaries in pay status, and the number of terminated vested participants and beneficiaries;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H32435288A83343E293794556713077F1"><enum>(XVI)</enum><text>the information contained on the most recent annual funding notice submitted by the plan under section 101(f) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H76BFBE37CBC74AF5A1A9A6F42C59C6D8"><enum>(XVII)</enum><text>the information contained on the most recent Department of Labor Form 5500 of the plan; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H0BF710F5E23C4A42852630962ABC7FD2"><enum>(XVIII)</enum><text>copies of the plan document and amendments, other retirement benefit or ancillary benefit plans relating to the plan and contribution obligations under such plans, a breakdown of administrative expenses of the plan, participant census data and distribution of benefits, the most recent actuarial valuation report as of the plan year, copies of collective bargaining agreements, and financial reports, and such other information as the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary's delegate, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor and the Director of the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation, may require.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H9866EB02968F47AA948DF0474020D040"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Electronic submission</header><text>The report required under clause (i) shall be submitted electronically.</text> </clause><clause id="HC1D2CED108E7497C8759D728DCD76527"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Information sharing</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary's delegate shall share the information in the report under clause (i) with the Secretary of Labor.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9EA8A88DAC384271B707858FC3E2ACA4"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Any failure to file the report required under clause (i) on or before the date described in such clause shall be treated as a failure to file a report required to be filed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6058">section 6058(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, except that section 6652(e) of such Code shall be applied with respect to any such failure by substituting <quote>$100</quote> for <quote>$25</quote>. The preceding sentence shall not apply if the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary's delegate determines that reasonable diligence has been exercised by the trustees of such plan in attempting to timely file such report.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A764CDEF5964DBD8F6CFCBB2ABF7F3E"><enum>(G)</enum><header>1974 UMWA Pension Plan defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>1974 UMWA Pension Plan</term> has the meaning given the term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9701">section 9701(a)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, but without regard to the limitation on participation to individuals who retired in 1976 and thereafter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H133CF7EFC724478A96BAE3302428641F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective dates</header>
 <paragraph id="H608089126FF14AB396FEC163F39BA0A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to fiscal years beginning after September 30, 2016.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C6021CAB70B4A5BB8CD5743CB8C57E0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text>Section 402(i)(4)(F) of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1232">30 U.S.C. 1232(i)(4)(F)</external-xref>), as added by this section, shall apply to plan years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAEB8531FE0D34BAFBC7EA3DAFD123FE9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Clarification of financing obligations</header>
 <subsection id="H035654BE0DE744D19B8C7E6570D06DE1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9704">section 9704</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H787F5D4543514AA1B36E50CE16DD0C82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3),</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H646014EBE1D0488C9526D7F60D2A3A9E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>three premiums</quote> and inserting <quote>two premiums</quote>, and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H165E5E944DF34C178121B1E54B8D02A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (2) and inserting a period.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8F328152FABF46DAB12AE35F4D5CDFA6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <paragraph id="HB1E54067730C4F7CA082EE7A8B9ECC2B"><enum>(1)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9704">Section 9704</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H40FA37158CE641B8AEA64260F5A0A86C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d), and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H227E79958B114F2DAB2A130CBAE7CCC2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (e) through (j) as subsections (d) through (i), respectively.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB0F915EA3CE46DCA19E8BB06C805D97"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Subsection (d) of section 9704 of such Code, as so redesignated, is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3A08BB9FB9624B4DB0BB3802069AD140"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>3 separate accounts for each of the premiums described in subsections (b), (c), and (d)</quote> in paragraph (1) and inserting <quote>2 separate accounts for each of the premiums described in subsections (b) and (c)</quote>, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68526FB5426A466BA30D209EEECF13D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or the unassigned beneficiaries premium account</quote> in paragraph (3)(B).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD92BB4085AF74043937889B2079DBD3C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Subclause (I) of section 9703(b)(2)(C)(ii) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>9704(e)(3)(B)(i)</quote> and inserting <quote>9704(d)(3)(B)(i)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D3DAA27E3EA46C58993540FE1FC7363"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Paragraph (3) of section 9705(a) of such Code is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H71DE48C8F2AE4277B9CA8DE6EDF25FA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the unassigned beneficiary premium under section 9704(a)(3) and</quote> in subparagraph (B), and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF114BEC76D54EC1BE9A1D4A8EEE687E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>9704(i)(1)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>9704(h)(1)(B)</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD0B3470CCE24269A6CA64DBB836D6BE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Paragraph (2) of section 9711(c) of such Code is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H92C79D79C8324085B773FC1D6901B504"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>9704(j)(2)</quote> in subparagraph (A)(i) and inserting <quote>9704(i)(2)</quote>,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AC15CC272EB414B990A42B901E0585B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>9704(j)(2)(B)</quote> in subparagraph (B) and inserting <quote>9704(i)(2)(B)</quote>, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17A27A0AA40F44768A6B1B7FD6C5075E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>9704(j)</quote> and inserting <quote>9704(i)</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H684E0087FB894ECCBD86CEE35A2FE813"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Paragraph (4) of section 9712(d) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>9704(j)</quote> and inserting <quote>9704(i)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H358AB2DA727841F6A73786327D810867"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elimination of additional backstop premium</header> <paragraph id="HCD421502E9544203BBA3A0FE08DAFAD2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9712">section 9712(d)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking subparagraph (C).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H627D3DD97E9345058B2245B043D895C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Paragraph (2) of section 9712(d) of such Code is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H6CBC2DFF8554468CA89378FCFEDEC2EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE367BB1AB0B5411C9DC3D754F4F141D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (A) and inserting a period, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04C54969A7884F1B965EC8C27E5E12B1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>shall provide for—</quote> and all that follows through <quote>annual adjustments</quote> and inserting <quote>shall provide for annual adjustments</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8A11DFBFBDDA4B76AFABFD1FF534F138"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to plan years beginning after September 30, 2016.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HDB87E9BFEE7A4C47946F8578AD6361CA"><enum>5.</enum><header>Customs user fees</header> <subsection id="H81560CE919DF456AA981CD8A3A004AF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 13031(j)(3)(A) of the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/58c">19 U.S.C. 58c(j)(3)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2025</quote> and inserting <quote>May 6, 2026</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7A387CBF0A7146F0A528C0ABB22757C9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rate for merchandise processing fees</header><text>Section 503 of the United States–Korea Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/41">Public Law 112–41</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3805">19 U.S.C. 3805</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>September 30, 2025</quote> and inserting <quote>May 6, 2026</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


