<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H248BB0991BE14B2ABFFFE70DB89108BA" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3712 IH: Major General Tim Lowenberg National Guard Cyber Defenders Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3712</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170908">September 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001064">Mr. Heck</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for the establishment and operation of reserve
			 component cyber civil support teams, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8E83D6A2C2BA40D3A8FBCADFEAE8E859" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB747CE78A39B497281867B292EECB068" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Major General Tim Lowenberg National Guard Cyber Defenders Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HFE6F40854A654BD3963A442E68AA47F0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment and operation of reserve component cyber civil support teams</header> <subsection id="HED8BC6D8F30E40F19EFA0649BAF23C10"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment and purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 12310(c) of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H13BD4E37E42840728F5F618222A6E707"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35E48DEB2F2647FCBE036F99D6D49279" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HE4FEDB9238634FCE8D1BCD2109166D3C" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An attack or natural disaster impacting a computer, electronic, or cyber network.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4AEEF02832EE4D4E91E67F2D17FDA3A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <subparagraph id="H6B8C992E25FE4DB785ACC8F5BA0C3487"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A Reserve may perform duty described in paragraph (1)</quote> and inserting <quote>(A) A Reserve may perform duty described in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of paragraph (1)</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6607E8C02898442584A8BBCF81AE2AFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H786D9BE807F246D48E8F27A226B374E4" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H1D24F143798744CEB6D7B9E120C4530D" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Reserve, including a Reserve assigned or attached to a reserve component cyber civil support team, may perform duty described in subparagraph (E) of paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E12AD95A8874F4E843687C567D878C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 12310(c) of title 10, United States Code, is further amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3A33FB3DE64D4CBEBD969750C62D4117"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">and Terrorist Attacks</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">, Terrorist Attacks, and Cyber Attacks</header-in-text></quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4C1ED7FC47643E787E09FBE21126875"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>weapons of mass destruction civil support team</quote> and inserting <quote>civil support team described in paragraph (3)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H160AF71B1F2643F48C54DB5BCC1DF9C4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prompt implementation of reserve component cyber civil support teams</header> <subsection id="H5E59563EF6CB416990AC0F1C9AA3C31F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Five-Year deadline for teams</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30, 2022, each State, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Virgin Islands shall have an operational reserve component cyber civil support team composed of reserve component members of the Armed Forces assigned under section 12310 of title 10, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE9B8EEB9C7A54FAA848113BB9F5A3320"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Progress report requirement</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2018, the Chief of the National Guard Bureau shall submit to Congress a report—</text>
 <paragraph id="H90B5C28DB8C74AA1B4AB77D9A2E781AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying which States, and whether the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, and the Virgin Islands, have satisfied the requirement imposed by subsection (a);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB94C156C5574FD19565BC779F753C41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishing a plan for meeting the deadline imposed by subsection (a);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H81543ABFE4694441B5D49D284488EAB6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assessing the level of involvement and assistance of the National Guard Bureau in the establishment and support of reserve component cyber civil support teams; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE12852C2EDC4144B2317A9C2B727D18"><enum>(4)</enum><text>evaluating the need for increased levels of such involvement and assistance.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B1E284A399E43D0B6CA671C90C7A1D0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Operational elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be considered operational, a reserve component cyber civil support team must be ready—</text>
 <paragraph id="H12D201BC50384F12B7452ADD52629752"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to perform duties relating to analysis and protection in support of responding to emergencies involving an attack or natural disaster impacting a computer, electronic, or cyber network;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4CA1167A162349DF9F2453AB18716209"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to advise and coordinate on any incident deemed critical for the protection of life, property, and maintenance of good order for the Governor;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5AE664679E624CC783FA819A3FE41F01"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to cooperate with and assist private sector owners and operators of critical infrastructure and key resources;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A29E81E86504184911A0C56588E3619"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to collaborate and participate in information sharing with Federal, State, and local Fusion Centers, emergency management authorities, and emergency management divisions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2A0C8EB9F0B6499780E67EAF37DC6614"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to maintain relationships and close coordination with—</text> <subparagraph id="HAEDDD8F13E19446B84E94B997B00F0CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State-based employees of the Protective Security Advisor Program Office of the Department of Homeland Security;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FACE82009B74DB09A681726AF6B581C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>cybersecurity advisors of the Department of Homeland Security (where assigned); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B7F1DB8DCE94A20818CC7F26BA5A845"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employees of the Office of Infrastructure Protection of the Department of Homeland Security.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H12580302206E4E4E953917B180D4DDCE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Oversight by National Guard Bureau</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To ensure standardization among reserve component cyber civil support teams, the National Guard Bureau Joint Staff shall provide program management and oversight as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7385C0DAFC34492F8D5DBF3C601716E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of a reserve component cyber civil support team shall undergo initial training comprising a military occupational specialty or Air Force Specialty Code initial skills course approved by a branch of the Armed Forces.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD9F000C6E1A946B18C51B264B689555D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Guard Bureau Joint Staff shall establish specific curricula for teams, which shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H991158B483B542F089656B0B8A8B2624"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include best-of-breed commercially available training and a National Guard-developed course focused on domestic coordination, communication, and cyber incident response skills; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C57214A32624127918AFB57681EA469"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be updated on a periodic basis based on the evolving circumstances of cyber threats, the needs of the public and private entities such teams support, and the relationships between such teams and such entities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H83C6FBA133B44D02BE8A68733EDA18C2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Guidance to States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Guard Bureau Joint Staff shall consult with the Council of Governors and other appropriate civilian authorities to establish guidance to States concerning situations that are appropriate for the involvement of a reserve component cyber civil support team.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7AD438669D2C4D9F90948E9C15BACD18"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Minimum length of service requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Guard Bureau Joint Staff may establish a minimum length of service for a member of a reserve component cyber civil support team.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H46C8A569D0924CEC91F45C8DD5201BF1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Treatment of records</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The requirements of section 552 of title 5, United States Code, shall apply to any reserve component cyber civil support teams composed of reserve component members of the Armed Forces assigned under section 12310 of title 10, United States Code.</text>
 </section><section id="H65A681EBFA634D6CBD0F1EC351428887"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Defense $50,000,000 to implement this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


