<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H254FB28DE89B4F88BF9C5FECCE76E1C9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4568 IH: Enhancing Geothermal Production on Federal Lands Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4568</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171206">December 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000573">Mr. Labrador</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 to promote timely exploration for geothermal resources under geothermal leases, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE379E292AB97414E90CD620F179DE19E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB502D7AC9D2C41C789FB31D02F2C9323" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhancing Geothermal Production on Federal Lands Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5232A53AEAC74B74BB26483AC9A240A4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Geothermal production on Federal lands</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1001">30 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H65A4E10DC1C745F6AC24D4820E92D9CD" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H2645E985352049EBBDCA98BFBFF71DA1"><enum>30.</enum><header>Geothermal exploration test projects</header> 
<subsection id="HDAF3CE047E8A4EC8A6C7F22B6B2EC2E2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of geothermal exploration test project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>geothermal exploration test project</term> means the drilling of a well to test or explore for geothermal resources on lands for which the Secretary has issued a lease under this Act, that—</text> <paragraph id="H616651EC284547E1B51319EEA157EB0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is carried out by the holder of the lease;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H382E2E21F2734DEB80E62816E596AA85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>causes—</text> <subparagraph id="H2D0EC34841C94ED0A28C79AF377DCBBB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>less than 5 acres of soil or vegetation disruption at the location of each geothermal exploration well; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5F36D7A486F8433082B548B6D5C3E5D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not more than an additional 5 acres of soil or vegetation disruption during access or egress to the test site;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E1FBAE512544F46A18E9A9B6DDC6E7D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is developed—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H18A5B33F3D414A6CAA002D35F55742CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>8 inches or less in diameter;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B8DEDC8C8A34FDFB7C15663BBC99CE0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a manner that does not require off-road motorized access other than to and from the well site along an identified off-road route;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H32306E3F033F40D9A937ECC401609F7E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>without construction of new roads other than upgrading of existing drainage crossings for safety purposes; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H10B08B50190548A7B0C17C7B42A61079"><enum>(D)</enum><text>with the use of rubber-tired digging or drilling equipment vehicles;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF1898CBB98845759BCAABE022A23773" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is completed in less than 90 days, including the removal of any surface infrastructure from the site; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D0BD8244417445EA6D688D12121E870"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requires the restoration of the project site within 3 years of the date of first exploration drilling to approximately the condition that existed at the time the project began, unless the site is subsequently used as part of energy development under the lease.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2BB866803F9244DE99223E15AD2ED457" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Categorical exclusion</header> 
<paragraph id="HF27704C0152C4278805873524F4B0039"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless extraordinary circumstances exist, a project that the Secretary determines under subsection (c) is a geothermal exploration test project shall be categorically excluded from the requirements for an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.) or section 1508.4 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H68CF05B176C1476881A5229C6E029421"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extraordinary circumstances definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>extraordinary circumstances</quote> has the same meaning given such term in the Department of the Interior Departmental Manual, 516 DM 2.3A(3) and 516 DM 2, Appendix 2 (or successor provisions).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE15CD8A063E440CE8924730F85DEC411"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Process</header> 
<paragraph id="H61A6D346975B473AA5F66ABA7457B396"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement to provide notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A leaseholder shall provide notice to the Secretary of the leaseholder’s intent to carry out a geothermal exploration test project at least 30 days before the start of drilling under the project.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB971E19FF0BC4528998FD502C2EA47BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review and determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 10 days after receipt of a notice of intent under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall, with respect to the project described in the notice of intent—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7204B9DA011243C2B84309E8B0EFEB9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine if the project qualifies for a categorical exclusion under subsection (b); and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC09A269FF3744485BA8F0A75FBEB9B77"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify the leaseholder of such determination.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H471334595C444E8BA03AFCA029C12407" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Opportunity to remedy</header> 
<subparagraph id="H55DF5149C4CA44A397C28C3B30B22F8F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines under paragraph (2)(A) that the project does not qualify for a categorical exclusion under subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="HAB9427526BDF43F381213EC036923659"><enum>(i)</enum><text> include in such notice clear and detailed findings on any deficiencies in the project that resulted in such determination; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H474011EC934F4F2EB14DB7AAC24DB347"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allow the leaseholder to remedy any such deficiencies and resubmit the notice of intent under paragraph (1).</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HF75DD89A8A43488886BB91B017E3DFCE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Geothermal leasing priority areas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1001">30 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref> et seq.) is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H03A1E25691674DA68EB0217440FE7C24" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H6D8A8EB14C6E4167A8E4AA1666BB7909" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>31.</enum><header>Geothermal leasing priority areas</header> 
<subsection id="H52C466EEB1C84E8BA395D008929B1F67"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of covered land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>covered land</quote> means land that is—</text> <paragraph id="H6811A93E33CA4D36BF6043CE40C94B97"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Federal land; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83C29A266EA84457BF0EAE60A884B8F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not excluded from the development of geothermal energy under—</text> <subparagraph id="HBCC276275DF74B66A5384A07C42F4EE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a land use plan established under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD1F04FB2845C4D0AB3094A290922770A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other Federal law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF99721DAD6CD48499139DCD13A163A85"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation of geothermal leasing priority areas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall designate portions of covered land as geothermal leasing priority areas as soon as practicable, but not later than 5 years, after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB2FE61005CE949E7B6413538029CB199"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Criteria for selection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining which covered lands to designate as geothermal leasing priority areas under subsection (b), the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall consider if—</text> <paragraph id="HDD63423D0A1F436488B78E37D3CEC385"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the covered land is preferable for geothermal leasing;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5EAE06D5A5AE40BE8696B9ECCBA0F57C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">production of geothermal energy on such land is economically viable, including if such land has access to methods of energy transmission; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H392A8CAF776549A789788AC947123B3E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the designation would be in compliance with section 202 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1712">43 U.S.C. 1712</external-xref>), including subsection (c)(9) of that section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEC90ACAD163D47FDAB1BF807B776FE35"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Review and modification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than once every 10 years, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HA87C42BD91174530BDFB633C0E3B6FAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review covered land and, if appropriate, make additional designations of geothermal leasing priority areas; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E2CE4B8706B47C2A921F7D7CFAE6727"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review each area designated as a geothermal leasing priority area under this section, and, if appropriate, remove such designation.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4C5EBF08D79D479A9E02ADBFC723AEAD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Programmatic environmental impact statement</header> <paragraph id="H63DE83AFFF604B22B37859B25DFF0B4D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial designations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall prepare a supplement to any final programmatic environmental impact statement for geothermal leasing that is the most recently finalized such statement with respect to covered land designated as a geothermal leasing priority area under subsection (b).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H979ECA3EA382461C8827554B3C9833E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent designations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each designation of a geothermal leasing priority area under subsection (d) shall be included in a programmatic environmental impact statement for geothermal leasing or in a supplement to such a statement.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H2DF8F178B8C2493BAC291525E60967C4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing any programmatic environmental impact statement for geothermal leasing or supplement to such a statement under this section, the Secretary shall consult, on an ongoing basis, with appropriate State, Tribal, and local governments, transmission infrastructure owners and operators, developers, and other appropriate entities.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7FE22C6CDD424CE483E6EEE579CEAC33"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Procedure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not delay issuing a permit or holding a lease sale under this Act because the supplement required under paragraph (1) has not been finalized by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H986D246573C34D09B5BCB2350A6EC1D6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Compliance with NEPA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines that the designation of a geothermal leasing priority area has been sufficiently analyzed by a programmatic environmental impact statement, the Secretary shall not prepare any additional analysis under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.) with respect to geothermal lease sales for such geothermal leasing priority area.</text></subsection> </section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H7B54147F8BAA42EA994869854D1BE634" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>4.</enum><header>Facilitation of coproduction of geothermal energy on oil and gas leases</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4(b) of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1003">30 U.S.C. 1003(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H494F0F93375D416BA70CABAB81D83FAA" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H4A7C30FAEF3B4D79B742686FA3AE2401"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Land subject to oil and gas lease</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Land under an oil and gas lease issued pursuant to the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/181">30 U.S.C. 181</external-xref> et seq.) or the Mineral Leasing Act for Acquired Lands (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/351">30 U.S.C. 351</external-xref> et seq.) that is subject to an approved application for permit to drill and from which oil and gas production is occurring may be available for noncompetitive leasing under subsection (c) by the holder of the oil and gas lease—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H89122729A2F14C25AAFA3D6AA670DCDD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on a determination that geothermal energy will be produced from a well producing or capable of producing oil and gas; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H70CDCB85828446B0BF7A7642D35AFBEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in order to provide for the coproduction of geothermal energy with oil and gas.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HD25CFC3674B54174BCE05C5A51826860" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Noncompetitive leasing of adjoining areas for development of geothermal resources</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4(b) of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1003">30 U.S.C. 1003(b)</external-xref>) is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE7D385597E047A2B5216F31E90B65A8" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HB1C87983CF104176BD705F5324EB0E69"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Adjoining land</header> <subparagraph id="H90112F1C109D483FA832366002F0FFD1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph:</text> 
<clause id="HB7F8FB958EC4457ABF16E30E489E4809"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Fair market value per acre</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fair market value per acre</term> means a dollar amount per acre that—</text> <subclause id="H690CE55AE84F46BEA9B8CC80A6837A49"><enum>(I)</enum><text>except as provided in this clause, shall be equal to the market value per acre (taking into account the determination under subparagraph (B)(iii) regarding a valid discovery on the adjoining land) as determined by the Secretary under regulations issued under this paragraph;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2C59F40425D940E49C5FBC30EC61221E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall be determined by the Secretary with respect to a lease under this paragraph, by not later than the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date the Secretary receives an application for the lease; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H862ECAEB30F54DBA9BF8A8908D60B3AA"><enum>(III)</enum><text>shall be not less than the greater of—</text> 
<item id="H51E877305F564929B721D8B15AA170D1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>4 times the median amount paid per acre for all land leased under this Act during the preceding year; or</text></item> <item id="H184542B7E7EE45AE9EBFDAA935E07762"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>$50.</text></item></subclause></clause> 
<clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73D31750F4FF457BBDB226F87F446CC1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Industry standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>industry standards</term> means the standards by which a qualified geothermal professional assesses whether downhole or flowing temperature measurements with indications of permeability are sufficient to produce energy from geothermal resources, as determined through flow or injection testing or measurement of lost circulation while drilling.</text></clause> <clause id="HCC194A76F7FA491393A21E640E044487"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Qualified Federal land</header><text>The term <term>qualified Federal land</term> means land that is otherwise available for leasing under this Act.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9E2792799BC94AE2AEE3588EB2BAD1AC"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Qualified geothermal professional</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified geothermal professional</term> means an individual who is an engineer or geoscientist in good professional standing with at least 5 years of experience in geothermal exploration, development, or project assessment.</text></clause> <clause id="H6E7E30338C184B7C8A9FB7D34ABADE7B"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Qualified lessee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified lessee</term> means a person who may hold a geothermal lease under this Act (including applicable regulations).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9DCF7CA873EC431D8371D25DDC87D897"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Valid discovery</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>valid discovery</term> means a discovery of a geothermal resource by a new or existing slim hole or production well, that exhibits downhole or flowing temperature measurements with indications of permeability that are sufficient to meet industry standards.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H41433FCDDBD04A2C8282DE56FB055541"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>An area of qualified Federal land that adjoins other land for which a qualified lessee holds a legal right to develop geothermal resources may be available for a noncompetitive lease under this section to the qualified lessee at the fair market value per acre, if—</text> 
<clause id="H53152902F8F440019FBCB26B58B46585"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the area of qualified Federal land—</text> <subclause id="H853C2E9E7BA04308A370CC96094CD60B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>consists of not less than 1 acre and not more than 640 acres; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2EC75CBFEAFB4DA7ABB4401DDFB44114"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is not already leased under this Act or nominated to be leased under subsection (a);</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H1B5F95F67E174303AEA7F54EDABCB88A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the qualified lessee has not previously received a noncompetitive lease under this paragraph in connection with the valid discovery for which data has been submitted under clause (iii)(I); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H98B69E9EBA5D4DC2B1EA568716E8A164"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>sufficient geological and other technical data prepared by a qualified geothermal professional has been submitted by the qualified lessee to the applicable Federal land management agency that would lead individuals who are experienced in the subject matter to believe that—</text> <subclause id="H1C326088E7E449019D56553854A0BDD3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>there is a valid discovery of geothermal resources on the land for which the qualified lessee holds the legal right to develop geothermal resources; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3C8E076BBE98498F85C837EE224F329B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that geothermal feature extends into the adjoining areas.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6F0FEED87E9F4ECF8432AC15DDD6F26D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Determination of fair market value</header> <clause id="HB1DEBEB1CADC44D193B9F1498FCDBEAF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> 
<subclause id="HDE329D5D00B744C7BEC20ADC18C0BAB6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>publish a notice of any request to lease land under this paragraph;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H309B429E43484028907BA43E3F4714FF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>determine fair market value for purposes of this paragraph in accordance with procedures for making those determinations that are established by regulations issued by the Secretary;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H12333CF600F849B9A2BB3AF04F05BD6D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>provide to a qualified lessee and publish, with an opportunity for public comment for a period of 30 days, any proposed determination under this subparagraph of the fair market value of an area that the qualified lessee seeks to lease under this paragraph; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB111FA53F19B4C36B2C329BC1695433A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>provide to the qualified lessee and any adversely affected party the opportunity to appeal the final determination of fair market value in an administrative proceeding before the applicable Federal land management agency, in accordance with applicable law (including regulations).</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HD20973F59ADC4DA093F130A28C30019E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation on nomination</header><text>After publication of a notice of request to lease land under this paragraph, the Secretary may not accept under subsection (a) any nomination of the land for leasing unless the request has been denied or withdrawn.</text></clause> <clause id="H7F4A81F8B2BC4E20B3BE1967E312D68C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Annual rental</header><text>For purposes of section 5(a)(3), a lease awarded under this paragraph shall be considered a lease awarded in a competitive lease sale.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2A10AD08702D48FA944AC82D6C5A8260"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary shall issue regulations to carry out this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

