<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H86C9A25C113C4B8887489FBCF0C157FF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3076 IH: Creating Advanced Streamlined Electronic Services (CASES) for Constituents Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3076</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170627">June 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000577">Mr. Graves of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000379">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend section 552a of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the Privacy Act) to require agencies to accept electronic release forms, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1B5A4DFD57CE4791883A232D307DA4CD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAC942448F4CD4366AE6D853CD6146582" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Creating Advanced Streamlined Electronic Services (CASES) for Constituents Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7D19708B79C74A9B9588CF885B9188B6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirement to accept electronic release forms under the Privacy Act</header> <subsection id="H0CD828DA0B2149448BD84CFF3A2494CE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 552a of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the Privacy Act) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H1340FBE6C91E493B929B32002D1F3E60" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HB9A1106A143D466E8C9DE0121573981B"><enum>(x)</enum><header>Requirement to accept electronic release forms</header> 
<paragraph id="HFC0D519492BE4D67B779224B1F2AE208"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agency shall establish a system that allows an individual, or another entity acting on behalf of that individual who has been authorized to act on behalf of the individual, to electronically submit a release form, signed by the individual, that grants another entity access to the record of the individual or any other information pertaining to the individual that is contained in the system.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H173029FBAB02411C81B8DDF32C72C031"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form of submission</header><text>The release form described in paragraph (1) may be submitted directly to the agency through an electronic form (without requiring the upload of any document), including any necessary authentication process, if the release form—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H87F14D47C3894C1CB58690975667F18F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is submitted by an individual; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H09987C56BAD041DBA9FA1BEC0D9AC6DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if submitted by another entity acting on behalf of an individual, includes a certification that the other entity has been authorized to act on behalf of the individual in the manner described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H41BB195E524C463AA2E9798B77677B14" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>OMB guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall establish a uniform release form to be used across agencies for the electronic submission described under subsection (x) of section 552a of title 5, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFF178CB943E24B3BA305F2FE4075589C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

