<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H36425E69578247B3A9E37448CAC30508" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3019 IH: Promoting Value Based Procurement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3019</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170622">June 22, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require executive agencies to avoid using lowest price technically acceptable source selection
			 criteria in certain circumstances, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HCEC9F27BAC384AD4873071D10FD6BAD3" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8625173F60C94C0DBDFE714521ADE168" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Value Based Procurement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6D20718F87A8494196C89D925363065D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Use of lowest price technically acceptable source selection process</header> <subsection id="H155FBA5DFCE14293BF6B82CE8F34B396"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It shall be the policy of the United States Government to avoid using lowest price technically acceptable source selection criteria in circumstances that would deny the Government the benefits of cost and technical tradeoffs in the source selection process.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEB6084BA3C7F405A9CD9EB732A8C920F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Revision of Federal Acquisition Regulation</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Acquisition Regulation shall be revised to require that, for solicitations issued on or after the date that is 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, lowest price technically acceptable source selection criteria are used only in situations in which—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA6574E567BD54F0BAFB0DBF73D6528E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an executive agency is able to comprehensively and clearly describe the minimum requirements expressed in terms of performance objectives, measures, and standards that will be used to determine acceptability of offers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H994A3CB23E6E4C119E0D4E44C69333DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the executive agency would realize no, or minimal, value from a contract proposal exceeding the minimum technical or performance requirements set forth in the request for proposal;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H42EA29A8C17B4E74B0C4357E0FFB4117"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the proposed technical approaches will require no, or minimal, subjective judgment by the source selection authority as to the desirability of one offeror’s proposal versus a competing proposal;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5EF5180AC6F349C3B51D2A373ECD7C8F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the source selection authority has a high degree of confidence that a review of technical proposals of offerors other than the lowest bidder would not result in the identification of factors that could provide value or benefit to the executive agency;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D1F340F856D4A5D93AB20ACB4362BDE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the contracting officer has included a justification for the use of a lowest price technically acceptable evaluation methodology in the contract file; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF83E156BC0DE42978DE7D0CE7F019996"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the executive agency has determined that the lowest price reflects full life-cycle costs, including for operations and support.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE0A6F9A1785E40A3845AA0195C7CEE84"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Avoidance of use of lowest price technically acceptable source selection criteria in certain
 procurements</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the use of lowest price technically acceptable source selection criteria shall be avoided in the case of a procurement that is predominately for the acquisition of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8B2D58CB98EB4E7EB63C053771B3F4AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information technology services, cybersecurity services, systems engineering and technical assistance services, advanced electronic testing, audit or audit readiness services, or other knowledge-based professional services;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD83344CE18EF4419A4438C3F7D2B31DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>personal protective equipment; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2AF8B94C2E034D44A2231310E450ABE6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>knowledge-based training or logistics services in contingency operations or other operations outside the United States, including in Afghanistan or Iraq.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8FBD7590623E4FFBA2233B9C470E312D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for three years, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the number of instances in which lowest price technically acceptable source selection criteria is used for a contract exceeding $2,000,000, including an explanation of how the situations listed in subsection (b) were considered in making a determination to use lowest price technically acceptable source selection criteria.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0A88A5F3A4C34A69B8CE36907FDD588C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H0057A5805FEB40F08CC217B3E9D700A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Executive agency</header><text>The term <quote>executive agency</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 102 of title 40, United States Code, except that the term does not include the Department of Defense.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H75B36C793F1E47F8BEFD00EA25A3921C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contingency operation</header><text>The term <quote>contingency operation</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 10, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9CD509BFC1F24DCFAF669D839FAE284C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


