<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H60C1B67FB1F74C24A752F0D85469CC50" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1969 IH: Safe Hydration is an American Right in Energy Development Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1969</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000465">Ms. Tsongas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to require testing of underground sources of drinking water in connection with hydraulic fracturing operations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4E1BED5B2F744C69BB731ACA3F3D774C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H20E30F448F86489EB30261AE3BA6E3DB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Hydration is an American Right in Energy Development Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAAB4598C42DD4C3990BF25701E6219CC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Testing of underground drinking water sources in connection with hydraulic fracturing operations</header> <subsection id="H3D0FCEF605344A7ABCB54F7D858427B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1421(b)(1) of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300h">42 U.S.C. 300h(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H548A99DC8FC8420C9D0C1FDA9AA7975D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF00365B238A3458EBD0BAF9CC18D3D41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC4A6910FE59440F7BAAD40EC6CDB2AB3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9EC0176BF814E01B7B100DC6B08856C" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HD6D4D97AF42C41BAA339C9D16609E0AF" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall prohibit the underground injection of fluids or propping agents pursuant to hydraulic fracturing operations related to oil, gas, or geothermal production activities unless the person proposing to conduct the hydraulic fracturing operations agrees to conduct testing and report data in accordance with section 1421A.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD7477EA5310048D590A0D56A3420FEAB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Testing and reporting requirements</header><text>Part C of the Safe Drinking Water Act is amended by inserting after section 1421 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300h">42 U.S.C. 300h</external-xref>) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F196FDB6D1D4207B58829006551B9ED" style="OLC"> <section id="H797790BA05264F4BA8DFC1E7267494BF"><enum>1421A.</enum><header>Testing of underground drinking water sources in connection with hydraulic fracturing operations</header> <subsection id="H943362D48D574F5DADC19A5D43DF4CD6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Regulations under section 1421(a) for State underground injection control programs shall, in connection with the underground injection of fluids or propping agents pursuant to hydraulic fracturing operations related to oil, gas, or geothermal production activities, require any person conducting such operations—</text>
<paragraph id="H59630DC7BDB2455EB3B26C8B8A050D0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to conduct testing of underground sources of drinking water in accordance with subsections (c) and (d)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H7D52C1EBAD684DC4B4E71077F7C425DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a site where, as of the date of enactment of this section, underground injection has not commenced for the first time—</text>
<clause id="H66CD05CC6A724876BFE450885D83CF91"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prior to commencement of underground injection at the site for the first time;</text></clause> <clause id="HF6F733D8AA67444DA064117906C30EDC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least once every 6 months during the period beginning at the commencement of underground injection described in clause (i) and ending at the cessation of such hydraulic fracturing operations; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HF582C6474A9E4A25A6C28D7C93AA2544"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>at least once every 12 months during the 5-year period following the end of the period described in clause (ii);</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3FF5F8D4E863452797A0BE6E15CCAC2B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a site where, as of the date of enactment of this section, there is no active underground injection, but underground injection has previously occurred at the site—</text>
<clause id="H17A5E2F2CE6E494383066640E34C6339"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prior to renewing underground injection at the site;</text></clause> <clause id="H0F0EB1E1F7684467AA5013FEBA565E11"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at least once every 6 months during the period beginning at such renewal of underground injection and ending at the cessation of such hydraulic fracturing operations; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H586DB563586A45229FB24F8D77B3FAE9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>at least once every 12 months during the 5-year period following the end of the period described in clause (ii); and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90E680802DE64F418DAEA4B5A8580B41"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a site where, as of the date of enactment of this section, such hydraulic fracturing operations are occurring—</text>
<clause commented="no" id="H44BFA21064F249E9BF08FAD01F47A7C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at least once every 6 months during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this section ending at the cessation of such hydraulic fracturing operations; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H3076DAC2AA444F9C999CFA1E263BBBD2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at least once every 12 months during the 5-year period following the end of the period described in clause (i); and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H60106A0ECDDD47B6803AB1894CB53AE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to submit reports to the Administrator on the results of testing under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (1) within 2 weeks of such testing.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA2CD1B2059B44E32957CA5B92230B7F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The testing and reporting requirements of subsection (a) do not apply with respect to hydraulic fracturing operations if there is no accessible underground source of drinking water within a radius of one mile of the site where the operations occur.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H68D55C2EBEE94307848BD9C3B7CF8200"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sampling locations</header><text>Testing required pursuant to subsection (a) shall occur—</text> <paragraph id="H5AE030D9A68B40AEA3F5D1E448A817B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at all accessible underground sources of drinking water within a radius of one-half mile of the site where the hydraulic fracturing operations occur; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HADC4B2555F2643B09F48889A602136DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if there is no accessible underground source of drinking water within such radius, at the nearest accessible underground source of drinking water within a radius of one mile of such site.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H62D83E308A18484B8118327011EF4425"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Testing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Testing required pursuant to subsection (a) shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HF3F90F2B124A4DFC86C0F364D8C2823F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be conducted by one or more laboratories certified pursuant to the Environmental Protection Agency’s program for certifying laboratories for analysis of drinking water contaminants; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF63B51AD0B7401CA33BD2E9CF548293"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include testing for any hazardous substance, pollutant, contaminant, or other factor that the Administrator determines would indicate damage associated with hydraulic fracturing operations.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H877F8A75A6F742538BC9FB3E0B771345"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Database; public accessibility</header>
<paragraph id="HF7DE2535802941C584EBD42143CA0393"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Database</header><text>The Administrator shall establish and maintain a database of the results reported pursuant to subsection (a)(2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D6837CBB8BB4391A5769F13EFDEE833"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public accessibility</header><text>The Administrator shall make such database publicly accessible on the Website of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9080EFD24CF14BA0B66B468D1FA0C451"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public searchability</header><text>The Administrator shall make such database searchable by zip code, allowing members of the public to easily identify all sites for which reports are submitted pursuant to subsection (a)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEF271CD7F5944C8087E9323940B403CF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>accessible underground source of drinking water</term> means an underground source of drinking water to which the person conducting the hydraulic fracturing operations can reasonably gain access.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H153F03DDE73042319CBAE2EFA0C9887D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 1421(d)(1)(B)(ii) of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300h">42 U.S.C. 300h(d)(1)(B)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>except as provided in subsection (b)(1)(E) of this section and section 1421A,</quote> before <quote>the underground injection of fluids or propping agents (other than diesel fuels) pursuant to hydraulic fracturing operations related to oil, gas, or geothermal production activities</quote>.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

