<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H18FBDE9536F3462EA7C5D49592E4F5A3" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4106 IH: Surviving Spouses Income Security Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4106</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171024">October 24, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="R000608">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for an increase in the amount of monthly
			 dependents and survivors income security benefit payable to surviving
			 spouses by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H99B76B96494342C2B0FAEBB8E896723B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H672CA3A1DBD34895A824FE71CA2012A2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Surviving Spouses Income Security Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H51A1BB22C8804046AAB6B7C531D2968A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Increase in amount of dependents and survivors income security benefit payable to surviving spouses by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="H330929285716415A991BF66534B748D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Increase</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1311(a) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB2E2B933F4C14AC5B9BA80E55481A4C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>of $1,154</quote> and inserting <quote>equal to 55 percent of the rate of monthly compensation in effect under section 1114(j) of this title</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2C45328B3BC4E79B2F250B7B0E69B74"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF745DC8B62974FC5943CB5B7437AD98D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header> <paragraph id="HC5B566DE09784722A92A38733727620C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided by paragraph (2), the amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to compensation paid under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/13">chapter 13</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, for months beginning after the date that is six months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H2704317BE3674034B8115BF8B896ED8C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for certain individuals</header>
 <subparagraph id="HED243A5D60D4421887DB8B96C5D099CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For months beginning after the date that is six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall pay to an individual described in subparagraph (B) dependents and survivors income security benefit under section 1311 of title 38, United States Code, in the monthly amount that is the greater of the following:</text>
 <clause id="HCDFC43D25D834B109D00511BE433D94D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The amount determined under subsection (a)(3) of such section 1311, as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEB087EE9AE2C401A9C7B2224F3F5E11E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The amount determined under subsection (a)(1) of such section 1311, as amended by subsection (a).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFF85C3998D2464FBEEE4281292333BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual described in this subparagraph is an individual eligible for dependents and survivors income security benefit under section 1311 of title 38, United States Code, that is predicated on the death of a veteran before January 1, 1993.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H673E5492F7FF4ECBB69DCCD20C384C60" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Modification of requirements for dependents and survivors income security benefit payable by
			 Department of Veterans Affairs for survivors of certain veterans rated
 totally disabled at time of death</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1318 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HCCA571AAC61042D8B9BFA22135CDE106"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC788131409F3454395BBFDB016F04ACB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7ABA9635162149C7B942E69F73E79FAD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0EC0D49A04348F491D26C4FC51E0FA6" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H06E62E3361B34502B6DA951FE1384822" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In any case in which the Secretary makes a payment under paragraph (1) of this subsection by reason of subsection (b)(1) and the period of continuous rating immediately preceding death is less than 10 years, the amount payable under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be an amount which bears the same relationship to the amount otherwise payable under such paragraph as the duration of such period bears to 10 years.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D91D4FC92404BFC97A0DF17D5524C0B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)(1), by striking <quote>10 or more years</quote> and inserting <quote>five or more years</quote>.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HC9C459E364A9479DA069435663AB3461" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Eligibility for dependents and survivors income security benefit payable by Department of Veterans Affairs for surviving spouses who remarry after age 55</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 103(d)(2)(B) of title 38, United States Code, is amended in the second sentence by inserting <quote>chapter 13 or</quote> after <quote>benefits under</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H7F5D0E4080534FBB93D40C8850F06A9D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Renaming of dependency and indemnity compensation to dependents and survivors income security
			 benefit</header>
 <subsection id="HB47E76E6C64147CC9C9EF2367815A18F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/13">Chapter 13</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2984ACFC8AF34590A2915400E6DA3F81"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>dependency and indemnity compensation</quote> each place it appears, including the table of sections, and inserting <quote>dependents and survivors income security benefit</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A1E090ACBC04CAFAC3E8CBB2BAE0B30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by conforming the typeface and typestyle, including capitalization, of such inserted matter to the typeface and typestyle as used in such stricken matter.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7FD05C10F72A4C44BCB730F70C75E10E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in law to dependency and indemnity compensation paid by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs pursuant to chapter 13 of such title shall be deemed to be a reference to dependents and survivors income security benefit.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


