<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA57783F1A9C440B282A5135028D895FE" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2981 IH: Open Our Democracy Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2981</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170621">June 21, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require all candidates for election for the office of Senator or Member of the House of
			 Representatives to run in an open primary regardless of political party
			 preference or lack thereof, to limit the ensuing general election for such
			 office to the two candidates receiving the greatest number of votes in
			 such open primary, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3181666B255B44AE8A470833D03E3959" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC17CD899C51A45218785FFAF4E18FE53" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Open Our Democracy Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1D28143E78AA4DA283875E5AB727376A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Election of Members of Congress Through Open Primaries</header> <subsection id="H3DAB2C9620B247008FEE7E45BB5F7EF1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rules for Election of Members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A candidate for election for the office of Senator or Member of the House of Representatives shall be elected to such office pursuant to the following elections held by the State in which the candidate seeks election:</text>
 <paragraph id="HAF2AB45C329A4E6C817B036B4AEB9ABE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An open primary election for such office held in accordance with subsection (b).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H54D54076CF944418ABDE22CA7F97D44C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A general election for such office held in accordance with subsection (c).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H275DA43C5AA14A8DAEBFE49D7D80E6C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Open Primaries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State shall hold an open primary election for each office of Senator or Member of the House of Representatives in the State under which—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7E7DC22BEEDE4A0DB64A6614BCA74145"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each candidate for such office, regardless of the candidate’s political party preference or lack thereof, shall appear on a single ballot; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFA76F1D15B3045EFA0136AE3BD03BA14"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each voter in the State who is eligible to vote in elections for Federal office in the State (in the case of an election for the office of Senator) or in the congressional district involved (in the case of an election for the office of Member of the House of Representatives) may cast a ballot in the election, regardless of the voter’s political party preference or lack thereof.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58F85CA330D14AF387F8E5E32071D412"><enum>(c)</enum><header>General Election</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State shall hold a general election for each office of Senator or Member of the House of Representatives in the State under which the 2 candidates receiving the greatest number of votes in the open primary election for such office (as described in subsection (b)), without regard to the political party preference or lack thereof of such candidates, shall be the only candidates appearing on the ballot.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H8827694841D34BCCB6BF772F900D2C19"><enum>3.</enum><header>Ability of candidates to disclose political party preferences</header>
 <subsection id="H2CA1A4178D5C4C27A8D135E355FC5343"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Option of Candidates To Declare Political Party Preference</header><text>At the time a candidate for the office of Senator or Member of the House of Representatives files to run for such office, the candidate shall have the option of declaring a political party preference, and the preference chosen (if any) shall accompany the candidate’s name on the ballot for the election for such office.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAF44AF96B7F8494B87BDD54B13362120"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation for Candidates Not Declaring Preference</header><text>If a candidate does not declare a political party preference under subsection (a), the designation <quote>No Party Preference</quote> shall accompany the candidate’s name on the ballot for the election for such office.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HAC56DE41D54E470698F04EE850346F65"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No Party Endorsement Implied</header><text>The selection of a party preference by a candidate under subsection (a) shall not constitute or imply endorsement of the candidate by the party designated, and no candidate in a general election shall be deemed the official candidate of any party by virtue of his or her selection in the primary.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H38312E8979FD46BB8D7436B51A9FA88A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Protection of Rights of Political Parties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall restrict the right of individuals to join or organize into political parties or in any way restrict the right of private association of political parties. Nothing in this Act shall restrict a party’s right to contribute to, endorse, or otherwise support a candidate for the office of Senator or Member of the House of Representatives. Nothing in this Act may be construed to prevent a political party from establishing such procedures as it sees fit to endorse or support candidates or otherwise participate in all elections, or from informally designating candidates for election to such an office at a party convention or by whatever lawful mechanism the party may choose, other than pursuant to a primary election held by a State. Nothing in this Act may be construed to prevent a political party from adopting such rules as it sees fit for the selection of party officials (including central committee members, presidential electors, and party officers), including rules restricting participation in elections for party officials to those who disclose a preference for that party at the time of registering to vote.</text>
		</section><section id="H9477F2B7CACA4224B96847A924CBBBB4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Treatment of Election Day in same manner as legal public holiday for purposes of Federal employment</header>
 <subsection id="H3E04382815C54ED8974AD23FAC1D6F0B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of any law relating to Federal employment, the Tuesday next after the first Monday in November in 2018 and each even-numbered year thereafter shall be treated in the same manner as a legal public holiday described in section 6103 of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF0CDCCA627054751B06AD3F5AC24A341"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress regarding treatment of day by private employers</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that private employers in the United States should give their employees a day off on the Tuesday next after the first Monday in November in 2018 and each even-numbered year thereafter to enable the employees to cast votes in the elections held on that day.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H03C635148BBC4C7CB6748EE7D91F8C14"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No Effect on Early or Absentee Voting</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the authority of States to permit individuals to cast ballots in elections for Federal office prior to the date of the election (including the casting of ballots by mail) or to cast absentee ballots in the election.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H57D10D39C50B4540B6F1946AAD0F3166"><enum>6.</enum><header>Requiring congressional redistricting to be conducted through plan of independent State commission</header>
 <subsection id="HEE049C2063144F13B1F0A13E0F15C209"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of Plan Required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any congressional redistricting conducted by a State shall be conducted in accordance with the redistricting plan developed and enacted into law by an independent redistricting commission established in the State in accordance with State law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0996EEC6922D47F6BFCD654E2ADD6FF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements for independent redistricting commission</header><text>The independent redistricting commission established in a State pursuant to subsection (a) shall have such members, who shall be appointed under such requirements, as the State may establish, so long as—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF68B6337A5F24C009AFA2B2964AAFC91"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the commission is prohibited from using partisan or political considerations in developing the State’s redistricting plan; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE04021C05A2C41758ABCC218C39AEFCE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no political party in the State has control over the commission.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB5906811BD146249EC0BE4F2D379472"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 22(c) of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide for the fifteenth and subsequent decennial censuses and to provide for an apportionment of Representatives in Congress</quote>, approved June 18, 1929 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/2a">2 U.S.C. 2a(c)</external-xref>), is amended by striking <quote>in the manner provided by the law thereof</quote> and inserting: <quote>in the manner provided by the Open Our Democracy Act of 2017</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAAB18BA48DE743AFB842D2C8D3B53AED"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section and the amendment made by this section shall apply with respect to congressional redistricting carried out pursuant to the decennial census conducted during 2020 or any succeeding decennial census.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HC1DB1243802B4E2AA2EE332329B33B8B"><enum>7.</enum><header>Member of the House defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>Member of the House of Representatives</term> includes a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress.</text> </section><section id="HDC780C49FACA476FB078276703666BF9"><enum>8.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as provided in sections 5(a) and 6, this Act shall apply with respect to elections occurring during 2018 or any succeeding year.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


