<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H43B725ACC57544CBA64B5C9A10DE31DC" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4485 IH: Savanna’s Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4485</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171129">November 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Attorney General to review, revise, and develop law enforcement and justice protocols
			 appropriate to address missing and murdered Indians, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9D746D24D0C7414DB1D642E09BC594B2" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1F0757A43B0A49E9A31156CF184B6587" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>Savanna’s Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF2B157F4068B4CC093B00AE984BF8182"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purposes</header> <subsection id="H27F1EBE5D8CE4818A01322569665DE4E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H0E5FD9EED78B43D5B1382CAE53C5141B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On some reservations, Indian women are murdered at more than 10 times the national average.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H34D8B500EDCC4DEDB7505B7A375690C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>American Indians and Alaska Natives are 2.5 times as likely to experience violent crimes—and at least 2 times more likely to experience rape or sexual assault crimes—compared to all other races.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC22D0199784346F0978B91D4C7D3620D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>More than 4 in 5 American Indian and Alaska Native women, or 84.3 percent, have experienced violence in their lifetime.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5553C90B469415DBE947697F73F1B87"><enum>(4)</enum><text>According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, homicide is the third leading cause of death among American Indian and Alaska Native women between 10 and 24 years of age and the fifth leading cause of death for American Indian and Alaska Native women between 25 and 34 years of age.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB1836A90F21C4DF89BE4391048789F06"><enum>(5)</enum><text>According to a 2010 Government Accountability Office report, United States Attorneys declined to prosecute nearly 52 percent of violent crimes that occur in Indian country.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB82581BEB6A1423895CD4E152EF8D665"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Investigation into cases of missing and murdered Indian women is made difficult for tribal law enforcement agencies due to a lack of resources, such as—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H87DB861CABF24F8DBD6702AFF5E2947D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>necessary training, equipment, or funding;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA7D15B4BEE54C779F535300B4C80B4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a lack of interagency cooperation; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41114531FE234167B7613F8D680517BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a lack of appropriate laws in place.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8260309BECB5404BAB581A2E00F42CF9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The complicated jurisdictional scheme that exists in Indian country—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H436BB26001F645C3ABF356B39590D01C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has a significant negative impact on the ability to provide public safety to Indian communities;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C596E7C54FE4A4E95D10FD65CF38965"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been increasingly exploited by criminals; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46301818944242C7B1B35C79F4C103D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>requires a high degree of commitment and cooperation among tribal, Federal, and State law enforcement officials.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7134A6505B3D47F8B2F44FC1D9EC3F3D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are—</text> <paragraph id="HED4E440F799045E8911573AB07E5C0A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to clarify the responsibilities of Federal, State, tribal, and local governments with respect to responding to cases of missing and murdered Indians;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H807DB1F0303449B09A1DE0811447A754"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to increase coordination and communication among Federal, State, tribal, and local law enforcement agencies;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86EEEB0E2D68401DAA40DCFD1E4153CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to empower tribal governments with the resources and information necessary to effectively respond to cases of missing and murdered Indians; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0DD4EDB3E22B4B50B6D7758998415967"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to increase the collection of data related to missing and murdered Indian women and the sharing of information among Federal, State, and tribal officials responsible for responding to and investigating cases of missing and murdered Indians.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H105BB2006E2341EC9070FE5F4EE94B2F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H6BA29323B6464EF49459D4BE82DB3E72"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal databases</header><text>The term <term>Federal databases</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H26C58AAAB10C49B49D0D159A2BF731B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the National Crime Information Center database;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE676FE67A13048AAAF6FF91554DD04A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Combined DNA Index System;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9FDA8BEFB344116B4AB7B97C3A4361C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Integrated Automated Fingerprint Identification System;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87D35AB6DF484C1AA9BD2F2505BD8A03"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Violent Criminal Apprehension Program;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7B790CF825C4376829E0F2CD13D8831"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7177B6CFBA8F49CDA00F147F5C3EE76D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other Federal databases relevant to responding to cases of missing and murdered Indians.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H07E54B1B27B04EE89E879581425AB167"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian</header><text>The term <term>Indian</term> means a member of an Indian Tribe.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA29857E3FD214317ABDB16C92715F220"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Indian country</header><text>The term <term>Indian country</term> has the meaning given the term in section 1151 of title 18, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE1E83C1A2964693BB606F5B74F5C4DE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FC01EC08B644DAC830D7917D9417C6E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Law enforcement agency</header><text>The term <term>law enforcement agency</term> means a Tribal, Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H3CB693E63EB84AC2A27E3369797FE6D5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Improving tribal access to Federal crime information databases</header> <subsection id="H815E165FFA5B458CBDFE9ACE90BD9715"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Tribal enrollment information</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall update the online data entry format for Federal databases to include a new data field for users to input the victim’s Tribal enrollment information or affiliation, as appropriate.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H602E06FD23914632817EF32EA57CC247"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header>
 <paragraph id="H71FAC975FF2D42F1946F1DEE8DFA4AA8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial consultation</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, in cooperation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall complete a formal consultation with Indian Tribes on how to further improve tribal data relevance and access to Federal databases, which shall also inform the development of law enforcement and justice protocols under section 5(a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFA5A5317077F4D4B9ADD129324C1A2E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual consultation</header><text>Section 903(b) of the Violence Against Women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20126">34 U.S.C. 20126</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HCA470302173145B4893B1961A6F82738"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBCFA91C72A57400492230E7FE4CECD86" style="OLC"> <paragraph commented="no" id="H920C6C1AE8EA4647A13F15E41379F1AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enhancing the safety of Indian women from domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, homicide, stalking, and sex trafficking;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H407D0DC0115248EAAB6DFFB4A40614D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA66E68D9A4C14350B59B58829F67296E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H288821DD08C94D08A9C5F314DDD82887" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H97FD02D1C2634DF89BCEE5C667316B99"><enum>(4)</enum><text>improving access to local, regional, State, and Federal crime information databases and criminal justice information systems.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8554F68C94794B119B20828D60403F7D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall prepare and submit a report to the Committee on Indian Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives that includes—</text>
 <paragraph id="H56A5617197844243A2332A3466B3B121"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the results of the formal consultation described in subsection (b)(1);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD5E5621060E54395809A93F1939660D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the outstanding barriers Indian Tribes face in acquiring full access to Federal databases and related national crime information systems; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0EBDD83C27914D7095DBC8CC9D6E9220"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the plan of action of the Department of Justice to—</text> <subparagraph id="HFBE87CA4D1C544D2A42A2337240C8589"><enum>(A)</enum><text>implement suggestions received from Indian Tribes through the consultation process; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF48D7F8A2E934FB5B30F766FDC1EFED0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>resolve the outstanding barriers described under paragraph (2).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H86154548FA9449278FB53B427754E0D4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Standardized protocols for responding to cases of missing and murdered Indians</header> <subsection id="HBA6CE895F8094314AC505359EF48457F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Standardized protocols for missing and murdered Indians</header> <paragraph id="H8D2500EB8FB04794B9400442FFA3A57C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the consultation process described in section 4(b)(1), the Attorney General, in cooperation with the Secretary of the Interior and in consultation with Indian Tribes, shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1E42A5F55C4F4C668AAE66F0BA685A71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review existing (as of the date of the review) law enforcement and justice protocols appropriate to missing and murdered Indians; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H701C226978E54A5B81D5C5849DF8F2B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommend such existing protocols, revise such existing protocols, or develop new protocols, as necessary, to establish protocols to serve as guidelines for law enforcement agencies with respect to missing and murdered Indians.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF72DC74744104189BDB2A7A95578E05A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Attorney General shall make the protocols under paragraph (1) publicly available and shall distribute them to law enforcement agencies.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4D7C61A5E4ED42C7B3579C7BFFD83BFA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The standardized protocols under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H0EB7A0C83F814A75BD98AFE30211CC9D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Guidance on inter-jurisdictional cooperation among law enforcement agencies at the Tribal, Federal, State, and local levels.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0EA5548961AF424C82A5CB9994BF4F4D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Standards on the collection, reporting, and analysis of data and information on missing persons and unidentified human remains appropriate to Indians, including standards on entering information to Federal databases on missing persons within a certain timeframe after receiving the missing persons report.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1D62E56427443E581612B4281AEE467"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Guidance on improving law enforcement response rates and follow-up to cases of missing and murdered Indians.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2ACC1031553546D2AB5B00A81B17DB27"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Methods to ensure access to victim services for Indian victims and their families.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7DCB59394447408F98604D07863D1FA0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Directions to United States attorneys</header> <paragraph id="H0BCE148F8142480DAE3B327B9120CB8F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Directions</header><text>Not later than 240 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall direct United States attorneys with jurisdiction to prosecute crimes in Indian country under sections 1152 and 1153 of title 18, United States Code, to develop written standard protocols to investigate cases of missing and murdered Indians that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H004EA43EC8D44805902614E703616430"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are guided by the standardized protocols under subsection (a);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE60A4C6E5324CB6961A292DC4A54D4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are developed in consultation with Indian Tribes and other Federal partners, including—</text>
 <clause id="H486A95B3140D478595AB5B4916DFA43F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text> </clause><clause id="H074D6D06F62C4D3193B999EF48B8CED2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1A835D88DD5D4BA69F8958093831E34E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Bureau of Indian Affairs; and</text> </clause><clause id="H41F2228805E24E04AC25E337BFEF3A69"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Indian Health Service;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6321A282DE9C401AAC13828F4A93164B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>detail specific responsibilities of each Federal partner; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FEAE2A66D0F49F99FFED4A50F4FC5DB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>shall be implemented not later than 60 days after the direction is issued.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7EA5E614C604366A67E2FEBB5D6602B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional directions</header><text>Not later than 240 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall direct United States attorneys with jurisdiction to prosecute crimes in Indian Country from an authority other than section 1152 or 1153 of title 18, United States Code, to discuss the Federal response to cases of missing and murdered Indians with their Tribal partners and Federal partners as appropriate during annual consultations.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H201D4513844F4FCA9475E8F12D4B83D4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Training and technical assistance</header><text>The Attorney General shall provide Indian Tribes and law enforcement agencies with training and technical assistance relating to the development and implementation of the law enforcement and justice protocols of the Indian Tribes and agencies, respectively, in accordance with the standardized protocols under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H30C26BC4A96445B2BAC185768C698DD0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, Federal law enforcement agencies with jurisdiction to investigate and prosecute crimes relating to missing and murdered Indians shall modify the law enforcement and justice protocols of the agency to satisfactorily comply with the standardized protocols under subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H8A04C50D4DEC41E6A70D42A03A819D56"><enum>6.</enum><header>Annual reporting requirements</header>
 <subsection id="H4925554896164811A2130A9940292F2F"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Beginning in the first fiscal year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General and the Secretary of the Interior shall jointly prepare and submit a report, to the Committee on Indian Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H89637F61FC104BD98EA403DA87CE8BA9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>includes known statistics on missing and murdered Indian women in the United States;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD78885BF890841E0945C093F0277322B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides recommendations regarding how to improve data collection on missing and murdered Indian women; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H06DADDA8CA2B4503B61CD16F05920F9F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>includes information relevant to the implementation of the standardized protocols developed under section 5(a).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


