<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8FB031F7D4FA4D1BBA14776646F34FB7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1486 IH: Securing American Non-Profit Organizations Against Terrorism Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1486</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170309">March 9, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide funding to secure non-profit facilities from
			 terrorist attacks, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7B55356CC0964F8193B857E3951183F7" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1005805BC66F4945A990E591D776B4C7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing American Non-Profit Organizations Against Terrorism Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HF3D4DFB1029D411FBA8B8BE1DD42B4E7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Non-profit security grant program</header> <subsection id="H80E2D2405BA04554B81A91DCDB2B5329"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle A of title XX of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/601">6 U.S.C. 601</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HC02989B116DE4C5EAC403C2029C054DE" style="OLC">
					<section id="HEC78975D1EDE4145AD24EBC8C025DD07"><enum>2009.</enum><header>Non-Profit Security Grant Program</header>
 <subsection id="H1F2CF0545E0944A9829F8B8128EA3DF2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Department a program to be known as the <quote>Non-Profit Security Grant Program</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>). Under the Program, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, shall make grants to eligible nonprofit organizations described in subsection (b), through the State in which such organizations are located, for target hardening and other security enhancements to nonprofit organizations that are at risk of a terrorist attack.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H074B2D0EF4DE47E38433F6319BA97CEA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible recipients</header><text>Eligible nonprofit organizations described in this subsection (a) are organizations that are—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H8EFC7630CF0D4BCE837836B636238C8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1976AED6C0E847B7A6212D5E369027AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determined to be at risk of a terrorist attack by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H304AB2AB059F413E96CD8F74EC7E54FC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation on eligible recipient determination</header><text>A nonprofit organization described in subsection (b) shall not be treated as ineligible to receive a grant under this section solely because such organization is not located within a jurisdiction receiving funding under section 2003.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H72903703E8374237BEC2F65EEA22C124"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Permitted uses</header><text>The recipient of a grant under this section may use such grant for any of the following uses:</text> <paragraph id="H3D263DEBB0434F8783AB128B1ACB8D6C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The acquisition or installation of certain security equipment, such as the acquisition or installation of security equipment on real property (including buildings and improvements) owned or leased by such recipient, specifically to prevent or protection against the risk of a terrorist attack.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8B47D01B7F248C1BE83BE02477E6418"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Fees for training relating to the protection of critical infrastructure key resources, including physical security and cybersecurity, target hardening, terrorism awareness, and employee awareness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFFF4DCF7C1D049CE813A712F21D7E8E3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any other appropriate activity, as determined by the Administrator.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF194861076D44D2994C934432B2E779D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022 to carry out this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1C6259D9C24343388093B90CA701CA93"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Administrator shall annually for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022 submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report containing information on the expenditure by each grant recipient of grant funds made under this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDDC142EB27F54D96B3FA2C23BA2E70A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 2002 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/603">6 U.S.C. 603</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>sections 2003 and 2004</quote> and inserting <quote>sections 2003, 2004, and 2009</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0A48D4CCAA754B9F88E3E3170794A339"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 2008 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H64F06DDB943140BFB1E503B1EAB940F1" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2009. Non-Profit Security Grant Program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


