<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H843D02A198C74D27AFFFF19D1C0A3200" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3877 IH: Fair Billing Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3877</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170928">September 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to protect health care consumers from surprise
			 billing practices, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H36DEB98ABDF54462A3787A4FF907B6E1" style="OLC">
 <section commented="no" id="H7A19F70B22234717B69DFE34DC9D922C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Billing Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H22DE8384C3F748C09EF8B0CE6DC09313"><enum>2.</enum><header>Protecting health care consumers from surprise billing practices</header> <subsection id="HD47BE895BB4043D792E4E2EBE725DDB3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Providers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1866 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395cc">42 U.S.C. 1395cc</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4969470CBED149B38C2D697A0ACED76D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text> <subparagraph id="HCF9F6DC8BC1549ABB14841799F639A7D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (X), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3565A898B581465FA801FCA1FCF55F04"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (Y), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H382F1A8A00D84AA79F061AACAA7D0259"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (Y) the following new subparagraph:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H434378F645AD460DA4E297730473506C" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H74DACCB6CEFB446CA10C096CC41419DF" indent="up1"><enum>(Z)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a hospital or critical access hospital, to meet the requirements of paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of subsection (l).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5809664EFA6E4944A087C9BF5A04376F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block id="H4F335C07429747238CF75D33BD157CF7" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H80362481DB6A47E19E8BF4E4D3961C9C"><enum>(l)</enum><header>No surprise billing at in-Network facilities; emergency services; external review of certain payments</header> <paragraph id="H8DEBC580AC124A5EB171227567332223"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No surprise billing at in-network facilities</header> <subparagraph id="H8AFCC02BE18D4FBB932BEB4725529EAE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), in the case of an individual with benefits under a health care plan who is furnished items or services at a relevant facility (including items or services furnished by a provider of services or supplier at such facility) that is within the health care provider network or otherwise a participating provider of services or supplier with respect to the health care plan of such individual, the relevant facility (or the provider of services or supplier) may not hold the individual liable for more than the amount that the individual would have been required to pay in cost sharing if such items or services had been furnished by a relevant facility (or, as applicable, by a provider of services or supplier) that is within the health care provider network or otherwise a participating provider of services or supplier with respect to the health care plan of such individual.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51931A4A15CD4245A97347B5EEB8ED1C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for notification and written consent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply in the case of a relevant facility (or provider of services or supplier at such facility) that, not later than 72 hours before furnishing items or services to an individual (or, in the case where such items or services are scheduled to be furnished less than 72 hours from the time of scheduling, 24 hours before furnishing such items or services), notifies such individual of an estimate of the individual’s anticipated total out-of-pocket cost of care for such items and services and obtains written consent from such individual.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H24FD152A3C384F9FB4C3A826DFA28084"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Emergency services</header><text>In the case of an individual with benefits under a health care plan who is furnished items or services with respect to an emergency medical condition at a hospital or critical access hospital (including items or services furnished by a provider of services or a supplier at the hospital or critical access hospital), the hospital or critical access hospital (or the provider of services or supplier) may not charge the individual more than the amount that the individual would have been required to pay in cost sharing if such items or services had been furnished by a hospital or critical access hospital (or by a provider of services or supplier) within such network or otherwise a participating provider of services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H46E23A07504243459EEB258B8D1846D6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A relevant facility shall participate in any review process requested, and comply with any determination made, under section 3 of the Fair Billing Act of 2017.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03B873B2B5594AF5B3B37179DAC222C7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H2239FC574886477B86E0194F686C18DF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Emergency medical condition</header><text>The term <term>emergency medical condition</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1867(e).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD184F0610B174FE897C69FABDF2266E2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Health care plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>health care plan</term> means—</text> <clause id="H4D25FA37F9734B52B75AF7080976376F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a group health plan;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4BF832B0022146A593105222B22AAA5E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>group health insurance coverage;</text> </clause><clause id="HE7965BA3D4B44B0E88593BB1A5993D74"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>individual health insurance coverage; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H2E006DF4FD9B405EB9A1ABFEDC0D70D5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Federal health care program (as defined in section 1128B(f)).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19685B18F7A04C6FA52401C6D3A5F451"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public Health Service Act terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>group health plan</term>, <term>group health insurance coverage</term>, and <term>individual health insurance coverage</term> have the meanings given those terms, respectively, under section 2791 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85E1462D29A8452182F11BEBEB5851D0"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Relevant facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>relevant facility</term> means a hospital or critical access hospital.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H194CA1D296DF4F8C890211CBDF7BAACF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Insurers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2719A of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-19a">42 U.S.C. 300gg–19a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88186F0104B54E63964CB15E8CED0C92" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H5F2FE22EE6FB44618A79192EC0F03AD2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Payment review process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance shall participate in any review process requested, and comply with any determination made, under section 3 of the Fair Billing Act of 2017.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H209FC5B2D35547CCA582C5535B3B9B23"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to items or services furnished on or after the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H53045EC4357A496AB76D675439BE9890"><enum>3.</enum><header>Review process for surprise billing practices</header>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H109A861B6C2A4C1399AC4E7DBBB64996"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State election</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State may elect, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary of Health and Human Services (the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall prescribe, to establish a review process described in subsection (c) to be available at the request of a health care plan or provider of services or supplier.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HDA708E41A4794550A93881AF1D41EC74"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Failure To establish an external review process or implement standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State that does not elect under subsection (a) to establish a review process described in subsection (c), the Secretary shall make available within the State such a review process to be available at the request of a health care plan or provider of services or supplier.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H22CD7727B8854D06978422E88ED13CB4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of payment from a health care plan to a provider of services or supplier for items or services furnished by such provider or supplier to an individual with benefits under such plan in a case in which section 1866(l)(1)(A) or subsection (l)(2) of such section applies and such plan or such provider or supplier requests a review of such payment, a review process described in this subsection is a process by which an independent health care expert determines the amount of the payment to be made by such plan to such provider or supplier using the methodology described in subsection (d) and notifies the individual furnished such items or services of such determination within 30 days of making such determination.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H33D183EAEBD340DD818F0041C934E7C0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Methodology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of payment from a health care plan to a provider of services or supplier for items or services furnished by such provider or supplier to an individual with benefits under such plan, the methodology described in this subsection consists of an independent health care expert determining an amount to be paid by the plan to the provider or supplier by selecting one of the following amounts:</text>
 <paragraph id="HE3A7E16986894D5EA187141A99B38359"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The lesser of—</text> <subparagraph id="H8B0477262C734F2B8317525AADCC4E5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount proposed by the provider of services or supplier that furnished such items or services; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD782F2F301F441D0AE8F0FD60577A303"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount that is equal to the 80th percentile of the amount paid for such items and services, as reported by a national all-payer claims database or, if available, a State or regional all-payer claims database, as determined by the independent health care expert.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF146B6574B44E69A107EBB11580E574"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The greater of—</text> <subparagraph id="H9BFDB49C22C142AA97F24CFFF760DD01"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount proposed by the health plan providing health benefits coverage to such individual with respect to such items and services; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4C31CE2E91742BFA1207422FB6F3C55"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1.25 multiplied by the Medicare fee schedule for such items and services (or, if such items and services are not covered under Medicare, an amount determined by the Secretary).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H359AC955F9BD4B729844EFC8F39A0861"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reconsideration</header><text>An individual furnished items or services by a provider of services or supplier for which payment is determined in accordance with the review process described in subsection (c) may, within 30 days of receiving notification of such determination, file a written request for a reconsideration of such determination with the independent health care expert making such determination. Such expert shall, within 30 days of receiving such request, determine whether such determination should be revised and notify such individual of any change to such determination.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE9AF97165C6148E187CDD18D2C52761E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Cost-Sharing clarification</header><text>Any cost sharing (including any copayment or coinsurance) that an individual may be responsible for after a determination is made under subsection (c) shall count towards such individual’s annual deductible with respect to the health care plan of such individual.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9FA5930D62A9416180C362210D2137D3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HFCDD135FA23B4076B0AAE111E7CE2F18"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Health care plan</header><text>The term <term>health care plan</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1866(l)(4) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395cc">42 U.S.C. 1395cc(l)(4)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB02ECA40503143D0BDD3468C30AEAF0F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Independent health care expert defined</header><text>The term <term>independent health care expert</term> means an individual who is, with respect to a payment for items and services—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H09AD406BB6A6430F8C54010AA287BE4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an expert in health care billing;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA95D15B91EFE45EC96983F77A7D5FE48"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">free of conflicts of interest with respect to such payment; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9A9923E7F4BB41D2AB109819991DBC2F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>appointed by a State or the Secretary to make determinations under the external review process described in subsection (c).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5AEE5A3C3D104CF38AEB2A0CAD7198AD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Provider of services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>provider of services</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1861 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF7BB820EBBA44387BF914717951895F8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given such term in section 210 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/410">42 U.S.C. 410</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E54AED874F3470F8531B7C724436BF5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Supplier</header><text>The term <term>supplier</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1861 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H7664E571F2FB430194E5F7C6138536A3"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Grants to States</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H861607A1413B4388904F77924D92079D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall provide grants, not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, to eligible States to establish and implement a review process described in subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H44EE95B5D97541FE9816A2F3C5139E5E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>eligible State</term> means a State that has elected under subsection (a) to establish a review process and that has submitted an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H70B407766CC14FAA8ED1EDA43CF8763B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services $4,000,000,000 to award grants under this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H3F4922FA0AAE4D2387EE20E9A2F2CDC3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall apply with respect to items or services furnished on or after the date that is one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


