<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF5F4B48330834638B11C03CF26ED8271" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3308 IH: Veterans Caregiver Improvement and Expansion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3308</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170719">July 19, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require an audit and review of the caregiver programs of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA95B00B455F5472A889F1C942C0FA129" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE780498BC7324F158C6F1459FF3F8042" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Caregiver Improvement and Expansion Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HCBF4CF44DC97465690AF81B282A63A21"><enum>2.</enum><header>Audit and review of Department of Veterans Affairs caregiver programs</header> <subsection id="H99E1A048C46A45E5A446E81A67329BB4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>GAO audit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct an audit of the caregiver programs of the Department of Veterans Affairs. Such audit shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAFB80C41301740E0B50FF10169315081"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a review of the budget formulations, execution, allocation, and use of funds for each program; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FCC95A859854D5A8603A131181ACC64"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the recommendations of the Comptroller General for streamlining and consolidating the two programs.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4C6D847A7A9641C58930E50B0E0E580A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Secretary of Veterans Affairs review</header><text>Not later than three months after the completion of the audit required under subsection (a), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress a report on the audit that includes the identification of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1223399B71104476AC62BE5BB9EE6954"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any changes recommended by the Comptroller General that the Secretary is able to implement without legislative changes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B744D728CE144FF89AB965EE601FF26"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any recommendation of the Comptroller General for legislative changes;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8AF7FFD839234A2DACAD95A7DA9B2E6F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any recommendation of the Comptroller General that the Secretary determines is problematic, overly expensive, or impractical; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H55D5C50E420F4FCCB9F146D2C4AC24DE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in the case of any recommendation identified under paragraph (3), a recommendation for an alternative approach to addressing the problem identified by the Comptroller General in making such recommendation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD57ACE4DBD294819A84F39513136148D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 24 months after the submittal of the report under subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H145A41CAD1204546A3A635C54EF02F10"><enum>(1)</enum><text>implement the changes described in paragraph (1) of such subsection;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H55D562D4DDB3449BA91EE2EA7E722274"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish national policies based on best practices for administering the caregiver programs designed to streamline and consolidate the caregiver programs; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H74D3D371804C45439247CF3D37A06FE6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish a database designed to monitor all Department programs that provide assistance to caregivers and all caregivers receiving assistance under a caregiver program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H35C892C5EDD74C6DA857ECEEE2A0C332"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H8AFE4EF55F904BA78D57631EFE845347"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>caregiver</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1720G(d)(1) of title 38, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B8A3F1F56004144B04DBE21E53FF617"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>caregiver programs</quote> means the following programs of the Department of Veterans Affairs:</text> <subparagraph id="H41C1CAEF1A1D42119F2ABB8D1E70B60B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The program for assistance and support services for caregivers under section 1720G of title 38, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1AEBD7DB01B40C88E190B58B22462EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The program to provide counseling, training, and mental health services for immediate family members and caregivers under section 1782 of such title.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


