<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD07DBDB0987E422C879EB2E50B97F517" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4049 IH: Equal Access to Quality Education Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4049</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171012">October 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program to ensure that students in high-need schools have equal access to a
			 quality education delivered by an effective, diverse workforce.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4199151020D544A69F68A77F8F0FF2D0" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8C3B2EC8690941DAB3F584B3A38C6400" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Equal Access to Quality Education Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H51725C65ACC84A17817C5CDF48BAB916"><enum>2.</enum><header>Equal access to quality education grant program</header> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A742D156A584B13BDC948D0AB405587"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education shall make grants on a competitive basis to eligible partnerships in high-need areas to—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDC858A1EECC54338864684F3BA8D7E69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and strengthen high-quality pathways for the teaching and education leadership professions;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5042FC6C1E61498FA6B4B11CD6B3CD40"><enum>(2)</enum><text>create professional induction programs for the teaching profession; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9499A86188954551A442E7425A260FA7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide a stable and collaborative learning environment for educators and students.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HABB6228C4E8F41CFAB366CE57FBAF254"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of the grant program established under this section shall be to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H74C1BBBF01694E83ACAFB46AAC6602B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase the percentage of profession-ready teachers in States, including teachers from under represented minority groups and teachers with disabilities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAEBE2CBF43394C2398932FCEE5ACE330"><enum>(2)</enum><text>close the achievement gap for students within subgroups that are not showing expected performance;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2B335DF85BEF485A93CE27FFD5FD7B24"><enum>(3)</enum><text>decrease shortages of profession-ready teachers in poor urban and rural areas;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEF0A59E0B37B485AAA6A6D1061C5714F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>decrease high turnover rates for educators in high-need schools;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6348B35B2F0497F990FA68F06A78393"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase the number of profession-ready teachers in shortage areas, including special education, bilingual education, and education for English language learners, and in science, mathematics, engineering, and technology;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD336384FD36242AD8E89F43BF676A2D1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>increase opportunities for enhanced and ongoing professional development that—</text> <subparagraph id="H2CD2C00DE59A4A8E922F6E3AC73A477B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improves the academic content knowledge of teachers in the subject areas in which teachers are certified or licensed to teach or in which the teachers are working toward certification or licensure to teach;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6043059A54EE4E95BBE5ADD0D9D0E598"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promotes strong teaching skills, including instructional strategies that address diverse needs, the use of data to inform instruction, and strategies to improve student achievement; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F38708AF77B4EF296C6E4EDA4E3F020"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides time for teachers to share their knowledge and innovation; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H82693369EFA446EB8A6FE006B62DD258"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide all educators with the knowledge base and professional skills to meet the needs of diverse learners, including English language learners and students with disabilities.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5FD2CE249559429CA43FCB6AA44354FA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header>
 <paragraph id="HEC9206F99EF0490B80A0BA073B8F8089"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applications required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible partnership that desires to receive a grant under this Act shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H40733C9AB4CB4A929871057A03FBCAEE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>An application submitted under paragraph (1) include—</text> <subparagraph id="H4D7F27A7C4B7427D8933FFA217711748"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of—</text>
 <clause id="H2C837ED30AAF445DB30B2F28FE0AC526"><enum>(i)</enum><text>how the eligible partnership will meet the purposes under subsection (b);</text> </clause><clause id="HCE8F706DD67644869CF9E4E2012DDD0A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how the partnership will carry out the activities required under subsection (d), including—</text>
 <subclause id="H86B735BFC1F046BCB9993CAEA8383401"><enum>(I)</enum><text>how the partnership will design, implement, or enhance a year-long and rigorous teaching residency program component; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE27744AA48584C0E9ADF17AB73E6E701"><enum>(II)</enum><text>how the partnership will design, implement, or enhance a rigorous teacher induction and retention program;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H8A88590BA46B4C3E99924DF292409A39"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of the partnership’s plan for continuing the activities carried out under a grant received under this Act after the grant funding ceases;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4897E49EEA0D4BECAD67331540A507AF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>how the grant will increase the number of profession-ready teachers —</text> <subclause id="HD663B17B66454EC69157B4CE6875B77E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in high-need schools operated by high-need local educational agencies (in urban or rural school districts); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H6994C773CDBD4C43A1F3CDE0C82900AE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in high-need academic subjects; and</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HAC98929B7D834F8B9E0AE597BF6CFF6C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>with respect to the teacher induction and retention program that will be carried out using the grant—</text>
 <subclause id="HDE43E4C6BD414C76896CBAA40D9A48A4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the partnership’s capability and commitment to, and the accessibility to and involvement of teachers in, the use of empirically based practice and scientifically valid research on teaching and learning;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H451AE569B13E4EC5BEED141C6F66B358"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a description of how the partnership will design and implement an induction program to support, through not less than the first 2 years of teaching, all new teachers who are prepared by the teacher preparation program in the partnership and who teach in the high-need local educational agency in the partnership, and, to the extent practicable, all new teachers who teach in such high-need local educational agency, in the further development of the new teachers’ teaching skills, including the use of mentors who are trained and compensated by such program for the mentors’ work with new teachers.</text>
							</subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEE16245178174DE4A15FA8D7A4EA5F4A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header>
 <paragraph id="H5C33B89385474223A447641671A3BD9F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required uses</header><text>An eligible partnership that receives a grant under this section shall use the funds to carry out the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBEB8D3A17014447885BA3852B5ECDC24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Establish or support a teacher preparation program that—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H0B9690C0671846F3B8C0A82C98288559"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requires participants in the program to complete at least one year of residency at a high-need school in the local educational agency participating in the eligible partnership;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFDD1BFCE49E34967A6572728B91B3254"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>requires participants in the program to teach in a high-need school in such local educational agency for at least 3 years after completing such residency; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H5A28B20B0A884A77B6A2E353813B960E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">awards a teaching credential, an undergraduate degree, or a Masters degree that meets State requirements for a teaching license or certification upon completion of the program.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF86123419E3B4B69B0F62214B83F65BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Establish or support a teacher induction and retention program that provides support and advances the retention of beginning teachers and principals during not less than the first 2 years of participation in such program, which promotes effective teaching and leadership skills and includes—</text>
 <clause id="HD4FBBDF8D384468D860E51DC35299C3F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>high-quality mentoring;</text> </clause><clause id="H6F79F0D6B240488A9C8A2EB5209EB38F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>periodic, structured time for collaboration and classroom observation opportunities with teachers in the same department or field, including mentor teachers, as well as time for information-sharing among teachers, principals, administrators, other appropriate educators, and participating faculty in the partner institution of higher education;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H50640058D7D64A8694A541605922D140"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the application of empirically based practice and scientifically valid research on instructional practices;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H940B97896B3F4F38B2A181A5113A385E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>opportunities for new teachers and principals to draw directly on the expertise of mentors, faculty, local educational agency personnel, and researchers to support the integration of empirically based practice and scientifically valid research with practice;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9F850608909841E0BA4D84893DEC1ED1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the development of skills in instructional and behavioral interventions derived from empirically based practice, and where applicable, scientifically valid research; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE8F42167D41540C5AC353A6B3F52DF2B"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>faculty who—</text> <subclause id="HF88F1434178E4A269DCCB4EEBB209400"><enum>(I)</enum><text>model the integration of research and practice in the classroom; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HAFBC981D72CB43CB93520FF342139129"><enum>(II)</enum><text>assist new teachers and principals with the effective use and integration of technology in instruction.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CA1F346D47E4BB29BD76B2D8A5AECD9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Otherwise fulfill the purposes described in subsection (b).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D30322237044968BBB09A2C92E8B624"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorized uses</header><text>In addition to the activities described in paragraph (1), a partnership that receives a grant under this section may use the funds for any of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H3AFB987531B94AFAB8E3838EFD45F9E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Providing support to each mentor teacher working with new teachers.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC43CAFCBA56F4D9F98E861CE4E280B08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Providing preparation in effective, evidence-based instructional assessment practices and classroom management strategies for general education teachers serving students with disabilities and students with limited English proficiency.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D46BC28889A4C168CB373DE58A54CE9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enabling teachers to engage in study groups, professional learning communities, and other collaborative activities and collegial interactions regarding instruction assessment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EFC77B5C3B24826AA9D411EEB53A7E9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Paying for release time and substitute teachers in order to enable teachers to participate in professional development and mentoring activities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBF7F2732A3C4F1A954D4ADCC282F9C6"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Creating libraries of professional material, catalogues of expert instruction, and education technology.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A7EAD4CEC704170ACF02CBC182275D2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Providing high-quality professional development for other instructional staff, such as paraprofessionals, librarians, and counselors.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECE090C2EDF342CF87BB91B26FA1EAA0"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Developing partnerships with businesses and community-based organizations.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF75DFA2686448D7AB7DFBBC452C4F37"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Providing tuition assistance, scholarships, or student loan repayment to teachers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65682988609446F190C977D1356C1D7C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Providing stipends or another financial incentive to participants in the teacher preparation program under paragraph (1)(A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE70AF1E130BC4D54A1EEE263FF367D70"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing support for home visitation, parenting education, and family engagement, especially for parents who have limited English proficiency.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H3F21B564099041D78AA0F56E14F727D5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Repayments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish such requirements as the Secretary determines to be appropriate to ensure that each participant of a teacher preparation program under this Act who receives a stipend or other financial incentive as described in subsection (d)(2)(I), but fails to complete the participant’s teaching obligation under subsection (d)(1)(A)(ii), repays all or a portion of such stipend or incentive to the eligible partnership that awarded such stipend or incentive.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB9D1D539278C47329F9F3145E0A7BE90"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible partnerships that meet the requirements of one of the following paragraphs:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7E800C396C4748599B380F37F77BFE48"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Demonstrating—</text> <subparagraph id="HBFFD88D5ED32427A85B319A5E7A22F0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a plan to recruit teachers from among minority and local candidates and from individuals with disabilities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23F7FE24961C46CAA5671AFD7ADD3C36"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of a valid and reliable teacher performance assessment.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB1C214EE8B84D5EA288B0A6E99E2F93"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Meeting the requirements of paragraph (1)(B) and including in the partnership—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5B5DDFC6933546388A5F0FF1C42FC551"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an institution of higher education that is an <term>eligible institution</term> for purposes of the TEACH Grant program under subpart 9 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070g">20 U.S.C. 1070g</external-xref> et seq.);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H867D8C750AE140EDAC3BF7E2CF771024"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Tribal College or University, as defined in section 316(b)(3) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c(b)(3)</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14E1C374B3B04524AFE44198A72EDA95"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institution, as defined in section 320(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059g">20 U.S.C. 1059g(b)</external-xref>);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC6A9D0D975B429D8CD0C19EFD344E9D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a Hispanic-serving institution, as defined in section 502(a)(5) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1101a">20 U.S.C. 1101a(a)(5)</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28B06BC2766A472F9091BC3BBA52C7AA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a historically Black college and university, as defined in section 631(a)(5) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1132">20 U.S.C. 1132(a)(5)</external-xref>).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F691E05C3A14C3BA72E8B92ABC8ED7C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Matching Requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="HD7906304FA6B4FEDB99F22A86167AFA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>The Federal share of the cost of any activities funded by a grant received under this section shall not exceed 75 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1FE99EB0CEDD45889D5F72812B53ABB4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment of non-Federal share</header><text>The non-Federal share may be paid in cash or in kind, fairly evaluated, including services.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB91487DE41F64D8DA918501D62E1AB1D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HCA66D7935EF546F1B343650C0734B2F3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible partnership</header><text>The term <term>eligible partnership</term> means a partnership—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4CA8ADC6D2EF40D5BCD3981189B046B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>between a high-need local educational agency and an institution of higher education; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H99C0D0C1D3714B4794F2FA8E4FF17370"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that may include a teacher organization or a nonprofit educational organization.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A702D6FEF064FE485EBA1A683F3DC2C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Family engagement</header><text>The term <term>family engagement</term> means a shared responsibility of families and schools for student success, in which schools and community-based organizations are committed to reaching out to engage families, especially parents of non-Native English speakers, in meaningful ways that encourage the families to actively support their children’s learning and development, as well as the learning and development of other children. The shared responsibility is continuous from birth through young adulthood and reinforces learning that takes place in the home, school, and community.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC06F239491640078EF235BDC0091B44"><enum>(3)</enum><header>High-need local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>high-need local educational agency</term> means a local educational agency—</text> <subparagraph id="H2771C88278774E1FA67AF9BDF2817B89"><enum>(A)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3D0A37A14F874633B35A4E90844EA808"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that serves not fewer than 10,000 low-income children;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6BCE58D9D688450C83ECC4C1F01A0754" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for which not less than 20 percent of the children served by the agency are low-income children;</text> </clause><clause id="H6D3668C7620144D89E3684BA61EA9FBC" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that meets the eligibility requirements for receiving funding under the Rural Education Achievement Program under part B of title V of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7341">20 U.S.C. 7341</external-xref> et seq.); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7EB591B23F02462E905F433FC8880704" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>that has a percentage of low-income children that is in the highest quartile among such agencies in the State; and</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7EFC56EB1704CC19B3F1CB8E1B76FF0"><enum>(B)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H19227391974F4ECD9811ADA228298968"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for which one or more schools served by the agency is persistently low achieving; or</text> </clause><clause id="HA9A88C236CB24344949C8CBD86EC3695" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for which one or more schools served by the agency has a high teacher turnover rate.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2D8D0DF9DBC496CBD675FAB2505F988"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF470DF1DB5E549E88F7C4BBE3093366D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Low-income children</header><text>The term <term>low-income children</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB945CA6CA4B7487984FF40036E35857F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">children from families with incomes below the poverty line (as defined by the Office of Management and Budget and revised annually in accordance with section 673(2) of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1981) applicable to a family of the size involved; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9986F7EBAB8F4957B0CBDC79F1E7CFEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>children who are eligible for free or reduced price lunches under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA99B2866079945F989E448E3C6758723"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Mentor teacher</header><text>The term <term>mentor teacher</term> means a teacher who—</text> <subparagraph id="H28E63DE8232F46CFA8A26E97F013E9EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is profession-ready;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H416B3B9436E049B2AF2128C9D63D1DBF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has a minimum of 3 years of teaching experience;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CD3950BBA25457DB38B278146DCAD8E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is recommended by the principal and other current master and mentor teachers on the basis of—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H8B130A09839F4D608E93FC462A20075E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">instructional excellence through observations and other evidence of classroom practice, including standards-based evaluations, such as certification by the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE1D54071CDBF472DA56CB4DB716AED34"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an ability, as demonstrated by evidence of student learning in high-need schools, to increase student learning; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8CA3156327EA48A4BE8D2E3F7354F34B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>excellent instruction and communication with an understanding of how to facilitate growth in other teachers, including new teachers; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFAD861C7CEF4CBF899C2E3E789D28CD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>participates in training and ongoing professional development on how to—</text> <clause id="H522A29372A9C404F934E38D03E41B4A4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>help teachers learn to improve student achievement;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7CF7ED37FCEF4ACAB58BEDD54B120C90"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>help teachers learn to improve instruction; and</text> </clause><clause id="H0E1B255E164F4AFC8A64BA16FB54C5C0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>facilitate mentor-to-mentor collaboration and coaching.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H962FC55839594AD9B3D0CD9CD2B7357F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Profession-ready</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>profession-ready</term>, when used with respect to a teacher, means a teacher who—</text> <subparagraph id="H528F81E9E7144361949D2733106B8F89"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has completed a teacher preparation program and is fully certified and licensed to teach by the State in which the teacher teaches;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9086BB4142DC4B41A613D6E6B79CFBE3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has demonstrated content knowledge in the subject or subjects the teacher teaches;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H591F8A979B63406B8EF626E7CEBC22F2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has demonstrated the ability to work with students who are culturally and linguistically diverse; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DDF8ED8D59D4627855D2E9208CCD5F1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has demonstrated teaching skills, such as through—</text> <clause id="H0F490D1324F54F8199E3FD5AB4B6C006"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a teacher performance assessment; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H580F7D831CD3455EB6077AB6073BE683"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other measures of teaching skills, as determined by the State.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBABEB6F600CD48CBBC23D6A2914E6F9A"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B0E8A9536134AFD8DDF5B0774FF4568"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Teacher performance assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>teacher performance assessment</term> means a program, based on State or national professional teaching standards, that will measure teachers’ curriculum planning, instruction, and assessment of students, including appropriate plans and adaptations for English language learners and students with disabilities, and multiple sources of evidence about student learning. Such assessment will be validated against professional assessment standards and reliably scored by trained external evaluators with appropriate auditing of scoring to ensure consistency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H757515B38ED94A8181DBE2F41800AF8A"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Teaching credential</header><text>The term <term>teaching credential</term> means a program of instruction for individuals who have completed a baccalaureate degree, that does not lead to a graduate degree, and that consists of courses required by a State for a teacher candidate to receive a professional certification or license that is required for employment as a teacher in an elementary school or secondary school in that State.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


