<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBFA167DB1578419C80983AB8910BA2EB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4540 IH: To amend the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to require Members of Congress to reimburse the Treasury for amounts paid as awards and settlements under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 in connection with violations of such Act which were committed personally by the Members, to prohibit the imposition of nondisclosure agreements as a condition of the payment of an award or settlement in connection with a violation of such Act, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4540</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171204">December 4, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to require Members of Congress to reimburse
			 the Treasury for amounts paid as awards and settlements under the
			 Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 in connection with violations of
			 such Act which were committed personally by the Members, to prohibit the
			 imposition of nondisclosure agreements as a condition of the payment of an
			 award or settlement in connection with a violation of such Act, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H64762B5B9EA9411CA038087CBB277AA4" style="OLC">
		<section id="H1D086F68C07541F29E902915128F158D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Personal liability of Members of Congress to reimburse Treasury for amounts paid as settlements and
			 awards under Congressional Accountability Act of 1995</header>
			<subsection id="HB975E3FCBECE4CC8A9E25B0A392B0E08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mandating reimbursement of amounts paid</header>
 <paragraph id="H826CF099ABA24F0F8DD0314A03536F5D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 415 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1415">2 U.S.C. 1415</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF5BD7F823F4F4D06936F3B1F1039523C" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HF0FDA8D09B3348B4A7E50AAE34D9F664"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Personal liability of Members of Congress for payment of settlements and awards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a payment is made from the account described in subsection (a) for an award or settlement resulting from a violation of part A of title II consisting of an act committed personally by a Member of the House of Representatives or a Senator, the Member or Senator shall reimburse the account for the amount of the award or settlement.</text>
						</subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H030CE7F9CFC8400EAE97C45791A1B4D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to payments made on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H190037A1501648E6AC8AA9ABEB0663D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reimbursement of amounts paid previously</header>
 <paragraph id="HAE98CC51E52E4AEBABA89BAD1CB68083"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requiring reimbursement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, prior to the date of the enactment of this Act, a payment was made from the account described in section 415(a) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 for an award or settlement resulting from a violation of part A of title II of such Act consisting of an act committed personally by an individual who, at the time of committing the act, was a Member of the House of Representatives or a Senator, the individual shall reimburse the account for the amount of the award or settlement, plus interest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C872463D88C432AAA0E012F055ED567"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>An individual shall meet the requirements of paragraph (1) not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1928DFBE3B44447E92B7856DF714FA98"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notifications by Office of Compliance</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Office of Compliance shall submit to each individual described in paragraph (1) a notice of the amount the individual is required to reimburse under such paragraph.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H82999E7E435F4C1283CA9582C998713B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reports on awards and settlements paid in connection with violations of Congressional
			 Accountability Act</header>
			<subsection id="H1244A48B25DC442983D6589CB6AB2212"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual report required</header>
 <paragraph id="HC5B2937CE0664145B843AB0F47D1D21B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 301 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1381">2 U.S.C. 1381</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15BFB09BCD7F4ACEB533C86E3623F6E1" style="OLC">
						<subsection id="H50808250ABD64B75A5C596F33FACD51D"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Annual report on awards and settlements paid in connection with violations by employing offices of
			 House and Senate</header>
 <paragraph id="HBDB3669551EA42FD8F8E315659625B25"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Office shall submit to Congress and publish on the Office’s public website a report listing all awards and settlements paid during the year in connection with violations of part A of title II which consisted of an act committed personally by a Member of the House of Representatives or a Senator, and shall include in the report the following information:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H163D990BBDB245578CDC92A6A9EB5E5E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the violation involved.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34988EEEE51B403AACF118C2F8A9EFF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The identification of the Member or Senator involved.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3572A1BDE2284DCCB833B5F2229D041A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The amount of the award or settlement.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB18DE607E343406CA0EC289A1B5879A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Protection of identity of individuals receiving awards and settlements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In preparing and submitting the reports required under this subsection, the Office shall ensure that the identity of any individual who received an award or settlement, or who made an allegation of a violation against an employing office, is not disclosed.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8EA743B3918F435BBE14B7F92ECCE6AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2018 and each succeeding fiscal year.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H410925379CA044C698EBF6CD96415986"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on awards and settlements previously paid</header>
 <paragraph id="H0977C87E77804B178D940CA6F90813E6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Office of Compliance shall submit to Congress and publish on the Office’s public website a report listing all awards and settlements paid under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 prior to fiscal year 2018 in connection with violations of part A of title II of such Act which were committed personally by Members of the House of Representatives or Senators, and shall include in the report the following information:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H302A5AED93C34D5B986F29DEDC9C0931"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the violation.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF5FBE23B2E4409794E82D691D52A95D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The identification of the Member or Senator.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC03B2E6CB9644771838A6BFCF2E118DC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The amount of the award or settlement.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED2F75768F734EABAA93DB3E026B7C67"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Protection of identity of individuals receiving awards and settlements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In preparing and submitting the report under this section, the Office shall ensure that the identity of any individual who received an award or settlement, or who made an allegation of a violation against an employing office of the House of Representatives or Senate, is not disclosed.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7D1B00DA942144EAB6DE843525AE5880" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibiting imposition of nondisclosure agreements as condition of award or settlement</header>
 <subsection id="HC854AE9B67E9480F93E05950EE8225CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Section 401 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1401">2 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3D095109AD2043EFB0E508702909D58C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Except as otherwise provided</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Procedures available</header-in-text>.—Except as otherwise provided</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7C5E915DFF54D00A67B62547A7F81F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF5E6CAB97994E869878D9BA323A175E" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HB0BFA9273AE54764A24D62CA236487DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibiting imposition of nondisclosure agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A nondisclosure agreement may not be imposed on any party as a condition of the payment of any award or settlement in connection with a violation of part A of title II consisting of an act committed personally by a Member of the House of Representatives or a Senator.</text>
						</subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD802C8A078DF44B391A2204558800BCF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Permitting individuals subject to existing nondisclosure agreements To make information public</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any individual who received an award or settlement prior to the date of the enactment of this Act in connection with a violation of part A of title II of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 consisting of an act committed personally by a Member of the House of Representatives or a Senator, and who signed a nondisclosure agreement as a condition of receiving the award or settlement, may, notwithstanding the terms of the agreement, make public any information relating to the award or settlement.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H00079A1CB78C45F2AD96FD567CE163A9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to awards and settlements paid in connection with the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


