<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H59721730B63440E58E8CABAF6E8188FC" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1517 IH: Status of the Sixth Amendment Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1517</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170313">March 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Governor of a State to submit to the Attorney General an annual report on the number
			 of individuals who represented themselves in court in criminal matters or
			 juvenile delinquency matters, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5C126E73251946029BC58FFC417BD516" style="OLC">
 <section id="H22C02FCC88BE428582D286E908E67D1C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Status of the Sixth Amendment Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H4EEC0DF818804E66835BE97E925B60F5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Finding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that the Sixth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States provides that <quote>In all criminal prosecutions, the accused shall enjoy the right to … have the Assistance of Counsel for his defense.</quote>.</text>
		</section><section id="H285F05726CF44F5C8764CE402211EA13"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on individuals who represent themselves in criminal matters or juvenile delinquency matters</header>
 <subsection id="HDAE4279BFFA240E986DDFE69EFD2C47A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Governor of each State that receives a grant from the Office of Justice Programs shall submit to the Attorney General a report which contains, at a minimum, the information described in subsection (b)(1) for each of the categories described in subsection (b)(2) for the previous year for that State.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HB67F2FFE086548A0B50407CA2BA2525B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of report</header>
 <paragraph id="H7C7C45E3A995414D9DB8BDB03437350A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information described</header><text>The information described in this paragraph is as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="H85F8ADFBFB604ECF8F7D6C369C6D52AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of charges for which an individual was prosecuted.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AC88D368D924300BC85373C888A01CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of charges for which a defendant waived his or her right to counsel.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4893B06BD51F49C19AB21B5E97BEAFDB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of charges for which a defendant was represented in court by counsel who was publicly appointed.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54FE9336EDF140D0B5E75022438E6517"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of charges for which a defendant was represented in court by counsel who was not publicly appointed.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H21BE2AAB8A704DC1A0A0AF8E425694AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Offense categories described</header><text>The categories of offenses described in this paragraph are as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="H9296AEEA54CD4970976FA4699B2D8849"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Criminal offenses for which a term of imprisonment of more than one year may be imposed.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43D8032CE69B4CD7B7EC225ACE68A07D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Criminal offenses for which a term of imprisonment of one year or less may be imposed, including misdemeanors, traffic violations, and violations of municipal ordinances.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC90D76940E3A4F87AE6C30DE6899D390"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Acts of juvenile delinquency or juvenile status offenses for which any term of detention may be imposed.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEB79F03B4B1B4187983F408796880A8F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of reports</header><text>The Attorney General shall make the reports required under subsection (a) publicly available on the Internet website of the Department of Justice.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


