<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H143A7F32AA7C45BF83FD7046E3437462" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3503 IH: To prohibit the payment of death gratuities to the surviving heirs of deceased Members of Congress.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3503</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170727">July 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the payment of death gratuities to the surviving heirs of deceased Members of Congress.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HAC6442FF6CA34D80BAC26D4D61F5D33D" style="OLC">
		<section id="HF0073419C9464B39BA7E63666FD6DBB4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibiting payment of gratuities to survivors of Members of Congress</header>
 <subsection id="HF730D86AF8264E20B76F47D2E4BC3698"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>No payment may be made from the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives, the contingent fund of the Senate, or any other appropriated funds for a death gratuity payment to the widow, widower, or heirs-at-law of any Member of Congress who dies after the commencement of the Congress to which the Member has been elected.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB732D3CD6A344DD88BDB824B5C90EDB4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No effect on other payments to survivors</header><text>Nothing in subsection (a) shall be construed to prohibit or affect the payment to any individual of any unpaid balance or salary or other sums due to a Member of Congress who dies after the commencement of the Congress to which the Member has been elected.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H5FBFE9FDAD794676A1BF7FD2873AE750"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, a <quote>Member of Congress</quote> means a Senator or a Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</text> </section></legis-body></bill> 

