<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFA893E9FB1CA4E429E00A425B857EF64" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 848</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170203">February 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000374">Mr. Abraham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001092">Mr. Collins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001062">Mr. Conaway</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000612">Mr. Denham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000563">Mr. Gibbs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000362">Mr. King of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000576">Mr. Long</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. McMorris Rodgers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000132">Mr. Vela</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000181">Mr. Nunes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000606">Mr. Pittenger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000569">Mr. Luetkemeyer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to incentivize efficient nutrient management practices and to clarify the citizen suit provisions of such Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6ABE4A6B76484FDAB792E19392F61870" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD808B346A82641C8BB136F68C0822EFE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Farm Regulatory Certainty Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB111A0042FE445DD906C263F91EF5012"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purposes</header> <subsection id="H2859A014980143C4A44C212B1386DE56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF3AF1EF280E14CFB92DAD64E170BF6B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress never intended the Solid Waste Disposal Act (commonly known as the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act) to govern animal or crop waste, manure, or fertilizer, or constituents derived from such sources, or the ways in which they are managed, stored, handled, or applied by agricultural operations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H49DD137BE5004B1EAA9559C5218DA169"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Environmental Protection Agency’s September 1979 regulations promulgated under the Solid Waste Disposal Act accurately reflect Congress’ intent not to regulate manure and crop residues under the Solid Waste Disposal Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H459C4E31416A4AEB867527CE90112FF4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress has confidence in the ability of the Natural Resources Conservation Service and the Environmental Protection Agency to, when appropriate, implement standards and recommendations for animal feeding operations (including concentrated animal feeding operations and large concentrated animal feeding operations) and other agricultural producers, as to appropriate storage and handling techniques for animal and crop waste, manure, and fertilizer, and the constituents derived from such sources, to reasonably protect water, air, and soil resources, as well as ensure public health.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H67FD59467CB2450A9AE98D10E4931533"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Continued judicial misinterpretation of Congress’ intent for the Solid Waste Disposal Act and the September 1979 rules promulgated under it could pose a very real threat to the vitality of the Nation’s agricultural community, which would lead to serious disruptions in the food supply.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD53C41CDCC8341F98A08087A920CBC67"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are—</text> <paragraph id="H25E9BE5F1BE64E3CA1D63D0BAC38BA7A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to clarify the intent of Congress with respect to the purpose and scope of the Solid Waste Disposal Act, specifically that it was not intended to regulate animal or crop waste, manure, or fertilizer, or constituents derived from such sources; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HBDCA877BAFCC419BA95B02DB80B0A606"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide legal clarity relating to individuals or entities diligently attempting to comply with State or Federal environmental or resource quality permits, standards, regulations, conditions, requirements, prohibitions, or orders.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H5C8DD82AFD874D29A219591933524F5B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definition of solid waste</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1004(27) of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6903">42 U.S.C. 6903(27)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, or, if originating from or utilized by an agricultural operation, animal or crop waste, manure, or fertilizer or constituents derived from such animal or crop waste, manure, or fertilizer</quote> after <quote>Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended (68 Stat. 923)</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H6C958A27E8B641569AEC72D54A993551"><enum>4.</enum><header>Citizen suits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7002(b)(1) of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6972">42 U.S.C. 6972(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1BF31F427A984BCFA270D8A9FB849584"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter following subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>subtitle C of this Act; or</quote> and inserting <quote>subtitle C of this Act;</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H35948459769F40478A55CBAFBB899A30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>order.</quote> and inserting <quote>order; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0451186B96AC47E69D9EE16B415F29D8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding after subparagraph (B) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5CD2F49C3F46462CADD62BF0CD9714DC" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HD9C2367729084275A7C9D2B0FA17739F" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an alleged violation by an agricultural operation—</text> <clause id="H63B7CC0E52D64C1F84CBCF9F2DA7FED0" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>if the Administrator or State is diligently seeking compliance with such permit, standard, regulation, condition, requirement, prohibition, or order in a Federal or State administrative proceeding; </text></clause> 
<clause id="H160577AB1160461BA08A627DE97B526D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the Administrator or State has, under any other law or regulation—</text> <subclause id="H07AE6E9A59F34DB58BEB3C4AD9DA57A5" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>commenced and is diligently prosecuting a civil or criminal action against such agricultural operation in a court of the United States or a State to address the same substance or activity that could otherwise be the subject of an action under subsection (a)(1)(A) of this section; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H47CE72DCC8A5434FAA3019271402BA67" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>commenced a Federal or State administrative proceeding against such agricultural operation to address the same substance or activity that could otherwise be the subject of an action under subsection (a)(1)(A) of this section; or</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H6AB6DE31E3F2432FAB0F16256657F482" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if the alleged violation concerns a substance or activity subject to a State plan approved under section 4007 of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

