<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H42E9409C57084E5E9DBF443B0FCA34D5" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4497 IH: To amend the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to prohibit the use of public funds to pay settlements and awards for workplace harassment and discrimination claims under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 which arise from acts committed personally by Members of Congress, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4497</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171130">November 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to prohibit the use of public funds to pay
			 settlements and awards for workplace harassment and discrimination claims
			 under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 which arise from acts
			 committed personally by Members of Congress, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HDDCD03B8F2A64D7E8A6A587BA1663A55" style="OLC">
		<section id="H47F7039B31184E6BAF2E70C9A966C6AF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibiting use of public funds to pay settlements and awards for claims under Congressional
			 Accountability Act of 1995 which arise from acts committed personally by
			 Members of Congress</header>
 <subsection id="H67067E31D1714E3A8B6098987C8E6BCF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Section 415 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1415">2 U.S.C. 1415</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H23C448431937409BBDAEE2B7DDAF519D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>subsection (c)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (c) and (d)</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7B6818529A3F4EAFBC92466F3D1D4742"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5B11BE51CD5E4B29A3865A9FBEA47DA9" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H6AB9F3A078034A7A91DD68B28142C0E0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No use of public funds for payments of awards and settlements in connection with acts committed personally by Members of Congress</header> <paragraph id="H92D08B7B45E24F68864CACD3DB8CFCAB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No funds of the Treasury of the United States, including the account described in subsection (a), an account of the House of Representatives or Senate, or any other account of the Federal Government, may be used for the payment of an award or settlement in connection with a violation of section 201(a) if the violation consists of an act committed personally by a Member of the House of Representatives or a Senator.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC64DF61EE4843BFBED5A6D3E2A518C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Personal liability of Members and Senators</header><text>A Member of the House of Representatives or Senator shall be personally liable for the payment of an award or settlement described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE622AA6E0DA641A69B6D18F8F7D75FFE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibiting use of campaign funds for payments</header><text>Section 313(b) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30114">52 U.S.C. 30114(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4713F82D627E4AB49A56A6DE79410174" style="traditional">
 <paragraph id="H033255DFBFBA46A4AC7154BC5C497C59"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibiting use to pay awards or settlements in claims brought against Members of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (2), a contribution or donation shall be considered to be converted to personal use if it is used to pay an award or settlement in connection with a violation of section 201(a) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 which consists of an act committed personally by a Member of the House of Representatives or a Senator.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6D35FE9E1CAD4B859AF90445B4CD2B7B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to settlements and awards paid on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC8F700B0F46340BBB49A46D2CC685558" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition against use of Members’ Representational Allowance for payments in connection with
			 allegations of violations of Congressional Accountability Act of 1995</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Members’ Representational Allowance of a Member of the House of Representatives may not be used to pay awards, settlements, or other compensation in connection with allegations of any violation of section 201(a) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 which consists of an act committed personally by the Member.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


