<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE38560A1866A4CF1B97F4EF99EA5670E" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3551 RH: C-TPAT Reauthorization Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 233</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3551</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–323]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001197">Ms. McSally</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="R000578">Mr. Reichert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001073">Mr. Hurd</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000580">Mr. Garrett</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HHM00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action><action-date>September 25, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action>
			<action-date>September 25, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on July 28, 2017</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To amend the Security and Accountability for Every Port Act of 2006 to reauthorize the
			 Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism Program, and for other
			 purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H5C1F8986020546EABA23552D8C575989" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0A5986B3140D4075A1B0F5DA5EF58175" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>C-TPAT Reauthorization Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H95017780B5FB430C8CA69A3E67C237E7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism</header> <subsection id="H982B7DD400B945099239B74AAFD42D3F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle B of title II of the Security and Accountability for Every Port Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/961">6 U.S.C. 961</external-xref> et seq.) is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD80FC0EB88DE4887ACF2940B8E218FD5" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
					<subtitle id="H47A96F0FED244CC6A4EAEFA5096EE3DF"><enum>B</enum><header>Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism</header>
						<section id="H4F8FC6904EF64DC9B388400D1E84D93B"><enum>211.</enum><header>Establishment of the Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism program</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H8A83F060AF3C4F12B137F4041DFB499C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established within U.S. Customs and Border Protection a voluntary government-private sector partnership program to be known as the Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism (C–TPAT).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H68E9F4E4B67E45C0BE14A80755C26F1A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purposes of the C–TPAT program are to—</text> <paragraph id="H56F6F41A4D784F1788BD5183EE42C5C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>strengthen and improve the overall security of the international supply chain and United States border security;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED50AF27EB5A4BEA945525A5425CEC4E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>facilitate the movement of secure cargo through the international supply chain;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HADB90F681D1B4A5FA17BCBF8E1CCE754"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure compliance with applicable law; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H65BCDFBA22704BA2828C7329B33EE3A7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>serve as the Authorized Economic Operator program for the United States.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7EC07F149B4F48B0AE50C261643E15D3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Director</header><text>There shall be at the head of the C–TPAT program a Director, who shall report to the Executive Assistant Commissioner of the Office of Field Operations (in this subtitle referred to as the <quote>Executive Assistant Commissioner</quote>) of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF4D04B9FC7194A74AE1366A55D30BBCD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Director of the C–TPAT program shall—</text> <paragraph id="H098F00B0A9D248AEA34B5B730D99ECD6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>oversee the activities of the C–TPAT program, including certification of C–TPAT participants;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6D20B3C0ED1541E0BF5BB974186BB7AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate and make revisions to security criteria pursuant to subsections (c) and (d) of section 213;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H77A922AB45C14A489F85D81158B6D207"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that participants receive a tangible and measurable benefit for participation; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H02C666A6DA5F4905BE62AB3D4319C2CC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>carry out other duties and powers prescribed by the Executive Assistant Commissioner.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H61DE9ACABEF04CECAF1A215F491B9C54"><enum>212.</enum><header>Eligible entities and notice of benefits</header>
 <subsection id="HBA317667C1F5436C8E551F7F528FF122"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>Importers, exporters, customs brokers, forwarders, air, sea, and land carriers, contract logistics providers, and other entities in the international supply chain and intermodal transportation system are eligible to apply for participation in the C–TPAT program.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H9FC1B632B56344F2B029B94F0307EC46"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tiered participation</header>
 <paragraph id="H4307923386934061847C161F5D04F73A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Applicants may be eligible to participate as Tier 1 or Tier 2 participants.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H978F7B4E82044E79AC219DFBD793850D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Importers</header><text>Importers may be eligible to participate as Tier 3 participants.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H78A55A2666894AA48AD78BA9C27E6EC9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>The Executive Assistant Commissioner may, in his or her discretion, extend Tier 3 participation to other entity types, if appropriate.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE5AD96B9BD1449E91FA4E413D7803BB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice of benefits</header>
 <paragraph id="H0356DA1D45904344BDCBF79313EE9FEA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall publish, on the U.S. Customs and Border Protection website and through other appropriate online publication, information about benefits to C–TPAT program participants.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08EE0830D9E8488FA64ADF6A8147458E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Changes</header><text>The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall publish, on the U.S. Customs and Border Protection website and through other appropriate online publication, notice of any changes to benefits to C–TPAT program participants not later than 30 days before any such changes take effect.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H98102B2214C84AD7A1F0375946A6EC35"><enum>213.</enum><header>Participation eligibility</header>
 <subsection id="H9A138B942D594F5FACD6C671A99D2469"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Executive Assistant Commissioner shall review all documentation submitted by an applicant pursuant to subsection (b)(2), conduct a background investigation of such applicant, and vet such applicant.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H428022200C854C74A8CDA7E27C07FDD0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>General requirements</header><text>To be eligible for participation in the C–TPAT program, an entity shall, at a minimum—</text> <paragraph id="H27A3DB94CE5E4A1F8A2A4B811C2B3DA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have a designated company employee authorized to bind such entity that is a direct company employee and will serve as the primary point of contact responsible for participation of such entity in the C–TPAT program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H66C3D956C1AF47CD97023CD91F828292"><enum>(2)</enum><text>at the time of initial application and annually thereafter, including in advance of any recertification or revalidation, submit an international supply chain security profile, which shall identify how such entity meets the minimum security criteria of the C–TPAT program established by the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and how such entity will maintain and enhance internal policies, procedures, and practices related to international supply chain security; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H946178E31DDB4024A54B60352CCDCE29"><enum>(3)</enum><text>meet any specific requirements for eligible entities, as established by the Commissioner.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBD2171D9E7714674B3CAA8DFDDF0F134"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Minimum security criteria</header><text>The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall establish minimum security criteria for participants in the C–TPAT program, review such minimum security criteria not less than once every two years, and update such minimum security criteria as necessary. Such minimum security criteria shall seek to address security vulnerabilities in the international supply chain.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0C5C2A2FACC2476BB9F8929DC3121CA7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional and updated criteria</header><text>The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection may establish additional and updated security criteria for individual C–TPAT program participants, categories of C–TPAT program participants, or particular entity types to meet in order to address a security vulnerability in the international supply chain.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2BEBACF272044FE39389068AC3FB0B67"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When establishing or updating security criteria in accordance with subsection (c), and when establishing additional or updated security criteria in accordance subsection (d), the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall consult with C–TPAT program participants and other interested parties, and shall—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H8E1F911A76F848B794DDDDE44E5641AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a cost benefit analysis of such proposed new, additional, or updated security criteria in consultation with the Commercial Customs Operations Advisory Committee established under section 109 of the Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/125">Public Law 114–125</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4316">19 U.S.C. 4316</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H09C9872B56504EEDA8D345A8081DAE59"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine operational feasibility and, where appropriate, conduct a phased implementation of such proposed additional or updated security criteria; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H153312066C6F4DE2ADB6C920E6DE1A85"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide C–TPAT program participants and other interested parties a 90-day comment period to review and comment on such proposed additional or updated security criteria.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFA0256466BE14F4B85D25995A82F41C8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection may waive the requirements of subsection (e) if the Commissioner determines there is a significant and imminent risk to the national security of the United States and such a waiver is necessary to protect such national security. Not later than 120 days after the issuance of any such waiver, the Commissioner shall announce on the U.S. Customs and Border Protection website and through other appropriate online publication the Commissioner’s intent to either withdraw such waiver or maintain such waiver while commencing efforts to establish minimum security criteria or establish additional or update existing security criteria in accordance with subsection (c) or (d), respectively.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="H604E93FAD2FF4D8CB711CA044C9D6A4A"><enum>214.</enum><header>Benefits for C–TPAT program participants</header>
 <subsection id="HEC71F532B652456BB91949EC1DEE5C6B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Executive Assistant Commissioner shall extend certain benefits to each C–TPAT program participant. Minimum benefits for each such participant shall include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD8D16314BD6243209FC456B27F01A9EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Assignment of a U.S. Customs and Border Protection Supply Chain Security Specialist.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8D23AE7B31C940BC884F00B3E79D7AAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Access to the C–TPAT program’s web-based Portal system and training materials.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H33E05D64C0EE46BB9D97FEDA35803A18"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A periodic and unclassified update on regional and other relevant threats to the international supply chain.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H00CDA33D8A0D445298BF4A562EA34AB0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Executive Assistant Commissioner shall make publicly available on the C–TPAT portal an annual assessment of the tangible benefits being realized by C–TPAT program participants.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H20E4761A0D6D463D8C035985955639B2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual assessment</header><text>The Executive Assistant Commissioner shall conduct, on an annual basis, an assessment of the benefits conferred to C-TPAT program participants. The Executive Assistant Commissioner shall determine a process to carry out such assessments, to include projected milestones and completion dates for addressing data reliability issues and, as necessary, correcting data weaknesses, so that U.S. Customs and Border Protection can produce accurate and reliable annual assessments that can be compared year-to-year.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="HFEEE54A72812433F82FEFEA8D65BAD00"><enum>215.</enum><header>Tier 1 participants</header>
 <subsection id="H818238560FAE4128BC4E0B558FAE5CD8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>The Executive Assistant Commissioner shall certify the security measures and international supply chain security practices of all applicants to and participants in the C–TPAT program in accordance with section 213(b)(2) and the guidelines referred to in subsection (c) of this section. Certified participants shall be Tier 1 participants.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB730AA128E6345BAA3F4B7B5C6633913"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Benefits for Tier 1 participants</header><text>Upon completion of the certification under subsection (a), a C–TPAT program participant shall be certified as a Tier 1 participant. The Executive Assistant Commissioner shall extend limited benefits to a Tier 1 participant.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC9A66AC34C38498E891A1A61EA2DA117"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this subtitle, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall update the guidelines and criteria for certifying a C–TPAT program participant’s security measures and supply chain security practices under this section. Such guidelines shall include a background investigation and review of appropriate documentation, as determined by the Commissioner.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1E5A66E5616B4C8090A01532A835CB59"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Timeframe</header><text>To the extent practicable, the Executive Assistant Commissioner shall complete the Tier 1 certification process within 90 days of receipt of an application for participation in the C–TPAT program.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="H2265E81B3E4744C08C5EE9960179BB53"><enum>216.</enum><header>Tier 2 participants</header>
 <subsection id="H36A0875878F14774AD33EA1E0E824F9A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Validation</header><text>The Executive Assistant Commissioner shall validate the security measures and international supply chain security practices of a Tier 1 C–TPAT program participant in accordance with the guidelines referred to in subsection (c) to validate such participant as a Tier 2 participant. Such validation shall include on-site assessments at appropriate foreign and domestic locations utilized by such Tier 1 participant in its international supply chain.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE5203D5254624AB5A6F3F51CD2A80BC9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Benefits for Tier 2 participants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Executive Assistant Commissioner, shall extend benefits to each C–TPAT participant that has been validated as a Tier 2 participant under this section. Such benefits may include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H5B352FD43A6E4F9A9A94047FC8213CB1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Reduced scores in U.S. Customs and Border Protection’s Automated Targeting System.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB0D773ED831946558044AEF578A46042"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reduced number of security examinations by U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2293625B3EC14301A7AF7BCC017A2A93"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Priority examinations of cargo.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H88C8D2FECFE4488EA061361601AE269E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Access to the Free and Secure Trade (FAST) Lanes at United States ports of entry.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9356FAC2A1B5483983D3FF033073C7E6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Recognition as a trusted trade partner by foreign customs administrations that have signed Mutual Recognition Arrangements with U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0053151E1D174EBE88204A05E933F7A2"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of importers, eligibility to participate in the Importer Self-Assessment Program (ISA) or successor compliance program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF7012FB47A1644BA8DD46252597481BF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this subtitle, the Commissioner shall develop a schedule and update the guidelines and criteria for validating a C–TPAT participant’s security measures and supply chain security practices under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5748470C2DF143D7A1ABE587DD06F85C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Timeframe</header><text>To the extent practicable, the Executive Assistant Commissioner shall complete the Tier 2 validation process for a C–TPAT program participant under this section within one year after certification of such participant as a Tier 1 participant.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="H6E0E2DB63C27451CBA45276D8F4226B2"><enum>217.</enum><header>Tier 3 participants</header>
 <subsection id="HB9BE7E1A369F48FDB4E8B33DA8BCCD7E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner shall establish a third tier of C–TPAT program participation that offers additional benefits to C–TPAT program participants that are importers or other entity types, in accordance with section 212(b), that demonstrate a sustained commitment to maintaining security measures and international supply chain security practices that exceed the guidelines established for validation as a Tier 2 participant in the C–TPAT program under section 216.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8909D79D53B3446F841BBA63A6DDB830"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>The Executive Assistant Commissioner may designate a Tier 2 C–TPAT program participant as a Tier 3 participant based on a review of best practices in such participant’s international supply chain that reflect a continued approach to enhanced international supply chain security, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="H77A6F6F16A804C11AB092527E147E4AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>compliance with any additional or updated criteria established by the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection under section 213(d) that exceed the guidelines established pursuant to section 216 for validating a C–TPAT program participant as a Tier 2 participant; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1DBE4A1F804E4C07962E7C8A0FED0C09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other factors that the Executive Assistant Commissioner determines appropriate.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5FE5D01297B04A6DB104ED227A1D0613"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Benefits for Tier 3 participants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Executive Assistant Commissioner, in consultation with the Commercial Customs Operations Advisory Committee established under section 109 of the Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/125">Public Law 114–125</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4316">19 U.S.C. 4316</external-xref>) and the National Maritime Security Advisory Committee established under section 70112 of title 46, United States Code, shall extend benefits to each C–TPAT program participant that has been validated as a Tier 3 participant under this section, which may include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HEABB1986A6A042F990A6422E2D1D77A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Further reduction in the number of examinations by U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H192EF0CBE0764F44B795B4855897C7E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Front of the line inspections and examinations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H36C9FF404EAB4BFD8B6D20A937EBFC12"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Exemption from Stratified Exams.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0082823B164048EBA99A47B3F0F98B8B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Shorter wait times at United States ports of entry.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0514BE6AD5E544B29E04B0DE5A285CA0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Access to the Free and Secure Trade (FAST) Lanes at United States ports of entry.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H29852CD5222741B88263075D8D75D732"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Recognition as a trusted trade partner by foreign customs administrations that have signed Mutual Recognition Arrangements with U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H35F1E401B6D447D59F23CC74B5D04A0F"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of importers, eligibility to participate in the Importer Self-Assessment Program (ISA) or successor compliance program.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF3DF5E9DB7C241E28BBB90BC1FD0D6B9"><enum>218.</enum><header>Consequences for lack of compliance</header>
 <subsection id="HD64CA735D35D41C6B086721B3FE02032"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If at any time the Executive Assistant Commissioner determines that a C–TPAT program participant’s security measures or international supply chain security practices fail to meet applicable requirements under this subtitle, the Executive Assistant Commissioner may deny such participant benefits otherwise made available pursuant to this subtitle, either in whole or in part. The Executive Assistant Commissioner shall develop procedures, in consultation with Commercial Customs Operations Advisory Committee, established under section 109 of the Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/125">Public Law 114–125</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4316">19 U.S.C. 4316</external-xref>), that provide appropriate protections to C–TPAT program participants, including advance notice and an opportunity for such participants to provide additional information to U.S. Customs and Border Protection regarding any such alleged failure, before any of such benefits are withheld. Such procedures may not limit the ability of the Executive Assistant Commissioner to take actions to protect the national security of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDA01A9B3F2D5457A94468AC313B402DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>False or misleading information; Lack of compliance with law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a C–TPAT program participant knowingly provides false or misleading information to the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the Executive Assistant Commissioner, or any other officers or officials of the United States Government, or if at any time the Executive Assistant Commissioner determines that a C–TPAT program participant has committed a serious violation of Federal law or customs regulations, or if a C–TPAT program participant has committed a criminal violation relating to the economic activity of such participant, the Executive Assistant Commissioner may suspend or expel such participant from the C–TPAT program for an appropriate period of time. The Executive Assistant Commissioner, after the completion of the process described in subsection (d), may publish in the Federal Register a list of C–TPAT program participants that have been so suspended or expelled from the C–TPAT program pursuant to this subsection.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3C9B678FB9FC4DC885C1A996DC1EB031"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If at any time the Executive Assistant Commissioner determines that a C–TPAT program participant poses a significant and imminent risk to the national security of the United States or has committed a serious violation of Federal law or customs regulations, or if a C–TPAT program participant has committed a criminal violation relating to the economic activity of such participant, the Executive Assistant Commissioner may suspend or expel such participant from the C–TPAT program for an appropriate period of time. The Executive Assistant Commissioner, after the completion of the process described in subsection (d), may publish in the Federal Register a list of C–TPAT program participants that have been so suspended or expelled from the C–TPAT program pursuant to this subsection.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HF2BE39406D884AA280E5245A1EB931AE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Right of appeal</header>
 <paragraph id="H0F080BE719EA44239113CD0A9B4B8B9E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall establish a process for a C–TPAT program participant to appeal a decision of the Executive Assistant Commissioner under subsection (a). Such appeal shall be filed with the Commissioner not later than 90 days after the date of such decision, and the Commissioner shall issue a determination not later than 90 days after such appeal is filed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8CDAA4B166DD4D8AA96F39329CC274BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appeals of other decisions</header><text>The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall establish a process for a C–TPAT program participant to appeal a decision of the Executive Assistant Commissioner under subsections (b) and (c). Such appeal shall be filed with the Commissioner not later than 30 days after the date of such decision, and the Commissioner shall issue a determination not later than 90 days after such appeal is filed.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEA5B1829688E481B91F90440C995653F"><enum>219.</enum><header>Validations by other DHS components</header>
 <subsection id="HC29B9210AE284A73A52E8C71C70B0D97"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection may recognize regulatory inspections conducted by other components of the Department of Homeland Security of entities as sufficient to constitute validation for C–TPAT program participation in cases in which any such component’s inspection regime is harmonized with validation criteria for the C-TPAT program. Such regulatory inspections shall not limit the ability of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to conduct a C–TPAT program validation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H2835B09B329443CB996B8AE2B34E1C92"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Revalidation</header><text>Nothing in this section may limit the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection’s ability to require a revalidation by U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H8B9EBE29DEAE41E69B5B7673C2707B08"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to authorize certifications of C–TPAT applicants to be performed by any party other than U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text>
							</subsection></section><section id="HBEB106936CDC41BDBA7BA9DE20F05DB1"><enum>220.</enum><header>Recertification and revalidation</header>
 <subsection id="H5F6740EBA0D047619E87BB4E293045A3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Recertification</header><text>The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall implement a recertification process for all C–TPAT program participants. Such process shall occur annually, and shall require—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5186558E875B482780F8D312AE8E1F36"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a review of the security profile and supporting documentation to ensure adherence to the minimum security criteria under section 213; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBD04CD9108274E8E898953E92FEC07E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>background checks and vetting.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5BFE81FFAA0646DF8C8CE43859748C1D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Revalidation</header><text>The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall implement a revalidation process for all Tier 2 and Tier 3 C–TPAT program participants. Such process shall require—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFD29F99104C9407F9CD514B956E4E673"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a framework based upon objective, risk based criteria for identifying participants for periodic revalidation at least once every four years following the initial validation of such participants;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6DDBB0901CE4A0EA7E6D8305A05EDE5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on-site assessments at appropriate foreign and domestic locations utilized by such a participant in its international supply chain; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H678F2B46F7B94E5FB20C508D207B33D1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an annual plan for revalidation that includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H804F054AB08D4D45BCB5292759F4ADEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>performance measures;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD052F5579C2E4C58B2EDE219B15369A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of the personnel needed to perform such revalidations; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BE1544B434B48F5AA85868E832DC84E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of participants that will be revalidated during the following year.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H15FE75392DEA41E1B7E2285E980BC5E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Revalidation under a Mutual Recognition Arrangement</header>
 <paragraph id="H5E1E5239C66649E5B16A14C9C9EF16A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon request from the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, all Tier 2 and Tier 3 C–TPAT program participants shall provide any revalidation report conducted by a foreign government under a Mutual Recognition Arrangement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1DF71859BD7147A29B5ABC596D44ECE2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recognition</header><text>The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection may recognize revalidations of entities conducted by foreign governments under a Mutual Recognition Arrangement as sufficient to constitute a revalidation for C–TPAT program participation under subsection (b).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC240D5AD8519401AAF786014237B5976"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No limitation</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to limit the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection’s ability to require a revalidation by U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H896EF50EFDFA46D183ED4AC3148E35BB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Designated company employees</header><text>Only designated company employees of a C–TPAT program participant under section 213(b)(1) are authorized to respond to a revalidation report. Third-party entities are not authorized to respond to a revalidation report.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H285D8F3B0D23484CBC1B78719C2FB758"><enum>221.</enum><header>Noncontainerized cargo and third party logistics providers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall consider the potential for participation in the C–TPAT program by importers of noncontainerized cargoes and non-asset-based third party logistics providers that otherwise meet the requirements under this subtitle.</text>
						</section><section id="HFE3738D546FB4AD4BE70EEEF94E51313"><enum>222.</enum><header>Program management</header>
 <subsection id="H79D5A8C1F0D34640A7F9F5810DE492F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall establish sufficient internal quality controls and record management, including recordkeeping (including maintenance of a record management system in accordance with subsection (b)) and monitoring staff hours, to support the management systems of the C–TPAT program. In managing the C–TPAT program, the Commissioner shall ensure that the C–TPAT program includes the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H543EF54A1F694A20B362687042F3E220"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A 5-year plan to identify outcome-based goals and performance measures of the C–TPAT program.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4EF6E3D47EE842E9815FA5B0B5184BAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An annual plan for each fiscal year designed to match available resources to the projected workload.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H857D35DD3FE24212BA22FBDC4717C7E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A standardized work program to be used by agency personnel to carry out the certifications, validations, recertifications, and revalidations of C–TPAT program participants.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0EF57E7DEA1044A8B876424CCA3D6B42"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with subsection (e), a standardized process for the Executive Assistant Commissioner to receive reports of suspicious activity, including reports regarding potentially compromised cargo or other border or national security concerns.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC441333F786542F8826381DDB205810A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Documentation of reviews</header>
 <paragraph id="H5F92963DB5584C028B465C70E03D5859"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall maintain a record management system to document determinations on the reviews of each C–TPAT program participant, including certifications, validations, recertifications, and revalidations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB949E08C4164842A2661B0730D35181"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Standardized procedures</header><text>To ensure accuracy and consistency within the record management system required under this subsection, the Commissioner shall develop, disseminate, and require utilization of standardized procedures for agency personnel carrying out certifications, validations, recertifications, and revalidations to report and track information regarding the status of each C-TPAT program participant.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HADF1EB15287B4D96A7835A3543637BCB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Confidential information safeguards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In consultation with the Commercial Customs Operations Advisory Committee established under section 109 of the Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/125">Public Law 114–125</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4316">19 U.S.C. 4316</external-xref>), the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall develop and implement procedures to ensure the protection of confidential data collected, stored, or shared with government agencies or as part of the application, certification, validation, recertification, and revalidation processes.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6E2306B0E6D346D88FD4A83B59934A84"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Resource management staffing plan</header><text>The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall—</text> <paragraph id="HD94BB8F85FF348D6B0F6C48F256C3618"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop a staffing plan to recruit and train staff (including a formalized training program) to meet the objectives identified in the 5-year strategic plan under subsection (a)(1); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4D18217B136C46FDADB07C31C3DE458F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide cross-training in post incident trade resumption for the C–TPAT Director and other relevant personnel who administer the C–TPAT program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3866EEC0CAA94EE59AE1E5DACC97018A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Engagement</header><text>In carrying out the standardized process required under subsection (a)(4), the Commissioner shall engage with and provide guidance to C-TPAT program participants and other appropriate stakeholders on submitting reports described in such subsection.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H136C4800E8374D0FA97D634C89282F15"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>In connection with the President’s annual budget submission for the Department of Homeland Security, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall report to the appropriate congressional committees on the progress made by the Commissioner to certify, validate, recertify, and revalidate C–TPAT program participants. Each such report shall be due on the same date that the President’s budget is submitted to Congress.</text></subsection></section></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE1E9E9D4E1744276A1BBD558AFDB99CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Saving clause</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H07A213791F9F408699873B142E52083A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall take effect and apply beginning on the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act with respect to applicants for participation in the C–TPAT program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2FB0825268F943408F1064BEE384CF11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply in case of C–TPAT program participants who are such participants as of the date specified in such paragraph. Such participants shall be subject to the amendments made by this Act upon revalidation of such participants to participate in such program. Until such time, such participants shall be subject to the requirements of the C–TPAT program as in existence on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H32EE39D67E0248C3B493062FB9219302"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Security and Accountability for Every Port Act of 2006 is amended by striking the items relating to subtitle B of title II and inserting the following new items:</text>
				<quoted-block changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" id="HC6171BF6A8AE4CF3BF05A6207526A21F" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
					<toc changed="added" committee-id="HHM00" regeneration="no-regeneration" reported-display-style="italic">
						<toc-entry level="subtitle">Subtitle B—Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 211. Establishment of the Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism program.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 212. Eligible entities and notice of benefits.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 213. Participation eligibility.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 214. Benefits for C–TPAT program participants.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 215. Tier 1 participants.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 216. Tier 2 participants.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 217. Tier 3 participants.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 218. Consequences for lack of compliance.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 219. Validations by other DHS components.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 220. Recertification and revalidation.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 221. Noncontainerized cargo and third party logistics providers.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 222. Program management.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>September 25, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


