<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H549541A7A15F47DA981B31B590F908D1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4572 IH: Worst-Case Scenario Hospital Preparedness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4572</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171206">December 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to enter into an arrangement with the National
			 Academy of Medicine to evaluate the preparedness of hospitals, long-term
			 care facilities, dialysis centers, and other medical facilities for public
			 health emergencies.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HBA81FE421E3244EBB30A970D5AB8EEE9" style="OLC">
 <section id="H01A908359A864C5EA3B552301A587023" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Worst-Case Scenario Hospital Preparedness Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H36ECFD2DED0046DC9270166D3839FBC3"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Academy of Medicine evaluation and report on the preparedness of hospitals, long-term care facilities, dialysis centers, and other medical facilities for public health emergencies</header> <subsection id="H4D9FEAFC7EE24B50B2C36B54111DB51B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Evaluation</header> <paragraph id="HD94D24CCD28B4FF2A8BACEBD08CED570"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Medicine or, if the National Academy declines to enter into such an arrangement, another appropriate entity under which the National Academy (or other appropriate entity) agrees to evaluate the preparedness of hospitals, long-term care facilities, dialysis centers, and other medical facilities nationwide for public health emergencies, including natural disasters.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE86F762617794CB4A95DB67C3907B071"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specific matters evaluated</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The arrangement under paragraph (1) shall require the National Academy of Medicine (or other appropriate entity)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB09B52B1BB624CA8AECF319F8F5E45A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to catalogue, review, and evaluate the efficacy of current rules and regulations for hospitals, long-term care facilities, dialysis centers, and medical facilities regarding emergency preparedness planning;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE50782C7E5644F74AC8535CE0309EC6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to identify and prioritize options to implement policies for hospitals, long-term care facilities, dialysis centers, and other medical facilities nationwide that address future threats;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BA1975425C246D798D05F5557ECDC36"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to review all Federal grant programs that affect the preparedness of hospitals, long-term care facilities, dialysis centers, or other medical facilities for public health emergencies and provide recommendations for improving such preparedness by—</text>
 <clause id="H6DFD5DADBCBB4A9F8021C6B723CCC08A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>improving such existing Federal grant programs; or</text> </clause><clause id="HF8E6B6EA3BDA4C9D82880877F5A3EAA9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>creating new Federal grant programs;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD337AEAB1824D2C9D9479BFF0DBB5AF"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to review, identify, and recommend best practices for improving emergency preparedness at hospitals, long-term care facilities, dialysis centers, and other medical facilities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4E55A9DD32F43909C2FA52FA41095DE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to identify and recommend best sources and guidelines for alterative or emergency power systems, including renewable sources, battery storage, and generators; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB952E1729D4A40EAA407A27DDAE65629"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to identify and recommend best practices and guidelines for emergency preparedness planning at hospitals, long-term care facilities, dialysis centers, and other medical facilities related to access clean water.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE484EB504BAB48E8AF523AC27144BCD0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <paragraph id="HDD1B57BB878E4E238B153CC9FCD49F6F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The arrangement under subsection (a)(1) shall require the National Academy of Medicine (or other appropriate entity) to submit to the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Congress, not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, a report on the results of the evaluation conducted pursuant to this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9482F5D9248E4301AB2CF2172A641FDE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HFE5EFDC3D0054C0997E01CC9BFA31BA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describe the findings and conclusions of the evaluation conducted pursuant to this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H671646FDD45842749A6684A3CCBDBFB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include a strategy for improving the preparedness of hospitals, long-term care facilities, dialysis centers, and other medical facilities nationwide for public health emergencies, including natural disasters.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


