<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HCBFD0E073F88486FB713E001ED37FB65" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2218 IH: Tennessee Wilderness Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2218</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170427">April 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To expand the Big Laurel Branch Wilderness and Sampson Mountain Wilderness in the Cherokee National
			 Forest in the State of Tennessee, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF8732E56D7CC413EA2315ED2279C9611" style="OLC">
 <section id="H270D7B0466A74274833D7F5615C505EB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tennessee Wilderness Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1AC4F27D3FF24306B548A67C421D24DC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of additional wilderness, Cherokee National Forest, Tennessee</header> <subsection id="HFB1939832A314CDFBC7DC5B746367471"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation of wilderness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.), the following parcels of Federal land in the Cherokee National Forest in the State of Tennessee are designated as wilderness and as additions to existing components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:</text>
 <paragraph id="HBA7942653B21453BBFA269ED24FDAC54"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain land comprising approximately 4,446 acres, as generally depicted as the <quote>Big Laurel Branch Addition</quote> on the map entitled <quote>Proposed Wilderness Areas and Additions-Cherokee National Forest</quote> and dated January 20, 2010, which shall be incorporated in, and shall be considered to be a part of, the Big Laurel Branch Wilderness.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE816FE03D5C45FA94B6BA7799A2396B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain land comprising approximately 2,922 acres, as generally depicted as the <quote>Sampson Mountain Addition</quote> on the map referred to in paragraph (1), which shall be incorporated in, and shall be considered to be a part of, the Sampson Mountain Wilderness.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDDEEDCC5417240AEB6F309627699B4E5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maps and legal descriptions</header>
 <paragraph id="H7F7BDF1CDE7246EB8EB9188A2845C222"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall submit maps and legal descriptions of the wilderness designated by subsection (a) with the appropriate committees of Congress.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7D4E95CE1D0427FB87FDC2943FD2E1D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions submitted under paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection in the office of the Chief of the Forest Service and the office of the Supervisor of the Cherokee National Forest.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB63B13D6C34645ABAB84FB98D4ABCB70"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Force of law</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions submitted under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may correct typographical errors in the maps and descriptions.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9892F30058924F019A68E8B22553F212"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header>
 <paragraph id="H5B6A104C98D741E5AE9DC2FC7981FA77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights, the Secretary of Agriculture shall administer the Federal land designated as wilderness by subsection (a) in accordance with the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131</external-xref> et seq.), except that any reference in that Act to the effective date of that Act shall be deemed to be a reference to the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H959193818FE644149D8E1CE80EEAC7FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife management</header><text>In accordance with section 4(d)(7) of the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133(d)(7)</external-xref>), nothing in this Act affects the jurisdiction of the State of Tennessee with respect to fish and wildlife management (including the regulation of hunting, fishing, and trapping) on the Federal land designated as wilderness by subsection (a).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


