<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H888EF46DD3694CE081A0FD36F0348690" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 679 IH: Construction Consensus Procurement Improvement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 679</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170124">January 24, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves of Missouri</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000604">Mr. Russell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 41, United States Code, to improve the manner in which Federal contracts for design
			 and construction services are awarded, to prohibit the use of reverse
			 auctions for design and construction services procurements, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HCE655F12A64842228A8A45F7F6DB33FD" style="OLC">
		<section id="HF4C21F312CBB40C19701DF04F12ECFA0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H60B9B3D0F69443418C948894C63BF20F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Construction Consensus Procurement Improvement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H5C213C1E86C64E6F9085F75D8EC32493"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc>
					<toc-entry idref="HF4C21F312CBB40C19701DF04F12ECFA0" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H6BCDC49180B44D928350996CDB5DCEA7" level="section">Sec. 2. Congressional findings.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8735CC7DFDC1488CA13539F03E263E82" level="section">Sec. 3. Design-build construction process improvement.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HED4BC9D6411E456D84D3D5DA8D14E73F" level="section">Sec. 4. Prohibition on the use of a reverse auction for the award of a contract for design and
			 construction services.</toc-entry></toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="H6BCDC49180B44D928350996CDB5DCEA7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="HA7F7F1DD1AB9407BAA60364DC3C3E3C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The acquisition procedures that are often used effectively to procure products and other forms of services are not always appropriate for the procurement of design and construction services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F5752BB17074B65A4A636DDA74C73B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Federal procurement officials often adopt contracting techniques from the private sector and have used those techniques effectively to procure products and services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFFFB99A9937E45398368578FBC572F49"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Design-build is a procurement technique Federal officials have adopted from the private sector that has worked well for the procurement of design and construction services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71F6E29A44004B68B273C2DFC4B3463B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The current statutory framework for design-build could benefit from legislative refinement.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDD0A5B64142B4F5CAC6E83D12C14EFC9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Reverse auctions are another procurement technique Federal officials have adopted from the private sector and used successfully to award contracts for the procurement of products that are commercially equivalent to commodities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAA1F374E9FF740068B417EA1C0E6D737"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Despite their success in other contexts, reverse auctions are generally inappropriate for the procurement of design and construction services, given the unique nature of each such project.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H8735CC7DFDC1488CA13539F03E263E82"><enum>3.</enum><header>Design-build construction process improvement</header>
			<subsection id="H062C42B7860D416AA664FF48BCB60C9D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Civilian contracts</header>
 <paragraph id="H280BE09CAE9F4E67894EEC9CDE848131"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3309(b) of title 41, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1CC83B90E6E14D89BDFE6E45F18F7E98" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H867FC11F8361427C96ABA0BBCB113310"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria for use</header> <paragraph id="H7DDBC99F46AA430AA75DC90668E093C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contracts with a value of at least <enum-in-header>$3,000,000</enum-in-header></header><text>Two-phase selection procedures shall be used for entering into a contract for the design and construction of a public building, facility, or work if a contracting officer determines that the project has a value of $3,000,000 or greater.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H89C356A52621445FBD7B30488827B6E6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contracts with a value less than <enum-in-header>$3,000,000</enum-in-header></header><text>For any project that a contracting officer determines has a value of less than $3,000,000, the contracting officer shall make a determination on whether two-phase selection procedures are appropriate for use for entering into a contract for the design and construction of a public building, facility, or work if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE2851CD57106413CA68BDEE46B409C61"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the contracting officer anticipates that 3 or more offers will be received for the contract;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12E57D418DB54615A64F070092338F6F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>design work must be performed before an offeror can develop a price or cost proposal for the contract;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B7CC0B88ED94684AC20A26D43AD24DB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the offeror will incur a substantial amount of expense in preparing the offer; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE8A98AB0B6D4CCC89F68979853F08D2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the contracting officer has considered information such as—</text>
 <clause id="HC797351711AE4349A365F294A68242D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the extent to which the project requirements have been adequately defined;</text> </clause><clause id="H6485EDD355BB48ECBC653D809495DCF8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the time constraints for delivery of the project;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H17ECE264B9C34716865AA6331668DE6C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the capability and experience of potential contractors;</text> </clause><clause id="HDF91B2124FD540D9B1674D04041D4C40"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the suitability of the project for use of the two-phase selection procedures;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCD01C23168354A5D99BD77BAC3C7777A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the capability of the agency to manage the two-phase selection process; and</text> </clause><clause id="HBBF1B50436D54F4BBF0EBBB32A66A235"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other criteria established by the agency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H49510744743542D2B89198E37190A2CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual reports</header>
 <subparagraph id="H96499CA99BE544C8995F8E77EFB683CA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than November 30 of 2018, 2019, 2020, 2021, and 2022, the head of each executive agency shall compile an annual report of each instance in which the agency awarded a design-build contract pursuant to section 3309 of title 41, United States Code, during the fiscal year ending in such calendar year, in which—</text>
 <clause id="HC4F29A3EBD3840B39172D94473FFF910"><enum>(i)</enum><text>more than 5 finalists were selected for phase-two requests for proposals; or</text> </clause><clause id="HD688E35F86914D80B36A1DB8FD3C3610"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the contract or order was awarded without using two-phase selection procedures.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE355FF56F181456AA458D3CA859C41BB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall facilitate public access to the reports, including by posting them on a publicly available Internet website. A notice of the availability of each report shall be published in the Federal Register.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDEB61F40F1DC487AB6315C247B567043"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO reports</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the deadline for each annual report under subsection (a)(2)(A), the Comptroller General of the United States shall issue a report analyzing the compliance of each executive agency with the requirements of section 3309 of title 41, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(1).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HED4BC9D6411E456D84D3D5DA8D14E73F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on the use of a reverse auction for the award of a contract for design and construction
			 services</header>
 <subsection id="HD557CD0A67A74922A56302BDFF9297B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Finding</header><text>Congress finds that, in contrast to a traditional auction in which the buyers bid up the price, sellers bid down the price in a reverse auction.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H37F7B6B1C21E42738140469741E714C9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Acquisition Regulation shall be amended to prohibit the use of reverse auctions as part of the two-phase selection procedures for awarding contracts for design and construction services.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAC3A2050F547438FB3EF5517E28FEDDA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H56A44301D4D04841B2C8190AB50105F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>design and construction services</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H64E8567A9296430B9FA26AEC6976AA71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>site planning and landscape design;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8E6E345C82E4D4CA97E678256D77400"><enum>(B)</enum><text>architectural and engineering services (as defined in section 1102 of title 40, United States Code);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AC3FE170BBB4670870B2DE0F934C646"><enum>(C)</enum><text>interior design;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H083AB04AA98748EB8DB9542B6608D277"><enum>(D)</enum><text>performance of substantial construction work for facility, infrastructure, and environmental restoration projects;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AEF7A06E53945D1BA81447D75633373"><enum>(E)</enum><text>delivery and supply of construction materials to construction sites; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H527B4BE42D094D99AC0FF2F234E58A3D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>construction or substantial alteration of public buildings or public works; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75037A12A0FB452FB96A39AC34B8B3DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>reverse auction</term> means, with respect to any procurement by an executive agency—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD382C31F5FFD4E2194A88AC153DEB6C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a real-time auction conducted through an electronic medium among 2 or more offerors who compete by submitting bids for a supply or service contract, or a delivery order, task order, or purchase order under the contract, with the ability to submit revised lower bids at any time before the closing of the auction; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE143DF716FB9407FB68D0545BA78BC87"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the award of the contract, delivery order, task order, or purchase order to the offeror, in whole or in part, based on the price obtained through the auction process.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


