<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD0CD3CD1DBA64AD1916B02A5F06F9C9E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 746 IH: Campus Fire Safety Education Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 746</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170130">January 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000210">Mr. King of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Education to make grants to support fire safety education programs on
			 college campuses.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HC04D40B4B8FC4A5A90D869B78E7C963A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H2EC1650A0F3B42E9ADF2A2F9DF3D071A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Campus Fire Safety Education Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HAA89EB8F0DCB4FBC8C136460E8A8BD70"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to help provide fire safety education and training to students attending institutions of higher education.</text>
 </section><section id="H8484192E9E3948B28271977C351F1C16"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H96EBC7CA277D453981A7B8F6C125CA9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2CEA7A26C1F3463BA1AAAD8CD6C99CF6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means an institution of higher education, or consortium of institutions of higher education located in the same State, in a collaborative partnership with a nonprofit organization or a public safety department. Such a collaborative partnership may also include a social fraternity or sorority exempt from taxation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, the active membership of which consists primarily of students enrolled at the institution or institutions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D79E741904C4378BD9A96DBDBA041DF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fire safety education program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fire safety education program</term> means a program that provides fire safety and prevention activities.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B59A8C37BD34C04BFE4B2D7D9FB3599"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H70F78A0F57CB470A91FEA8399F91AD80"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H1E51F884AEB544AA8252642C92803DEF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of the campus fire safety education competitive grant program</header> <subsection id="H17ADA814C27544148491728CF2C92CE8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of grant program</header><text>From the amounts appropriated under section 7, the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator, shall establish a grant program to award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities for—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDFE78A257C9248C7AEA103D5E7F47983"><enum>(1)</enum><text>initiating, expanding, or improving fire safety education programs at institutions of higher education; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9F61AEF7BB414DA49D8D22AB6C612FDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increasing fire safety awareness among students enrolled at such institutions, including students living in off-campus housing.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H867DB82C30BF4B82944CC428CBB04422"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To seek a grant under this Act, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2550ECB66EEA4F2BA57737AF3B790468"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection priority</header><text>In making grants under this Act, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that plan to use grant funds to initiate, expand, or improve fire safety education programs that include educational material specifically prepared for students with physical, sensory, or cognitive disabilities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1AA0B37AA5B746C1BE670ADE4C17BF5E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grant period</header><text>Grants under this Act shall be awarded for not longer than a 2-year period, and may be renewed for an additional 2-year period, at the Secretary’s discretion.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HDB61BA9C634B48FBA153621CEFC0FB07"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grant size</header>
 <paragraph id="H6A0A68C935044586A47A4009D2B5C71A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary shall ensure that grants awarded under this Act are of sufficient size and scope to enable eligible entities to carry out all required activities and otherwise meet the purpose of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H12BC095A31FA404CA1103894B0A65B8C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum amount</header><text>An eligible entity may not be awarded more than $250,000 per fiscal year under this Act.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC1CE58EFEC3E41628FB30DA1B99641B6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity receiving a grant under this Act shall provide non-Federal matching funds in an amount equal to not less than 25 percent of the costs of the activities for which assistance is sought. Such non-Federal matching funds may be in cash or in-kind.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEF14D31DCA1448D1A10E8FA49563DBE4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text>Funds made available under this Act shall be used to supplement, not supplant, other Federal, State, or private funds that would otherwise be expended to carry out fire safety education programs.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HF4717F73A7C14C9EA37B4162F58E7974"><enum>5.</enum><header>Required uses of funds</header>
 <subsection id="HF0466AABC3B6468CAFBB98BF3CFB9E42"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Required Uses of Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity receiving a grant under this Act shall use grant funds to initiate, expand, or improve a fire safety education program that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6B3A43E21C364AC3B8775ED3A9BB5338"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible entity that is an institution of higher education, reaches, to the extent practicable, all students enrolled in the institution of higher education, including students living on-campus and off-campus;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFD6C998E0587480AA3F4095251C4BB81"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is carried out in a manner to ensure maximum exposure to, increase awareness of, and effectuate change in behavior with respect to fire safety by students through—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD3FF8C80E76847078B5B00A99D8D0351"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conducting outreach to students at a minimum of twice per academic year (at the beginning of the fall and spring semesters, or the equivalent); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2682A7E672F344DBAA16293DFB98A1D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>measures that provide fire safety information to any student upon the request of the student;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8805C96D6EB4B0B8A978E0CF1CA9738"><enum>(3)</enum><text>includes minimum instruction with respect to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB798330FA67C4E1B8153B25E5AAE0810"><enum>(A)</enum><text>awareness of fire behavior;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2B50E47E28D49F183F5738AD6EBE38F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mechanisms of fire injury and death;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8AA4F52ABE949F6B992D5D604DB4F2A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>common ignition scenarios;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H644E58A67CC649E1A96CC31502A7DDFB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>fire safety systems such as automatic fire sprinklers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E868D3797D84A8FB89890B4AFBA8FCA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>fire alarms;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B48210A48C148F9AA2E97ACB45DD1A5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>fire extinguishers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE2F2304CF104A22AA89F63019AACA3F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>importance of means of egress;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF70D668239844C7BA0308BB9F4AAE2A6"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fire prevention techniques that may prevent a fire from occurring (such as candle safety, cooking safety, and smoking safety); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5043CC4FDF4404C9957C6A3CEBB3865"><enum>(I)</enum><text>fire safety actions to be taken if a fire occurs to minimize the potential for death, injury, and property damage (such as knowing how to use a fire extinguisher, how to put out a cooking fire, calling 911, and evacuating); and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AAF756A839A41DA90F0F4332B3A7D03"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes a mechanism for carrying out the evaluations described in subsection (b).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF4DC87695DB4AAD89480A9B2B908CE5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Evaluations</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the end of an eligible entity’s grant period, the eligible entity shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAF1109DEA31B442F9123EB7A3832751B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct an evaluation on the effectiveness of the program carried out by the eligible entity in increasing awareness or improving fire safety behavior at such eligible entity; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H401103BF84CB459092FF7359BAB1B005"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prepare and submit to the Secretary a report on the results of the evaluation conducted by the entity.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5C6BCB9B04F64DCBBCF6CE6BF8210558"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <subsection id="H381ABA0362C9411C8A06966A5A4FEC17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of receipt of the first report submitted pursuant to section 5(b)(2) and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall provide to Congress a report that includes the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA47A6F360495487BB11E07FA6CB31ADF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number and types of eligible entities receiving assistance under this Act.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB6F5FC924CDA4FF6A5373F0F4FE15193"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The fire safety education programs being implemented with assistance under this Act and the costs of such programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1400DAD54354273856C79654C21C8E8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any other information determined by the Secretary to be useful in evaluating the overall effectiveness of the program established under this Act in improving the fire safety knowledge of college students.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1008BCE41F894CACB1F3E1F58C5EA406"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Best practices report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator, shall use the information provided under subsection (a) to publish a report of best practices for initiating, expanding, or improving fire safety education programs that shall be made available to all institutions of higher education and other interested parties.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H94108FFE5E3E4CE1B583E1221E1A72CB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $15,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


