<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE571C8F890DB46B29A5C6E0603CA8D5E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3904 IH: Data Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3904</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171002">October 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Federal Trade Commission to prescribe rules that require covered entities to secure
			 sensitive personally identifiable information against a security breach.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H370079E3F8F04A559D49E80C44E26EEB" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5A6F08B09A6A428EAB74FC9D4E54F979" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Data Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H083FBD5F1C8F42FDB7B93B29377D02AC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reasonable measures to secure sensitive personally identifiable information</header> <subsection id="HF80899F6723248BFBFBB2E8753ABFA43"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rules required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall prescribe rules in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, that require a covered entity to employ reasonable measures to secure sensitive personally identifiable information maintained by such entity against a security breach.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFCFDCC94C97A4D52B4DF90DC37385D88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Factors for consideration in determining reasonableness</header><text>The rules prescribed under subsection (a) shall provide for the consideration, in determining whether measures employed by a covered entity are reasonable, of factors that include the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H67A9D0D65CF94D9EABE00AE2716C2F84"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the covered entity follows any applicable best practices issued by the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H79E47C493FB34B9AAAB4700B9329AD45"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the covered entity takes reasonable steps to keep software up-to-date in order to mitigate security vulnerabilities, especially critical security vulnerabilities, in any database or other computer system in which sensitive personally identifiable information is maintained by such entity.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB86C2022EDC04B64901F9CDAD9A46553"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consideration of binding arbitration clauses in determining civil penalty amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a violation of the rules prescribed under subsection (a) results in a security breach and the covered entity experiencing such breach offers any credit, identity theft, fraud, or similar monitoring or protection service to consumers as a result of such breach, in determining the amount of a civil penalty under section 5(m) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(m)</external-xref>) for such violation, the court shall consider, in addition to the factors required to be considered under such section, imposing a higher penalty if the terms and conditions applicable to such service include a requirement that any disputes be resolved by binding arbitration (or a requirement that consumers take action to opt out of binding arbitration) than if such terms and conditions did not include any such requirement.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H3C21125B03B6450AAD8EED3BA7A65823"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header>
 <subsection id="H0BC4CA2A6C18403482660769D0E2C7BC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of a rule prescribed under section 2(a) shall be treated as a violation of a rule prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0E33404AB95441EBB02147AD8394AEE8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall enforce the rules prescribed under section 2(a) in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41</external-xref> et seq.) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act. Any person who violates such a rule shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H16CEC145FC014D52A785D34612EB9DFF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HDF16AF2BE6B5483583728DAC5F0830CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H829029D9B6D34485B2977BB3C2C10ECD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means any person, partnership, or corporation—</text> <subparagraph id="H9E3E62CDCAE34BE18987D0B3724712ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>over which the Commission has jurisdiction under section 5(a)(2) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(a)(2)</external-xref>); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A15F968ABB34F92BF0C6C45036D5C57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that maintains sensitive personally identifiable information of more than 100,000 individuals.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2C035C7BA9954B6CBFD39FE4A4EC7ED3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Security breach</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H836F17079CE14457A58690CC36739F8E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>security breach</term> means a compromise of the security, confidentiality, or integrity of, or the loss of, computerized data that results in, or there is a reasonable basis to conclude has resulted in—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HF71E7F1D3B1B42AC8605182AEEFDDD74"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the unauthorized acquisition of sensitive personally identifiable information; or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H21ABB64C18AA4D0EA0D6934AA3933C98"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>access to sensitive personally identifiable information that is for an unauthorized purpose, or in excess of authorization.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5C0BCBC1F67442518AD36BF2FC96E743"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>security breach</term> does not include any lawfully authorized investigative, protective, or intelligence activity of a law enforcement agency of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State, or of an element of the intelligence community (as defined in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>)).</text>
				</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C858F1DCAF2450E829DD54BFB99B8AB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sensitive personally identifiable information</header>
 <subparagraph id="HE7F23C27C33843C98C1BB9478FF2580A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>sensitive personally identifiable information</term> means any information or compilation of information, in electronic or digital form, that includes one or more of the following:</text>
 <clause id="H1BBCB08A857E4E04BB9385CF413404A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An individual’s first and last name or first initial and last name in combination with any two of the following data elements:</text>
 <subclause id="HE8234B5D81934EE0A012F48F860BEEA5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Home address or telephone number.</text> </subclause><subclause id="HE830D205124F43D09A431A640128EA20"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Mother’s maiden name.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD922FCC34381494799DFAE6528B3F73B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Month, day, and year of birth.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HCEC8219A1A6D409BABC2F4AC87CAAF7F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A Social Security number (but not including only the last four digits of a Social Security number), driver’s license number, passport number, or alien registration number or other Government-issued unique identification number.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H16DF8B0F7EB34B31AE26EBB4AC69F3E5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Unique biometric data such as a finger print, voice print, a retina or iris image, or any other unique physical representation.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6995010B90734E48A89812F0CABC0875"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A unique account identifier, including a financial account number or credit or debit card number, electronic identification number, user name, or routing code.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H50AE03928FDA4281B47642D5B8E1385C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A user name or electronic mail address, in combination with a password or security question and answer that would permit access to an online account.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6BD1C750E7D047B59D8C2608FC36A2E6"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Any combination of the following data elements:</text> <subclause id="H46B102FB456D43028B5EAEB85E7CA3FA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>An individual’s first and last name or first initial and last name.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H67C0342096334108AFCB175E756EE48F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>A unique account identifier, including a financial account number or credit or debit card number, electronic identification number, user name, or routing code.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H0C1F29B27C9F4167AB0FB212617CEF9D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Any security code, access code, or password, or source code that could be used to generate such codes or passwords.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AEFC0CE2CE44F4686E83A6A54A172A3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Modified definition by rulemaking</header><text>The Commission may, by rule prescribed in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, amend the definition of <quote>sensitive personally identifiable information</quote> to the extent that such amendment will accomplish the purposes of this Act. In amending the definition, the Commission may determine—</text>
 <clause id="H4BDDFEB6AA124148A7E044AAD1AC8A84"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that any particular combinations of information are sensitive personally identifiable information; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF2626B1371BC44498E2AD64150D9D527"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that any particular piece of information, on its own, is sensitive personally identifiable information.</text>
					</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


