<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4206245030764C4AB551832796577F76" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3590 IH: Environmental Justice and Civil Rights Restoration and Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3590</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To restore, reaffirm, and reconcile environmental justice and civil rights, provide for the
			 establishment of the Interagency Working Group on Environmental Justice
			 Compliance and Enforcement, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA21CD6353F654B239D5E08CE5D25AFC0" style="OLC">
		<section id="HEF8AAFFBD3064F69A547892FA92B1441" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="HA9D25AA98929463EA5087D58E34106D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Environmental Justice and Civil Rights Restoration and Enforcement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H1D9D2EDCDD0E4970802CB17A5D75D32A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="HEF8AAFFBD3064F69A547892FA92B1441" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE4EBC17594254A49BF9A7364765F3810" level="section">Sec. 2. Statement of policy.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H1FA60409A1E043F091937068DA5A7DA2" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HCD4BEEB5A3D84F7DA5B4DC3CB877267F" level="section">Sec. 4. Prohibited discrimination.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA3E7A1795C6D41F2BC5125BAC281EA49" level="section">Sec. 5. Right of action.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H78E4B3023C2542FCB979C84B32B700AF" level="section">Sec. 6. Rights of recovery.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HE2058E90F4F94516AFD22E24B15AC791" level="section">Sec. 7. Interagency Working Group on Environmental Justice Compliance and Enforcement.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HEA68F2B88591462F8933D5BA4A0C83CA" level="section">Sec. 8. Responsibilities of Federal agencies.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H0F5EE28722674E7891193A221A12F968" level="section">Sec. 9. Ombudsmen.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HA7FF120B751B472D85D838B638A6A81E" level="section">Sec. 10. Training of employees of Federal agencies.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB57EA871CC59439FBEA86ACF1806F275" level="section">Sec. 11. Grant programs.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5BB8F73CFEE64DCFBCE824882412B80E" level="section">Sec. 12. Environmental justice basic training program.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4D4EA6724A64484B8DF005645B324786" level="section">Sec. 13. National Environmental Justice Advisory Council.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HAFAD8AF0B9CA4403AD5781FD489CF1E0" level="section">Sec. 14. Environmental Justice Clearinghouse.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBB62415FC72349DA998C5976CF4F5C1F" level="section">Sec. 15. Public meetings.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H743CD625AA1A4519BE9FFDF636532719" level="section">Sec. 16. Supplemental environmental projects for environmental justice communities.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H045342E5B7A64E8298C91DC0D1062382" level="section">Sec. 17. Evaluation by Comptroller General of the United States.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
 </subsection></section><section id="HE4EBC17594254A49BF9A7364765F3810"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of Congress that each Federal agency should—</text> <paragraph id="H3B6013C00522417ABB4331605996ED44"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seek to achieve environmental justice as part of its mission by identifying and addressing, as appropriate, disproportionately high and adverse human health or environmental effects of its programs, policies, practices, and activities on communities of color, low-income communities, rural communities, and Tribal and indigenous communities in each State of the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA12D0E44CC3543E5838F2B3C37F44524"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promote meaningful involvement and due process in the development, implementation, and enforcement of environmental laws;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H290CD6BB1E25424C8B3315A337C0B9D6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide direct guidance and technical assistance to environmental justice communities focused on increasing community understanding of the science, regulations, and policy related to Federal agency action on environmental justice issues; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H779D377C6AC54222A4DE463DA9246715"><enum>(4)</enum><text>cooperate with State governments, Tribal Governments, and local governments to address pollution and public health burdens in environmental justice communities, and build healthy, sustainable, and resilient communities.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H1FA60409A1E043F091937068DA5A7DA2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H65AD88EEA4A94291A900EE3F99DCDD0E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1A409D7132E41EDB660E2D75D14B422"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advisory council</header><text>The term <term>Advisory Council</term> means the National Environmental Justice Advisory Council established by the President under section 13.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC6B5AEA4EC140E1A2F328C577146CBB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Aggrieved person</header><text>The term <term>aggrieved person</term> means a person aggrieved by discrimination on the basis of race, color, or national origin.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H05DD91D1B9114A8E9E3841B21401FDB8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Clearinghouse</header><text>The term <term>Clearinghouse</term> means the Environmental Justice Clearinghouse established by the Administrator under section 14.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24094C39086C4765B850B08CAF99B902"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Community of color</header><text>The term <term>community of color</term> means a population of individuals who are members of one or more of the following population groups:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H688CCC0D7182474AAF9D19767DA0F377"><enum>(A)</enum><text>American Indian or Alaskan Native.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03A00886B714417CAFD770DE285D38F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Asian or Pacific Islander.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA03C8996F83842C2BF3E8375554039C6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Black, not of Hispanic origin.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAE6B48D4614484BBC4C5697C2F9473B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Hispanic.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C8C22E769A84A4E99E63F802C8D9907"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Covered agency</header><text>The term <term>covered agency</term> means an agency described in section 7(c).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H665DC47E1EB24DFBBB41BFC8BED4E46F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Demonstrates</header><text>The term <term>demonstrates</term> means meets the burdens of going forward with the evidence and of persuasion.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H042533BD4AF44F1C8C6B952093AB082B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE2F00F2A8C6948689202F7DD8046A6B9"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Disparate impact</header><text>The term <term>disparate impact</term> means an action or practice that, though appearing neutral, actually has the effect of subjecting persons to discrimination because of their race, color, or national origin.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB9FD6A60C08F4DC88CE516ABEA49D7AC"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Disproportionate burden of high and adverse human health or environmental effects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>disproportionate burden of high and adverse human health or environmental effects</term> means situations where there exists significantly higher and more adverse human health or environmental effects on communities of color, low-income communities, rural communities, and Tribal and indigenous communities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBEFC98E2E03A4A0BB7A557C991E90FB6"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Environmental justice</header><text>The term <term>environmental justice</term> means the fair treatment and meaningful involvement of all people regardless of race, color, culture, national origin, or income, with respect to the development, implementation, and enforcement of environmental laws, regulations, and policies to ensure that each person enjoys—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H408D6D38DC9D4C15B9103994DF2F5D99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the same degree of protection from environmental and health hazards; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A78876321B24A4AB2607B79FE73DF8A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>equal access to any Federal agency action on environmental justice issues in order to have a healthy environment in which to live, learn, and work.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6E183694699D444A88ED55D49E0DC969"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Environmental justice community</header><text>The term <term>environmental justice community</term> means a community with significant representation of communities of color, low-income communities, rural communities, and Tribal and indigenous communities, that experiences, or is at risk of experiencing, significantly higher and more adverse human health or environmental effects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H158E34FA4003449AB0ABF2EC563B50E6"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Environmental law</header><text>The term <term>environmental law</term> includes the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</external-xref> et seq.), the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251</external-xref> et seq.), the Energy Policy Act of 2005, the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.), the Pollution Prevention Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/13101">42 U.S.C. 13101</external-xref> et seq.), the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300f">42 U.S.C. 300f</external-xref> et seq.), and the Solid Waste Disposal Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6901">42 U.S.C. 6901</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H920F351CC5924AC6A4C45592F7B9CD2C"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Fair treatment</header><text>The term <term>fair treatment</term> means the conduct of a program, policy, practice or activity by a Federal agency in a manner that ensures that no group of individuals (including racial, ethnic, or socioeconomic groups) experience a disproportionate burden of high and adverse human health or environmental effects resulting from such program, policy, practice, or activity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE597E5EB6E304FA096755152454D95B7"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Indian tribe</term> in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H040F88E2E5B741138B9AB464C6F24B3D"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Local government</header><text>The term <term>local government</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0D0F2900A5BC45D78E107D154FEDAEF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a county, municipality, city, town, township, local public authority, school district, special district, intrastate district, council of governments (regardless of whether the council of governments is incorporated as a nonprofit corporation under State law), regional or interstate governmental entity, or agency or instrumentality of a local government;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAEA7047316F4A9A814B4A33834A82B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe or authorized Tribal organization, or Alaska Native village or organization, that is not a Tribal Government; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8FA7F657E5A4A24B9925722B4A278B4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a rural community.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E86EFF71172463ABBBD5B35E7A511B5"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Low-income community</header><text>The term <term>low-income community</term> means a population of individuals whose family’s taxable income for the preceding year did not exceed 150 percent of the poverty level amount.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H57E97E8FB3034DB69FFD6D624551AD4D"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Rural community</header><text>The term <term>rural community</term> means a population of individuals not included within an urban area (as defined by the Census Bureau).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1FE6DA596E8E47E7B7224791C274CD94"><enum>(19)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H44795DCDF0CA430C81E968BBC9951479"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Tribal and indigenous community</header><text>The term <term>Tribal and indigenous community</term> refers to a population of people who are members of a federally recognized Indian Tribe, including those living on a different reservation or living outside Indian country, State-recognized Indian Tribes, Alaska Natives, Native Hawaiians, Native Pacific Islanders, and Native Americans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBE751EF174064B298CE206830D065C09"><enum>(21)</enum><header>Tribal government</header><text>The term <term>Tribal Government</term> means the governing body of any Indian Tribe, Alaska Native Tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, or community that the Secretary of the Interior acknowledges to exist as an Indian Tribe under the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9945D811BB2B4C6BBA8858FFE8B3D3C2"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Working group</header><text>The term <term>Working Group</term> means the Interagency Working Group on Environmental Justice Compliance and Enforcement established by the President under section 7.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HCD4BEEB5A3D84F7DA5B4DC3CB877267F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibited discrimination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 601 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H652FB4647AB24B0EA8927B87FD2A40F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>No</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) No</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7693D63CA08E4864BF91179FCB57E8B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HDED29AA5BD8C44E9AE7F96C59769D81A" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H582ED023C9BB49AEAC131A1669928FA4"><enum>(b)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H060B0A0EA21B410BB5496EBF70F44B16"><enum>(1)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE552C2CF014E46618826D2DDA116DE2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Discrimination (including exclusion from participation and denial of benefits) based on disparate impact is established under this title only if—</text>
 <clause id="H7405041175F24D03A78534411D45EA5D" indent="up2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a person aggrieved demonstrates that a covered agency has a program, policy, practice, or activity that causes a disparate impact on the basis of race, color, or national origin and the covered agency fails to demonstrate that the challenged program, policy, practice, or activity is related to and necessary to achieve the nondiscriminatory goal of the program, policy, practice, or activity alleged to have been operated in a discriminatory manner; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBF0E4F2A954947AAA16580AF812812B7" indent="up2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the aggrieved person demonstrates (consistent with the demonstration required under title VII with respect to an <quote>alternative employment practice</quote>) that a less discriminatory alternative program, policy, practice, or activity exists, and the covered agency refuses to adopt such alternative program, policy, practice, or activity.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD03A852E7DF40109B378EFAC77E7ED7" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7DA82EA04D7D457B94F721A678D4AB33"><enum>(i)</enum><text>With respect to demonstrating that a particular program, policy, practice, or activity causes a disparate impact, the aggrieved personal shall demonstrate that each particular challenged program, policy, practice, or activity causes a disparate impact, except that if the aggrieved person demonstrates to the courts that the elements of the covered agency’s decision-making process are not capable of separation for analysis, the decision-making process may be analyzed as 1 program, policy, practice, or activity.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4764A7B7D86B4A63AE68BE3F596726D8" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If the covered agency demonstrates that a specific program, policy, practice, or activity does not cause the disparate impact, the covered agency shall not be required to demonstrate that such program, policy, practice, or activity is necessary to achieve the goals of its program, policy, practice, or activity.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H75768DF32E4F4B31902DE509FCE2B0D1" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A demonstration that a program, policy, practice, or activity is necessary to achieve the goals of a program, policy, practice, or activity may not be used as a defense against a claim of intentional discrimination under this title.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H72D6C5B2C0EC4C76B6CAFC823DD34BB3"><enum>(c)</enum><text>No person in the United States shall be subjected to discrimination, including relation, because such person opposed any program, policy, practice, or activity prohibited by this title, or because such person made a charge, testified, assisted, or participated in any manner in an investigation, proceeding, or hearing under this title.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HA3E7A1795C6D41F2BC5125BAC281EA49"><enum>5.</enum><header>Right of action</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 602 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d-1">42 U.S.C. 2000d–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE1BA7146C8E44E80823D33414ACDB349"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(a)</quote> before <quote>Each Federal department and agency which is empowered</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5C7D1984FE59409F9E28F85801015F25"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H925F940FCC6B4A4996D3869D286E675D" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H7A915A8A6ECD45C29811FE95F724B24D"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Any person aggrieved by the failure of a covered agency to comply with this title, including any regulation promulgated pursuant to this title, may file suit in any district court of the United States having jurisdiction of the parties, without respect to the amount in controversy and without regard to the citizenship of the parties.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H78E4B3023C2542FCB979C84B32B700AF"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rights of recovery</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 602 the following:</text>
			<quoted-block id="HCDD2F8D6C516460C9FC14A912C519286" style="OLC">
				<section id="H3238583770594239A37283F6E2115D92"><enum>602A.</enum><header>Actions brought by aggrieved persons</header>
 <subsection id="HAFF69E76CA8D48ECBFCFF98D4957B4B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Claims based on proof of intentional discrimination</header><text>In an action brought by an aggrieved person under this title against a covered agency who has engaged in unlawful intentional discrimination (not a practice that is unlawful because of its disparate impact) prohibited under this title (including its implementing regulations), the aggrieved person may recover equitable and legal relief (including compensatory and punitive damages), attorney’s fees (including expert fees), and costs of the action, except that punitive damages are not available against a government, government agency, or political subdivision.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5F0ABA72DF7A4BB19EE96F1B4572DD1E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Claims based on the disparate impact standard of proof</header><text>In an action brought by an aggrieved person under this title against a covered agency who has engaged in unlawful discrimination based on disparate impact prohibited under this title (including implementing regulations), the aggrieved person may recover attorney’s fees (including expert fees), and costs of the action.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section commented="no" id="HE2058E90F4F94516AFD22E24B15AC791"><enum>7.</enum><header>Interagency Working Group on Environmental Justice Compliance and Enforcement</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H68C563F78F4D4FEE8FC5B967C5C6ADEE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the President shall establish a working group to be known as the Interagency Working Group on Environmental Justice Compliance and Enforcement.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HAC4FD6DCAA8F4186B6E4607E98B0705D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Working Group are—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H25FC0635134F427F9E92B89FD6412155"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to advise and assist Federal agencies in identifying and addressing, as appropriate, the disproportionate human health and environmental effects of Federal programs, policies, practices, and activities on communities of color, low-income communities, rural communities, and Tribal and indigenous communities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEC917C8A4F4441E7A5E4C43CC00CF38D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to promote meaningful involvement and due process in the development, implementation, and enforcement of environmental laws;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC15728DF7E224072A2184D8C3F7CF5C1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to provide direct guidance and technical assistance to environmental justice communities focused on increasing community understanding of the science, regulations, and policy related to Federal agency actions on environmental justice issues; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBC17EFEA226D4AD5861A73EB10F3E12A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to cooperate with State governments, Tribal Governments, and local governments to address pollution and public health burdens in environmental justice communities, and build healthy, sustainable, and resilient communities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD508069A1C054DA3AC0840D76DB78126"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Working Group shall be composed of a representative from each of the following:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H8A979EEC8FEF4B10AF4BB8D50CD6745A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Department of Agriculture.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBCC1BDECCFC549E4AE2E9BCB081FC93D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Department of Commerce.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H310FACCCA7E74872B7FBAB1D370F80E4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Department of Defense.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC951E1778B7A48A198C0C789C3776CB5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Department of Energy.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE6DFD06632E74DD080136FE084628701"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Department of Health and Human Services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0585D71DA0F7454596D917429EB112E3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEF6AF4C35B2E4EA88AD557155920792A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Department of the Interior.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7F3B1051AE7E45CF90FCFCE74B93C63B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Department of Justice.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7DE85EDEFCE7400AA4FC0833B5830213"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Department of Labor.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEB574FC5911D4479AB4F5C8CFAF81232"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Department of Transportation.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H91D7FA34CF1E4229A1242F3F9C4229EE"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD241798825D2435EA6A9CE7532743D42"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Office of Management and Budget.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF2E0B7F6E0C447D2A139CFF3C1327FC4"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The Office of Science and Technology Policy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB3FEF624E7B6479CAB50BB2E0B120898"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The Office of the Deputy Assistant to the President for Environmental Policy.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H305AEDE799F1460EB2969BA6A2C6CD86"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The Office of the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H05B703A1FBA844B89AF1DD8EFA3F1571"><enum>(16)</enum><text>The National Economic Council.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDDCB9F0F14A1478397BCD39A168FD36C"><enum>(17)</enum><text>The Council on Environmental Quality.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H21549B30F9DC469697B1714D9828DD59"><enum>(18)</enum><text>The Council of Economic Advisers.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3D4C8353509D47038EA198C76D87DE64"><enum>(19)</enum><text>Any other agency that the President may designate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HEE473C7BD34C42C590642BC6F9B006F5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Governance</header><text>The President, or designee, shall serve as Chairperson of the Working Group.</text> </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC4388DB79F6B4F7493FD68557374D0D8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report to president</header><text>The Working Group shall report to the President through—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H71BB74EAA8DB462D8AD98AE27D787676"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Council on Environmental Equity;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA3B919D7A43C429B878470CB5530FC35"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Deputy Assistant to the President for Environmental Policy; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFB9A5BB554214A36B8631FB95CA01E08"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC73A1F42FAEE401CB807F8DAF2943E1F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Uniform consideration guidance</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H1ABE347ACDE642778F5F436FD7DE91D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To ensure that there is a common level of understanding of terminology used in dealing with environmental justice issues, not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Working Group shall develop and publish in the Federal Register a guidance document that outlines the ways in which the following considerations will be taken into account in defining communities as environmental justice communities:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H5CF337F878DC47A5B6135EE69542F4CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Health disparities.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H54AB29E279B64682821833510C06EE01"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Environmental exposure disparities.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD2A1EA43139340D0A074BBE81CE9C4B0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Intrinsic biological factors, including age, sex, and race or ethnicity.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H504C62D8F7B74781B13E6C0C7F047389"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Social stressors, including poverty, housing quality, access to health care, education, and lack of community resources.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H59CA2BFC4E4D4E07A09C2CAACC0C02C5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Cumulative impacts or risks.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFFECD92935B5470B8FF35F5C48BE0745"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Additional elements in the community that indicate vulnerability or susceptibility to high and adverse human health and environmental effects (including climate change).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB6434896511344AAB72836082BAA7426"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Capacity of communities to address environmental concerns.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8A5AF0D95E9E4D87AB2C94BAAC19C2CA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public comment</header><text>For a period of not less than 30 days, the Working Group shall seek public comment on the guidance document developed under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8A327B28017347A0965391904291F5EF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Documentation</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of publication of the guidance document under paragraph (1), the head of each Federal agency participating in the Working Group shall document the ways in which the Federal agency will incorporate guidance from the document into the environmental justice strategy of the Federal agency.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H0206C9AB1C6C443EBF6D6CCBA078B0A7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Development of interagency Federal environmental justice strategy</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H66AE566882774D12804D6C9C4845909F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, after notice and opportunity for public comment, the Working Group shall develop and promulgate a coordinated interagency Federal environmental justice strategy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB8DA9C0B802F4AAC887AE28DA258CCB5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Working Group shall consider each environmental justice strategy developed and finalized by each Federal agency that participates in the Working Group under section 8(b).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H10866802DE244458B9CB89CFE7BB122E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Report to president</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HEF50027A56DC4A4BB4C231450E63265B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date described in subsection (g)(1), the Working Group shall, through the Chairperson of the Council on Environmental Quality, the Deputy Assistant to the President for Environmental Policy, or the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy, submit to the President a report that contains—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HF2566F6B216A42BC8F3DFCE66E935BFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the implementation of the interagency Federal environmental justice strategy; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H39142E1F4A1A41BD8F8E9E42C1E38D08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a copy of the finalized environmental justice strategy of each Federal agency that participates in the Working Group.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HED7A371572934B529C619A3EADF6A432"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The head of each Federal agency that participates in the Working Group shall make the report described in paragraph (1) available to the public (including by posting a copy of the report on the website of each Federal agency).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HEA68F2B88591462F8933D5BA4A0C83CA"><enum>8.</enum><header>Responsibilities of Federal agencies</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HDC6A9490032241129A7187C2EC0FE177"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conduct of programs</header><text>Each Federal agency that participates in the Working Group shall conduct each program, policy, practice, and activity of the Federal agency that adversely affects, or has the potential to adversely affect, human health or the environment in a manner that ensures that each such program, policy, practice, or activity does not have an effect of excluding any individual from participating in, denying any individual the benefits of, or subjecting any individual to discrimination or disparate impact under, such program, policy, practice, or activity of the Federal agency because of the race, color, national origin, or income level of the individual.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H834279048D2E41669BABD1B57A847EBA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal agency environmental justice strategies</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HEB1A3900A2A94816B0453830443E1FBB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and after notice and opportunity for public comment, each Federal agency that participates in the Working Group shall develop and finalize an agencywide environmental justice strategy that—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H3C5AB64C800E4A79B0933220298A620F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies and addresses any disproportionately high or adverse human health or environmental effects of its programs, policies, practices, and activities on—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HE42EB31994D44F119983DC65B2469040"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">communities of color;</text> </clause><clause id="HFB6574E4941D49368A51F20A01B50406"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>low-income communities;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3958D22944584A77984A7DA8D53BEECD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>rural communities; and</text> </clause><clause id="H3B0A733C4A2E4EB38C60511FDD2421F0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Tribal and indigenous communities; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDBB61C20446A4081A1A713FD021638D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>complies with each requirement described in paragraph (2).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8E046C33A54F44FD89CD7D014530B618"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each environmental justice strategy developed by a Federal agency under paragraph (1) shall contain—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H485BE2E5698F414FAC16D60086CFDE49"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment that identifies each program, policy, practice, activity (including any public participation process) of the Federal agency, relating to human health or the environment that the Federal agency determines should be revised—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HD9DC7DEDB0054BA09CD2C35ABD8D03DE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to ensure that all persons have the same degree of protection from environmental and health hazards;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H2E265B99592043D9B47587BF7DC8838F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to ensure meaningful involvement and due process in the development, implementation, and enforcement of environmental laws;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HD8D4C1076B7F47258527D083A5633A8E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to improve direct guidance and technical assistance to environmental justice communities with respect to the understanding of the science, regulations, and policy related to Federal agency action on environmental justice issues;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HB71054432F1B4C8DA333F87D3006C9D5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to improve cooperation with State governments, Tribal Governments, and local governments to address pollution and public health burdens in environmental justice communities, and build healthy, sustainable, and resilient communities;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H1C12B725375B44EA8A448EF9214C2128"><enum>(v)</enum><text>to improve Federal research and data collection efforts related to—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H469A3EB3130944C1AA50A982530CF557"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the health of and environment of communities of color, low-income communities, rural communities, and Tribal and indigenous communities;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HC92590F94F8C4CD2B6B24E2696EE26A1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>climate change; and</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H73B89FC9F4C3425EA8A284012D2E76D0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the inequitable distribution of burdens and benefits of the management and use of natural resources, including water, minerals, or land; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HA795C23B66D544E7B8473BC7D069A589"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>to reduce or eliminate disproportionately high and adverse human health or environmental effects on communities of color, low income communities, rural communities, and Tribal and indigenous communities; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1236A46F79734891820CA6686E6D985C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a timetable for the completion of—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HB82C57367AD74CAF9A831E56A4D0089F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each revision identified under subparagraph (A); and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HD890763623104C398F99AD22858DA983"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an assessment of the economic and social implications of each revision identified under subparagraph (A).</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H521B7025F1FD41F7B550FDE9274ECCFC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0156A495DFAE40A397DF6853D31FAF85"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the finalization of an environmental justice strategy under this subsection, and annually thereafter, a Federal agency that participates in the Working Group shall submit to the Working Group a report describing the progress of the Federal agency in implementing the environmental justice strategy of the Federal agency.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0C9DA8BC23754CCB85162092357BB9EC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Periodic reports</header><text>In addition to the annual reports described in subparagraph (A), upon receipt of a request from the Working Group, a Federal agency shall submit to the Working Group a report that contains such information as the Working Group may require.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0DEFA409840B464F95D4C9ABB0307A5C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Revision of agencywide environmental justice strategy</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, each Federal agency that participates in the Working Group shall—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H96B936AADB64487D830F0D94A2E26BA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluate and revise the environmental justice strategy of the Federal agency; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC860964463A5467CAEDE52619D7D774A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to the Working Group a copy of the revised version of the environmental justice strategy of the Federal agency.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFE9BC1EFAAAF421C892ED9E61E1E30B1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Petition</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H94DCC7F480914756A131C030CCFD0AC1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of a Federal agency may submit to the President a petition for an exemption of any requirement described in this section with respect to any program or activity of the Federal agency.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3D2D74C841A44FCAB5CC3DC027243E19"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability to public</header><text>Each petition submitted by a Federal agency to the President under subparagraph (A) shall be made available to the public (including through a description of the petition on the website of the Federal agency).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9A128D5D87094DBFB6939EBAAE280EC9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>In determining whether to grant a petition for an exemption submitted by a Federal agency to the President under subparagraph (A), the President shall consider whether the granting of the petition would likely—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H2364989421534F6A9FA5292E49224C78"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">result in disproportionately high and adverse human health or environmental effects on communities of color, low-income communities, rural communities, and Tribal and indigenous communities; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HBE90AE813A7D4F3E9F058ED5762CC149"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>exacerbate any disproportionately high and adverse human health or environmental effect on any community of color, low-income community, rural community, or Tribal and indigenous community.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8811B460E5124054A8821C94D9F29140"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Appeal</header>
 <clause commented="no" id="H2B97F683AB554AAFB9F0B9400753CA66"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which the President approves a petition under this paragraph, an individual may appeal the decision of the President to approve the petition.</text>
						</clause><clause commented="no" id="H7F6EE361CD6D40D4B69AEE4EC9278A8E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Written appeal</header>
 <subclause commented="no" id="HD37B179B92474002B3C0C0EFB4167E21"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To appeal a decision of the President under subparagraph (A), an individual shall submit a written appeal to—</text>
 <item commented="no" id="H69C0B8B315024EA5880703DD09DF8B69"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the Council on Environmental Quality;</text> </item><item commented="no" id="H6BFEDC5667CA4BA7A903A656E200C481"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the Deputy Assistant to the President for Environmental Policy; or</text>
 </item><item commented="no" id="H7EE932DD3D3E4E7BAD2D3870A59EB937"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy.</text> </item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H080A127BAB954974A0D128444356388C"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A written appeal shall contain a description of each reason why the exemption that is the subject of the petition is unnecessary.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H5B0241C676E24D759273EE17F75AEBCE"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Requirement of president</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which an official described in clause (ii)(I) receives a written appeal submitted by an individual under that clause, the President shall provide to the individual a written notification describing the decision of the President with respect to the appeal.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0F5EE28722674E7891193A221A12F968"><enum>9.</enum><header>Ombudsmen</header>
 <subsection id="HF16D2A8FCCDA43CF97290D68B895B929"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator shall establish within the Environmental Protection Agency a position of Environmental Justice Ombudsman to receive, review, and process complaints and allegations with respect to environmental justice programs and activities of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7B86C4A868AF44228D09CB31792F6703"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>The Environmental Justice Ombudsman shall—</text> <paragraph id="HC3885C3DF5534F9A83B64AEEF98A1B71"><enum>(1)</enum><text>report directly to the Administrator; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEFBFE8403721400C9460569E7ABEAE1E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not be required to report to the Office of Environmental Justice.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB37E285D46F0441B82E04ECE16AFD122"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regional staff</header> <paragraph id="H1F0351C4D79E43F6BD686DE54C639BC1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority of environmental justice ombudsman</header><text>The Administrator shall allow the Environmental Justice Ombudsman to hire such staff as the Environmental Justice Ombudsman determines to be necessary to carry out at each regional office of the Environmental Protection Agency the responsibilities of the Environmental Justice Ombudsman described in subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC48140484034D2EA78F344FCC6ACA7D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Full-time position</header><text>Each individual hired by the Environmental Justice Ombudsman under paragraph (1) shall be hired as a full-time employee of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HA7FF120B751B472D85D838B638A6A81E"><enum>10.</enum><header>Training of employees of Federal agencies</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HB8D20DE1800C4811A086E368028DF18A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial period of training</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall offer to each employee of the Environmental Protection Agency an opportunity to participate in an environmental justice training program to ensure that each employee of the Environmental Protection Agency—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H43C2442BBDD6491F9EE6FBB3D29D15D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has received training in environmental justice; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6935FE5F184D495380D2074D3D1435E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is capable of—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD914FF5B0DDD4A04B53C65358EAC432A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>appropriately incorporating environmental justice concepts into the daily activities of the employee; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6CAF624D70B14B29AB9D205897A02E2D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increasing the meaningful participation of individuals from environmental justice communities in the activities of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HFCB496855C5D4126AD2126702F313D56"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mandatory participation</header><text>Effective on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, each individual hired by the Environmental Protection Agency after that date shall be required to participate in environmental justice training.</text>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD4807FB01F464544A58E9C2A3673C986"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirement relating to certain employees</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HE62817A2F27C4F4ABE43DDA46CDA8A5F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to each Federal agency that participates in the Working Group, not later than 30 days after the date on which an individual is appointed to the position of environmental justice coordinator, environmental justice ombudsman, or any other position the responsibility of which involves the conduct of environmental justice activities, the individual shall be required to possess documentation of the completion by the individual of environmental justice training.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H09FDD5C509A84410B389B87DEBEB8AE3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>If an individual described in paragraph (1) fails to meet the requirement described in that paragraph, the Federal agency at which the individual is employed shall transfer the individual to a different position until the date on which the individual completes environmental justice training.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8DB31695D529489A9D9538C0FDA633EF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of each Federal agency that participates in the Working Group shall evaluate the training programs of such Federal agency to determine if such Federal agency has improved the rate of training of the employees of such Federal agency to ensure that each employee has received environmental justice training.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HB57EA871CC59439FBEA86ACF1806F275"><enum>11.</enum><header>Grant programs</header>
			<subsection commented="no" id="H0558E9A73534416F98DF59F3F4ECF10F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Environmental justice community grant program</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H81652C0652D1440991A1EB7C6047FCCB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator shall establish a program under which the Administrator shall provide grants to eligible entities to assist the eligible entities in—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H5DEEEF20EE25445E95070D22465D276B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>building capacity to address issues relating to environmental justice; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCEF61F209BB84419A6B42FC9E50705AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carrying out any activity described in paragraph (4).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H93FB7288C059430789B07E9FFB131ADE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), an eligible entity shall be a nonprofit, community-based organization that conducts activities to reduce the disproportionate health impacts of environmental pollution in the environmental justice community at which the eligible entity proposes to conduct an activity that is the subject of the application described in paragraph (3).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8EA84AA86BC54D038C7A11D17E65F9B9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), an eligible entity shall submit to the Administrator an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator may require, including—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB3377B5F9C84472BA1AFF9702F7A1E00"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an outline describing the means by which the project proposed by the eligible entity will—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H8155762DBAAE435DB0DB309799D87DA0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to environmental and public health issues at the local level, increase the understanding of the environmental justice community at which the eligible entity will conduct the project;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H0FCB871C280049F4A180C11B3CECD0B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improve the ability of the environmental justice community to address each issue described in clause (i); and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H23FDB220BA8D466995A25FD9CAA19B39"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>facilitate collaboration and cooperation among various stakeholders (including members of the environmental justice community);</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8B582D0F9E3F4C678717D0D5B10B21BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a proposed budget for each activity of the project that is the subject of the application;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBA7ABF5121674F8387173A937765AA18"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a list of proposed outcomes with respect to the proposed project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4F06B086449E4CB2BCAC19CD7F10EF93"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of the ways by which the eligible entity may leverage the funds of the eligible entity, or the funds made available through a grant under this subsection, to develop a project that is capable of being sustained beyond the period of the grant; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H020B0D9FD2714B1E97A41086C0952404"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of the ways by which the eligible entity is linked to, and representative of, the environmental justice community at which the eligible entity will conduct the project.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7D205D0BA0534B86B610D080A3FEEE25"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity may only use a grant under this subsection to carry out culturally and linguistically appropriate projects and activities that are tailored to the needs of the environmental justice community at which the eligible entity proposes to conduct the project or activity to address environmental justice concerns and improve the health or environment of the environmental justice community, including activities—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H6ECDE6CF2A444B5ABEC76D82377DF26D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to create or develop collaborative partnerships;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H279FABC71D024A668DFA12E34DB544B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to educate and provide outreach services to the environmental justice community;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H72EF84FA12DD40A5A1CBBEAE6FB48130"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to identify, and implement projects to address, environmental, or public health concerns; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9181439EC92F4D0FB7C232413FD718E0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to develop a comprehensive understanding of environmental or public health issues.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBAAD6D065162442DBF58FEAF9F75AD18"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD0F3BC49131D4BC0BE16923513D56424"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the Committees on Energy and Commerce and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Environment and Public Works and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report describing the ways by which the grant program under this subsection has helped community-based nonprofit organizations address issues relating to environmental justice.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H35230B18BBDB4B42A2BFC753B313CA5C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Administrator shall make the report required under subparagraph (A) available to the public (including by posting a copy of the report on the website of the Environmental Protection Agency).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3721755C53644BF2B1DABD4E6F0BEC51"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H519FEA7BC73E4C6CA088DA2AB5F1727F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State grant program</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H8B8C702E2A8F461CB17251A05014026F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator shall establish a program under which the Administrator shall provide grants to States to enable the States—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2900AB7038E84E72B00113FBF4FE54A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to establish culturally and linguistically appropriate protocols, activities, and mechanisms for addressing issues relating to environmental justice; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5076B443986C45FB84AB4C9E1ADEEC7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to carry out culturally and linguistically appropriate activities to reduce or eliminate disproportionately high and adverse human health or environmental effects on environmental justice communities in the State.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBDAC6E8572E349D4B0E4F22E457260B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB41DF190E8414B0399464B6C082FB8C6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), a State shall submit to the Administrator an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator may require, including—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H0127D70B7E0D42BC855844C440A2585D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a plan that contains a description of the means by which the funds provided through a grant under paragraph (1) will be used to address issues relating to environmental justice at the State level; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HA5DECBC4E34645B4B09B98A48E91F523"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assurances that the funds provided through a grant under paragraph (1) will be used only to supplement the amount of funds that the State allocates for initiatives relating to environmental justice.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H320D44687EB841B8AB676C6A6723CE95"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ability to continue program</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), a State shall demonstrate to the Administrator that the State has the ability to continue each program that is the subject of funds provided through a grant under paragraph (1) after receipt of the funds.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H44712C4DE6F0477091224393D7531B3E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H7BF6402F6ED34E118358B2F0DA9A3E8D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the Committees on Energy and Commerce and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Environment and Public Works and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report describing—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H6BE01F63F03345168BED5C24B6E73C11"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the implementation of the grant program established under paragraph (1);</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H53040380990741988E7C409CAA80AA9C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the impact of the grant program on improving the ability of each participating State to address environmental justice issues; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HD7B2ECBA1AAA41D7B5E7E6FF3F5AF9D9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the activities carried out by each State to reduce or eliminate disproportionately high and adverse human health or environmental effects on environmental justice communities in the State.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE72118AC40314706BDE835B848580CFF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Administrator shall make the report required under subparagraph (A) available to the public (including by posting a copy of the report on the website of the Environmental Protection Agency).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6B79A68DA076427880D20FB2437089E7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H01CB03B5FE71484EB7CBE4C02A1D20EE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Tribal grant program</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HCABAAE0A7EA5474FA2807E64911C76BD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator shall establish a program under which the Administrator shall provide grants to Tribal Governments to enable the Indian Tribes—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H409865EAE43C45C5831D687DA2B6830F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to establish culturally and linguistically appropriate protocols, activities, and mechanisms for addressing issues relating to environmental justice; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1EB04214B72F43D49C27AA838B2FA9EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to carry out culturally and linguistically appropriate activities to reduce or eliminate disproportionately high and adverse human health or environmental effects on environmental justice communities in Tribal and indigenous communities.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H261D57D1B90D484EA13561D975BB9218"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4E2F92FB24D1417EAAE08328C4BB86B2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), a Tribal Government shall submit to the Administrator an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator may require, including—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H3E274247DAB14959884F78B891DFCB52"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a plan that contains a description of the means by which the funds provided through a grant under paragraph (1) will be used to address issues relating to environmental justice in Tribal and indigenous communities; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HE78D9D0604D34DDCA18EC1F48BC90E3D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assurances that the funds provided through a grant under paragraph (1) will be used only to supplement the amount of funds that the Tribal Government allocates for initiatives relating to environmental justice.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF758F438AF4A464FA7F36D0138883CE0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ability to continue program</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), a Tribal Government shall demonstrate to the Administrator that the Tribal Government has the ability to continue each program that is the subject of funds provided through a grant under paragraph (1) after receipt of the funds.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2725387D668D42C0B7CC858B354E3F0C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4F8C87F560FE485CA3A6EDC8F28188C2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the Committees on Energy and Commerce and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Environment and Public Works and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report describing—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HB045F0264D1A4775BB71933C9C1FE187"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the implementation of the grant program established under paragraph (1);</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HCEB5F622F4A546D18F1E056AE5469161"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the impact of the grant program on improving the ability of each participating Indian Tribe to address environmental justice issues; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H3D8CFF6E34044CDF934BB75CED6398CD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the activities carried out by each Tribal Government to reduce or eliminate disproportionately high and adverse human health or environmental effects on applicable environmental justice communities in Tribal and indigenous communities.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB1C555BF7BA842E8BB4804FAD3498F2A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Administrator shall make the report required under subparagraph (A) available to the public (including by posting a copy of the report on the website of the Environmental Protection Agency).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC0513382A1EB4A5C89D37832C0525E58"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H528192A46EF34AD3A4605DE6951FA4E1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Community-Based participatory research grant program</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H58C0D323EFF04015ABD12CC2E4053E18"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator, in consultation with the Director, shall establish a program under which the Administrator shall provide not more than 25 multiyear grants to eligible entities to carry out community-based participatory research—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H1557C80ADD08421188BF01FAE9625E33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to address issues relating to environmental justice;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFBD8838656164FE59508E2A8E2116CCF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to improve the environment of residents of environmental justice communities; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD94D3AA0629D47308F35907647025D02"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to improve the health outcomes of residents of environmental justice communities.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5CBFEBE89FFB479DA90186C812AE99FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a multiyear grant under paragraph (1), an eligible entity shall be a partnership comprised of—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2FE46403FDB0451C90E2DAC62C83B1CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an accredited institution of higher education; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2B92F538111E4C72AFDFD4AC42EBBE5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a community-based organization.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H64307FADCD884F7490A5CB71F03A6692"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a multiyear grant under paragraph (1), an eligible entity shall submit to the Administrator an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator may require, including—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H6F6873CB913B482FBA3FBC29FA4B3850"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a detailed description of the partnership of the eligible entity that, as determined by the Administrator, demonstrates the participation of members of the community at which the eligible entity proposes to conduct the research; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H18E8A4F55D76419E972E400F6D713AB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H286C37926AA3476CADB8069A367CF656"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the project proposed by the eligible entity; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HDF39C9D2EF5943259D443DCA744605B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the ways by which the project will—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="HB92706F624904E55A54EA7DB93F04CDA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>address issues relating to environmental justice;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H5D65DE861AEE4117AA75DA7AB34AFEBD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>assist in the improvement of health outcomes of residents of environmental justice communities; and</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H54E59C1F93F44C1C829358F36A7F94EF"><enum>(III)</enum><text>assist in the improvement of the environment of residents of environmental justice communities.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H42893A38A75B44D28E66BFBFDD9A5DBB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H5BB8F73CFEE64DCFBCE824882412B80E"><enum>12.</enum><header>Environmental justice basic training program</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H05EF7B9A11E34B869753B2F28BBAB1B8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator shall establish a basic training program to increase the capacity of residents of environmental justice communities to identify and address disproportionately high and adverse human health or environmental effects by providing culturally and linguistically appropriate—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H1EE86E8F74EC49D7B85517C1C26D724A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>training relating to—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HFB9324EFFCEC4273824C2EA696592156"><enum>(A)</enum><text>basic and advanced techniques for the detection, assessment, and evaluation of the effects of hazardous substances on human health;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H03E9C64C98E241088EB1348B19E626C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>methods to assess the risks to human health presented by hazardous substances;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8C5DB02D4401482A82D09BF6BED46EC6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>methods and technologies to detect hazardous substances in the environment; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H758844708AB14958964951C53B44B8F8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>basic biological, chemical, and physical methods to reduce the quantity and toxicity of hazardous substances; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3197881A22BA46C7B9AA41A3748B849F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>short courses and continuation education programs for residents of communities who are located in close proximity to hazardous substances to provide—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H85308ED7166546E698CF65A7E780572C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>education relating to—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HDA236B7D9D3D46EF9927CB6303DD2BD9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the proper manner to handle hazardous substances;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H53211BABAEAE4B4F975B203A61B3BD6C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the management of facilities at which hazardous substances are located (including facility compliance protocols); and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H8E7B493C194444A7A6C0C28C3058C7F3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the evaluation of the hazards that facilities described in clause (ii) pose to human health; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9A85AEF6FF8B405F84DEBBB1B0A8CBEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training on environmental and occupational health and safety with respect to the public health and engineering aspects of hazardous waste control.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H89168DE899B042429A25DFD9BD4A0067"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant program</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HC08AEB9885994C249C156895BA10C070"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>In carrying out the training program, the Administrator may provide grants to, or enter into any contract or cooperative agreement with, an eligible entity to carry out any training or educational activity described in subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA0C9DB05F67E41FC9BAB5B4725378670"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>To be eligible to receive assistance under paragraph (1), an eligible entity shall be an accredited institution of education in partnership with—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC7EE1B8BBD354C05898FE90ED76540C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a community-based organization that carries out activities relating to environmental justice;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H44EE9624916346AFB1AD8CF4CBF8A9BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a generator of hazardous waste;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7E7B8EFCECF54182ABA407F29305D937"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any individual who is involved in the detection, assessment, evaluation, or treatment of environmental waste;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5C7B0EED7BED433BA40D81EF65494442"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any owner or operator of a facility at which hazardous substances are located; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H43C1B3465D1342FD97956218EB2ABFB2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any State government, Tribal Government, or local government.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H25573D174C1D4138BEEBE82D70B1C216"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Plan</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HD3FB6A515CA84464994B7D7E87802876"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in consultation with the Director, shall develop and publish in the Federal Register a plan to carry out the basic training program described in subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6BB5396D0651490E811C978F331FDB9D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The plan described in paragraph (1) shall contain—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H0E5CBE5667ED4737AFDCE909CD721798"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list that describes the relative priority of each activity described in subsection (a); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H07E9406560F640F9B8463CBA7CD6AE45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of research and training relevant to environmental justice issues of communities adversely affected by pollution.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3CE7C789238343D8B46F16E180E9B6BB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination with federal agencies</header><text>The Administrator shall, to the maximum extent practicable, take appropriate steps to coordinate the activities of the training program described in the plan with the activities of other Federal agencies to avoid any duplication of effort.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H32FBA0DFD3AE4C7EA9969B2C0505E6D1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H652C4307BAF5432FA7794C5EB3F278FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the Committees on Energy and Commerce and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Environment and Public Works and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report describing—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H9DC0D791F17F409AAD0E8A12E43C1908"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the implementation of the training program established under subsection (a); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB1082D84A6AB4EB8986E791C465801EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the impact of the training program on improving training opportunities for residents of environmental justice communities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H97ADB18867F947D7A0C70EB7F1974517"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Administrator shall make the report required under paragraph (1) available to the public (including by posting a copy of the report on the website of the Environmental Protection Agency).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H85D5829F1E9B49C48D0E1D37DFEE4D32"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text>
			</subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H4D4EA6724A64484B8DF005645B324786"><enum>13.</enum><header>National Environmental Justice Advisory Council</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H2CEED84035A1404181B2F62992C8BC70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The President shall establish an advisory council to be known as the National Environmental Justice Advisory Council.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H98D47E94CE4245FBBE9041462A8495FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Advisory Council shall be comprised of 26 members who have knowledge of, or experience relating to, the effect of environmental conditions on communities of color, low-income communities, rural communities, and Tribal and indigenous communities, including—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H2349BEFDF44B4B9F8CA3DA05F5D81FC1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>representatives of—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H12441DF26D0C4697B43E99E61755D64C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>community-based organizations that carry out initiatives relating to environmental justice;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4C2729C69AA04AD2910EAA157367937D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>State governments, Tribal Governments, and local governments;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC1298EF39C154D48BC2C3C7EA3B11BFD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Indian Tribes and other indigenous groups;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC7BD6B456C49427D9C3FA1738E596CE4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>nongovernmental and environmental organizations; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF1D41E9D39934DAB9FCADD9E7622AC56"><enum>(E)</enum><text>private sector organizations (including representatives of industries and businesses); and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H06AA3887333F467B92D07121A0EC4CE2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>experts in the fields of—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HDA65E3E166DB408E96BD068E20F4920F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>socioeconomic analysis;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H713409583F0547D493FE038079FF6698"><enum>(B)</enum><text>health and environmental effects;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAB0370021ADF4874BB3EF68A14567D80"><enum>(C)</enum><text>exposure evaluation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H92A84078FB4743ACA30B4202133E1546"><enum>(D)</enum><text>environmental and civil rights law; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HECF49E8A7D4A4DF9A692F2FF5F3E1232"><enum>(E)</enum><text>environmental health science research.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HFD2FBDD86CBF4F3ABDFC45A45FC48F47"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Subcommittees; workgroups</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H2F643EEFDD3D451793B26DAC051A3262"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Advisory Council may establish any subcommittee or workgroup to assist the Advisory Council in carrying out each duty of the Advisory Council described in subsection (d).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEFBA6061D8FD4CD59B17148B41AFD9D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Upon the request of the Advisory Council, each subcommittee or workgroup established by the Advisory Council under paragraph (1) shall submit to the Advisory Council a report that contains—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2838D41549AF478485D06AC43A6EC29A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of each recommendation of the subcommittee or workgroup; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4EAF19346BB24D349BE66F78AC53C145"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any advice requested by the Advisory Council with respect to any duty of the Advisory Council.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H10DB7D82325044558F68707C39495EFB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Advisory Council shall provide independent advice and recommendations to the Environmental Protection Agency with respect to issues relating to environmental justice, including advice—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H8C21B7AA028941B18B5226CB54F24E8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to help develop, facilitate, and conduct reviews of the direction, criteria, scope, and adequacy of the scientific research and demonstration projects of the Environmental Protection Agency relating to environmental justice;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H55987FF410464D72AF735B3A889E3D54"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to improve the participation, cooperation, and communication with respect to such issues—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HBFDE1FEAA81F49D186A2036B7E63F6AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>within the Environmental Protection Agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1E7DA32796B447B5886C173B103AC4A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>between the Environmental Protection Agency and other entities; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD1E2C843AED5454EB9472F6632729F8B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>between, and among, the Environmental Protection Agency and Federal agencies, State, and local governments, Indian Tribes, environmental justice leaders, interest groups, and the public;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H22ECAA1722294F2CB7EBA0387D2C9587"><enum>(3)</enum><text>requested by the Administrator to help improve the response of the Environmental Protection Agency in securing environmental justice for communities of color, low-income communities, rural communities, and Tribal and indigenous communities; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDB425C8B79D746A7A83A300954FD439B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>on issues relating to—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H80ACFA553B4E46A99FB263677F0B751A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the developmental framework of the Environmental Protection Agency with respect to the integration by the Environmental Protection Agency of socioeconomic programs into the strategic planning, annual planning, and management accountability of the Environmental Protection Agency to achieve environmental justice results throughout the Environmental Protection Agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H63A944217CAA4F06B0CC44243501F50E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the measurement and evaluation of the progress, quality, and adequacy of the Environmental Protection Agency in planning, developing, and implementing environmental justice strategies, projects, and programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7483702907624A5599E5F28902188BCA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any existing and future information management systems, technologies, and data collection activities of the Environmental Protection Agency (including recommendations to conduct analyses that support and strengthen environmental justice programs in administrative and scientific areas);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H68471352115A44668ADFC4AF095237FD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the administration by the Administrator of grant programs relating to environmental justice assistance; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H447DC09FB88C42EA848F6B58E1F45559"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the awareness of, and education training, and other outreach activities conducted by, the Environmental Protection Agency relating to environmental justice.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD4C13A8A7ECD4E27883AECBA40C41B82"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Meetings</header>
				<paragraph commented="no" id="HFD5C4C8BF2EB43CF8D515915AF3D6572"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Frequency</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HAF8F8F2354C945B9A0ED981F9D05A8CA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the Advisory Council shall meet biannually.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H402BD91D9F3B48C08C0A855580C8D148"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority of administrator</header><text>The Administrator may require the Advisory Council to conduct additional meetings if the Administrator determines that the conduct of any additional meetings are necessary.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H38E2ACA8692845AD88D2198CD059DA63"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public participation</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA562ED5078C14551A72B831A2902D9F8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), each meeting of the Advisory Council shall be open to the public to provide the public an opportunity—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H54BFA83D3B544068996D323BBD718D01"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to submit comments to the Advisory Council; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H12CF7D90FDEA434F894D112B1D52D801"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to appear before the Advisory Council.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2E1B57BE8F714B70A300C21FCF91C72E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority of Administrator</header><text>The Administrator may close any meeting, or portion of any meeting, to the public.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE28BD3124A39477FAFD4118E4570D01F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>FACA</header><text>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall apply to the Advisory Council.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H856812C7C8D645CB89CE8454570A554C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>The Administrator may provide to any member of the Advisory Council travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for an employee of an agency under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from the home or regular place of business of the member in the performance of the duties of the Advisory Council.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HAFAD8AF0B9CA4403AD5781FD489CF1E0"><enum>14.</enum><header>Environmental Justice Clearinghouse</header>
 <subsection id="H94554425755E4170AD743524183DE71F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall establish an internet-based clearinghouse to be known as the Environmental Justice Clearinghouse.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0EE4D947068845EDAB7058CE21B068D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The Clearinghouse shall be comprised of culturally and linguistically appropriate materials, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFFC8F222FE4F4089A5FAF47352843CB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information describing the activities conducted by the Environmental Protection Agency to address issues relating to environmental justice;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAAB3239727C541C9846B9E79BC291078"><enum>(2)</enum><text>copies of training materials provided by the Administrator to help individuals and employees understand and carry out environmental justice activities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H323EE8FDBAE046199EC1A47CEC10DEDD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>links to web pages that describe environmental justice activities of other Federal agencies;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA76F36D539B04009A90F581BEC566D00"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a directory of individuals who possess technical expertise in issues relating to environmental justice;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H97C7429BA88747C2BFD06678B396EEF1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a directory of nonprofit and community-based organizations that address issues relating to environmental justice at the local, State, and Federal levels (with particular emphasis given to nonprofit and community-based organizations that possess the capability to provide advice or technical assistance to environmental justice communities); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9EF98E827E434AB79670EADC73A0B63F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any other appropriate information as determined by the Administrator.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA733BF04EB2E4239B32ADA3445317408"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing the Clearinghouse, the Administrator shall consult with individuals representing academic and community-based organizations who have expertise in issues relating to environmental justice.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H81EC7A6C7E854AA4A022A0C35A84CE0E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual review</header><text>The Advisory Council shall—</text> <paragraph id="H5CA98A09463B4B4094DA230825C930CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a review of the Clearinghouse on an annual basis; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0BA9C7F5817E4B9AACA5A362B9EB430A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommend to the Administrator any updates for the Clearinghouse that the Advisory Council determines to be necessary for the effective operation of the Clearinghouse.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBB62415FC72349DA998C5976CF4F5C1F"><enum>15.</enum><header>Public meetings</header>
 <subsection id="H87FCA65000A94392B4F9B9C26E9377F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and biennially thereafter, the Administrator shall hold public meetings on environmental justice issues at each regional office of the Environmental Protection Agency to gather public input with respect to the planning of future environmental justice activities of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1A42010A037F4956B1C4DB8F69693D9F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required attendance of certain employees</header><text>In holding a public meeting under subsection (a), the Administrator shall ensure that at least 1 employee of the Environmental Protection Agency at the level of Assistant Administrator is present at the meeting to serve as a representative of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H743CD625AA1A4519BE9FFDF636532719"><enum>16.</enum><header>Supplemental environmental projects for environmental justice communities</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator shall ensure that all supplemental environmental projects developed as part of a settlement relating to violations in an environmental justice community—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCD29F04AF8844428935CE2FF8570E3FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are developed through consultation with, and with the meaningful participation of, individuals from the affected environmental justice community; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H30CBE2B3DE8C40CBB90DCA8C3C0925C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>result in a quantifiable improvement to the health or well-being of individuals in the affected environmental justice community.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H045342E5B7A64E8298C91DC0D1062382"><enum>17.</enum><header>Evaluation by Comptroller General of the United States</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and biennially thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committees on Energy and Commerce and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, and the Committees on Environment and Public Works and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, a report that contains an evaluation of the effectiveness of each activity carried out in accordance with this Act, including, for the period covered by the report, an evaluation of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H775C393C533B4A3E8E4D3E5554616A38"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the ways by which the Working Group has developed and implemented the interagency Federal environmental justice strategy;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H57605EB48F6B4FED953656D8B80BF113"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the ways by which each Federal agency that participates in the Working Group has developed and implemented its environmental justice strategy;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H49DB7B7DFF6E4D978C685EDCEA769516"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the effectiveness of each grant program carried out under this Act; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA1F40C721519488E9F9B9E72DB5142DF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the effectiveness of the Environmental Protection Agency in carrying out the meeting and reporting requirements under this Act.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


