<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD51198E09FFA4668B22EA96B22B00A90" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4324 RH: Strengthening Oversight of Iran’s Access to Finance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 334</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4324</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–452]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-date date="20171109">November 9, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
		</action>
		<action><action-date>December 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000611">Mr. Poliquin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000017">Mr. Zeldin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Thomas J. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action>
			<action-date>December 7, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
			<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
			<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on November 9, 2017</action-instruction>
		</action>
		<action display="yes">
			<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to make certifications with respect to United States and
			 foreign financial institutions’ aircraft-related transactions involving
			 Iran, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H16DCFEAA2CF441EDB08CCA6052765FE2" reported-display-style="italic" style="OLC">
 <section id="HEFAC7723D53C4D1EB1543514AEE2BEE9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Oversight of Iran’s Access to Finance Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H957439B423294DD88AEECC1EDE9F7ABA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HA4AB5A50A0404FADBE15673E1CD5A32B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPOA), informally known as the Iran nuclear deal, the Obama administration agreed to license the sale of commercial passenger aircraft to Iran, the world's foremost state sponsor of terrorism and a jurisdiction of primary money laundering concern.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A11A7E87AD64CBC89AFDAAA446ABF94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In April 2015, prior to the adoption of the JCPOA, Secretary of the Treasury Jacob Lew, in publicly advocating for its provisions, stated: <quote>Make no mistake: deal or no deal, we will continue to use all our available tools, including sanctions, to counter Iran’s menacing behavior. Iran knows that our host of sanctions focused on its support for terrorism and its violations of human rights are not, and have never been, up for discussion.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1FD0C152AA464A4B81EBF2B8DCB76CA0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In March 2016 remarks to the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, Secretary Lew, in reference to U.S. commitments under the JCPOA, stated: <quote>While we have lifted the nuclear sanctions, we continue to enforce sanctions directed at support for terrorism and regional destabilization, and missile and human rights violations.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H18457253CF2E4F77AC244C3810B63653"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In an April 2016 forum at the Council on Foreign Relations, Secretary Lew stated that, under the JCPOA, the U.S. committed to lifting its nuclear sanctions, <quote>but the U.S. financial system is not open to Iran, and that is not something that is going to change</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3F2510DDD33147CE9C36F4616F4B67BD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In September 2016, the Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) issued licenses permitting the export of up to 97 aircraft for use by Iran Air, the Islamic Republic of Iran's flagship state-owned carrier. These licenses included authorization for U.S. financial institutions <quote>to engage in all transactions necessary to provide financing or other financial services</quote> in order to effectuate the sales. In November 2016, OFAC licensed an additional 106 aircraft for purchase by Iran Air, which are also eligible for financing authorized by OFAC.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9B9528483504545AC5A9BE82B874492"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Department of the Treasury had sanctioned Iran Air in 2011 for its use of commercial passenger aircraft to transport rockets, missiles, and other military cargo on behalf of the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) and Iran’s Ministry of Defense and Armed Forces Logistics, both of which had been designated under Executive Order 13382 for weapons proliferation-related activities. In October 2017, the IRGC went on to be designated under Executive Order 13224 for its support of the IRGC-Qods Force, which has provided support to terrorist groups such as Hizballah, Hamas, and the Taliban.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0D3845C1177D45BEA615D5A719442E1F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Among Iran Air’s sanctionable activities, the airline delivered missile or rocket components to the Assad government in Syria, which like Iran is classified as a state sponsor of terrorism.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BF94D72BF6D4C8187A145F35701C10D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Assad regime is responsible for a civil conflict that has claimed an estimated 400,000 lives, including through the government's deployment of chemical weapons and barrel bombs against unarmed civilians and children.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H54FA442E64634D5DAD9AA62B1E4FBC8B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Despite being delisted in 2016, Iran Air has continued to fly known weapons resupply routes to government-controlled areas of Syria. According to research by the Foundation for Defense of Democracies, between Implementation Day of the JCPOA on January 16, 2016, and May 4, 2017, Iran Air operated at least 134 flights to Syria, which included stops in Abadan, Iran, a suspected IRGC logistical hub for airlifts to the Assad regime.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7ADF9D35792846ED9F34EC0F2E3428C3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In November 2016 correspondence to the Chairman of the House Committee on Financial Services, the Department of the Treasury noted that the commitment to delist Iran Air under the JCPOA <quote>does not affect our ability to designate, or re-designate, any Iranian airline that engages in sanctionable activity. The United States retains the ability to designate any individual or entity that engages in sanctionable activities under our authorities targeting conduct outside the scope of the JCPOA, including Iran’s support for terrorism, human rights abuses, ballistic missile program, and other destabilizing activities in the region.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H787E30A566F8417E9C83BB4D0B5186B5"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In April 2017, Iran announced a deal for Aseman Airlines to purchase up to 60 commercial aircraft, a transaction that would require authorization by OFAC. Aseman Airlines’ chief executive officer, Hossein Alaei, has for decades served as a senior member of the IRGC.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H6B2F90BE646247DCAACF2FB28565AB05"><enum>3.</enum><header>Certifications for aircraft-related transactions by United States and foreign financial
			 institutions</header>
 <subsection id="H85FCFB4A689F40389F9B5896404C8AC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after authorizing a transaction by a United States or foreign financial institution in connection with the export or re-export of a commercial passenger aircraft to Iran (or, for an authorization made after January 16, 2016, but before the date of the enactment of this Act, not later than 60 days after such date of enactment), and every 180 days thereafter for the duration of the authorization, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit the report described under subsection (b) to the appropriate congressional committees.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H73463DC142A347FD9E00077E9FF6030B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report with respect to financial institutions’ Iran-related transactions and due diligence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a financial institution and a transaction described under subsection (a), a report is described under this subsection if it contains—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3876C5DDE6F747BC8E95F01BBC12ABB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of financial institutions that, since January 16, 2016, have conducted transactions authorized by the Secretary in connection with the export or re-export of commercial passenger aircraft to Iran;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H63950A0CA1D644F38BC6687E712DA66A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>either—</text> <subparagraph id="H0CD5A4DF3689453A9E36DD7C6B2DE8B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a certification that—</text>
 <clause id="H8B94E2F902B4457182500F28821F2E4A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the transaction does not pose a significant money laundering or terrorism financing risk to the United States financial system;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE956DDFCFBCF41418E86FED2B1A6AE35"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the transaction will not benefit an Iranian person that, since the date that is one year preceding the date of the certification—</text>
 <subclause id="H506287B9C73645CA978DD40A8A25B72C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has knowingly transported items used for the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction, including systems designed in whole or in part for the delivery of such weapons; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3BFF966CC06641F78F59AB8CFADADA2F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has knowingly provided transportation services or material support for, or on behalf of, any person designated under Executive Orders 13224, 13382, or 13572; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H2F8F566D9F324036A47C9B3BE4C6B86D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any financial institution described under subsection (b)(1) has had since the date such authorization was made, or, if the authorization is no longer in effect, had for the duration of such authorization, appropriate policies, procedures, and processes in place to avoid engaging in sanctionable activities that may result from the financial institutions’ exposure to Iran; or</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF06AABA2161E417B8A78FDAB3530E85A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a statement that the Secretary is unable to make the certification described under subparagraph (A) and a notice that the Secretary will, not later than 60 days after the date the determination is submitted to the appropriate congressional committees, issue a report on non-certification described under subsection (c) to the appropriate congressional committees.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H920DF2B4F5A54F839CF067811067AAAC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on non-certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a financial institution and a transaction described under subsection (a), a report on non-certification is described under this subsection if it contains—</text>
 <paragraph id="H53C4AC9C21584958AD1CADD6D3DF9B17"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed explanation for why the Secretary is unable to make the certification described under subsection (b)(2);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6EDDA706E40A4A45B7F5D6889D8739FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a notification of whether the Secretary will—</text> <subparagraph id="H9443741881EE4339B69C40A56C634D78"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not amend the authorization of the transaction with respect to a financial institution, notwithstanding such non-certification;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB337EF600BCD408D9B9F79CBD828F4EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>suspend the authorization until the Secretary is able to make such certification;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5FCD3A4DED64686BE139423EB77A4F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>revoke the authorization; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DAFE7F1D11B41B1B1A52EB1780C55E4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>otherwise amend the authorization; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA5C3217487448F0B04B5647EBC357B0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an explanation of the reasons for any action to be taken described under paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD48493683D4423F8C1124F19EAB8031"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may waive, on a case-by-case basis, the provisions of this Act for up to one year at a time upon certifying to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9FAF5EDD19114C3AB6EE114DF0610A23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Government of Iran has—</text> <subparagraph id="H246C06A622EB4BB294A3484FF8CBE61C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>made substantial progress towards combating money laundering and terrorism financing risk emanating from Iran; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB080102F2A1424C86DAAE112EFD93E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has significantly reduced Iran’s—</text> <clause id="H56AE86A799F94B999EED0F8E23F458A0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>destabilizing activities in the region; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9D11F07ED83F48DBBB7AF329EA6494E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>material support for terrorist groups; or</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H446CC5087EA84F94B392407820008C0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such waiver is important to the national security interests of the United States, with an explanation of the reasons therefor.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A488F8383F9469596438DA39D10BD6E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall cease to be effective on the date that is 30 days after the date on which the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text>
				<paragraph id="HF91994BE59534C13B2D1006DFF2805CD"><enum>(1)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H64F77B7F6634424EBDD68C61701B4922"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary does not find, under section 5318A of title 31, United States Code, that reasonable grounds exist for concluding that Iran is a jurisdiction of primary money laundering concern; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph changed="added" committee-id="HBA00" id="H9148877252D04361956112FBD62AA325" indent="up1" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Iran has ceased providing support for acts of international terrorism; or</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H858F277162EA4163AA3309801BBF94FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>terminating the provisions of this section is vital to the national security interests of the United States, with an explanation of the reasons therefor.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1012F0FE17264421A7B30B8A2540DED2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="HDE64A16F73264B498B44C711F4D8ADE8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the committees on Financial Services and Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the committees on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H804209A9109F4F60839207214470FF84"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Financial institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>financial institution</quote> means a United States financial institution or a foreign financial institution.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA237EEF154C944C2989352630EDF8042"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign financial institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>foreign financial institution</quote> has the meaning given that term under section 561.308 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED9DBB4575014E9A942FDF5766B3FFFF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>knowingly</quote>, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H640E5FEF73EB4F669F95A96FA46D6ADB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Treasury.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H554AEE32C0474CCFBFF03C3A916BDD65"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United States financial institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>United States financial institution</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>U.S. financial institution</quote> under section 561.309 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>December 7, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the
			 Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


