<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5160D7B5C6EE4AF58F36F6C6EAB9209A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2867 IH: Job Opportunities Between our Shores Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2867</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170608">June 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to establish a pilot program to facilitate
			 education and training programs in the field of advanced manufacturing.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H61B5AE139EE84C1781E6401319C3ECB7" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC2CCF37A7C2940FE92DBD7198AECCB7A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Job Opportunities Between our Shores Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>JOBS Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBDDE99BCAE1E42428EF500DAF371A715"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program to support advanced manufacturing workforce development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 169 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86245C4F86F24FC9A3A6BC9A73AE641F" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="HC99FF16A1FFA4B658987E62F03803CAB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Advanced manufacturing workforce development program</header>
 <paragraph id="H0318CFEDB1B6457E9C7E56E343ED53CB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under a plan published under subsection (b), the Secretary shall, through grants or contracts, carry out demonstration and pilot projects for the purpose of facilitating education and training programs in the field of advanced manufacturing. Such projects shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H56D32BF0049D40949C6B9B8F1061BE16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>target skills and competency development in communities with expected growth in advanced manufacturing;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80B622A5551C4E5192FFBC2CC184D54E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide education and training for available jobs or job openings that are anticipated in advanced manufacturing which result in an industry-recognized and nationally portable credential, including an educational certificate or degree, an occupational license, an industry-sponsored certificate or certification, as well as a registered apprenticeship certificate or degree;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H612D8B7174E24268B19B83E17AFD5AF3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>educate individuals about opportunities for career advancement within advanced manufacturing; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H369BEBBD0427448A812203B0387A5F65"><enum>(D)</enum><text>give priority to incumbent workers, dislocated workers, and unemployed individuals.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC36B39BE4BFD407AA21564A196343DC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header>
 <subparagraph id="H64CBB12AB89148BD84081549AA462FE8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following entities in any of the several States or territories, in partnership with a manufacturer who employs individuals with advanced manufacturing skills, shall be eligible to receive a grant or be party to a contract under a project established under paragraph (1):</text>
 <clause id="H1A60BD08345E4CFBBF0E1E86411A6234"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual community or technical college, such as a public community college, a nonprofit community college, a tribally controlled college, or a tribally controlled university.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HF2580015E03540409F0CEB8E59E6A2B7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A community college district.</text> </clause><clause id="H1B284A6C69FA4B73BBFB17ADC62FA67A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A State community college system.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H138FB308494542F6B2BD7E2F02537729"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A local workforce investment board, in partnership with one or more one-stop career centers, that specifies one or more community or technical colleges where education and training activities will occur.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA04312B85F294953B419806B2828FE60"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Other entity that would serve educationally underserved communities.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC1DD0BFA176489AB311B69B530BDBF2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall give priority to any consortia of the entities described in subparagraph (A) that leverage substantial non-Federal funding for the program.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8F346DA1B0A4D0189B91B12688FFB3A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Applications from eligible entities described in paragraph (2) shall be submitted at such time and in such form and manner as the Secretary shall determine, but shall include the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCE7DF97A732346E18F06CE9913431050"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the eligible entity or entities, evidence of each eligible entity’s capacity to carry out activities in support of the strategic objectives described in paragraph (1), a description of the expected participation and responsibilities of the eligible entity, or each of the eligible entities in the case of a consortium.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3726331DF4A4033876FF0C075A19CFD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of education and training activities to be provided that will—</text> <clause id="HA11CDCECA06849929821277A35F1D92E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>develop skills and competencies demanded by advanced manufacturing firms;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA107943F60C6446DA7AF508F196E011B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>lead to an employer- or industry-recognized credential; and</text> </clause><clause id="H4BE288B478FC4CD8933CDA3F496A06AA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>educate individuals about opportunities for career advancement and wage growth within advanced manufacturing.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF92C08B6FAB04524A019DFD632421FC4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how the economy where the entity resides would benefit, including—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HC180C54A559448C29C724C997797E31A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>evidence of the growth of advanced manufacturing in State or locality;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HAC698C04CB414F50A076CEDB8BB61612"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the potential for additional job growth with investments in advanced manufacturing; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H597ECFD2697D4CF59F25DB7B46478F87"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>exposure of incumbent or dislocated workers to new advanced manufacturing technology skill sets.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56C2988CE79144D9BE348035971C5C97"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how the eligible entity would employ evidence-based training models that integrate academic instruction with training, including on-the-job training in advanced manufacturing to meet performance goals described in paragraph (6).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38CC69516B2A41478EBACD7191BEBEA2"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how the eligible entity will coordinate with State or local workforce investment boards and State or local economic development officials.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB32C9BA75FDB4530938076FBFB3F95B4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>Activities to be carried out under a project funded under paragraph (1) may include—</text> <subparagraph id="HD2209BD231DB446D865044C3270D0424"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">classroom and on-site experiential learning;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66B8C22B54CC46DB82C6D80B14C2AF7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on-the-job training;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8BB84D337044D69AE4C19601B0A9D3A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>training which fits into an industry-recognized competency model for advanced manufacturing;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD29C76A45F25431C97A648BBF316D3A6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>development and implementation of registered apprenticeship and pre-apprenticeship programs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3569F92F1968491B9A0B432DB84C5730"><enum>(E)</enum><text>coordination with local workforce investment boards implementing and utilizing existing articulation agreements with universities and other educational partners;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8BBE31F8C5640B789A5C12D9E7986CE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>distance learning; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5ABD3840E290452DA8D6474F14A6F9CC"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any other activity the Secretary considers appropriate for training in advanced manufacturing.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AF0F4A8993B4C8597EB7D48D2C2B5A9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Performance goals and measures</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC73898597E2C49FAA7F0C1948CBFBA31"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Goals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The goals of the activities described in paragraph (4) shall be to—</text> <clause id="HE5F913805DB140D58E057B824D52C792"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhance the skill-sets of incumbent workers who live in communities with expected growth in advanced manufacturing, and for such workers to obtain an industry-recognized and nationally portable credential including an educational certificate or degree;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF2606FE2671E45BC8607B822F6F212D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>develop competencies for individuals with limited experience in advanced manufacturing;</text> </clause><clause id="HD2C0A2AD13474C1982A5324B1358F929"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>strengthen community college partnerships with advanced manufacturing firms in an effort to meet firms’ needs for adaptability in training of incumbent workers;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7E09FD4134A54F668A71297346327E4F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>strengthen partnerships with local workforce investment boards and, if applicable, local education agencies; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H28A712BC5AEB40F49A9BCDFD470D5088"><enum>(v)</enum><text>help incumbent workers develop skills which lead to greater earnings.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CEEBB0171B646C99815666D2C078A48"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Measures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall negotiate and reach agreement with the eligible entities that receive grants and assistance under this subsection on performance measures that will be used to evaluate the performance of the eligible entity in carrying out the activities described in paragraph (4). Each performance measure shall consist of such an indicator of performance and may include—</text>
 <clause id="H9283DC68669147B785E96C3FC94F7926"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of workers, including dislocated workers and unemployed individuals, receiving employer- or industry-recognized credentials;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H21D2CB642F40465FB8091535D12C1BD0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of workers, including dislocated workers and unemployed individuals, attaining basic skills, as described in an industry-recognized and nationally portable competency model for advanced manufacturing;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H687FE826DA0C467E812590E14A07C54D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of incumbent workers whose training meets employer’s worker-skill needs to enhance operations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5794AF9F19FA45FCA2A6D3AC83164507"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>earnings growth as a result of additional training provided through partnership; and</text> </clause><clause id="H718AA1416A834831A7C65B6365B4A456"><enum>(v)</enum><text>other measures the Secretary determines necessary to meet goals described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H315E30C3183444A1908A48D588C22B38"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 1 year after the date of the first disbursement of funds under this subsection, the Secretary shall provide for the continuing evaluation of the programs funded under this subsection, as required by section 172, and shall transmit a report of the evaluation to Congress not later than 2 years after such date.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HE8503CCE02754B99A657163D4DD42253"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall take effect as if enacted as part of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3101">29 U.S.C. 3101</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


