<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3B15CC12045C42B19107A0B353E787A7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1025 IH: Eyes on the Courts Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1025</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170213">February 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for media coverage of Federal appellate court proceedings, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HB3B2FC35E63A45B78E62BC11425D6670" style="OLC">
 <section id="H181D9FE3C6744CF0ACBE7362036D2881" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Eyes on the Courts Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD98B95C151824FDE861FD6B96DD1F14E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Media coverage in Federal appellate court proceedings</header> <subsection id="H68B72061E14C480399D2A7C5BCF087DC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="H178AAF1F5EE1438081DEEB0FFAB1426E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Presiding judge</header><text>The term <term>presiding judge</term> means the judge presiding over a proceeding in an appellate court of the United States. In proceedings in which more than one judge participates, the presiding judge shall be the senior active judge so participating or, in the case of a circuit court of appeals, the senior active circuit judge so participating, except that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H646D0FAF19AB48738F434DCDBBE7B4BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in en banc sittings of any United States circuit court of appeals, the presiding judge shall be the chief judge of the circuit whenever the chief judge participates; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FAF75AE2553427FB853BF3C592F294F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in en banc sittings of the Supreme Court of the United States, the presiding judge shall be the Chief Justice whenever the Chief Justice participates.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B40FD3D60F94BDE9EC54FC398C27279"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appellate court of the United States</header><text>The term <term>appellate court of the United States</term> means any United States circuit court of appeals and the Supreme Court of the United States.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA9959B9527746C2828994C2AE118A4E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Media coverage of court proceedings</header> <paragraph id="H314A075F63A2481282B0C754AC02AC2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The presiding judge in a proceeding of an appellate court of the United States shall permit the photographing, electronic recording, audio-visual coverage, broadcasting, televising, or streaming in real time or near-real time on the Internet of that proceeding to or for the public, unless—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7350E78CBD7143A2B4B4EBA10D3E8313"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the presiding judge determines in writing, on the motion of any party to the proceeding or sua sponte, that allowing such photographing, recording, broadcasting, televising, or streaming would violate the due process rights of a party to the proceeding or is otherwise not in the interests of justice; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8469C4B599E4ADD881B6AE997987A44"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the determination under paragraph (1) is published at least 72 hours before the proceeding begins.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H627BA7E4639D476C9030A265BC8D2D95"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interlocutory appeals barred</header><text>The determination of a presiding judge under paragraph (1)(A) may not be challenged through an interlocutory appeal.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB25EA9147CBC400DBA583DE77A795A7B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>The Judicial Conference of the United States may promulgate guidelines with respect to the management and administration of photographing, recording, broadcasting, televising, or streaming described under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC8E8190A9BC54E8284DFDC848414B05D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>In the interests of justice and fairness, the presiding judge of each appellate court of the United States may promulgate rules and disciplinary measures for the courtroom use of any form of media or media equipment and the acquisition or distribution of any of the images or sounds obtained in the courtroom. The presiding judge may also require written acknowledgment of the rules by anyone individually or on behalf of any entity before being allowed to acquire any images or sounds from the courtroom.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2575D8C44EF84D06801DC6896BCE7D6A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This Act shall apply with respect to any proceeding in an appellate court of the United States that begins on or after the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


