<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5A99F906F76B4AB095C6FC425EA6D130" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4358 IH: Missed Opportunities in Low Income Housing Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4358</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170217">November 9, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis of Georgia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Commissioner of Internal Revenue to report on applications for tax credits under the
			 low-income housing tax credit program that, in the preceding fiscal year,
			 were approved but not allocated.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H7F67B8575B434773BF8AA49C92471BEA" style="OLC">
 <section id="H4EB6E6B879F04DC4BCE4793EE979BECC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Missed Opportunities in Low Income Housing Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="idDA45BFF2B4044E6AA225E3F2DD5525F5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on applications for low-income housing tax credit program that were approved but not allocated</header> <subsection id="idD01FE5F9087D488DB2E102F6223DE1FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than December 31 of each fiscal year, the Commissioner of the Internal Revenue Service shall submit a report to the Congress on applications for tax credits under the low-income housing tax credit program that, in the preceding fiscal year, were approved but not allocated credits.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id2D387C6212CF4913B2CD1C9CE739A30C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report required by subsection (a) shall specify each of the following:</text> <paragraph id="id07F0A86C3F1043E6A574FE201864BBE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of applications for tax credits under the low-income housing tax credit program that were approved by State Housing Finance Agencies but not allocated credits.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id3DDBCB188DB14AB191042FECDE8E35B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The total number of apartment buildings, apartment units, single family dwellings, duplexes, and townhouses proposed in applications that were approved by State Housing Finance Agencies but did not receive an allocation of low-income housing tax credit program credits.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6153B4B90A3D44C48A2FB838080D4F6B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The total number of people who could have taken residency in units proposed by approved applications that did not receive tax credits.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4E0912395E8B40DEA7990E76D189C2FC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="id8F4CDA68A66448BEB4079071DAF89D2F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>low-income housing tax credit program</term> means the low-income housing tax credit program as authorized under section 252 of the Tax Reform Act of 1986 to provide an incentive for the development and rehabilitation of affordable rental housing.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


