<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD47845119473400B8326F0CF3937CBBB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1907 IH: Election Infrastructure and Security Promotion Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1907</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170405">April 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Maxine Waters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to conduct research and development to mitigate the
			 consequences of threats to voting systems, to amend the Help America Vote
			 Act of 2002 to require the voting systems used in elections for Federal
			 office to comply with national standards developed by the National
			 Institute of Standards and Technology for operational security and ballot
			 verification, to establish programs to promote research in innovative
			 voting system technologies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HBA1EB838A5DE4E19AC1344CA1CB4297D" style="OLC">
		<section id="H98F6A7889D8B413B89BBBB0AE3656F20" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H7A99ECFBD8DB47FD9441BD0CF597AAFB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Election Infrastructure and Security Promotion Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H8CEEFBD172C742A997DF226AAA3F48AE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H98F6A7889D8B413B89BBBB0AE3656F20" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H23018F689ED943F4ABC5436A15907F62" level="title">Title I—Election Infrastructure and Security</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB161F04BB5FD4DEB9698B035AF8FBD9B" level="section">Sec. 101. Definition of critical infrastructure.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H001674254DB640F8A5A1415F95920401" level="section">Sec. 102. Designation of voting systems as critical infrastructure.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4F9AE97041A64777B629F5F227F24590" level="section">Sec. 103. Voting system threat and research and development.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H1635AF82FD834366ACFE400B9E9B2AA5" level="title">Title II—National Standards for Voting System Security</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HDA1A8F2B884D49E985EE65448CF964AC" level="section">Sec. 201. Development of standards.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H11AF366135B048A3835BAC21DD539949" level="section">Sec. 202. Requiring States to comply with standards in administration of elections for Federal
			 office.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H04B2BEE4121341F3874A37304228610B" level="section">Sec. 203. Incorporation of standards into certification and testing of voting systems.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H50FBE30D3D154DADB581A3AD3432DD70" level="title">Title III—National Standards for Transparency and Verification of Ballot Counting</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H89672A0AA7424810B073081212AE24B1" level="section">Sec. 301. Development of standards.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H40E84354C8C540399A9024AA8F3B2C9E" level="section">Sec. 302. Requiring States to comply with standards in administration of elections for Federal
			 office.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H19A3140751AA4B3B83EA998B2FA28BC6" level="title">Title IV—Research and Development</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H3AF22B4BDCCA4735B7639E3FCDE41E0D" level="section">Sec. 401. Innovative election technology research and development.</toc-entry></toc>
			</subsection></section><title id="H23018F689ED943F4ABC5436A15907F62"><enum>I</enum><header>Election Infrastructure and Security</header>
 <section id="HB161F04BB5FD4DEB9698B035AF8FBD9B"><enum>101.</enum><header>Definition of critical infrastructure</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title, the term <term>critical infrastructure</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1016 of the Critical Infrastructure Protection Act of 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5195c">42 U.S.C. 5195c(e)</external-xref>).</text>
 </section><section id="H001674254DB640F8A5A1415F95920401"><enum>102.</enum><header>Designation of voting systems as critical infrastructure</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Assistant Secretary of the National Protection and Programs Directorate, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB8230707024B4D7399439A14C2E84F62"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designate voting systems used in the United States as critical infrastructure;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEED013C9E9A4426CB15DCC232974016E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include threats of compromise, disruption, or destruction of voting systems in national planning scenarios; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C1F002A89594666A753120A24CC48A6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conduct a campaign to proactively educate local election officials about the designation of voting systems as critical infrastructure and election officials at all levels of government of voting system threats.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="H4F9AE97041A64777B629F5F227F24590"><enum>103.</enum><header>Voting system threat and research and development</header>
 <subsection id="H9F1D071261E54E339EABF22872B25D35"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In furtherance of local election official preparedness and response, the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Under Secretary for Science and Technology, and in consultation with other relevant agencies and departments of the Federal Government and relevant State and local election official operators of election infrastructure, shall conduct research and development to mitigate the consequences of voting systems threats.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE52828ACEA1A4807B698F7CB5BBDC247"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The scope of the research and development under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HBD47FDA23EC2400E9A5C3BB84DCD44B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An objective scientific analysis of the risks to critical election infrastructures from a range of threats.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H388F30362AAD478788CD89B4184BAB81"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Determination of the voting system assets and infrastructures that are at risk from intrusion, compromise, disruption or destruction.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BE6DA5C88734797990EDA7CE2D7E054"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An evaluation of emergency planning and response technologies that would address the findings and recommendations of experts, including those of a Commission to Assess the Threat to the United States from election administration or voting system attack.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1188BDB5C05247409689B95DA07BF98C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An analysis of technology options that are available to improve the resiliency of critical infrastructure to voting system threats.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H84AC0D6D075E48B2A4639FEA589D3D3B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The restoration and recovery capabilities of critical infrastructure under differing levels of damage and disruption.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H533CDD9042E54B75A506124BF14A5FC5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Comprehensive plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H711B373A95D4469B9C34EBC92EC08CAC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a comprehensive plan to protect and prepare the critical infrastructure of the voting systems used in the United States against threats, including from acts of terrorism.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4291FFC4017249708B7448EB08E881AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Plan requirements</header><text>The comprehensive plan shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HABEFDC1760FD4E4BAE77A6CA1CF77943"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be based on findings of the research and development conducted under subsection (a);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EBA6722056E422A97C74519FB41D67B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be developed in consultation with the relevant Federal sector-specific agencies (as defined under Homeland Security Presidential Directive for critical infrastructures); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1C730144D20457D9EF29EC210523F95"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be developed in consultation with State and local election officials.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE9585F4F884496F8EDD7EFB80202E39"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Secretary shall update the plan required under this subsection biennially.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H1635AF82FD834366ACFE400B9E9B2AA5"><enum>II</enum><header>National Standards for Voting System Security</header>
			<section id="HDA1A8F2B884D49E985EE65448CF964AC"><enum>201.</enum><header>Development of standards</header>
 <subsection id="HFAFAA894097A446E91987F4246979089"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall develop standards for ensuring the operational security of the voting systems used in elections for Federal office, including the physical and cybersecurity of such systems and security requirements for the personnel who operate such systems.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB880188E60984A65B754F96BDFAD190A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of Standards</header><text>In developing standards under this title, the Director shall ensure the following:</text> <paragraph id="H594DCA274B2F4AA7AD4CBB64DEB6C59F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The standards shall set forth specific, evidence-based security requirements for the operation of each individual component of voting systems, including components for marking ballots, scanning ballots, aggregating vote tallies from vote counters, and electronic poll books.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2AB07734DDEC42618592D15BDF872B8F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The standards shall set forth specific, evidence-based requirements for the interoperability of the components, based on data standards established by the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H245268E429E340E38CE8814F470F7AB2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>No system or device upon which ballots or votes are cast or tabulated shall be connected to the Internet at any time through any publicly accessible network.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H692A0DB7F21345D5B028AE945E137320"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No system or device upon which ballots or votes are cast or tabulated shall contain, use, or be accessible by any wireless, power-line, or concealed communication device.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E2F2F888A664EC4B554355C75390E8A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadline; updates</header>
 <paragraph id="H358F8A93662B4D388E179DD7EBA560E6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Deadline for initial standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall develop the standards under this title not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3199636A4854FB7B85DDB895D30D6ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Director may update the standards under this title at such times as the Director considers appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H11AF366135B048A3835BAC21DD539949"><enum>202.</enum><header>Requiring States to comply with standards in administration of elections for Federal office</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 301(a) of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21081">52 U.S.C. 21081(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B61CE26F13846A8B63DEE10EFD15545" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HB55291EC365F4FB9BA5B7F4353166133"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Compliance with security standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In operating the voting system, the State shall comply with the applicable standards developed by the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology under title II of the Election Infrastructure and Security Promotion Act of 2017 for ensuring the operational security of voting systems.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H04B2BEE4121341F3874A37304228610B"><enum>203.</enum><header>Incorporation of standards into certification and testing of voting systems</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 231(a) of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20971">52 U.S.C. 20971(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2F97D684B5B451AB86A8A88AA763E3F" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HFB9586920A0E4E448293354A9995CA7A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ensuring compliance with operational security standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The testing and certification of voting system hardware and software carried out under this subtitle shall test whether voting systems are in compliance with the applicable standards developed by the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology under title II of the Election Infrastructure and Security Promotion Act of 2017 for ensuring the operational security of voting systems, including testing whether the components of voting systems meet the component-specific security requirements and the system interoperability requirements under such standards.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="H50FBE30D3D154DADB581A3AD3432DD70"><enum>III</enum><header>National Standards for Transparency and Verification of Ballot Counting</header>
			<section id="H89672A0AA7424810B073081212AE24B1"><enum>301.</enum><header>Development of standards</header>
 <subsection id="HD5ED4D485E1D460E825625B29EBC2C0D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall develop standards for ensuring that the process by which ballots are counted in elections for Federal office is transparent and permits voters to verify that votes in such elections are counted correctly.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H748ACD4CA80B41EBB0155B5F92D08886"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of standards</header><text>In developing standards under this title, the Director shall ensure the following:</text> <paragraph id="HA025842D37E944B699FA001423C8C6FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Election officials will provide the public with sufficient evidence to verify the results of an election for Federal office, including through the establishment of tracking procedures that permit members of the public to track the ballots counted in the election, so long as such procedures ensure the anonymity of the individuals who cast the ballots.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE745922E92574FE3B5624AE5DCE007F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>All of the data used or produced by the relevant components of a voting system used in an election for Federal office.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCA38755B60E44C45A53A2CDA7F131A10"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Election officials shall make all of the relevant components of a voting system used in an election for Federal office available to other parties (such as other officials of the State, research organizations, and institutions of higher education) to duplicate the testing procedures used to certify the use of the system for use in such elections.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H965DE8D6F905444C8CA80C8DB65F0B06"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadline; updates</header>
 <paragraph id="H46D88A6AF99C4139B8D2E734468FE0EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Deadline for initial standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall develop the standards under this title not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDCA17E376E744885B2C3BCFBF5D20E2B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Director may update the standards under this title at such times as the Director considers appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD87B125E9D2448C49C12071F9593F613"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relevant components defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>relevant components</term> means, with respect to a voting system, each component of the system which is involved with counting ballots and producing a tally of the ballots cast, including the source code, build tools, build procedure documentation, test plans, test fixtures, and software and hardware specifications.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H40E84354C8C540399A9024AA8F3B2C9E"><enum>302.</enum><header>Requiring States to comply with standards in administration of elections for Federal office</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 301(a) of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21081">52 U.S.C. 21081(a)</external-xref>), as amended by section 202, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11F64BF20CD24AF9871D8315B7689896" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H0C91EE74219B471995FC0F7B36AF07EE"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Compliance with transparency and ballot verification standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In operating the voting system, the State shall comply with the applicable standards developed by the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology under title III of the Election Infrastructure and Security Promotion Act of 2017 for ensuring that the process by which ballots are counted in elections for Federal office is transparent and permits voters to verify that votes in such elections are counted correctly.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="H19A3140751AA4B3B83EA998B2FA28BC6"><enum>IV</enum><header>Research and Development</header>
			<section id="H3AF22B4BDCCA4735B7639E3FCDE41E0D"><enum>401.</enum><header>Innovative election technology research and development</header>
 <subsection id="H1CA12ACC517F49C3B0F3C4D31123A351"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Science Foundation, in cooperation with the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, shall establish an election technology innovation research and development program. Such program—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8F9FD64EF05C4629BE1F5CD3E593088E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall support the development of hardware and software technologies and systems for marking ballots, scanning ballots, aggregating tallies from counters, and electronic poll books; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H76DE78BBBEB14E718B9C530004D96C40"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may also support research and development on other elements of technology for voting, election administration, auditing, and other election-critical operations.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA846EBD237BA417CA060348DED9627E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The National Science Foundation shall, to the extent practicable and in consultation with the Election Assistance Commission and the National Institute of Standards and Technology, ensure that technologies developed through assistance provided under this section—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB052AA60D69544E9A584456DA2885125"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conform to any applicable standards and guidelines for design and for data interoperability established by the National Institute of Standards and Technology; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC3F96D8F88524F6897BB0CCE736C3C57"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are made available for use by Federal, State, and local governments at no cost.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

