<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H97DE884F8C3146538277AE97B624884D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3905 IH: Minnesota’s Economic Rights in the Superior National Forest Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3905</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171002">October 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000258">Mr. Peterson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000587">Mr. Lewis of Minnesota</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require congressional approval of any mineral withdrawal or monument designation involving the
			 National Forest System lands in the State of Minnesota, to provide for the
			 renewal of certain mineral leases in such lands, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5AB4983211D5498E84AAAF0D70E55760" style="OLC">
 <section id="H310378DCF9AB41789314F7763D7E0034" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Minnesota’s Economic Rights in the Superior National Forest Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H1EE5113E7FE4428FA8E1EB6F669017EA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Condition on mineral withdrawal of National Forest System lands in Minnesota</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Minerals within the National Forest System lands in the State of Minnesota shall not be subject to withdrawal from disposition under United States mineral and geothermal leasing law unless the withdrawal is specifically approved by an Act of Congress enacted after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </section><section id="H6BDF6CC817E54FC2BA2EF448D0FCC444"><enum>3.</enum><header>Condition on monument designation on National Forest System lands in Minnesota</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 320301 of title 54, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA8598E5F0A247D5B7DAF8FCB7154780" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H3FA3B62452B64C1A8EA08EE67D959D94"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation on extension or establishment of a national monument in Minnesota</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No extension or establishment of national monuments on National Forest System lands in the State of Minnesota may be undertaken except by express authorization of Congress.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="HDCF28B796ED74CBE82C148F35C940BBE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Clarifying the nature of mineral rights on Forest System lands in Minnesota</header>
			<subsection id="H96FEF6105255430396FD955B868F2EEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mineral leases issued within Forest System lands in Minnesota</header>
 <paragraph id="H7A7F0C1E298C4C199F08B161AF0CAEC9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All mineral leases issued within the exterior boundaries of National Forest System lands in the State of Minnesota under the authority of the Act of June 30, 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/508b">16 U.S.C. 508b</external-xref>), or section 402 of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1946 (5 U.S.C. App.), are indeterminate preference right leases that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF7311489E646431AB3E4E1CB3F07FE38"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be issued for an initial 20-year period; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7A4378B8902457794379E846B6E2BEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as provided in paragraph (2), shall be renewable after the period described in subparagraph (A) for 10-year renewal periods.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H29435561D39940E993DD8C2EFD151813"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements for renewal</header><text>A lease shall be renewed under paragraph (1)(B)—</text> <subparagraph id="H9184C40BECC5400BA0F013BE832E9381"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the lessee has complied with the terms and conditions of the lease during the preceding lease period; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32F636911FBD49FDB830200E0EEB6109"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on the condition that, at the end of each ten-year renewal period, such reasonable readjustment of the terms and conditions of the lease may be prescribed by the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, for the purpose of—</text>
 <clause id="HFF69C065CC7241E19A70EA42843EC767"><enum>(i)</enum><text>encouraging production; or</text> </clause><clause id="HF05720F63FF440C3BDCECCAB0CE2C377"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>addressing changing conditions within the lease area.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE10E8EF72BA6409498FF596E624CDAB4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Suspension of operations</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior may suspend operations under a lease described in subsection (a) when—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0F400456A6BE47C9BAB08DD76C4256BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the lease can only be operated at a loss due to market conditions; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H60B137DDA36847E696AE941C290108F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>operations are interrupted by strikes.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77D6D51C2AF7479DA75403DE3E291C09"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Permits for use of surface lands</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to lands subject to a lease pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, may issue permits for the use of surface lands not included in the lease for purposes connected with, and reasonably necessary to, the exploration, development, and use of the deposits covered by the lease.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4BE70032072B4D4FB2AC5B4DF9C00177"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability to mineral leases</header><text>This section shall apply with respect to all mineral leases described in subsection (a), including—</text> <paragraph id="HBD41030C8E294DE2821A3EFC51676C17"><enum>(1)</enum><text>leases that on the date of the enactment of this section are not in effect; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE6CFB7241B74A1197AB6A742B33AC80"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the hard rock mineral leases for the Superior National Forest in Minnesota identified as MNES–01352 and MNES–01353.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H842BCF2498FF44EEBDCC1CA598231B51"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicability of National Environmental Policy Act of 1969</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4331">42 U.S.C. 4331</external-xref> et seq.) shall apply with respect to a mineral lease described in subsection (a). In the case of the renewal of the existing hard rock mineral leases referred to in subsection (d)(2), the Bureau of Land Management shall complete the pending environmental assessment no later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H349D4DBA2EC64D8C9B5553FB3929D23B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exclusion of Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed as permitting the prospecting for development and utilization of mineral resources within the Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness or Mine Protection Area.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


