<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H47FE6C2E81D448E5A459AD59546A9DBB" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2913 IH: Mental Health in Schools Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2913</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170615">June 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to revise and extend projects relating to children and
			 violence to provide access to school-based comprehensive mental health
			 programs.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H2618B6B292CC427589F85C22919491D8" style="OLC">
 <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E686AA99E884721BBCA537BB0113BAB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mental Health in Schools Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD262A0D3AC954E96A824CFCD7C7D2AE0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the purpose of this Act to—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8661C612B204400F835B0D2F0040B9A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>revise, increase funding for, and expand the scope of the Project AWARE State Educational Agency Grant Program carried out by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in order to provide access to more comprehensive school-based mental health services and supports;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25940401331545AAB58D1ED782B7FB79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide for comprehensive staff development for school and community service personnel working in the school; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD1AD95319574AFC9C1F6D414C1C0DB4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide for comprehensive training for children with mental health disorders, for parents, siblings, and other family members of such children, and for concerned members of the community.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H0CA9C6A7BF1E4C1A8CF02808D08164E7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Amendments to the Public Health Service Act</header>
 <subsection id="H7E1307B315214C7AA247A1CC56ACA58E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Technical amendments</header><text>The second part G (relating to services provided through religious organizations) of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290kk">42 U.S.C. 290kk</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD05FB0F0559E47D0B48ED852D5D7B17F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating such part as part J; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H94422B832C174ED48050B16A3E24D5BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating sections 581 through 584 as sections 596 through 596C, respectively.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C08DA092EEA489C90197EBEC99F00CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>School-Based mental health and children and violence</header><text>Section 581 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290hh">42 U.S.C. 290hh</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC127D7062D5E43A092621118E16D4BA4" style="OLC"> <section id="H420245D286EA444ABB1C5B8C6B779D17"><enum>581.</enum><header>School-based mental health and children and violence</header> <subsection id="HB1C53B7EAC7A4D4BB4543DD929652720"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in collaboration with the Secretary of Education and in consultation with the Attorney General, shall, directly or through grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements awarded to eligible entities described in subsection (c), assist local communities and schools (including schools funded by the Bureau of Indian Education) in applying a public health approach to mental health services both in schools and in the community. Such approach should provide comprehensive age appropriate services and supports, be linguistically and culturally appropriate, be trauma-informed, and incorporate age appropriate strategies of positive behavioral interventions and supports. A comprehensive school mental health program funded under this section shall assist children in dealing with trauma and violence.</text>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H148F07AEAADB4B5CA1A9818BC08C10A8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>Under the program under subsection (a), the Secretary may—</text> <paragraph id="H8A4280001C8C4FD8B9EA7787DA8A21C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide financial support to enable local communities to implement a comprehensive culturally and linguistically appropriate, trauma-informed, and age-appropriate, school-based mental health program that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HC85AEA31C33A4C3E91EBAED0482A8691"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">builds awareness of trauma;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34ACD399DD7B4CA6B77390B1FE553AC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">trains appropriate staff to identify signs of trauma or mental health disorders; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE18A0AD91C504BBFB67081F2619834F0"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incorporates positive behavioral interventions, family engagement, student treatment, and multi-generational supports to foster the health and development of children;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H49198600365E47CFB0CC11779879494D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to local communities with respect to the development of programs described in paragraph (1);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6882E5007BFC4F218B00E85117D90DEB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide assistance to local communities in the development of policies to address child and adolescent trauma and mental health issues and violence when and if it occurs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD617BDED94EA457682E5E013A06466DB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>facilitate community partnerships among families, students, law enforcement agencies, education systems, mental health and substance use disorder service systems, family-based mental health service systems, child welfare agencies, health care service systems (including primary care physicians), faith-based programs, trauma networks, and other community-based systems; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BC766258A0E486C9C62DF7A4902F045"><enum>(5)</enum><text>establish mechanisms for children and adolescents to report incidents of violence or plans by other children, adolescents, or adults to commit violence.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4A84B8AF1CF6456D99DE698BC8181793"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="HA95897B5956B4AC2900D35BE8C640785"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under subsection (a), an entity shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H34C718DCC76A4662B5F855F1D71B1BEC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be a partnership that—</text> <clause id="H033098D64DE242359B4222585C7615D5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall include a State educational agency and one or more local educational agencies, with a local educational agency serving as the lead partner; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HFD83A494405C4085BD5C9D9940D67C98"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may include, in accordance with paragraph (2)(A)(i), appropriate public or private entities that use evidence-based interventions, as defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>); and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE57AE6DD854407E824A1486328CB1F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit an application, that is endorsed by all members of the partnership, that contains the assurances described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H251C8BB1660343229BECBB364D82C940"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required assurances</header><text>An application under paragraph (1) shall contain assurances as follows:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H6FF566203F4D419E995B78D67EDB8DB0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>That the eligible entity will ensure that, in carrying out activities under this section, the eligible entity will enter into a memorandum of understanding—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H16FC2B6F624A45FE9085FB06FA6483EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with at least 1 public or private mental health entity, health care entity, law enforcement or juvenile justice entity, child welfare agency, family-based mental health entity, trauma network, or other community-based entity; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HA32877CCE5F44F12A2805D49518DEB20"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that clearly states—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="HFDAAE6046F2F4A4182DB6FB99908BB1C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the responsibilities of each partner with respect to the activities to be carried out, including how family engagement will be incorporated in the activities;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H42E1FC50C8684A1DB11CB14E7961C3B0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>how school-employed and school-based mental health professionals will be utilized for carrying out such responsibilities;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H0D0F1C4D895F4504ADB851ABAA55E09A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>how each such partner will be accountable for carrying out such responsibilities; and</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H92202501ABB64A4882C09306C53A972A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the amount of non-Federal funding or in-kind contributions that each such partner will contribute in order to sustain the program.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0BA3BA13D16B43E28EDEF70A5AC6AB04"><enum>(B)</enum><text>That the comprehensive school-based mental health program carried out under this section supports the flexible use of funds to address—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H0E1650A8E1DA42BDBB1A4DB09912D532"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the promotion of the social, emotional, and behavioral health of all students in an environment that is conducive to learning;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H9F9CD7ADE0F74C97A4A44876458CAAA8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the reduction in the likelihood of at risk students developing social, emotional, behavioral health problems, or substance use disorders;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HF5172F3C13A5489DB930AC2A46D0A110"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the early identification of social, emotional, behavioral problems, or substance use disorders and the provision of early intervention services;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H68CAB475F18B4207A453DF7F01D98F9B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the treatment or referral for treatment of students with existing social, emotional, behavioral health problems, or substance use disorders; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HB9145052DEEA4327846C0250F088D4C0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the development and implementation of programs to assist children in dealing with trauma and violence, including program curricula, school supports, and after-school programs.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61FE146666FC4CC5AC6753E5B5C1733F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the comprehensive school-based mental health program carried out under this section will provide for in-service training of all school personnel, including ancillary staff and volunteers, in—</text>
 <clause id="H65F5EED5C1CE4B15883755809001FC32"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the techniques and supports needed to identify early children with trauma histories and children with, or at risk of, mental illness;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H02433D86EE844DE5A400D0AA4E6B33EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the use of referral mechanisms that effectively link such children to appropriate treatment and intervention services in the school and in the community and to follow-up when services are not available;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4BA24128316B48ED965F37D38E01A6FC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>strategies that promote a school-wide positive environment;</text> </clause><clause id="H6668E092C86745F588753CFBFC251DBC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strategies for promoting the social, emotional, mental, and behavioral health of all students; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H585384050CE14482AB8AAD2F5CB534F9"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strategies to increase the knowledge and skills of school and community leaders about the impact of trauma and violence and on the application of a public health approach to comprehensive school-based mental health programs.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15D887E0491C4FBF956DA4C51D791D81"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the comprehensive school-based mental health program carried out under this section will include comprehensive training for parents, siblings, and other family members of children with mental health disorders, and for concerned members of the community in—</text>
 <clause id="HA405DD17F06C4BF49BE4AB98370B151E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the techniques and supports needed to identify early children with trauma histories, and children with, or at risk of, mental illness;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H95CD76A7E9DA4D59A86CDBADFE82CE45"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the use of referral mechanisms that effectively link such children to appropriate treatment and intervention services in the school and in the community and follow-up when such services are not available; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6802830A47C145AEA4D8867A0E9A1C5F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>strategies that promote a school-wide positive environment.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAAA4C76827D0473B9DDC7D4D15C31E94"><enum>(E)</enum><text>That the comprehensive school-based mental health program carried out under this section will demonstrate the measures to be taken to sustain the program after funding under this section terminates (which may include seeking funding for the program under a State Medicaid plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</external-xref> et seq.) or a waiver of such a plan).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC2570C0CA3E74BB6810EFC1A63D39AA6"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the eligible entity is supported by the State agency with primary responsibility for behavioral health to ensure that the sustainability of the programs is established after funding under this section terminates.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H766B8D2733324389A7D4276E68091097"><enum>(G)</enum><text>That the comprehensive school-based mental health program carried out under this section will be based on trauma-informed and evidence-based practices.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF71722D23BA246CB8E13E9145BE3A258"><enum>(H)</enum><text>That the comprehensive school-based mental health program carried out under this section will be coordinated with early intervening activities carried out under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD18DCDE6D1C14498B9A01F724953CBC7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>That the comprehensive school-based mental health program carried out under this section will be trauma-informed and culturally and linguistically appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H646FCD3EDBC142A6B2645AE092ACE778"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the comprehensive school-based mental health program carried out under this section will include a broad needs assessment of youth who drop out of school due to policies of <quote>zero tolerance</quote> with respect to drugs, alcohol, or weapons and an inability to obtain appropriate services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF630DD7213C948DF9D729A81025E2232"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the mental health services provided through the comprehensive school-based mental health program carried out under this section will be provided by qualified mental and behavioral health professionals who are certified or licensed by the State involved and practicing within their area of expertise.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H98BE1D830DB740AE944E95E884841263"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordinator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any entity that is a member of a partnership described in paragraph (1)(A) may serve as the coordinator of funding and activities under the grant if all members of the partnership agree.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H87015C90582447408A4620390D2907E5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compliance with HIPAA</header><text>A grantee under this section shall be deemed to be a covered entity for purposes of compliance with the regulations promulgated under section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 with respect to any patient records developed through activities under the grant.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6223836AB7CD40D98A1A01C89149CDDE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Geographical distribution</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements under subsection (a) will be distributed equitably among the regions of the country and among urban and rural areas.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9BA9FA5CFFF7479D9A555A78EC580E87"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duration of awards</header><text>With respect to a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under subsection (a), the period during which payments under such an award will be made to the recipient shall be 5 years. An eligible entity described in subsection (c) may receive only one award under this section, except that an eligible entity that is providing services and supports on a regional basis may receive additional funding after the expiration of the preceding grant period.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H596D88927B6645FAAF10AD084F8B703D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Evaluation and measures of outcomes</header>
 <paragraph id="H5CAFA57F16A24133AEAAC73C61346FD1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development of process</header><text>The Administrator shall develop a fiscally appropriate process for evaluating activities carried out under this section. Such process shall include—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H03B2231C06AD495F99A4306540F56BEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the development of guidelines for the submission of program data by grant, contract, or cooperative agreement recipients;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAF97BEE6B2A481E9AD91C642BB3EB9B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the development of measures of outcomes (in accordance with paragraph (2)) to be applied by such recipients in evaluating programs carried out under this section; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H639AB31CA00145E6950C2578FD9F7264"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the submission of annual reports by such recipients concerning the effectiveness of programs carried out under this section.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1F383BB6C83429F9A59B4210C25EAD4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Measures of outcomes</header>
 <subparagraph id="H4F18EA87157D45BF859B397660DE6103"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall develop measures of outcomes to be applied by recipients of assistance under this section, and the Administrator, in evaluating the effectiveness of programs carried out under this section. Such measures shall include student and family measures as provided for in subparagraph (B) and local educational measures as provided for under subparagraph (C).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB257015411484A288193AC4AA69695B4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Student and family measures of outcomes</header><text>The measures of outcomes developed under paragraph (1)(B) relating to students and families shall, with respect to activities carried out under a program under this section, at a minimum include provisions to evaluate whether the program is effective in—</text>
 <clause id="H529CA8BA1F37499AB997A23629158199"><enum>(i)</enum><text>increasing social and emotional competency;</text> </clause><clause id="H9030267744E5468684674443DE7BE2BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>increasing academic competency (as defined by the Secretary);</text>
 </clause><clause id="H95E49BBCE6F84E8281FFFCB73C208881"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>reducing disruptive and aggressive behaviors;</text> </clause><clause id="HB91BA0EAF82E4E7E8C54906EE171E8C8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>improving child functioning;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H90446E853D9B45C5B9CD4B7B539A6790"><enum>(v)</enum><text>reducing substance use disorders;</text> </clause><clause id="H211BB15E75C1437DAC427D1554006D4A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>reducing suspensions, truancy, expulsions, and violence;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H3CB01E05003142CF9460B79A22F4CDE0"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>increasing high school graduation rates, calculated using the four-year adjusted cohort graduation rate or the extended-year adjusted cohort graduation rate (as such terms are defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)); and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB749C7D865E40048083BA90867B0F9A"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>improving access to care for mental health disorders.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC68A315C55B54E0695245B3DA2584636"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Local educational outcomes</header><text>The outcome measures developed under paragraph (1)(B) relating to local educational systems shall, with respect to activities carried out under a program under this section, at a minimum include provisions to evaluate—</text>
 <clause id="H78513174FF70433BACE17E4AA18F4EA7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the effectiveness of comprehensive school mental health programs established under this section;</text> </clause><clause id="HD86200F77E6B4AE386177736733D0FA1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the effectiveness of formal partnership linkages among child and family serving institutions, community support systems, and the educational system;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H37C151F8A42F4B199B24516CE572E369"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the progress made in sustaining the program once funding under the grant has expired;</text> </clause><clause id="H9C0AC0E4C2BC4997BF264C83E2CCD195"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the effectiveness of training and professional development programs for all school personnel that incorporate indicators that measure cultural and linguistic competencies under the program in a manner that incorporates appropriate cultural and linguistic training;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF5126C805C144971A8FD9DC76F6114B2"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the improvement in perception of a safe and supportive learning environment among school staff, students, and parents;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC797138A85A74BFBA2E351D698A05AF2"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the improvement in case-finding of students in need of more intensive services and referral of identified students to early intervention and clinical services;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF1C6390730B943A191BAF5E7F94D629C"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the improvement in the immediate availability of clinical assessment and treatment services within the context of the local community to students posing a danger to themselves or others;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H70178F985D1D462697467251B1AC619F"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the increased successful matriculation to postsecondary school; and</text> </clause><clause id="H50BBF848548149C9B67AB5B7B2A5E4C5"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>reduced referrals to juvenile justice.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H063C9A623C484818B3C6A7DFFAB3E22E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Submission of annual data</header><text>An eligible entity described in subsection (c) that receives a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section shall annually submit to the Administrator a report that includes data to evaluate the success of the program carried out by the entity based on whether such program is achieving the purposes of the program. Such reports shall utilize the measures of outcomes under paragraph (2) in a reasonable manner to demonstrate the progress of the program in achieving such purposes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28C38D7793264A6CBF9E61420178CF4C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Evaluation by Administrator</header><text>Based on the data submitted under paragraph (3), the Administrator shall annually submit to Congress a report concerning the results and effectiveness of the programs carried out with assistance received under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H79F40F1CB86944EB9999A9DE301CAB0E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>An eligible entity shall use not more than 10 percent of amounts received under a grant under this section to carry out evaluation activities under this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF3CC54A2B8F14050AB154CB2665233F9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Information and education</header><text>The Secretary shall establish comprehensive information and education programs to disseminate the findings of the knowledge development and application under this section to the general public and to health care professionals.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H842894D58B1F47CDB8EAF5330E555406"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Amount of grants and authorization of appropriations</header>
 <paragraph id="HFA269E9657C44D29ACADB3038D7BFFE4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amount of grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant under this section shall be in an amount that is not more than $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022. The Secretary shall determine the amount of each such grant based on the population of children up to age 21 of the area to be served under the grant.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H767E4ECB011C4A94B0CBF40F384EFD08"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $200,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H71B54C5E6F2449C28539E03922FC045D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part G of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290hh">42 U.S.C. 290hh</external-xref> et seq.), as amended by this section, is further amended by striking the part heading and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F1D65E672B74033821624CE091A2D79" style="OLC">
					<part id="H0722064CC1B34CBEAC1A808765B76973"><enum>G</enum><header>School-based mental health</header></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


