<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HEB91805767CF4F48B075C75F6F505811" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4165 IH: New Economy Works to Guarantee Independence and Growth Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4165</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171027">October 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000597">Mr. Rice of South Carolina</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a safe harbor for determinations of worker
			 classification, to require increased reporting, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H6C45317904724856893933725764B04B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6E8816AA598C40428FB2BA249AA78E9A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>New Economy Works to Guarantee Independence and Growth Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NEW GIG Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5543BCBBA2DE4EFE970DD1091AAF9E2B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Determination of worker classification</header> <subsection id="H08FB714EDE004DA7BFE94C62897D2FCC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/79">Chapter 79</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99E79FA38ED340BF9C8CA22386569865" style="OLC">
					<section id="HBD2479230A704C9EA07E7D0F623D56AE"><enum>7706.</enum><header>Determination of worker classification</header>
 <subsection id="H12EA35E0652444DD9D381AC9F6DDA3E1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this title (and notwithstanding any provision of this title not contained in this section to the contrary), if the requirements of subsections (b), (c), and (d) are met with respect to any service performed by a service provider, then with respect to such service—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7A26CB93EEB745A99B027BE89CB6B79B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the service provider shall not be treated as an employee,</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC131442AAA5140D3A5009D3B2E7E847D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the service recipient shall not be treated as an employer,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1ED2A6D47850447297AEA2B370F9BF1E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any payor shall not be treated as an employer, and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4EFA02DF7DD14023A045C43BF45B7EF1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the compensation paid or received for such service shall not be treated as paid or received with respect to employment.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H252DA62952A540D99C2777ED0823B06E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>General service provider requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="HB1E27D720CB74E6FADB5805CF90FB536"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The requirements of this subsection are met with respect to any service if the service provider either—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBC3AB215233E46DEB4C6FB1DCACD4094"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meets the requirements of paragraph (2) with respect to such service, or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD92EA5DB73C547108092758B7C517142"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a service provider engaged in the trade or business of selling (or soliciting the sale of) goods or services, meets the requirements of paragraph (3) with respect to such service.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB97FFC945BCC423391D17F42A376E1A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>General requirements</header>
 <subparagraph id="H037BEA3B3EE64D05A9A62C6CD2E93AA7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of this paragraph are met with respect to any service if the service provider, in connection with performing the service—</text>
 <clause id="H85A51A5849A5403BAE801627646AA5FF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>incurs expenses—</text> <subclause id="H6A7BB35A0C6A49BE974BC4B9FC22A2BE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>which are deductible under section 162, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF4768F52B40C47ABA5EEE774DDC89721"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a significant portion of which are not reimbursed,</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H6BC5DA52CE5C4C17AECD42884121A2AA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>agrees to perform the service for a particular amount of time, to achieve a specific result, or to complete a specific task, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3645AE8326294EE2A8DF58A3C88650B8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>satisfies not less than one of the factors described in subparagraph (B).</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H844A46EB67E242E4BD78CAC4571683D2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Factors</header><text>The factors described in this subparagraph are the following:</text>
 <clause id="HB6AF4079F67A4D348E623721FE09E5A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The service provider has a significant investment in assets or training which are applicable to the service performed.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4DD818849D054F49B3918F69C1D74410"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The service provider is not required to perform services exclusively for the service recipient or payor.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6EFE9DC7CF684D9A84E8A384AB54174E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The service provider has not been treated as an employee by the service recipient or payor during the 1-year period ending with the date of the commencement of services under the contract described in subsection (d).</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0978A3E73FC84CCFA00B602507364E06"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The service provider is not compensated on a basis which is tied primarily to the number of hours actually worked.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H697D35B660C64BF2A0D41EEC73F30A94"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Alternative requirements with respect to sales persons</header><text>In the case of a service provider engaged in the trade or business of selling (or soliciting the sale of) goods or services, the requirements of this paragraph are met with respect to any service provided in the ordinary course of such trade or business if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE52A6A0E2FFD4F3CA6655B121D8024D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the service provider is compensated primarily on a commission basis, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F1F429BF113402385295B3B6C671D83"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">substantially all the compensation for such service is directly related to sales of goods or services rather than to the number of hours worked.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B790D2003404F14B2506B8A86DDEBB5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Place of business or own equipment requirement</header><text>The requirement of this subsection is met with respect to any service if the service provider—</text> <paragraph id="H39BC8192D68C4C759B8C53562DED90C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has a principal place of business,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H057252176C344F608AA4C1C6370B61E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not provide the service primarily in the service recipient’s place of business,</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDB727EC6FB3454BB564EB3C45D9B3CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>pays a fair market rent for use of the service recipient’s place of business, or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4648C7640DD94A59877A14533112FD53"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provides the service primarily using equipment supplied by the service provider.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8EA18CE50B1347E3B3B7BC1A66674B0E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Written contract requirement</header><text>The requirements of this subsection are met with respect to any service if such service is performed pursuant to a written contract between the service provider and the service recipient (or payor) which meets the following requirements:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF86F50DF9FB14784AE4F8E3DFAC6702D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The contract includes each of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H6028A79B5CC740749940053FDC983226"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The service provider’s name, taxpayer identification number, and address.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H833FFC149BC24851876CBE342EDE57BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A statement that the service provider will not be treated as an employee with respect to the services provided pursuant to the contract for purposes of this title.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF1A519920A54080B90D995FEE58B389"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A statement that the service recipient (or the payor) will withhold upon and report to the Internal Revenue Service the compensation payable pursuant to the contract consistent with the requirements of this title.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F23A004560047DBAAB800CCFE051B22"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A statement that the service provider is responsible for payment of Federal, State, and local taxes, including self-employment taxes, on compensation payable pursuant to the contract.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H630759BFAB4348C8B199CBA2D91A0524"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A statement that the contract is intended to be considered a contract described in this subsection.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H67A5510AB6934FEEBDD95B977438280F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term of the contract does not exceed 2 years. The preceding sentence shall not prevent one or more subsequent written renewals of the contract from satisfying the requirements of this subsection if the term of each such renewal does not exceed 2 years and if the information required under paragraph (1)(A) is updated in connection with each such renewal.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A2E3CDAA32A4EA5B202F00B494332AD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The contract (or renewal) is signed (which may include signatures in electronic form) by both the service recipient (or payor) and the service provider not later than the date on which the aggregate payments made by the service recipient (or payor) to the service provider exceeds $1,000 for the year covered by the contract (or renewal).</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBEDB663D96CB47A48446BDD5EA0DEC65"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="HCCD4B72D3CB54710A00D8277855BE86E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of making any determination with respect to the liability of a service recipient or payor for any tax during any taxable year with respect to a service provider, the application of this section shall be conditioned on either the service recipient or the payor satisfying the reporting requirements applicable to such service recipient or payor under section 6041(a), 6041A(a), or 6050W with respect to such service provider for such period.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE502CC36132A4F50A3DC327EDBD27AE1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reasonable cause</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1), such reporting requirements shall be treated as met if the failure to satisfy such requirements is due to reasonable cause and not willful neglect.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB06842CFA9154050AB3FE5EEC396A166"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exception for services provided by owner</header><text>This section shall not apply with respect to any service provided by a service provider to a service recipient if the service provider owns any interest in the service recipient or any payor with respect to the service provided. The preceding sentence shall not apply in the case of a service recipient the stock of which is regularly traded on an established securities market.</text>
						</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H5E1F3AD64D394B3B9584A49607F6D762"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exception for personal services</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H03AF6A93EADF4E4AA0E9D019EA3D385D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This section shall not apply with respect to any service provided for the personal purposes of the service recipient.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6D2C21371C8746518908434D961A9ED9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply in the case of any services provided to a service recipient who is not the payor.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B21007C4EA94F669C84CBE14AD18FEB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Limitation on reclassification by Secretary</header><text>For purposes of this title—</text> <paragraph id="HEA8C917EDB2344339447EFF86ACA71AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Effect of reclassification on service recipients and payors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination by the Secretary that a service recipient or a payor should have treated a service provider as an employee shall be effective with respect to the service recipient or payor no earlier than the notice date if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB14106E306FC4F668FED13EFA0360DD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the service recipient or the payor entered into a written contract with the service provider which meets the requirements of subsection (d),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA24980B19DB843528ADF2B0079437400"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the service recipient or the payor satisfied the applicable reporting requirements of section 6041(a), 6041A(a), or 6050W for all relevant taxable years with respect to the service provider,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F04CB187B884D858801FA1C8C5FEA10"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the service recipient or the payor collected and paid over all applicable taxes imposed under subtitle C for all relevant taxable years with respect to the service provider, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6506282FBE1F4B478FD6DD84145AA86C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the service recipient or the payor demonstrates a reasonable basis for having determined that the service provider should not be treated as an employee under this section and that such determination was made in good faith.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H285961C7BC9B49FB870211FB03E54401"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of reclassification on service providers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination by the Secretary that a service provider should have been treated as an employee shall be effective with respect to the service provider no earlier than the notice date if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAB92CBF267B942BB87B0F953931DAFD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the service provider entered into a written contract with the service recipient or payor which meets the requirements of subsection (d),</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22EF5070390B467EAC972231D796CE8D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the service provider satisfied the applicable reporting requirements of sections 6012(a) and 6017 for all relevant taxable years with respect to the service recipient or payor, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF36D3ABD9AD44728810651EF0D0617D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the service provider demonstrates a reasonable basis for determining that the service provider is not an employee under this section and that such determination was made in good faith.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC8E054F235545519F7CBF4B8A6BCCED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice date</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>notice date</quote> means the 30th day after the earliest of—</text> <subparagraph id="H4AD82518DD8545C3817CC4870C285D6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date on which the first letter of proposed deficiency which allows the service provider, the service recipient, or the payor an opportunity for administrative review in the Internal Revenue Service Office of Appeals is sent,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15B3A94C074948FD8DD8906E480048E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date on which a deficiency notice under section 6212 is sent, or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D56F95B18BA468A98D837C49C4BEA2B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the date on which a notice of determination under section 7436(b)(2) is sent.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65E75B756D22407BA4C98CE91A0A6F47"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reasonable cause exception</header><text>The requirements of paragraphs (1)(B) and (2)(B) shall be treated as met if the failure to satisfy such requirements is due to reasonable cause and not willful neglect.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71434BA14D2A4E0783E367056354D5FC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>No restriction on administrative or judicial review</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as limiting any provision of law which provides an opportunity for administrative or judicial review of a determination by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0CCDC61B20AF49F49F438384268F9AB0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as—</text> <paragraph id="H616AF8B268FD4800A84E8FF0C0A5537B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>limiting the ability or right of a service provider, service recipient, or payor to apply any other provision of this title, section 530 of the Revenue Act of 1978, or any common law rules for determining whether an individual is an employee, or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H328728DC4D234AF8B522E0D5CFFC43F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishing a prerequisite for the application of any provision of law described in paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6DB7729968004FC4A77B1101EE856FDB"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text>
							<paragraph id="H6831CEF6EE1E4BC9B4CE9B9FF5242654"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Service provider</header>
 <subparagraph id="H69FB4356884E412EB56EECF5DE9E6BB9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>service provider</quote> means any qualified person who performs service for another person.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC107FDAF851D41C6944664951B0379BB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified person</header><text>The term <quote>qualified person</quote> means—</text>
 <clause id="H4DE6F06A3A7E405CA57A4C101037016E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any natural person, or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HAE7A95E22CB04071812150197951B969"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any entity if any of the services referred to in subparagraph (A) are performed by one or more natural persons who directly own interests in such entity.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F78DE106419416794708298BC470717"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Service recipient</header><text>The term <quote>service recipient</quote> means the person for whom the service provider performs such service.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H72D70E5C32974C92B56035A8CD9A213A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Payor</header><text>The term <quote>payor</quote> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9BB417DC3A134F29A434C516110C8F32"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any person, including the service recipient, who pays the service provider for performing such service, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H899C97B765EE45AB8A25FA9CF27E66A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any third party settlement organization, as defined in section 6050W(b)(3).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C425A4A38A048A3ABD40D074CB3BC4F"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Notwithstanding section 530(d) of the Revenue Act of 1978, the Secretary shall issue such regulations as the Secretary determines are necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H903C3308A61345A794ED63F218CF11DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Withholding by payor in case of certain persons classified as not employees</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3402">Section 3402</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subsection (s) as subsection (t) and inserting after subsection (r) the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07BF1DB671274CDFB2CB14A50F7438C7" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H9B90DBFCFF4E4DB0AE7B3985CE8E5EB6"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Extension of withholding to payments to certain persons classified as not employees</header>
 <paragraph id="H71E13C07F26A42FEBB6339FE6F245A2B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this chapter and so much of subtitle F as relates to this chapter, compensation paid pursuant to a contract described in section 7706(d) shall be treated as if it were a payment of wages by an employer to an employee.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BBCED48B6D0431D8C92B806A99D65FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount withheld</header><text>Except as otherwise provided under subsection (i), the amount to be deducted and withheld pursuant to paragraph (1) with respect to compensation paid pursuant to any such contract during any calendar year shall be an amount equal to 5 percent of so much of the amount of such compensation as does not exceed $20,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2914993D6A6E4F94833D2F0ED194F8E7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Direct sellers of promotional products</header><text>Subsection (b) of section 3508 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H483A49861D974C8D97ED608F0176D5F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1B9D6283DC4D4CA299A895B02D906179"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8287F9208F454810BE9FD86A55C8EBEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by adding <quote>or</quote> at the end; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2367EBC42CBD4295AA1446B6DE9EF450"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (iii) the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H883170CAE6E44355BF621F5FF3EEB01C" style="OLC"> <clause id="H8CB19962137B4D668059DAF8DA0F89A5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is engaged in the trade or business of selling, or soliciting the sale of, promotional products from other than a permanent retail establishment,</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H90499819565742AABE6CFB4256A50591"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (4); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H931972271C224C51A2D2EC1C6FE81B36"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6DE48DCF5FDD4C8396E768BB010D9950" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H32E7A9CC6F1B46DFB3DA25075300518C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Promotional product</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (2)(A)(iv), the term <term>promotional product</term> means a tangible item with permanently marked promotional words, symbols, or art of the purchaser.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB8A2F66BB3B0445D97D3B34B1CCD6298"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting</header> <paragraph id="H133B9A17EAB24C759D7D2BA9863168AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information at source</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6041">Section 6041</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEE1947E429BB4AE0A4EDC0A1745A2966"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="H539B2FD113434DFF870BE41307C9A269"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="tax">$600</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="tax">$1,000</header-in-text></quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB29E05DD1DEC4627A8B0CE7FF47E0B02"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$600 or more in any taxable year</quote> and inserting <quote>$1,000 or more in any taxable year</quote>; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD7CFD02DA074D3AB11FBEE16F783E7D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBF2F931F003486B8019D94ACFBE77F6" style="OLC">
							<subsection id="HA69491AF5B474FE99E269F457B2FB127"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Special rules for certain persons classified as not employees</header>
 <paragraph id="HDB9374B7BAD34CBE9C51DC3053CFC130"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any service recipient or payor required to make a return under subsection (a) with respect to compensation to which section 7706(a) applies—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1EE3503E0D67436FBE20AEF37EB49DD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such return shall include—</text> <clause id="H9823A5E3E56342D68FE604D1A130B08B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the aggregate amount of such compensation paid to each person whose name is required to be included on such return,</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEB12C8DB510B4C6EA7E782093C729C4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the aggregate amount deducted and withheld under section 3402(s) with respect to such compensation, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H97DBCC8B34C2459296117C732D076A3D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an indication of whether a copy of the contract described in section 7706(d) is on file with the service recipient or payor, and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A2F672B2E3B401AB72E9A7DE840FB23"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the statement required to be furnished under subsection (d) shall include the information described in subparagraph (A) with respect to the service provider to whom such statement is furnished.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H62DC9BC2D4594D92930A8C043ABD5EB6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Terms used in this subsection which are also used in section 7706 shall have the same meaning as when used in such section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DD2B5AA93404213A833EEA654DE8641"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Returns regarding payments of remuneration for services and direct sales</header><text>Section 6041A of such Code is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H8DAA5296965C4F449022B931DB998209"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) of subsection (a), by striking <quote>$600</quote> and inserting <quote>$1,000</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE79CF67FB9243BDB6BA13371F0DAD02"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H92BE713C326E4BD5903C64738796FA37" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H119046C60F6345CB800C8905B5ECE385"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Special rules for certain persons classified as not employees</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of subsection (h) of section 6041 shall apply for purposes of this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H965E2863980244CD8954BBA1812E6CE0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Returns relating to payments made in settlement of payment card and third party network
 transactions</header><text>Section 6050W of such Code is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H2E9B1F538EDD48FEA997458DAA32F9E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by amending paragraph (3) to read as follows:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A0D4E4929CD4DB5B820B6E732459035" style="OLC">
							<paragraph id="H1A4E54058E3F4A87AB9900FFD5A9CC3D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Third party network</header>
 <subparagraph id="HEAC380186F0E4A2D988B3736618104A1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>third party payment network</quote> means any agreement or arrangement—</text> <clause id="H0E76C59027C34CC48FE40E1E1A28CA22"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which involves the establishment of accounts with a central organization or marketplace platform by a substantial number of persons who—</text>
 <subclause id="HE70AE8DCD1174A81A215A451353EEE0C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are unrelated to such organization or platform,</text> </subclause><subclause id="HDE7379AC466840CE8D669AAF18BFFF08"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provide goods or services, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HEB0A682433274795BC45A84C3EDABE5E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>have agreed to settle transactions for the provision of such goods or services pursuant to such agreement or arrangement,</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H0DCD6E03C61E4B26A35EB358BC56ECCC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which provides for standards and mechanisms for settling such transactions, and</text> </clause><clause id="H1908295E45B5418CAA5E6F74A2F1486F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>which guarantees persons providing goods or services pursuant to such agreement or arrangement that such persons will be paid for providing such goods or services.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3A995E881884ED0876B1364A6C01085"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The term <term>third party payment network</term> shall not include any agreement or arrangement which provides for the issuance of payment cards.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEE0A82B4E3D4D1CBC7084E2A8A3015A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Marketplace platform</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>marketplace platform</term> means any person who—</text>
 <clause id="HBBFE1D4B6FD245B38AA14BB801812BAC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>operates a digital website or mobile application that facilitates the provision of goods or services by providers to recipients,</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBEC0FB0613804C60A91D46DE59CE6E1F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enters into an agreement with each provider stating that such provider will not be treated as an employee with respect to such goods or services,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H01C164707BD548CCBC6579BEC90EC918"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provides standards and mechanisms for settling such facilitated transactions, and</text> </clause><clause id="H41EC986EDE3C42258D0C5D1BB99D0151"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>guarantees each provider of goods or services pursuant to such agreement that the provider will be paid for such facilitated transaction.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5436AE4D464C448D866B9895BDA9FE61"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending subsection (e) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H36452A83D8F44FE1A9DD08C49ECDC5E1" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H20E7AF66367841E18CA04F7D169E05EE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exception for de minimis payments by third party settlement organizations</header> <paragraph id="H255140BE7E99475FA1DA7A195A0ED01C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A third party settlement organization shall be required to report any information under subsection (a) with respect to third party network transactions of any participating payee only if the amount which would otherwise be reported under subsection (a)(2) with respect to such transactions exceeds $1,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDD5481635DE47B3B454BAB3013CC618"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Election to report</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), a third party settlement organization may elect to report any information under subsection (a) with respect to third party network transactions of any participating payee for which the amount reported under subsection (a)(2) with respect to such transactions is equal to or less than $1,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC51446187520414FA063C31E2C82DE0B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (f)—</text> <clause id="H578B307729BD44F6876B7FE6C6DD241F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC5D20DD202CB495282FB1A21891846E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H6799A6152922472FBB58D00BDA8CC458"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following new paragraph:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6301E51246BC42CC91C3FD8AB139B736" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HC4D1D9E7418D428C846787176607493D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the amount, if any, withheld pursuant to section 3402(s).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H846E0F7E78EC42768A3FAA08C69C9DEC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Proceedings for determination of employment status</header><text>Paragraph (1) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7436">section 7436(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6976DE2A84304E989FDB4ED4EBA9F234" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H18F6BCD38C8F4374A6266DDAF3CCDD9C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Petitioner</header><text>A pleading may be filed under this section only by—</text> <subparagraph id="H2AC6540175084FE3A8800736CE1B3FED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the person for whom the services are performed, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF05785821F344E584FAF03ED46B5DD2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any service provider (as defined in section 7706(j)(1)) which the Secretary has determined should have been treated as an employee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H21AD4C976F9D467781549B9FAC31F5E0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/79">chapter 79</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA5987B0BEE4A44979D7B3BA54DF13FD9" style="OLC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H99E79FA38ED340BF9C8CA22386569865" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="HBD2479230A704C9EA07E7D0F623D56AE" level="section">Sec. 7706. Determination of worker classification.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE8BA76CEB3B14482B1CD5B2757021024"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to services performed after December 31, 2017 (and to payments made for such services after such date).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


