<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HD7EC40F9966147B4A3A025CAA9783D50" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3169 IH: VA Acquisition Workforce Improvement and Streamlining Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3169</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170710">July 10, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000611">Mr. Poliquin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster of New Hampshire</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Appropriations</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve the hiring, training, and efficiency of acquisition personnel and organizations of the
			 Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H05279DEC6C104C47B10A9472E092B1A2" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE370F648512844329B37D8E33D6F99E9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>VA Acquisition Workforce Improvement and Streamlining Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0B25E4AAB31B44EB970FCE90C63BD496" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improvement to hiring and training of acquisition personnel of Department of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="H9625B4EE7EFF4BBEACC864B5FF623E2E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Training and certification programs</header> <paragraph id="H4061267CC2984FCCB45AECD999D8A53D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30 of the fiscal year following the fiscal year during which this Act is enacted, the Secretary shall implement covered training curricula and covered certification programs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA61FB5CA2C8F4D28B21846F8A1100A71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration of relevant programs of Department of Defense</header><text>In designing and implementing covered training curricula and covered certification programs under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall use as models existing training curricula and certification programs that have been established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/87">chapter 87</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, as determined relevant by the Secretary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD92E22C68A14772BE11E17E230A8B60"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Method of training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may develop the training curricula under paragraph (1) in a manner that provides such training in any combination of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H425C9C77F2284F64B2A7D1D606871F3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>training provided in person;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E6450C7A31840D18D956F79FB07193C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training provided over an internet website; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EE7614683D24B70B2CDD342C9446633"><enum>(C)</enum><text>training provided by another department or agency of the Federal Government.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70709F0BCE924A9091A545782E627984"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Levels of certifications</header><text>The Secretary may develop the certification programs under paragraph (1) in a manner that uses—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD7559F226B874320A9A2A71FEB935B01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>one level of certification; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3ABAEF6AA893451E901C96C3D3305551"><enum>(B)</enum><text>more than one level of certification, as determined appropriate by the Secretary with respect to the level of certification for different grades of the General Schedule.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H33E7CAB00A9947D0B6E7684AA488FD0B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Initial goal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30 of the second fiscal year following the fiscal year during which this Act is enacted, the Secretary shall ensure that the majority of employees subject to the covered certification programs achieve the certification or the appropriate level of certification pursuant to paragraph (4)(B), as the case may be.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F1B700FA0F74152801066ED9CF2F5B9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Subsequent goal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After carrying out paragraph (5), the Secretary shall ensure that each employee subject to the covered certification programs achieves the certification or the appropriate level of certification pursuant to paragraph (4)(B), as the case may be, as quickly as practicable.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E95184308D24B4C8F4756EBBB4C02A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Improvements to hiring of entry-Level positions</header>
 <paragraph id="H61C47927A62C4117AFE418A2E742F67E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall prioritize the use of acquisition internship programs to hire employees to entry-level positions relating to acquisition in the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEE935AB9B4EE409DB90C937206CDDEFD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Goal</header><text>Not later than September 30 of the fiscal year following the fiscal year during which this Act is enacted, the Secretary shall ensure that the annual number of participants in acquisition internship programs is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD0FFB494C7E142C7B92E69082D758D03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not fewer than twice the number of participants in such programs during fiscal year 2017; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H349750C5148C4C1E8243B5050AB9F6D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not more than four times the number of participants in such program during such fiscal year.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFD3000BD819426788C006553F0064FD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out paragraph (2) until the date on which the Secretary certifies to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate that the projected number of graduates of acquisition internship programs is sufficient to satisfy the human capital needs of the Department with respect to acquisition, taking into account the rate of attrition and projected retirements of personnel.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H456F4555F292448C98B360FBEE8D215D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfers</header>
 <paragraph id="H6534BD6D84AA4716A59E42996FED6690"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>In addition to any other transfer authority of the Secretary, the Secretary may transfer or reprogram amounts identified under section 3 as cost savings in order to make such amounts available for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H81D85CE2C6E4433287A060BE42CA9BA2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the salaries and travel expenses of participants in acquisition internship programs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H26064DB90B024380A3476A0C58F5D896"><enum>(B)</enum><text>covered training programs; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H767616935D12471595C76E4BDD4E9F52"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the design and implementation of covered certification programs.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H88E0ECF9589E44C0B2FD305DF9F0F9F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorizations</header><text>A transfer made from one account to another under the authority of paragraph (1) shall be deemed to increase the amount authorized for the account to which the amount is transferred by an amount equal to the amount transferred.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1E0D1E3E9759448CA3B472CD92D99745"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improvement to efficiency of acquisition organizations of the Department of Veterans Affairs</header>
 <subsection id="H3BC76DBB0AB44008BD6981ACC64387B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop a plan to reduce duplication and to increase efficiencies with respect to the acquisition functions of the Department of Veterans Affairs, with an emphasis on procurement and logistics functions, in a manner that achieves cost savings in an amount necessary to carry out section 2. The Secretary shall ensure that such plan—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H3D6FA468D80248628C4FC0D61166A839"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in all respects and to the greatest extent practicable, seeks to place procurement employees and logistics employees in close geographic proximity to the other employees of the Department for whom the procurement employees and logistics employees procure supplies or services;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE5AA36C1B93B43349FD22E69A1E888C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not place any procurement employee in a formal reporting or subordinate-supervisor relationship with an employee of the Department for whom the procurement employee procures supplies or services; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H451A79D3DA9242269F9D68FAE5E2121F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not achieve cost savings through demotions, furloughs, or liquidations, as defined in part 351 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC564FA2FA6A4B05A127F4D4EC0F1206"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters included</header><text>In developing the plan under subsection (a), the Secretary shall determine whether to carry out the following activities:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC7875AB06BF04A719C516404704DF3EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consolidate or abolish (and transfer functions to the procurement or logistics activities of individual facilities of the Veterans Health Administration, the Network Contracting Offices of the Veterans Health Administration, the Procurement and Logistics Office of the Veterans Health Administration, or the Office of Acquisition, Logistics, and Construction of the Department)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBCA2E9DEC2C4456FA60E89675446887E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Service Area Office East;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA739D60DFAE41399F10648FE4A16CD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Service Area Office Central;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FCA9246247A4973BA6DEFB28C730BCF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Service Area Office West; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9AF0B1812DD40C5B6D57FD8A1EF416E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Program Contacting Activity Central Office.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCB2C4AD95DD45D5B8E32E2C4A4B5E3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the functions of the Procurement and Logistics Office of the Veterans Health Administration and the Office of Acquisition, Logistics, and Construction of the Department, consolidate one or more of the following functions into one of the respective offices:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBD0A90F639BE4B6999E09FBB94A913BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Policy making functions.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32F4F50DE29846E19E975D241ED9227A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Contract quality assurance and review functions.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CFBE889F64E422CA447A18F5667038D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Real property management functions.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24D5CB9ECD71463B9F18B925A538ED90"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Business operations functions.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAB8EA2C266146F2A06DA51B5EB0E36A"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Health care acquisition.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF98D1D62E57C4EC19C131BD7134FBFA8"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Logistics functions.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEFBE83B153CC4196A1A5D814A2A4FB4F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the fiscal year during which this Act is enacted, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate the plan developed under subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCF352BC9A38048E2A97AED1306B16787"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Secretary shall commence implementation of the plan developed under subsection (a) beginning on the date that is 30 days after submitting the plan under subsection (c).</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H2FC83FE63E8641759B4B9BB75085B3C6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HF94E66239F54419EB3A267A1893474DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>acquisition internship programs</term> means programs administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, including the Warriors to Workforce Program and the Acquisition Intern Program, under which the Secretary employs—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1B58216777E04EC0A283703A9D2E7A36"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a veteran, while the veteran earns an undergraduate degree and completes found­a­tion­al training courses relating to acquisition; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB911C16D79C746F39300465EC0E24C9A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual who completes progressive training courses relating to acquisition and participates in rotational work assignments relating to acquisition.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD9887C7258849AF99058A539101BB99"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>covered certification programs</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H2ED7E6D3223647D18171175225231335"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to logistics employees, a program to certify knowledge and skills relating to logistics; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B2553D9495143FDB687E96AFF8536DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to employees of the Department who are members of occupational series relating to construction or facilities management, or who award or administer contracts for major construction, minor construction, or non-recurring maintenance, including as contract specialists or contracting officers’ representatives, a program to certify knowledge and skills relating to construction or facilities management.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA75C819A2E944F58D8F90511CC0C657"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>covered training curricula</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H5C0CE5261AE042C8A40484E2A1B9D612"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to logistics employees, a training curriculum relating to logistics; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4312838E955046468EF175EF83AD5EB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to employees specified in paragraph (2)(B), a training curriculum relating to construction or facilities management.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE80892685560409B907CCFCF213271E9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>logistics</term> includes supply chain management.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7018BCE3AB0A48B687D68EB9636126C9"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>logistics employee</term> means an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs who is a member of an occupational series relating to logistics, or who performs logistics functions within the Office of Acquisition, Logistics, and Construction of the Department or the Veterans Health Administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1EFC2828A45545EAB677DD3CCBBE0DDA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>procurement employee</term> means an employee of the Department who is a member of an occupational series relating to procurement.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


