<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H96D55F87722045A29F519A4E9454F645" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3968 IH: Small Business Cybersecurity Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3968</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171005">October 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Small Business Act to provide loan guarantees for the acquisition of cybersecurity
			 technology and services by eligible small businesses, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4EE547C92ABD4FAB84A2318B20EF4B8D" style="OLC">
 <section id="HDE5ACCC4BC1D43F5A46DC9C09EAFD6ED" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small Business Cybersecurity Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H26C2376071E248E082CEF31C7EF31423"><enum>2.</enum><header>Loan guarantees for cybersecurity technology and services</header> <subsection id="HDF5A27DA4B8E4C08AEA470B1607EF7C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCB8AE6ECB4F94A6085ECA8B5F65E4F67"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 47 as section 48; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF039637E408345CCA55705B79C8D5C94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting the following new section after section 46:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0AA6DB20C3C245618495DAAB36F7CD9B" style="OLC">
						<section id="H8E95EC19B6134C0CA7846AC653DD6061"><enum>47.</enum><header>Loan guarantees for cybersecurity technology and services</header>
 <subsection id="HA5B1F9895C0E4389917C689A0915D6E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>As used in this section:</text> <paragraph id="H4C1B8C31F7D44326ACFBC5B18B7DB978"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cybersecurity technology and services</header><text>The term <term>cybersecurity technology and services</term>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE34BEC75C8D144D1B864FA4D80CB9F07"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text> <clause id="H9E643BB9ED5543E4B47CA3A120CC701E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>computer hardware, software, and related technology that—</text>
 <subclause id="HB919A7D11F45404A833E5839620B02AC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>supports the prevention of damage to, protection of, and restoration of computers, electronic communications systems, electronic communications services, wire communication, and electronic communication, including information contained therein, to ensure its availability, integrity, authentication, confidentiality, and nonrepudiation;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3CDA3F2A57844C80B6D2B57A62580299"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is purchased by an eligible small business;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HF0B5694FACD944FC9A901D2E8CA6F5A7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>provides for encryption of data, detection of malware, or protection of information and information systems from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, disruption, modification, or destruction;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H5256A01A28AB4A75B98385AB76395E6A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meets any requirements established by the Small Business Development Center Cyber Strategy developed under section 1841(a) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; 130 Stat. 2662); and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HAC03929C2B884942AECA71C0BBA2EF1F"><enum>(V)</enum><text>meets any industry best practices standards;</text> </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H96A45565338A46D8AA7DE6A30462E08C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an insurance product available for purchase by an eligible small business that provides coverage for losses caused by a cyber attack on such business;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H02E3A2D31A69477890C04EB27B572A4D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>services related to—</text> <subclause id="H9C5A8AA4A1B64583A9DFEB53BBE14171"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the installation of computer hardware, software, and related technology described under clause (i); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC42AA044184C462CA98725576C4304F9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>training on security principles for employees of an eligible small business; or</text> </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H25D6FD08E83C4FE3BE144C90285044CC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>has the meaning given such term by the Administrator; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36172AD32DEF49E39C2895EE28F6C87F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include information technology whose sole use is financial management, maintenance of inventory of basic supplies, or appointment scheduling.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H656792C2420246B3A9ED1760CC746FAA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible small business</header><text>The term <term>eligible small business</term> means a small business concern that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H454A36B7713C4EBF9C708A4AACDDB285"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has 100 or fewer employees;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9564E30EA53D4B16B90DE273CF904332"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been in business for at least 1 year; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H01052D8B3FAF42D58616DAC267C5B591"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has obtained training from a small business development center.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA8D762A7ADDC4C5298DAA6F0776E53B8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prime rate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>prime rate</term> means the discount window primary credit interest rate most recently published in the Federal Reserve Statistical Release on selected interest rates (daily or weekly), commonly referred to as the H.15 release, or any successor publication.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF705B3C672E04301AA2A848624683712"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Loan guarantees for eligible small businesses</header>
 <paragraph id="H4D1350189AD8457997FDADCA270B0639"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Guarantee percentage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), the Administrator may guarantee up to 90 percent of the amount of a loan made to an eligible small business for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE94DF721F7554A6CBE851FD28795EED2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the acquisition of cybersecurity technology and services for use in the business operations of the eligible small business; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5A9AF8997D7446988733A683DC61132"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the costs associated with the installation or use of such cybersecurity technology and services.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEE734E5EBAC405DA6FB4C475056E048"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations on guarantee amounts</header><text>The maximum amount of the principal of a loan guaranteed under this section may not exceed $50,000. The aggregate total amount of the principal of loans guaranteed under this section in a year may not exceed $500,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H91B0E4F50AF8429F8BE2DD28BC91D17C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each loan guaranteed under this section, the Administration shall assess, collect, and retain such fees as are necessary to reduce to zero the cost to the Administration of making guarantees under this section. As used in this subsection, the term <term>cost</term> has the meaning given that term in section 502 of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/661a">2 U.S.C. 661a</external-xref>).</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H7A2D73D635C1451CBAAB41DF93161C55"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interest rates</header>
 <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC995DC00CC6247D392A4F0630F78CB4D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fixed rate loans</header><text>With respect to a fixed rate loan guaranteed under this section, the interest rate for such a loan may not exceed—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBB4AEF81B27C47428BE9A93DB5F79E3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for a loan in an amount greater than $25,000, the prime rate; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H072A68C0C4054460AB9726F096362511"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for a loan in an amount less than or equal to $25,000, the prime rate plus 3.25 percent.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H97A0CBFE063444C1A7C1C298F013DFE7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Variable rate loans</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2C13E3F66DE04C9F91C90A71F89CC217"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to a variable rate loan guaranteed under this section, the interest rate for such a loan shall equal—</text>
 <clause id="H1E2ECA70F7904910907F5FEC7E562A72"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the prime rate plus the spread described under subparagraph (B); or</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HE50503AA5F9F40FEA5D69ED9E4A56897"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the optional peg rate, as calculated quarterly by the Administrator and published in the Federal Register, plus the spread described under subparagraph (B).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF9F2157D5F54D9D96964EBACBF79937"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Negotiation of spread and rate of change</header><text>The lender and the borrower shall negotiate the amount of the spread which will be added to the interest rate described under subparagraph (A) and select the frequency at which the spread will change, which shall be no more often than monthly and shall be consistent over the term of the loan.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H860F2833444B4402A9352C11A94E5B05"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Deferral period</header><text>The Administrator may defer payment of the principal and interest on a loan guaranteed under this section for a period not to exceed 3 years.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="H70B8FA3A7BF242C38385AD7A9AAA7D44"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Terms and conditions for loan guarantees</header>
 <paragraph id="H1E9B46D8A99C4F65BE606D2DE667C354"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A loan guaranteed under this section shall be subject to such terms and conditions as the Administrator may prescribe, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H98944818F27644ACAD52C6CE0E5AD5A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>explicit standards for use in periodically assessing the credit risk of guaranteed loans;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB2E81E6988042FCB9E03FC7956AB10F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a requirement that the final maturity of such a loan may not exceed 7 years; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA23846538BC4A52B74B42F0A0630774"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a requirement that such a loan may not be subordinated to another debt contracted by the borrower or to any other claims against the borrower in the case of default.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB708DD7695A443BB9F138EBAFF7370C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Restrictions</header><text>The Administrator may not guarantee a loan under this section—</text> <subparagraph id="HA2DBD430EDA04CB1A0077426D33F51EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>unless the Administrator determines that the lender is responsible, that there is a reasonable assurance of repayment, and that adequate provision is made for servicing the loan on reasonable terms and protecting the financial interest of the United States;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H681498469CD24DD28B77383B15E71897"><enum>(B)</enum><text>except to the extent that appropriations of budget authority to cover their costs are made in advance, as required under section 504 of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E52C363E6FD4F6C929312A4DEA62554"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if—</text> <clause id="H2EDE18BFBCB04D4AAA5207D7055E57A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the income from such loan is excluded from gross income for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H26BB01B7736F4315BFB8626AEF05B8E7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the guarantee provides significant collateral or security, as determined by the Administrator, for other obligations the income from which is so excluded.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0D2D96DF1054742B722A5D1BF1C3CCA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Guarantees</header><text>A loan guarantee provided under this section shall be conclusive evidence that—</text> <subparagraph id="HCE7DDF798E654196804ABB38AB2E3DE4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the guarantee has been properly obtained;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDF1B358FFCD455BA2A58D8AB8C911CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the underlying loan qualified for such guarantee; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D12B184992F4BF4B8E4A3217A443E94"><enum>(C)</enum><text>absent fraud or material misrepresentation by the holder and the lender, the guarantee is presumed to be valid, legal, and enforceable.</text>
									</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4444505EB124924AC1BA6BD532CDC5A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Payment of losses</header>
 <paragraph id="H1D4465EB601E45FCBBD444DE30CC59D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If, as a result of a default by a borrower under a loan guaranteed under this section, and after the holder of the loan has made collection efforts and instituted enforcement proceedings as the Administrator may require, the Administrator determines that the holder of the loan has suffered a loss, the Administrator shall pay to such holder the percentage of such loss specified in the guarantee contract. Upon making any such payment, the Administrator shall be subrogated to all the rights of the recipient of the payment. The Administrator shall be entitled to recover from the borrower the amount of any payments made to the holder of the loan under this paragraph.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BB1CE37E88E403F989555A1DEFCB3DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Forbearance</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to preclude any forbearance for the benefit of the borrower which may be agreed upon by the parties to the guaranteed loan and approved by the Administrator, if budget authority for any resulting subsidy costs (as defined in section 502(5) of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990) is available.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDA930DB3B4F430AAEA6EF7879C1267A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Management of property</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law relating to the acquisition, handling, or disposal of property by the United States, the Administrator may complete, recondition, reconstruct, renovate, repair, maintain, operate, or sell any property acquired by the Administrator pursuant to this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3DFCB9BBE74A49239B8FE5B9A719C246"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Sunset of authority</header><text>The authority of the Administrator to make new loan guarantees under this section shall terminate after the end of the 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this section.</text>
							</subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0EA9BE9555FF4C86BEF805D2A79640F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date that is 30 days after the date on which the Small Business Development Center Cyber Strategy developed under section 1841(a) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; 130 Stat. 2662) is submitted to the Committees on Homeland Security and Small Business of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


