<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2EE784A38C764208891483417D11C661" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3144 IH: To provide for operations of the Federal Columbia River Power System pursuant to a certain operation plan for a specified period of time, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3144</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20170629">June 29, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. McMorris Rodgers</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H001056">Ms. Herrera Beutler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000791">Mr. Walden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To provide for operations of the Federal Columbia River Power System pursuant to a certain operation plan for a specified period of time, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HDAABED37613B4AC0B1ECA24860C403AA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC1400AA8145348369E19BD4BA9DFF017" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H3D35A5BE44F04ECCB7B8F1E60B105187"><enum>(1)</enum><header>FCRPS</header><text>The term <term>FCRPS</term> means the Federal Columbia River Power System.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB157536A9D2C4C32883E57EDDB2D05CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretaries</header><text>The term <term>Secretaries</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HC5B9AF686A954F4A871452979DF0D654"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7AFABCB9947E486FB3F7FFE0EAC62806"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Energy, acting through the Bonneville Power Administration; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87056AA6C0864A97B500C9123EFBCE22"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Secretaries of the Army, acting through the Army Corps of Engineers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDCC6C2F882DF46AE8EC9131C72841B8D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Supplemental Opinion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Supplemental Opinion</term> means the document titled <quote>Endangered Species Act Section 7(a)(2) Supplemental Biological Opinion</quote>, NOAA Fisheries Log Number NWR–2013–9562, and dated January 17, 2014, which supplements, without replacing, the 2008 and 2010 FCRPS Biological Opinions and the Reasonable and Prudent Alternative contained therein.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H3F2F042C6C264351900E08246525DB74"><enum>2.</enum><header>Operation of FCRPS</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretaries shall operate the FCRPS in a manner consistent with the reasonable and prudent alternative set forth in the Supplemental Opinion until the later of the following dates:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFFC61CB8062C485286F99C5550D407FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>September 30, 2022.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF07FB6A12273439DB48585EA6752F994"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The date upon which a subsequent final biological opinion for the FCRPS operations is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9AECC2B273904A3A8A1DC2A585A11F03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issued after completion of the final environmental impact statement on a record of decision for a new operations plan for the FCRPS; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEC97DDFC19A64B89A90C61AC66F56D59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in effect, with no pending further judicial review.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H500F27500B074A5DAB752359A846EA3D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Amendments to Supplemental Opinion</header> 
<subsection id="H94CBA84E43184EA2B37CED88A923DF93"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 2, the Secretaries may amend portions of the Supplemental Opinion and operate the FCRPS in accordance with such amendments, before the date established under section 2 if all of the Secretaries determine, in the sole discretion of each Secretary, that—</text> <paragraph id="H130CE1573819490ABCC3904BCEC831D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the amendment is necessary for public safety or transmission and grid reliability; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H06A5DF23370848FE9DCD74E5DC379A3C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the actions, operations, or other requirements that the amendment would remove are no longer warranted.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H052ED16D6260493291857ED8BEF5FC6A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restriction on amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The process described in subsection (a) shall be the only method by which the Secretaries may operate the FCRPS during the time period established under section 2 in any way that is not consistent with the reasonable and prudent alternatives set forth in the Supplemental Opinion.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H63C6E420693F4CC48AB85D78880CEDF2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Limitation on restricting FCRPS electrical generation or navigation on the Snake River</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No structural modification, action, study, or engineering plan that restricts electrical generation at any Federal Columbia Power System hydroelectric dam, or that limits navigation on the Snake River in the State of Washington, Oregon, or Idaho, shall proceed unless such proposal is specifically and expressly authorized by an Act of Congress enacted after the date of submission to Congress of a proposal for such modification, action, study, or engineering plan, respectively.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

