<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H732E6157573D45EB95AF21FDD151001D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3201 IH: Maritime Administration Authorization and Enhancement Act for Fiscal Year 2018</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3201</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170712">July 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend and enhance certain maritime programs of the Department of Transportation, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H24787ED1A64A4AF0B89B4A32A80170CB" style="OLC">
		<section id="HECB72B48FB3941AE99A8E9753890DD6F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="HDBD6E156E34E4D5A9D8F4B94668627E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Maritime Administration Authorization and Enhancement Act for Fiscal Year 2018</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H53F289A6CA134DFBAD8C2CD49DA3E89A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc>
					<toc-entry idref="HECB72B48FB3941AE99A8E9753890DD6F" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H052FFE92C7EF45D1833B4F73A7F817FB" level="section">Sec. 2. Authorization of the Maritime Administration.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HBF29425FCC674983B95E498C93A0E065" level="section">Sec. 3. Removal adjunct professor limit at United States Merchant Marine Academy.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H72624354925B42659E1EBE28239123E3" level="section">Sec. 4. Acceptance of guarantees in conjunction with partial donations for major projects of the
			 United States Merchant Marine Academy.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H93CD8929517D49B6A997C37AF673AD8E" level="section">Sec. 5. Authority to pay conveyance or transfer expenses in connection with acceptance of a gift to
			 the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H8A195B011A4B46FF8E4ED2415D2A789D" level="section">Sec. 6. Authority to participate in Federal, State or other research grants.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HD015700E929442A69D3D83BF66D56A61" level="section">Sec. 7. Continuing funding for the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H7727221EA3AD45C98A2D74FA48CEC66F" level="section">Sec. 8. Access to satellite phone during Sea Year program.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 9. Assistance for small shipyards and maritime communities.</toc-entry></toc>
			</subsection></section><section id="H052FFE92C7EF45D1833B4F73A7F817FB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization of the Maritime Administration</header>
 <subsection id="H151222351D174F9C93201111ED6199F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Transportation for fiscal year 2018, to be available without fiscal year limitation if so provided in appropriations Acts, for programs associated with maintaining the United States merchant marine, the following amounts:</text>
 <paragraph id="HEC417BF7CF4148A5B2BAAFADC422405A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For expenses necessary for operations of the United States Merchant Marine Academy, $99,902,000, of which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H84A019E375D147618BCED3FE134D9025"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$74,851,000 shall be for Academy operations, including—</text> <clause id="HDB991A86A5374AA894B995F7295A3DA6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the implementation of section 3514(b) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017, as added by section 8; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD55E27D710E0432680E475A5E8BAFC98"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>staffing, training, and other actions necessary to prevent and respond to sexual harassment and sexual assault; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1904E1E4189B4A9198390551B86C3ACB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$25,051,000 shall remain available until expended for capital asset management at the Academy.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H60D84FA620374BD8B1F309C4E8B7A831"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For expenses necessary to support the State maritime academies, $29,550,000, of which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEFCB53D391F746F9BE49C0C2B4EDA630"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$2,400,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2018, for the Student Incentive Program;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H092F33D8F75C4C56992AE1B653E75524"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$3,000,000 shall remain available until expended for direct payments to such academies;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D3C89A6BEEB4D27BF3D527588B4A2F5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$22,000,000 shall remain available until expended for maintenance and repair of State maritime academy training vessels;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B84C0C05B514002AE3377FE56FE11F9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>$1,800,000 shall remain available until expended for training ship fuel assistance; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H589B67E47E0F444EA26752CA9C938A63"><enum>(E)</enum><text>$350,000 shall remain available until expended for expenses to improve the monitoring of the service obligations of graduates.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2ECC1A8B46348BC8D6527F20CF39BF2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For expenses necessary to support the National Security Multi-Mission Vessel Program, $36,000,000, which shall remain available until expended.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E540E3C8D3641458D2209F30BCCEBFF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For expenses necessary to support Maritime Administration operations and programs, $58,694,000.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B9C5227E3674878B88FC70B7B6AA39E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>For expenses necessary to dispose of vessels in the National Defense Reserve Fleet, $20,000,000, which shall remain available until expended.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8E465548317645E084FA84E2CA0CD7D8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>For administrative expenses associated with the program authorized under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/537">chapter 537</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, $3,000,000, which shall remain available until expended.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEA4DB7162FEE4ECA8B6DE023DF1B0CCA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assistance for small shipyards and maritime communities</header><text>Section 54101(i) of title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3D8AB50EDC8E4BE498BB5A67D2E1CB3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>2015 through 2017</quote> and inserting <quote>2018 through 2020</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD025171422CF4E3996BBB7756B29E643"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>$5,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$7,500,00</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF78E8F407EDA4220ACABCBAD3C08739B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>$25,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$27,500,000</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBF29425FCC674983B95E498C93A0E065"><enum>3.</enum><header>Removal adjunct professor limit at United States Merchant Marine Academy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 51317 of title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1DB2584C0F7D4AD28CD9331B8E213AF3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H29D76036EC294FF197CD7565D412CD5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H549EDB7CF1F2471995F208748E6B1043"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H27D0DBDFEF1040CCAC708ECACAA1E951"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subsections (c) and (d).</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H72624354925B42659E1EBE28239123E3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Acceptance of guarantees in conjunction with partial donations for major projects of the United States Merchant Marine Academy</header> <subsection id="H6EFC35FC54F74941BCDF7F2F719D762C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Guarantees</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/513">Chapter 513</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H556DAC950ECD457A9031816066715F4C" style="USC">
					<section id="H8E6B2E7E2E4246E69D3140EDD14D2154"><enum>51320.</enum><header>Acceptance of guarantees with gifts for major projects</header>
 <subsection id="H699BC6B25DAD43CAB528E788FDBAFFF0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H5C8DA2B38F064419BCD5EAC4B94ECEEC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Major project</header><text>The term <term>major project</term> means a project estimated to cost at least $1,000,000 for—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H781E8ABBF4BD41859598B02BC44668E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the purchase or other procurement of real or personal property; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDB375D307F54691BD10D48E366F8481"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the construction, renovation, or repair of real or personal property.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50AD4FD049244F42925BCBB5A9058008"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Major United States commercial bank</header><text>The term <term>major United States commercial bank</term> means a commercial bank that—</text> <subparagraph id="HCA042F17553A4843A94DFB9877259737"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is an insured bank (as defined in section 3(h) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813(h)</external-xref>));</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4535AB06BFB4C6BA7FB590EAC21EF5B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is headquartered in the United States; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E6EAF52594B455392BDBDF1BF752BAC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has total net assets of an amount considered by the Maritime Administrator to qualify the bank as a major bank.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H87D0165300324239AE81FCF839B24396"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Major United States investment management firm</header><text>The term <term>major United States investment management firm</term> means—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H5C2A0C14810643A9A836DF50AEB21542"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any broker or dealer (as such terms are defined in section 3 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c</external-xref>));</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0C6FF8009D964304834D19D5DE8D82CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any investment adviser or provider of investment supervisory services (as such terms are defined in section 202 of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80b-2">15 U.S.C. 80b–2</external-xref>)); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H245CDEAD8ED946C0BE8EF50E13CF1482"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a major United States commercial bank that—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HE12BA639AB7F43238945C1C409EADBDC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is headquartered in the United States; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8CBC8347FA534E13AE6B12860B81D6EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>holds for the account of others investment assets in a total amount considered by the Maritime Administrator to qualify the bank as a major investment management firm.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B6253DA006B4EBC8D7EA6400524A596"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualified guarantee</header><text>The term <term>qualified guarantee</term>, with respect to a major project, means a guarantee that—</text> <subparagraph id="H44F2B6C674CC42319D7166A9BB930D48"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is made by one or more persons in connection with a donation for the project of a total amount in cash or securities that the Maritime Administrator determines is sufficient to defray a substantial portion of the total cost of the project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18D783CA0B134486B8D05A0B7228D417"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is made to facilitate or expedite the completion of the project in reasonable anticipation that other donors will contribute sufficient funds or other resources in amounts sufficient to pay for completion of the project;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0AAE87097FF4F27A638F15C2633B220"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is set forth as a written agreement providing that the donor will furnish in cash or securities, in addition to the donor's other gift or gifts for the project, any additional amount that may become necessary for paying the cost of completing the project by reason of a failure to obtain from other donors or sources funds or other resources in amounts sufficient to pay the cost of completing the project; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6B5581E7F6E411A87E00A7A5BCB0976"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is accompanied by—</text> <clause id="HDE600CFCDDDA4C39B918B55D248B2910"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an irrevocable and unconditional standby letter of credit for the benefit of the United States Merchant Marine Academy that is in the amount of the guarantee and is issued by a major United States commercial bank; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H04B1ABE40DB241839B90E26046D87253"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a qualified account control agreement.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0BE2558ADCD4F0C961C024BF71ACF9B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Qualified account control agreement</header><text>The term <term>qualified account control agreement</term>, with respect to a guarantee of a donor, means an agreement among the donor, the Maritime Administrator, and a major United States investment management firm that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0407DEAA8653428C87C038826D6C2B4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensures the availability of sufficient funds or other financial resources to pay the amount guaranteed during the period of the guarantee;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7345144B474A4E199A09BCD4A8B7CEEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides for the perfection of a security interest in the assets of the account for the United States for the benefit of the United States Merchant Marine Academy with the highest priority available for liens and security interests under applicable law;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CE95B028B4A40CF9447E5C78282E855"><enum>(C)</enum><text>requires the donor to maintain in an account with the investment management firm assets having a total value that is not less than 130 percent of the amount guaranteed; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B8776BCDDCB4A7D8E9BA6FE51ACDCB1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>requires the investment management firm, whenever the value of the account is less than the value required to be maintained under subparagraph (C), to liquidate any noncash assets in the account and reinvest the proceeds in Treasury bills issued under section 3104 of title 31.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H747A93E8FE634C389E729355C0DCD33A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Acceptance authority</header><text>Subject to subsection (d), the Maritime Administrator may accept a qualified guarantee from a donor or donors for the completion of a major project for the benefit of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4FBD106DC5F941CFB7311E8693705A8B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Obligation authority</header><text>The amount of a qualified guarantee accepted under this section shall be considered as contract authority to provide obligation authority for purposes of Federal fiscal and contractual requirements. Funds available for a project for which such a guarantee has been accepted may be obligated and expended for the project without regard to whether the total amount of funds and other resources available for the project (not taking into account the amount of the guarantee) is sufficient to pay for completion of the project.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD57DCF776BEB4FC4B17A374F2C889E3B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The Maritime Administrator may not accept a qualified guarantee under this section for the completion of a major project until 30 days after the date on which a report of the facts concerning the proposed guarantee is submitted to Congress.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8ED18CA76C0D4263899C580F4D4C2F67"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibition on commingling funds</header><text>The Maritime Administrator may not enter into any contract or other transaction involving the use of a qualified guarantee and appropriated funds in the same contract or transaction.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6E1324E04FCD40228078AA621F951CD1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/513">chapter 513</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HD824F3D13D124CA29F7490134B7C55C4" style="USC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry idref="H8E6B2E7E2E4246E69D3140EDD14D2154" level="section">51320. Acceptance of guarantees with gifts for major projects.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H93CD8929517D49B6A997C37AF673AD8E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authority to pay conveyance or transfer expenses in connection with acceptance of a gift to the
 United States Merchant Marine Academy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 51315 of title 46, United States Code, is amended by inserting at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEDEFCF647EF847ED97D1B9AD5A786BB4" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H2833E1F596594DF59DFD7AFFD6A2D8C4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Payment of expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Maritime Administrator may pay all necessary expenses in connection with the conveyance or transfer of a gift, devise, or bequest accepted under this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H8A195B011A4B46FF8E4ED2415D2A789D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to participate in Federal, State or other research grants</header>
 <subsection id="HE852815F8F8047DF8607BE03A35267A3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Research grants</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/513">Chapter 513</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, as amended by sections 3 through 5, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE9D00FCD8AA4358A847B7E51E0FFE3F" style="USC">
					<section id="H005B33EF60714F97AC571626641350E2"><enum>51321.</enum><header>Grants for scientific and educational research</header>
 <subsection id="HDA9A6774684B498094425FC954916D4B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this section, the term <term>qualifying research grant</term> is a grant that—</text> <paragraph id="H6C7FA4670E5E4140BE4923C43E4F9BAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is awarded on a competitive basis by the Federal Government (except for the Department of Transportation), a State, a corporation, a fund, a foundation, an educational institution, or a similar entity that is organized and operated primarily for scientific or educational purposes; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9824B2DCBA94C1DAF699F6429D76F48"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is to be used to carry out a research project with a scientific or educational purpose.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0F4BC8A9DB2942B698DA8A2F97B883D9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Acceptance of qualifying research grants</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the United States Merchant Marine Academy may compete for and accept qualifying research grants if the work under the grant is to be carried out by a professor or instructor of the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="HB22CEB78A0254EAABAEA52BE6D9A34B5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration of grant funds</header>
 <paragraph id="H979C2263ADF34614B6B81533FEBFB395"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment of account</header><text>The Maritime Administrator shall establish a separate account for administering funds received from research grants under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H43E8CF975A504782AF885C7310B47D02"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of grant funds</header><text>The Superintendent shall use grant funds deposited into the account established pursuant to paragraph (1) in accordance with applicable regulations and the terms and conditions of the respective grants.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E5D4AAC4E11443A98C3569A7A70882C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Related expenses</header><text>Subject to such limitations as may be provided in appropriations Acts, appropriations available for the United States Merchant Marine Academy may be used to pay expenses incurred by the Academy in applying for, and otherwise pursuing, a qualifying research grant.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H66424E9295C343879ED6E6F631D15681"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/513">chapter 513</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, as amended by section 4(b), is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H49C9CB9CBA084FA592BDE54566D57162" style="USC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry idref="H005B33EF60714F97AC571626641350E2" level="section">51321. Grants for scientific and educational research.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="HD015700E929442A69D3D83BF66D56A61"><enum>7.</enum><header>Continuing funding for the United States Merchant Marine Academy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 51301 of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7F95143F66349CC8183F22FFB7BD1BC" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H048CECD724644787B86B47E2F1276714"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Continuing funding</header> <paragraph id="HEFF3BE1675474554948377C9116D64D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Out of any funds in the general fund of the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there are hereby appropriated such sums as may be necessary for operations of the United States Merchant Marine Academy for any period during which interim or full-year appropriations are not in effect for the United States Merchant Marine Academy, for fiscal year 2018, and for each fiscal year thereafter.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE45DC979A2F64F2D9F2C15EF8D907A65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Amounts made available for a fiscal year under this subsection shall remain available until the earlier of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H41C25346FBC84FC89481C0337A1E6C50"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the enactment into law of an appropriation for such fiscal year (including a continuing appropriation for such operations); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H294B6A2B75B146C1841AD22A5AFED6F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the enactment into law for the Maritime Administration of the applicable regular appropriation for such fiscal year, or continuing appropriations resolution for such fiscal year, without any appropriation for such operations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="H7727221EA3AD45C98A2D74FA48CEC66F"><enum>8.</enum><header>Access to satellite phone during Sea Year program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3514 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5C8019E6B74D428F86FBBD6FDCBD53FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Not later than</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B14D6727BE842F098110EBA77CD7485" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HA61860CFAD6B445F90618C2C99194974"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Vessel operator requirements</header><text>Not later than</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE532CBF0D195424AA8E7FB13575F4576"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC47D37F5FEE4420A59F885919C242D5" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H73A68DE7417B4038AE534506F74B337E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Satellite phone access</header><text>The Maritime Administrator shall ensure that each student participating in the Sea Year program is provided or has access to a functional satellite communication device. A student may not be denied from using such device whenever the student determines that such use is necessary to prevent or report sexual harassment or assault.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H11945EF150C645A395FD9403F4EC130B"><enum>9.</enum><header>Assistance for small shipyards and maritime communities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 54101 of title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H05ABAC0E4BB94E45B69506E1A8479A5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB59DD01679E14EDFA37C447016225BC8" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H84771879F1DC44DB967CAE18B05AB6AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Awards</header>
 <paragraph id="H15DD15E796734100964F5B3814B51D83"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In providing assistance under the program, the Administrator shall take into account—</text> <subparagraph id="HB99B954178474C698AE9EC89DB67222E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the economic circumstances and conditions of maritime communities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91E130242A35467CA10F6BEC1452F8A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>projects that would be effective in fostering efficiency, competitive operations, and quality ship construction, repair, and reconfiguration; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H194A5059A8214F449777BBD10FC022EB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>projects that would be effective in fostering employee skills and enhancing productivity.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6678C9D3A8B4298840591789CDFE5F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing of award</header> <subparagraph id="HCA0B55FFB71340078228BDE5D89E25C9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Administrator shall award grants under this section not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of the appropriations Act for the fiscal year concerned.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H708009C6027B4C749EDB84A2CAC18418"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reallocation of unused funds</header><text>If a grant is awarded under this section and, for any reason, the grant funds are not used by the grantee, the Administrator may reallocate such unused funds to award another grant under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF7C8C6756A0B46B49C91CA98383BCE9D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF040EBC748674976950DD618076ABB2F" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H51974372CC014481953F3218E60B77C7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Buy american</header> <subparagraph id="H4450668BD1004BA18705E7B0BEA03D33"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>A grant provided under this section may be used for a project only if the steel, iron, and manufactured goods used in the project are produced in the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC5269208137243219F670C4AFDF36CEC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Administrator may waive subparagraph (A) if the Administrator determines that the waiver would be permitted under section 5323(j)(2) of title 49.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


