<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE amendment-doc PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/amend.dtd//EN" "amend.dtd">
<amendment-doc amend-degree="first" amend-type="engrossed-amendment"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2288 EAS: Veterans Appeals Improvement and Modernization Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<engrossed-amendment-form>
<congress display="no">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="no">1st Session</session><legis-num display="no">H.R. 2288</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">In the Senate of the United States,</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20170801">August 1, 2017.</action-date></action><legis-type display="yes">Amendment:</legis-type></engrossed-amendment-form><engrossed-amendment-body><section id="id6cdadcc721104816824d13e30092b471" section-type="resolved"><text>That the bill from the House of Representatives (H.R. 2288) entitled <quote>An Act to amend title 38, United States Code, to reform the rights and processes relating to appeals of decisions regarding claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</quote>, do pass with the following</text></section><amendment><amendment-instruction blank-lines-after="0"><text>Strike all after the enacting clause and insert the following:</text></amendment-instruction><amendment-block blank-lines-after="1" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic"><section id="id9d1a3d11-e89b-4298-9f21-2dc397bed568" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Appeals Improvement and Modernization Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id1a6d8b97-39b9-4557-a5b5-4d19f703dcfa"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reform of rights and processes relating to appeals of decisions regarding claims for benefits under laws administered by Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="id569cd742-476f-4ce1-952d-85aa551852d1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 101 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbb37ff0b-89fb-404b-9f40-d761c3e8f185" style="OLC"><paragraph id="id1c71ec27-074e-4490-9929-9ee9b4aeac1d"><enum>(34)</enum><text>The term <term>agency of original jurisdiction</term> means the activity which entered the original determination with regard to a claim for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76254a4a-399b-40d8-b309-f52f09930088"><enum>(35)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>relevant evidence</term> means evidence that tends to prove or disprove a matter in issue.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb695a536-63b5-4be5-bb9a-b68f93b17d1e"><enum>(36)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>supplemental claim</term> means a claim for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary filed by a claimant who had previously filed a claim for the same or similar benefits on the same or similar basis.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id865723ce-4a62-40f8-a4ee-063d61384570"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice regarding claims</header><text>Section 5103(a) of such title is amended—</text><paragraph id="id02019ef4-0fd6-4107-8512-6f322a985fe8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>The</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b71f147-f1cc-46a1-8828-99b3c2b49b6b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(B)(i) by striking <quote>, a claim for reopening a prior decision on a claim, or a claim for an increase in benefits;</quote> and inserting <quote>or a supplemental claim;</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id63cdfe9b-a932-4c42-8581-7b065a7933e3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71e52409-2af1-4b6d-b889-43cb120cb58b" style="OLC"><paragraph id="idbbcb31c7-2704-4835-8dae-fe72273d7c24" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The requirement to provide notice under paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to a supplemental claim that is filed within the timeframe set forth in subparagraphs (B) and (D) of section 5110(a)(2) of this title.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1ca4537a-aa30-4bd9-be89-fde9ffcb52c9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Modification of rule regarding disallowed claims</header><text>Section 5103A(f) of such title is amended—</text><paragraph id="id5a7fc550-339e-4a9e-afc1-8f8578680362"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>reopen</quote> and inserting <quote>readjudicate</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8db77605-d111-4808-87bc-049a0a725be8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>material</quote> and inserting <quote>relevant</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf99875bd-bd4c-403b-a8ef-cdb413b410a9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Modification of duty to assist claimants</header><text>Section 5103A of such title is amended—</text><paragraph id="id2f1ad7f8-a71e-498b-a8c9-c0a99df59192"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (e) through (g) as subsections (g) through (i), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd645073-2510-48c4-8bfa-446befff175c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) the following new subsections:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66cebf8e-de07-4a11-a24d-9235ccd37d17" style="USC"><subsection id="id4b64d4e4-a6c0-49a8-a8f5-93cfba3a28d5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicability of duty to assist</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id34b991a0-7799-4684-bfb7-75bb25b8e725"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary’s duty to assist under this section shall apply only to a claim, or supplemental claim, for a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary until the time that a claimant is provided notice of the agency of original jurisdiction’s decision with respect to such claim, or supplemental claim, under section 5104 of this title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idac5c141f-2363-49ce-9401-e722137137af" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary’s duty to assist under this section shall not apply to higher-level review by the agency of original jurisdiction, pursuant to section 5104B of this title, or to review on appeal by the Board of Veterans’ Appeals.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id60f6c609-c05c-4012-9786-4750b6bff528"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Correction of duty to assist errors</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id9fe0c34a-8e83-4311-b0bb-a139d7ec2602"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If, during review of the agency of original jurisdiction decision under section 5104B of this title, the higher-level adjudicator identifies or learns of an error on the part of the agency of original jurisdiction to satisfy its duties under this section, and that error occurred prior to the agency of original jurisdiction decision being reviewed, unless the Secretary may award the maximum benefit in accordance with this title based on the evidence of record, the higher-level adjudicator shall return the claim for correction of such error and readjudication.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3533f04b-fa15-424d-8b52-6cc9425d4310" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idab5b037f-0bf7-46b4-9008-40805402c996"><enum>(A)</enum><text>If the Board of Veterans’ Appeals, during review on appeal of an agency of original jurisdiction decision, identifies or learns of an error on the part of the agency of original jurisdiction to satisfy its duties under this section, and that error occurred prior to the agency of original jurisdiction decision on appeal, unless the Secretary may award the maximum benefit in accordance with this title based on the evidence of record, the Board shall remand the claim to the agency of original jurisdiction for correction of such error and readjudication.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idff9008b4-1f9f-44a1-b32f-37303af1ac05" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Remand for correction of such error may include directing the agency of original jurisdiction to obtain an advisory medical opinion under section 5109 of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd41ac602-8ee0-4c04-b11f-be0c0c179fc6" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to imply that the Secretary, during the consideration of a claim, does not have a duty to correct an error described in paragraph (1) or (2) that was erroneously not identified during higher-level review or during review on appeal with respect to the claim.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd8983cd4-d47e-4351-bd54-e3cd20b92cec"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Decisions and notices of decisions</header><text>Subsection (b) of section 5104 of such title is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5127a6ad-30bf-48aa-8582-98f81248b56e" style="OLC"><subsection id="ide373bcaa-cea4-4c7f-974d-2d9034b84210"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Each notice provided under subsection (a) shall also include all of the following:</text><paragraph id="id9a12366e-da02-4458-8fc8-1e1bd0ca73bb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Identification of the issues adjudicated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id86b79eb9-2daa-47fc-9273-235f6f58d3c7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A summary of the evidence considered by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida310b506-efe8-495e-b727-72c67d520954"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A summary of the applicable laws and regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id76a80f2e-f21f-4279-a798-40a5342a55d1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Identification of findings favorable to the claimant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c399aa3-b783-4899-b13e-6912b8fc788f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In the case of a denial, identification of elements not satisfied leading to the denial.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd8ef3090-0452-4223-be2a-91207d3149f4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An explanation of how to obtain or access evidence used in making the decision.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida34dc172-490f-4212-9ec9-a47e4d66669a"><enum>(7)</enum><text>If applicable, identification of the criteria that must be satisfied to grant service connection or the next higher level of compensation.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id88eea0bb-5252-4991-baa2-4a19064ee51b"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Binding nature of favorable findings</header><paragraph id="idb173b1ad-fef9-44bc-a071-9d9184f1a059"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter 51 of such title is amended by inserting after section 5104 the following new section:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3edd18a7-8127-4e68-9f54-f4b69c684bc7" style="USC"><section id="id27e36a65-841f-4a68-86ee-ac24e88c6419"><enum>5104A.</enum><header>Binding nature of favorable findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any finding favorable to the claimant as described in section 5104(b)(4) of this title shall be binding on all subsequent adjudicators within the Department, unless clear and convincing evidence is shown to the contrary to rebut such favorable finding.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id3950ba41-35d1-46e4-8068-7bb39fa489d7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 51 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 5104 the following new item:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5ca2ee15-d9c6-4a9d-891b-5a770afe6e3c" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5104A. Binding nature of favorable findings.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd864098e-0ae9-4c57-82ff-1095264ad9dc"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Higher-level review by agency of original jurisdiction</header><paragraph id="id372a9204-6f7f-4443-8bc3-9fab329e7248"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter 51 of such title, as amended by subsection (f), is further amended by inserting after section 5104A, as added by such subsection, the following new section:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd7bcd7f-f38a-4b3f-82bf-e331e11de5d0" style="USC"><section id="id1071eb9b-7344-4937-8b79-57d4c1519cc5"><enum>5104B.</enum><header>Higher-level review by the agency of original jurisdiction</header><subsection id="idafe96e63-0db6-4768-b871-923b6f4532ad"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id11596816-2a37-4033-9edb-a415db4d29ba"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A claimant may request a review of the decision of the agency of original jurisdiction by a higher-level adjudicator within the agency of original jurisdiction.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf2369283-444a-44bc-ae2f-8d8882b2ac23" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall approve each request for review under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc1362144-74fe-4717-ad18-f8983f7c746b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Time and manner of request</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id69e40903-1584-4e55-a413-1a3841b70d13"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A request for higher-level review by the agency of original jurisdiction shall be—</text><subparagraph id="id7ca589f7-3641-4679-9b0b-5a244e44e17b" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in writing in such form as the Secretary may prescribe; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6e151f11-e2e8-43bc-adc1-49e62722affb" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>made within one year of the notice of the agency of original jurisdiction’s decision.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc9827ad3-38da-4bdb-8fc7-ae6259f1656b" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Such request may specifically indicate whether such review is requested by a higher-level adjudicator at the same office within the agency of original jurisdiction or by an adjudicator at a different office of the agency of original jurisdiction. The Secretary shall not deny such request for review by an adjudicator at a different office of the agency of original jurisdiction without good cause.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3943dff3-d2f4-4215-924f-748f355b2348"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Decision</header><text>Notice of a higher-level review decision under this section shall be provided in writing and shall include a general statement—</text><paragraph id="id6801f2d6-76a3-4bbc-accf-6f0c966a136e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reflecting whether evidence was not considered pursuant to subsection (d); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id569d19a9-545b-4789-b75b-1d9ca16443ed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>noting the options available to the claimant to have the evidence described in paragraph (1), if any, considered by the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3657a8a2-47b1-4c77-b9bf-09f93f019532"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evidentiary record for review</header><text>The evidentiary record before the higher-level adjudicator shall be limited to the evidence of record in the agency of original jurisdiction decision being reviewed.</text></subsection><subsection id="idd24ba234-1584-4fc0-80cc-664932c00b7c"><enum>(e)</enum><header>De novo review</header><text>A review of the decision of the agency of original jurisdiction by a higher-level adjudicator within the agency of original jurisdiction shall be de novo.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idb9023265-ce72-42cf-a38c-775bd45d7f1e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 51 of such title, as amended by subsection (f), is further amended by inserting after the item relating to section 5104A, as added by such subsection, the following new item:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf2cbaed5-90a4-4318-8f4a-34600f5bb2f6" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5104B. Higher-level review by the agency of original jurisdiction.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idccfef182-1ff2-479a-9ec3-0d2749b056cc"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Options following decision by agency of original jurisdiction</header><paragraph id="ide9f402d4-62fb-440c-a956-cde02810dccc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter 51 of such title, as amended by subsection (g), is further amended by inserting after section 5104B, as added by such subsection, the following new section:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id84526e93-9559-4b8a-830d-141789c1b7c4" style="USC"><section id="id4c667e32-90f6-41bb-8d07-504b340c88e6"><enum>5104C.</enum><header>Options following decision by agency of original jurisdiction</header><subsection id="id4ccf227a-cbc7-4123-81a6-343a481fd03a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Within one year of decision</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id181ef0df-0479-43f5-9966-49a5f793c24e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subject to paragraph (2), in any case in which the Secretary renders a decision on a claim, the claimant may take any of the following actions on or before the date that is one year after the date on which the agency of original jurisdiction issues a decision with respect to that claim:</text><subparagraph id="id2ee62c3a-7daa-48df-9fac-857706003281" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>File a request for higher-level review under section 5104B of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3cdf35d3-b5a3-4470-bdff-8f2248d21d13" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>File a supplemental claim under section 5108 of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7372145c-b0a9-4169-8317-009b232db765" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>File a notice of disagreement under section 7105 of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1109dc47-3106-4703-b930-4f9b6755d5c8" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id3dd5bea5-c6d7-490d-8db0-d577c6bdde08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Once a claimant takes an action set forth in paragraph (1), the claimant may not take another action set forth in that paragraph with respect to the same claim or same issue contained within the claim until—</text><clause id="id5838e923-c07d-4c93-b633-c861acd9f0b6" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the higher-level review, supplemental claim, or notice of disagreement is adjudicated; or</text></clause><clause id="id8bff1713-1870-413a-bbe9-3056df607589" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the request for higher-level review, supplemental claim, or notice of disagreement is withdrawn.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4253acb5-073c-4fd9-9b20-8b2efaac65f0" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit a claimant from taking any of the actions set forth in paragraph (1) in succession with respect to a claim or an issue contained within the claim.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddbd9d535-3df4-4317-aac5-3524563c9503" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit a claimant from taking different actions set forth in paragraph (1) with respect to different claims or different issues contained within a claim.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida87f300e-d69b-4d49-935f-39d5209a8b0e" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Secretary may, as the Secretary considers appropriate, develop and implement a policy for claimants who—</text><clause id="id6bad780a-802f-48cb-ac15-b2511c3f835d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>take an action under paragraph (1);</text></clause><clause id="id7a8f06dc-7eb8-4277-a0af-f099e2db26de"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>wish to withdraw the action before the higher-level review, supplemental claim, or notice of disagreement is adjudicated; and</text></clause><clause id="idccef697b-32a1-456e-8f2e-303d854fd785"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in lieu of such action take a different action under paragraph (1).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id244e6a6b-bcce-4a63-b775-e5e57491f22a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>More than one year after decision</header><text>In any case in which the Secretary renders a decision on a claim and more than one year has passed since the date on which the agency of original jurisdiction issues a decision with respect to that claim, the claimant may file a supplemental claim under section 5108 of this title.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="ida5bca471-5c8d-4855-bc25-c8db199dfaf8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 51 of such title, as amended by subsection (g), is further amended by inserting after the item relating to section 5104B, as added by such subsection, the following new item:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id916faba2-8618-4b31-baa2-60a96cd8c306" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5104C. Options following decision by agency of original jurisdiction.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3bf53565-fe31-451a-af69-a194274f4834"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Supplemental claims</header><paragraph id="id4271f789-fce5-439a-b0fb-c123f9ce121c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 5108 of such title is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e6bad46-0e68-42d8-904d-1e817ba925c9" style="USC"><section id="id35ede637-6448-49c4-8813-62c6fc5d6929"><enum>5108.</enum><header>Supplemental claims</header><subsection id="id943740595176483CA7B3310BE22D9232"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If new and relevant evidence is presented or secured with respect to a supplemental claim, the Secretary shall readjudicate the claim taking into consideration all of the evidence of record.</text></subsection><subsection id="id0BBF448C68A545A8A389A5AE3918015D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duty to assist</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id2C04D435B4344E2FB0A4A9857AA7BD2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a claimant, in connection with a supplemental claim, reasonably identifies existing records, whether or not in the custody of a Federal department or agency, the Secretary shall assist the claimant in obtaining the records in accordance with section 5103A of this title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2D4060DD1F374C2FA6C53072FD8D610E" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance under paragraph (1) shall not be predicated upon a finding that new and relevant evidence has been presented or secured.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id1AFD3680EA36413998295D94234714C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Section 5108 of such title, as amended by paragraph (1), shall not be construed to impose a higher evidentiary threshold than the new and material evidence standard that was in effect pursuant to such section on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfa8e0647-e543-48b8-9a21-d59d5e429d35"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 51 of such title is amended by striking the item relating to section 5108 and inserting the following new item:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7fe337a5-9812-4f3a-a6bf-3ed07f6734fd" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5108. Supplemental claims.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddce8c321-d398-4479-a084-6255aaef9ad7"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Remand to obtain advisory medical opinion</header><text>Section 5109 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7186c1f1-fbba-4963-9e41-ecbe423a6621" style="OLC"><subsection id="idd487574c-3ffa-427c-bc79-bcd64c181584"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id14e3ec4e-f879-45b5-8036-1f2ec5a1bb89"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Board of Veterans’ Appeals shall remand a claim to direct the agency of original jurisdiction to obtain an advisory medical opinion from an independent medical expert under this section if the Board finds that the Veterans Benefits Administration should have exercised its discretion to obtain such an opinion.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1fca71f3-758f-4fe1-a8f5-1fe8c6d5b371" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Board’s remand instructions shall include the questions to be posed to the independent medical expert providing the advisory medical opinion.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idd2ac223e-e342-4111-8daf-eb9fcc596470"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Restatement of requirement for expedited treatment of returned and remanded claims</header><paragraph id="idab86d56f-f3fc-4bd5-87c6-92da3212ef15"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 5109B of such title is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb913e0c7-d6db-4aa8-8314-fe06722fba64" style="USC"><section id="id3b05279c-d2d5-4cc6-b671-05a2cffe7a89"><enum>5109B.</enum><header>Expedited treatment of returned and remanded claims</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall take such actions as may be necessary to provide for the expeditious treatment by the Veterans Benefits Administration of any claim that is returned by a higher-level adjudicator under section 5104B of this title or remanded by the Board of Veterans' Appeals.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id47bd03da-af51-4931-9343-e3cb0b1add57"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 51 of such title is amended by striking the item relating to section 5109B and inserting the following new item:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id92d179ac-2db9-4b48-8901-e03b825e9cdb" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">5109B. Expedited treatment of returned and remanded claims.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8dc90e83-57f2-4db6-8ab6-d512788186e6"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Effective dates of awards</header><text>Section 5110 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id36afe0da-ac4b-4e51-9823-8afa9a0fae71"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subsection (a) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce9a9366-7374-4004-a4a9-cd1d50f2179b" style="OLC"><subsection id="idb9193445-4961-4990-a457-5c908b928f27"><enum>(a)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idfe8b046d-06b3-4a39-b856-2d4f118c419a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Unless specifically provided otherwise in this chapter, the effective date of an award based on an initial claim, or a supplemental claim, of compensation, dependency and indemnity compensation, or pension, shall be fixed in accordance with the facts found, but shall not be earlier than the date of receipt of application therefor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf7294e5c-b1e0-4603-b873-7a92900c1f8f" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For purposes of determining the effective date of an award under this section, the date of application shall be considered the date of the filing of the initial application for a benefit if the claim is continuously pursued by filing any of the following, either alone or in succession:</text><subparagraph id="idb966f3d4-114f-482e-9355-f9d542454a08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A request for higher-level review under section 5104B of this title on or before the date that is one year after the date on which the agency of original jurisdiction issues a decision.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4cf44ac3-24d0-489d-b3fa-7cd45db70591"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A supplemental claim under section 5108 of this title on or before the date that is one year after the date on which the agency of original jurisdiction issues a decision.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id07863ada-fc43-492c-859f-60ee408cf7f0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A notice of disagreement on or before the date that is one year after the date on which the agency of original jurisdiction issues a decision.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaa3adc38-b61f-49f4-83b0-594ca3785fa5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A supplemental claim under section 5108 of this title on or before the date that is one year after the date on which the Board of Veterans’ Appeals issues a decision.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96544a71-dbaa-4253-99f7-10cccf1af85b"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A supplemental claim under section 5108 of this title on or before the date that is one year after the date on which the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims issues a decision.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6428a38e-4c5e-455b-8b54-c04ae3124303" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, for supplemental claims received more than one year after the date on which the agency of original jurisdiction issued a decision or the Board of Veterans’ Appeals issued a decision, the effective date shall be fixed in accordance with the facts found, but shall not be earlier than the date of receipt of the supplemental claim.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idc61e0763-b5c5-444b-bf76-8251b8eefbd0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (i), in the first sentence—</text><subparagraph id="idde3a7872-e25a-44f6-9203-894f274281f9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>reopened</quote> and inserting <quote>readjudicated</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8203b5d1-3a06-4712-954f-6ca21b82968f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>material</quote> and inserting <quote>relevant</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc2783a4d-9d4d-46f0-b5e8-b99f0b2e7a68"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>reopening</quote> and inserting <quote>readjudication</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id32425736-1870-4d49-b556-d38c71f70c78"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Definition of award or increased award for purposes of provisions relating to commencement of period of payment</header><text>Section 5111(d)(1) of such title is amended by striking <quote>or reopened award</quote> and inserting <quote>award or award based on a supplemental claim</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb63ae10e-baf0-4627-b7b5-b92b4270b9ba"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Modification of limitation on fees allowable for representation</header><text>Section 5904(c) of such title is amended, in paragraphs (1) and (2), by striking <quote>notice of disagreement is filed</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>claimant is provided notice of the agency of original jurisdiction’s initial decision under section 5104 of this title</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc07b15b0-117f-4913-bd17-0853bbfdaf63"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Clarification of Board of Veterans' Appeals referral requirements after order for reconsideration
			 of
 decisions</header><text>Section 7103(b)(1) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>heard</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>decided</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7d8ec16a-88a2-400b-8e5f-8b4b678017fd"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Conforming amendment relating to readjudication</header><text>Section 7104(b) of such title is amended by striking <quote>reopened</quote> and inserting <quote>readjudicated</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb3ae3e9a-3c2f-4051-ba2f-ef94e1d71d01"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Modification of procedures for appeals to Board of Veterans' Appeals</header><paragraph id="id220d261d-9637-4b51-8c25-49d3772e2cc8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 7105 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="idc1102855-4f77-4dce-9c6b-889804a9b31c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking the first sentence and inserting <quote>Appellate review shall be initiated by the filing of a notice of disagreement in the form prescribed by the Secretary.</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida1fbfb11-08fc-47fc-90b3-cc84e26b7622"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending subsection (b) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9fdb2b77-1aa5-4f1b-a99b-76632bf58b18" style="OLC"><subsection id="id7ee18e0f-767e-4002-8324-ed4edcd158ec"><enum>(b)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idafb2fb3a-c185-4261-90f8-fa7429a1e13e"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id290aa930-f41b-418d-9c53-267009e23cf2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except in the case of simultaneously contested claims, a notice of disagreement shall be filed within one year from the date of the mailing of notice of the decision of the agency of original jurisdiction pursuant to section 5104, 5104B, or 5108 of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7d0b3d12-282b-48fd-af0e-9a7489f0e279" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A notice of disagreement postmarked before the expiration of the one-year period shall be accepted as timely filed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idec5a8152-36d9-4f45-883d-17b15f17911f" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A question as to timeliness or adequacy of the notice of disagreement shall be decided by the Board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide44fea96-7899-4fe8-9d9d-e311d4716041" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id2fcd828d-5b63-4768-b2d3-9675d0ad809e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Notices of disagreement shall be in writing, shall identify the specific determination with which the claimant disagrees, and may be filed by the claimant, the claimant's legal guardian, or such accredited representative, attorney, or authorized agent as may be selected by the claimant or legal guardian.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id49c2a1c9-e6bc-4b1e-8676-c6873f84dd78" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not more than one recognized organization, attorney, or agent may be recognized at any one time in the prosecution of a claim.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb7e57f3a-7a46-480a-8fbd-cb3018f21820" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Notices of disagreement shall be filed with the Board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c5924a0-ac1c-44af-86b6-f26a140c52af" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The notice of disagreement shall indicate whether the claimant requests—</text><subparagraph id="id61254e2d-daf6-4832-a837-8435d0c07911"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a hearing before the Board, which shall include an opportunity to submit evidence in accordance with section 7113(b) of this title;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6848e4cf-d339-4354-aaf3-cf0cbcf6d5aa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an opportunity to submit additional evidence without a hearing before the Board, which shall include an opportunity to submit evidence in accordance with section 7113(c) of this title; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd6cb09b5-06b4-4050-9c0f-ff60760daeae"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a review by the Board without a hearing or the submittal of additional evidence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfda51338-3325-4bde-b2fa-5f086b37ef1e" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary shall develop a policy to permit a claimant to modify the information identified in the notice of disagreement after the notice of disagreement has been filed under this section pursuant to such requirements as the Secretary may prescribe.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd6e4874f-49a9-4f5f-81a8-a30142d45f31"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by amending subsection (c) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide0c2ee18-2b6e-40bd-bd7a-6ed6ca98387b" style="OLC"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id257b0592-5078-4ccf-8caa-18bca934556e"><enum>(c)</enum><text>If no notice of disagreement is filed in accordance with this chapter within the prescribed period, the action or decision of the agency of original jurisdiction shall become final and the claim shall not thereafter be readjudicated or allowed, except—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21DF6BF8360849F88FDAEF5AE80CDCDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of a readjudication or allowance pursuant to a higher-level review that was requested in accordance with section 5104B of this title;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7117568C4DF04DFCB5C05BD79886414A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as may otherwise be provided by section 5108 of this title; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA4CB4D32B31E4C7CB202090E31F80BA8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>as may otherwise be provided in such regulations as are consistent with this title.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7d97aff5-b2ee-44f5-b90d-021a036de541"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d) and inserting the following new subsection (d):</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d8e972c-99f5-49a2-8d37-6f032c3c55e7" style="OLC"><subsection id="id31479a52-d9c2-43c6-9481-003006340f21"><enum>(d)</enum><text>The Board may dismiss any appeal which fails to identify the specific determination with which the claimant disagrees.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9bdfdebe-034e-47db-a539-2a64bf490b55"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by striking subsection (e); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide214e70b-e0b3-4ee6-b096-043d1fbfb777"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">notice of disagreement and</header-in-text></quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idee36f295-eaf8-494d-b45a-978d46257543"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 71 of such title is amended by striking the item relating to section 7105 and inserting the following new item:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9bf62d48-d8b2-46c8-b16d-efa114f9a5cc" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">7105. Filing of appeal.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida4e400f7-9d0d-41ed-babb-d998c19ae7a5"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Modification of procedures and requirements for simultaneously contested claims</header><text>Subsection (b) of section 7105A of such title is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b6cc8e3-5e84-4881-a1cf-faea79616b7a" style="OLC"><subsection id="id7b6d3da0-2af4-40ce-9eec-ee3a68b93275"><enum>(b)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="ida0d170a8-61da-45c0-9378-b278665df3b8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The substance of the notice of disagreement shall be communicated to the other party or parties in interest and a period of thirty days shall be allowed for filing a brief or argument in response thereto.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb6887c84-1f49-4453-b8a7-2a0f7cb3287d" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Such notice shall be forwarded to the last known address of record of the parties concerned, and such action shall constitute sufficient evidence of notice.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idc25fd8a9-b9b7-4357-bb19-d6f269589503"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Repeal of procedures for administrative appeals</header><paragraph id="id422853dc-90e5-413f-b4b2-58dd3449a005"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter 71 of such title is amended by striking section 7106.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaae6454b-dc51-4580-8da6-b463d51e291a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 71 of such title is amended by striking the item relating to section 7106.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id35e9813d-a099-45b7-acad-07e46a6a72e0"><enum>(t)</enum><header>Modifications relating to appeals: dockets; hearings</header><text>Section 7107 of such title is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id626009a4-4302-4544-9d01-3996d4f48e9e" style="USC"><section id="id2d1d22df-12fc-4e7b-8835-aa5adc89ba6d"><enum>7107.</enum><header>Appeals: dockets; hearings</header><subsection id="idf034f6b9-44d0-43c8-8783-2bd1c6004af2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Dockets</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idda3bcdf1-ff79-4490-a141-27e12fb49e19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the Board shall maintain at least two separate dockets.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida7d924cc-9999-4c6b-ab4c-0c138c4d45c4" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Board may not maintain more than two separate dockets unless the Board notifies the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives of any additional docket, including a justification for maintaining such additional docket.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id34b9d30a-f6e1-4e55-9f73-8c29d35eeb38" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id07af908c-89be-4b8f-be8d-cb9ef92c5f18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Board may assign to each docket maintained under paragraph (1) such cases as the Board considers appropriate, except that cases described in clause (i) of subparagraph (B) may not be assigned to any docket to which cases described in clause (ii) of such paragraph are assigned.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id682774fd-70d7-44b9-b156-8665b23cef84" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Cases described in this paragraph are the following:</text><clause id="id9650565b-907f-4c55-a900-b6540a001aa4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Cases in which no Board hearing is requested.</text></clause><clause id="id16f615f0-e8d9-4f45-844b-2546bd8dc5cc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Cases in which a Board hearing is requested in the notice of disagreement.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide60f6fea-4a0b-4be5-b701-9d0f2537393f" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), each case before the Board will be decided in regular order according to its respective place on the docket to which it is assigned by the Board.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id795536ca-535b-4f77-8fcc-9bbee3e626eb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advancement on the docket</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id48b4aa66-ed07-4318-99f7-6164d1e649cd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A case on one of the dockets of the Board maintained under subsection (a) may, for cause shown, be advanced on motion for earlier consideration and determination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6de006a5-66fc-40a4-ab5d-3c8011db4788" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any such motion shall set forth succinctly the grounds upon which the motion is based.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf48c66ba-9941-4179-afa4-96179157f0a7" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Such a motion may be granted only—</text><subparagraph id="ideca1d20c-baa0-401a-89fe-59a5f0af5a9e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the case involves interpretation of law of general application affecting other claims;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id434fe6d5-0243-47d3-b2e0-636254530f73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the appellant is seriously ill or is under severe financial hardship; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc2302f75-114e-48e5-b887-dfd9120ec636"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for other sufficient cause shown.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfda76c88-be05-4404-a133-402466253231"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Manner and scheduling of hearings for cases on a docket that may include a hearing</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id5137eadc-41c7-441a-8160-82b4d8bcd796"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For cases on a docket maintained by the Board under subsection (a) that may include a hearing, in which a hearing is requested in the notice of disagreement, the Board shall notify the appellant whether a Board hearing will be held—</text><subparagraph id="id4bd37903-3773-4478-a5b8-28859d113f78" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at its principal location; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0c6e347e-5daf-4c89-8f9f-6ee41abd3df4" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by picture and voice transmission at a facility of the Department where the Secretary has provided suitable facilities and equipment to conduct such hearings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id69080aa6-e712-4273-bf7c-a5f9fed58e55" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id368d2902-1379-41b4-a4b2-807ffac0ad86"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Upon notification of a Board hearing at the Board’s principal location as described in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1), the appellant may alternatively request a hearing as described in subparagraph (B) of such paragraph. If so requested, the Board shall grant such request.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcdcd6116-7a7b-469d-9fd9-8dbc0f7c5920" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Upon notification of a Board hearing by picture and voice transmission as described in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1), the appellant may alternatively request a hearing as described in subparagraph (A) of such paragraph. If so requested, the Board shall grant such request.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8937560d-5c53-47cb-a106-137a225c8db4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Screening of cases</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to preclude the screening of cases for purposes of—</text><paragraph id="ideb07921d-eb01-4fed-be39-4ed4c3b40020"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determining the adequacy of the record for decisional purposes; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc38162ef-ed36-4bda-92a0-1f76214fb687"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the development, or attempted development, of a record found to be inadequate for decisional purposes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9ee3903d-20c4-4866-8abd-554e18fc85e9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Policy on changing dockets</header><text>The Secretary shall develop and implement a policy allowing an appellant to move the appellant's case from one docket to another docket.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id327db6b5-5186-49a4-b338-eda112d00b02"><enum>(u)</enum><header>Repeal of certain authority for independent medical opinions</header><paragraph id="id5cc2d4ee-a41a-4b59-9f52-b7f8b654544e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 7109 of such title is repealed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddbc2a952-6544-413c-9670-18cfc874d650"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 5701(b)(1) of such title is amended by striking <quote>or 7109</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id35f724c0-00bc-4549-a288-0601d00bb7d5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 71 of such title is amended by striking the item relating to section 7109.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id484c317c-62c3-440e-adf9-da25d4cfea00"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Clarification of procedures for review of decisions on grounds of clear and unmistakable error</header><text>Section 7111(e) of such title is amended by striking <quote>, without referral to any adjudicative or hearing official acting on behalf of the Secretary</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="id6fe81a6c-40fb-4fb2-82af-acf40ae60802"><enum>(w)</enum><header>Evidentiary record before Board of Veterans' Appeals</header><paragraph id="id4f82c99b-0fbd-4ac3-87b6-2ef977a74063"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter 71 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id02dca12c-ea71-43d9-a279-d049949bd51c" style="USC"><section id="id40ba986f-711c-490c-a5b8-60855e86d5c6"><enum>7113.</enum><header>Evidentiary record before the Board of Veterans' Appeals</header><subsection id="id94f61f79-a8cb-4476-8e46-e2e8f2f1add3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cases with no request for a hearing or additional evidence</header><text>For cases in which a hearing before the Board of Veterans' Appeals is not requested in the notice of disagreement and no request was made to submit evidence, the evidentiary record before the Board shall be limited to the evidence of record at the time of the decision of the agency of original jurisdiction on appeal.</text></subsection><subsection id="id475a3207-cf10-4180-a43b-5a39b42b2673"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cases with a request for a hearing</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id753d147e-37ad-4aa2-90bf-322a071e9c86"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), for cases in which a hearing is requested in the notice of disagreement, the evidentiary record before the Board shall be limited to the evidence of record at the time of the decision of the agency of original jurisdiction on appeal.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida2c16576-c4f9-4e02-8407-adc6b21b0548" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The evidentiary record before the Board for cases described in paragraph (1) shall include each of the following, which the Board shall consider in the first instance:</text><subparagraph id="id935228be-8b9a-44e5-b95f-35593a2bfb3b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Evidence submitted by the appellant and his or her representative, if any, at the Board hearing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id74a164a4-116b-41c2-a4af-530361a899af"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Evidence submitted by the appellant and his or her representative, if any, within 90 days following the Board hearing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2c027575-12f5-4a99-adb0-babac5a679de"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cases with no request for a hearing and with a request for additional evidence</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idca87c4b7-6937-4997-afb1-e81b1e356de1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), for cases in which a hearing is not requested in the notice of disagreement but an opportunity to submit evidence is requested, the evidentiary record before the Board shall be limited to the evidence considered by the agency of original jurisdiction in the decision on appeal.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idab2daf07-f9d2-4f26-9fe5-1c73ff5c5a7b" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The evidentiary record before the Board for cases described in paragraph (1) shall include each of the following, which the Board shall consider in the first instance:</text><subparagraph id="idafcd0865-b60c-46cb-99b8-deb2981c3863"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Evidence submitted by the appellant and his or her representative, if any, with the notice of disagreement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0d20d22d-bc52-4dd5-95ab-fcf5e575d608"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Evidence submitted by the appellant and his or her representative, if any, within 90 days following receipt of the notice of disagreement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id9185e194-d7d7-4b28-b1f5-65b345970f79"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification when evidence not considered</header><text>Section 7104(d) of such title is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id0e796696-52bc-4ac2-bff7-f89c63b834aa"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id97216fda-8612-4eef-bc6a-8a2cb6871941"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (2) as paragraph (3); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id975ada4f-d2b3-4964-974a-21ad8fe713cf"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following new paragraph (2):</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5197bcef-9f3c-4b08-9bc7-f219b34a9a50" style="OLC"><paragraph id="ide73f66b1-992f-4a7e-a21e-9126aeda1133"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a general statement—</text><subparagraph id="id01eb28d7-788c-4621-90b7-d6ec685f4a00"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reflecting whether evidence was not considered in making the decision because the evidence was received at a time when not permitted under section 7113 of this title; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id974f365e-9ee7-468a-ad51-c950c38c7a20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>noting such options as may be available for having the evidence considered by the Department; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8f610211-8378-40c4-8c4b-6e7247a6947a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 71 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7112 the following new item:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1334d8d7-4499-4eb7-b8db-5928c35c6656" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">7113. Evidentiary record before the Board of Veterans' Appeals.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id26103d3d-d32e-45fe-b094-07778bbde678"><enum>(x)</enum><header>Applicability</header><paragraph id="ide70610a8-7ac0-4c5e-abf4-014772329ad9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the amendments made by this section shall apply to all claims for which notice of a decision under section 5104 of title 38, United States Code, is provided by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs on or after the later of—</text><subparagraph id="id94f9421c-197d-432c-b475-e54a5ee7662e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date that is 540 days after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id75206ac4-efa0-4e1a-972e-728269799eaa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date that is 30 days after the date on which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs submits to the appropriate committees of Congress—</text><clause id="id71FA16549ED54109872626C3BB8D3E3A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a certification that the Secretary confirms, without delegation, that the Department of Veterans Affairs has the resources, personnel, office space, procedures, and information technology required—</text><subclause id="id5249f6bd-79a7-4854-a48f-249e7d0b676b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to carry out the new appeals system;</text></subclause><subclause id="id242c737e-27c7-4d9c-9bf2-5ee6ecc42ed9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to timely address appeals under the new appeals system; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id569494FD46F94C8BBA6E9B9FB9D162C0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to timely address appeals of decisions on legacy claims; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idCAC3B0F83B5E44B79EBAA76C1DCA533B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a summary of the expectations for performance outcomes that the Secretary used in making the certification under clause (i)(III) and a comparison of such expected performance outcomes with actual performance outcomes with respect to appeals of legacy claims before the effective date of the new appeals system.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b11fc8e-5e14-4a2d-8622-c68288c88084"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>In determining whether and when to make a certification under paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary shall collaborate with, partner with, and give weight to the advice of veterans service organizations and such other stakeholders as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9979b0d5-b3fe-4925-a8b8-534c8959949e"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Early applicability</header><text>The Secretary may apply the new appeals system to a claim with respect to which the claimant—</text><subparagraph id="id26f72a7e-2e48-442f-8b93-299733398ed9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>receives a notice of a decision under section 5104 of such title after the date of the enactment of this Act and before the applicability date set forth in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6d15b74e-52a2-45c1-97e3-092ea70eca6e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>elects to subject the claim to the new appeals system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id30c2464d-ca09-4f4a-b04e-7eb739a418fc"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Phased rollout</header><text>The Secretary may begin implementation of the new appeals system in phases, with the first phase of such phased implementation beginning on the applicability date set forth in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc675abaf-0c15-41d6-b8c1-f3658ced7c54"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Treatment of legacy claims</header><text>With respect to legacy claims, upon the issuance to a claimant of a statement of the case or supplemental statement of the case occurring on or after the applicability date specified in paragraph (1), a claimant may elect to participate in the new appeals system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6cd22238-dbb9-44f7-aec4-43cd8b255782"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Publication of applicability date</header><text>Not later than the date on which the new appeals system goes into effect (or the first phase of the new appeals system goes into effect under paragraph (4), as the case may be), the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register such date.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8bc4592c-dad3-4aba-a27a-e5b9419ee9f5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="id32287ec6-d414-4dc6-a00d-5d894ad35537"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><clause id="idca656ca1-14be-4b17-84f8-d5ef1a7922d4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans' Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></clause><clause id="idfdebe6e1-46b5-46aa-acb2-c2f6681b0901"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans' Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8ab6cb59-c0bc-46c5-9e0a-74117bedd400"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Veterans service organization</header><text>The term <term>veterans service organization</term> means any organization recognized by the Secretary for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of title 38, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id34aed86a-13d8-4df0-8606-6520bd1aa22a"><enum>(y)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section or any of the amendments made by this section shall be construed to limit the ability of a claimant to request a revision of a decision under section 5109A or 7111 of title 38, United States Code.</text></subsection></section><section id="id5c0d1233-0635-477c-ac0f-e21c352d80f9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Comprehensive plan for processing of legacy appeals and
 implementing new appeals system</header><subsection id="idfe676d4a-14f7-4bf2-b9cf-56ba0d5e13a3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plan required</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress and the Comptroller General of the United States a comprehensive plan for—</text><paragraph id="idff63017f-713e-4cfb-b1b3-e04de792f48c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the processing of appeals of decisions on legacy claims that the Secretary considers pending;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc63158f1-aa0e-47fd-8b1e-b11ff16673fd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implementing the new appeals system;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idba26dfab-c3a5-417c-83d0-29e99fed4a19"><enum>(3)</enum><text>timely processing, under the new appeals system, of—</text><subparagraph id="id9c55f4f4-89cd-4889-a7b8-a3e8e4c28039"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supplemental claims under section 5108 of title 38, United States Code, as amended by section 2(i);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfa14a48d-6299-4aef-8305-8b73415eae76"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requests for higher-level review under section 5104B of such title, as added by section 2(g); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae4e7334-5dd8-41b2-991c-c1a151b497c1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>appeals on any docket maintained under section 7107 of such title, as amended by section 2(t); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id16d42830-d7f2-443f-a4fb-89e1564467c7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>monitoring the implementation of the new appeals system, including metrics and goals—</text><subparagraph id="ida3df6f96-5faa-4a8d-bbbd-ec56e90ef0f7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to track the progress of the implementation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7f0ba811-5be3-49c9-9bb9-131c4be1e859"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to evaluate the efficiency and effectiveness of the implementation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb76df3fe-8317-4df6-9e66-d6588006af30"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to identify potential issues relating to the implementation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idab395395-e09b-4191-b80b-877fa1cc846e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The plan required by subsection (a) shall include, at a minimum, the following:</text><paragraph id="id538518bd-e95b-4d84-bbcd-feaaf7e13508"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Delineation of the total resource requirements of the Veterans Benefits Administration and the Board of Veterans’ Appeals, disaggregated by resources required to implement and administer the new appeals system and resources required to address the appeals of decisions on legacy claims.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1b213168-ad3e-4fe4-9e4d-e11119db8903"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Delineation of the personnel requirements of the Administration and the Board, including staffing levels during the—</text><subparagraph id="idcd3891c2-4729-4cd3-a46f-63cb0c4fa337"><enum>(A)</enum><text>period in which the Administration and the Board are concurrently processing—</text><clause id="id32ceaaa8-2cd9-470f-8e18-ded4c528f431"><enum>(i)</enum><text>appeals of decisions on legacy claims; and</text></clause><clause id="id08c615dd-cb07-4f4b-9ee8-0672da527bde"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>appeals of decisions on non-legacy claims under the new appeals system; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida13a393d-6849-46db-b858-296d18a35a56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the period during which the Administration and the Board are no longer processing any appeals of decisions on legacy claims.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id507a2fd5-fa56-49d1-ad76-5627fdb86bc3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Identification of the legal authorities under which the Administration or the Board may—</text><subparagraph id="id56c9acb5-dc7a-4d4f-a9ab-56c095de54e1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hire additional employees to conduct the concurrent processing described in paragraph (2)(A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62251e9a-6fcf-4316-b314-a0e07bf9d63f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>remove employees who are no longer required by the Administration or the Board once the Administration and the Board are no longer processing any appeals of decisions on legacy claims.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide7f97d9e-f885-4fb4-acfb-de28b1b0498b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An estimate of the amount of time the Administration and the Board will require to hire additional employees as described in paragraph (3)(A) once funding has been made available for such purpose, including a comparison of such estimate and the historical average time required by the Administration and the Board to hire additional employees.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2A0795C8043F4DDD8BC47DB7C96F80BD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of the amount of training and experience that will be required of individuals conducting higher-level reviews under section 5104B of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 2(g).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA2A1CDC7491140029BE3851577C63EEF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An estimate of the percentage of higher-level adjudicators who will be employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs who were Decision Review Officers on the day before the new appeals system takes effect or had experience, as of such date, comparable to that of one who was a Decision Review Officer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6EFE2E90810248698877DD5D2C62EB44"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A description of the functions that will be performed after the date on which the new appeals system takes effect by Decision Review Officers who were Decision Review Officers on the day before the date the new appeals system takes effect.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2aff9608-e5c4-4f9e-aead-caa16d65992e"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Identification of and a timeline for—</text><subparagraph id="idbf386b3f-ac47-4592-bfd2-eac9ef1d446f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any training that may be required as a result of hiring new employees to carry out the new appeals system or to process appeals of decisions on legacy claims; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbba59bca-fab9-4b3d-ba05-feb8bd19aaea"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any retraining of existing employees that may be required to carry out such system or to process such claims.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfe0b9b9a-2c83-422f-94a8-952bc410923e"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Identification of the costs to the Department of Veterans Affairs of the training identified under paragraph (8) and any additional training staff and any additional training facilities that will be required to provide such training.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7bb60aa9-679d-464c-9f07-33f9952d9ac0"><enum>(10)</enum><text>A description of the modifications to the information technology systems of the Administration and the Board that the Administration and the Board require to carry out the new appeals system, including cost estimates and a timeline for making the modifications.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id14a3ae36-0656-4f76-bde3-d3fb81d053c8"><enum>(11)</enum><text>An estimate of the office space the Administration and the Board will require during each of the periods described in paragraph (2), including—</text><subparagraph id="id7ef8a297-35be-4bad-8a53-33d3b3912db3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an estimate of the amount of time the Administration and the Board will require to acquire any additional office space to carry out processing of appeals of decisions on legacy claims and processing of appeals under the new appeals system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idff6458e9-7f2c-433c-9679-a3fe8007a4e4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a comparison of the estimate under subparagraph (A) and the historical average time required by the Administration and the Board to acquire new office space; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id389cf749-d349-4910-90a1-708117faebf0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a plan for using telework to accommodate staff exceeding available office space, including how the Administration and the Board will provide training and oversight with respect to such teleworking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3acdb9cc-921f-4290-88b2-4ea412e958a2"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Projections for the productivity of individual employees at the Administration and the Board in carrying out tasks relating to the processing of appeals of decisions on legacy claims and appeals under the new appeals system, taking into account the experience level of new employees and the enhanced notice requirements under section 5104(b) of title 38, United States Code, as amended by section 2(e).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idce2cbd32-6fff-46ab-aeaa-41f03980cd0c"><enum>(13)</enum><text>An outline of the outreach the Secretary expects to conduct to inform veterans, families of veterans, survivors of veterans, veterans service organizations, military service organizations, congressional caseworkers, advocates for veterans, and such other stakeholders as the Secretary considers appropriate about the new appeals system, including—</text><subparagraph id="ida8e20e49-d8b1-41e7-8046-e9e064f7e105"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the resources required to conduct such outreach; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0767d3af-f73e-4b97-ad88-c52086673202"><enum>(B)</enum><text>timelines for conducting such outreach.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id703001e0-aeec-4567-879d-fb0cc05f33f6"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Timelines for updating any policy guidance, Internet websites, and official forms that may be necessary to carry out the new appeals system, including—</text><subparagraph id="id19494b19-9c6a-40ba-80aa-62957e083b71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identification of which offices and entities will be involved in efforts relating to such updating; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id72f1b438-69cc-4906-a286-13d7bd9ea895"><enum>(B)</enum><text>historical information about how long similar update efforts have taken.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id37378dcc-554b-41df-bb97-1264b224908e"><enum>(15)</enum><text>A timeline, including interim milestones, for promulgating such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the new appeals system and a comparison with historical averages for time required to promulgate regulations of similar complexity and scope.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id447ffe29-6fb8-492c-8f40-0b304dc34f5a"><enum>(16)</enum><text>An outline of the circumstances under which claimants with pending appeals of decisions on legacy claims would be authorized to have their appeals reviewed under the new appeals system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida5c976bc-26d1-4edf-8f15-64a4037fcf9c"><enum>(17)</enum><text>A delineation of the key goals and milestones for reducing the number of pending appeals that are not processed under the new appeals system, including the expected number of appeals, remands, and hearing requests at the Administration and the Board each year, beginning with the one year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, until there are no longer any appeals pending before the Administration or the Board for a decision on a legacy claim.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfbf14a6d-00e9-49a8-9774-1b1b29a3741e"><enum>(18)</enum><text>A description of each risk factor associated with each element of the plan and a contingency plan to minimize each such risk.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd7e5aae1-6863-4605-8787-dd8c4f8428e2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review by Comptroller General of the United States</header><paragraph id="ide9b30e67-674c-49a4-ab07-c4f72a011423"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the Comptroller General of the United States receives the plan required by subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall—</text><subparagraph id="id2a6bc747-d8e3-4701-aea5-61025cb33453"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assess such plan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id441db303-0f60-43b1-b974-bdc7f793a23d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notify the appropriate committees of Congress of the findings of the Comptroller General with respect to the assessment conducted under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd3cc5be8-78b1-4ffb-bb97-633e9967b695"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The assessment conducted under paragraph (1)(A) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="ide08a63e0-0910-4835-9e9d-e29f9fb3fc21"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of whether the plan comports with sound planning practices.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id49029eec-0848-413a-83fc-d90f7ab0a2b6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Identification of any gaps in the plan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc276a4f1-122b-4ec5-b185-87495edeb6f2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Formulation of such recommendations as the Comptroller General considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ideccd2cf7-0909-4339-ae7a-a515840b4f35"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Periodic progress reports</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which the Secretary submits the plan under subsection (a), not less frequently than once every 90 days thereafter until the applicability date set forth in section 2(x)(1), and not less frequently than once every 180 days thereafter for the seven-year period following such applicability date, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress and the Comptroller General a report on the progress of the Secretary in carrying out the plan and what steps, if any, the Secretary has taken to address any recommendations formulated by the Comptroller General pursuant to subsection (c)(2)(C).</text></subsection><subsection id="id3FF6F40661B9413D9FA725135D517E9C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Secretary shall make available to the public on an Internet website of the Department of Veterans Affairs—</text><paragraph id="idA087EE5565CF4F7986FDC3CACAC5FCF4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the plan required by subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idCF70C754EAB34823B4F0986AF2C6829F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the periodic progress reports required by subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id96cc7bd1-b760-498f-a91e-91b0cb699664"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><paragraph id="id2169fd57-a49e-478c-b813-79b21cf03634"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans' Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a7c0fe7-74d4-4972-a7ab-0fd9cdbf035d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans' Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id9e2f4b9a-8b2d-4673-afae-d75012a6626c"><enum>4.</enum><header>Programs to test assumptions relied on in development of comprehensive plan for processing of
			 legacy appeals and
 supporting new appeals system</header><subsection id="idb4b9ba04-bb14-4879-b53b-7153931dea50"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><paragraph id="id20c83b3d-14e4-4a81-be2f-9389291866a1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may carry out such programs as the Secretary considers appropriate to test any assumptions relied upon in developing the comprehensive plan required by section 3(a) and to test the feasibility and advisability of any facet of the new appeals system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id480ca0d2-08da-4fc2-97a9-6196f1fb0eb8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting required</header><text>Whenever the Secretary determines, based on the conduct of a program under paragraph (1), that legislative changes to the new appeals system are necessary, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives notice of such determination.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2d782345-307e-4ae9-bd89-c72171f37e8c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs program on fully developed appeals</header><paragraph id="id09c6a9b3-78b4-4c3f-90c5-94ee3063bc04"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may, under subsection (a)(1), carry out a program to provide the option of an alternative appeals process that shall more quickly determine such appeals in accordance with this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idccfd139a-d856-4571-8c85-f3378fba4454"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Election</header><subparagraph id="id508f081b-bc67-4be3-b038-3559b161a9b2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Filing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with subparagraph (B), a claimant may elect to file a fully developed appeal under the program by filing with the Secretary all of the following:</text><clause id="ide9091cd9-f4a6-4f9b-bce1-c390a0fb1c79"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The notice of disagreement under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/71">chapter 71</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, along with the written election of the claimant to have the appeal determined under the program.</text></clause><clause id="id0f9e9b34-bd78-41d7-938e-49a87b309a2b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>All evidence that the claimant believes is needed for the appeal as of the date of the filing.</text></clause><clause id="ida339fc74-0451-4832-81f4-60438d4934e2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A statement of the argument in support of the claim, if any.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id44cb2341-f730-49c6-9ebe-e34dff4ca4df"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A claimant shall make an election under subparagraph (A) as part of the notice of disagreement filed by the claimant in accordance with subparagraph (A)(i).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id13fda841-7ee1-43c3-884f-efe36f29bba3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Triage</header><text>The Secretary shall, upon expiration of the period specified in paragraph (3)(C)(iii), ensure that an assessment is undertaken of whether an appeal filed under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph satisfies the requirements for appeal under the program and provide appropriate notification to the claimant of the results of that assessment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id965d0a37-d741-46d0-9559-0fd503211023"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Reversion</header><clause id="idaa940e07-d663-4446-bdc2-6d5c6df238cb"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Elected reversion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At any time, a claimant who makes an election under subparagraph (A) may elect to revert to the standard appeals process. Such a reversion shall be final.</text></clause><clause id="id82ac180a-500b-458b-a9f4-ae36d7584078"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Automatic reversion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A claimant described in clause (i), or a claimant who makes an election under subparagraph (A) but is later determined to be ineligible for the program under paragraph (1), shall revert to the standard appeals process without any penalty to the claimant other than the loss of the docket number associated with the fully developed appeal.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="ida2d6180c-22cc-4f38-ab3b-21bd591ef67b"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text>In providing claimants with notices of the determination of a claim during the period in which the program under paragraph (1) is carried out, the Secretary shall conduct outreach as follows:</text><clause id="id5374c00b-3908-4c49-9b15-a437a441f6c7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Secretary shall provide to the claimant (and to the representative of record of the claimant, if any) information regarding—</text><subclause commented="no" id="id547e90bf-1422-47c8-921f-366f642384f6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the program, including the advantages and disadvantages of the program;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="idc0f32c61-2a2f-4f4c-9304-8a8fb4cf5649"><enum>(II)</enum><text>how to make an election under subparagraph (A);</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id46f5d24a-08e7-487f-b6f3-5491d8e103ef"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the limitation on the use of new evidence described in subparagraph (C) of paragraph (3) and the development of information under subparagraph (D) of such paragraph;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id43c1d297-fd3a-4e34-bdae-73c645e73e6b"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the ability of the claimant to seek advice and education regarding such process from veterans service organizations, attorneys, and claims agents recognized under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/59">chapter 59</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="idfe4d5771-c72f-44ce-818e-7d53486853d8"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the circumstances under which the appeal will automatically revert to the standard appeals process, including by making a request for a hearing.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="ide084300a-f6c4-4306-82b4-ca55ad1a6392"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Secretary shall collaborate, partner with, and give weight to the advice of the three veterans service organizations with the most members and such other stakeholders as the Secretary considers appropriate to publish on the Internet website of the Department of Veterans Affairs an online tutorial explaining the advantages and disadvantages of the program.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id52a06c84-e5ff-4b36-ac4b-28967f1c127c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment by Department and Board</header><subparagraph id="id1819011f-6580-4af5-abfc-555b995261e0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the election of a claimant to file a fully developed appeal pursuant to paragraph (2)(A), the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="ide7a28a87-6b49-4a6d-a57d-595485f43b8f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not provide the claimant with a statement of the case nor require the claimant to file a substantive appeal; and</text></clause><clause id="ide2c7e731-6779-4eed-9d7c-fd18ed4e4df1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>transfer jurisdiction over the fully developed appeal directly to the Board of Veterans’ Appeals.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idbce55d9e-4844-4d59-9114-989dd18f3c38"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Docket</header><clause id="idc562e1ba-4349-400c-9bd8-36c1cbb79418"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board of Veterans’ Appeals shall—</text><subclause id="idd3bdadfc-3ae7-44b5-9227-91db56c9cef1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>maintain fully developed appeals on a separate docket than standard appeals;</text></subclause><subclause id="id04fb1aba-8fc9-4c82-a19f-88af7d28fa43"><enum>(II)</enum><text>decide fully developed appeals in the order that the fully developed appeals are received on the fully developed appeal docket;</text></subclause><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1417b1cb-a775-4f26-854c-d3ee102511dc"><enum>(III)</enum><text>except as provided by clause (ii), decide not more than one fully developed appeal for each four standard appeals decided; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id889da493-a333-49ed-b38b-c3409e4fecaa"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, decide each fully developed appeal by the date that is one year following the date on which the claimant files the notice of disagreement.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="ida929da9f-07ff-4317-86aa-0da2a33e0196"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning one year after the date on which the program commences, the Board may adjust the number of standard appeals decided for each fully developed appeal under clause (i)(III) if the Board determines that such adjustment is fair for both standard appeals and fully developed appeals.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idb8fa67ab-ad3f-4113-884e-5c1f3ec4ee47"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation on use of new evidence</header><clause id="id7a95b9c3-45ac-47b2-b680-a1ebff48622d"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided by clauses (ii) and (iii)—</text><subclause id="idefa63718-3df6-4455-b27c-36d5ec8e7ab7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a claimant may not submit or identify to the Board of Veterans’ Appeals any new evidence relating to a fully developed appeal after filing such appeal unless the claimant reverts to the standard appeals process pursuant to paragraph (2)(D); and</text></subclause><subclause id="idb728b644-7194-4c21-a30b-dc5d8d6529fd"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if a claimant submits or identifies any such new evidence, such submission or identification shall be deemed to be an election to make such a reversion pursuant to paragraph (2)(D).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id0870d31f-6eb9-4ad9-8399-b7eaf6e7f5a0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Evidence gathered by Board</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause (i) shall not apply to evidence developed pursuant to subparagraphs (D) and (E). The Board shall consider such evidence in the first instance without consideration by the Veterans Benefits Administration.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="ide0a758b2-c489-4579-b4dd-6fd6021d0af8"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Representative of record</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The representative of record of a claimant for appeals purposes, if any, shall be provided an opportunity to review the fully developed appeal of the claimant and submit any additional arguments or evidence that the representative determines necessary during a period specified by the Board for purposes of this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2fdc81d5-2402-4850-970c-11b91621df3c"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Prohibition on remand for additional development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Board of Veterans’ Appeals determines that a fully developed appeal requires Federal records, independent medical opinions, or new medical examinations, the Board shall—</text><clause id="ida6eca495-895f-4480-aa39-5ff54ca60c6f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in accordance with subparagraph (E), take such actions as may be necessary to develop such records, opinions, or examinations in accordance with section 5103A of title 38, United States Code;</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc898013-452e-4ecf-9624-b9c7a0365529"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">retain jurisdiction of the fully developed appeal without requiring a determination by the Veterans Benefits Administration based on such records, opinions, or examinations;</text></clause><clause id="id82458b2e-c8f2-49f6-bbf6-8a5a0a4dcc80"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure the claimant, and the representative of record of a claimant, if any, receives a copy of such records, opinions, or examinations; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idae7f8ac3-b2d6-4be7-9ff0-72c06ebd031f"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide the claimant a period of 90 days after the date of mailing such records, opinions, or examinations during which the claimant may provide the Board any additional evidence without requiring the claimant to make a reversion pursuant to paragraph (2)(D).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id353fa4d0-fdd2-429c-87b8-649224f9f915"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Development unit</header><clause id="id4ec2ec02-312e-49c0-b151-8f2a145879a8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Veterans’ Appeals shall establish an office to develop Federal records, independent medical opinions, and new medical examinations pursuant to subparagraph (D)(i) that the Board determines necessary to decide a fully developed appeal.</text></clause><clause id="idee0115cd-dedd-44d7-931c-80297059e963"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text><subclause id="id1f8c802a-0061-4186-af04-1cb71c158dc4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>ensure that the Veterans Benefits Administration cooperates with the Board of Veterans’ Appeals in carrying out clause (i); and</text></subclause><subclause id="ide3ee2597-5452-44be-84f9-56aa6492c1d7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>transfer employees of the Veterans Benefits Administration who, prior to the enactment of this Act, were responsible for processing claims remanded by the Board of Veterans’ Appeals to positions within the office of the Board established under clause (i) in a number the Secretary determines sufficient to carry out such subparagraph.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id812db0f9-91ac-4714-987a-39e5bce0b4b2"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 7107 of title 38, United States Code, the Secretary may not provide hearings with respect to fully developed appeals under the program. If a claimant requests to hold a hearing pursuant to such section 7107, such request shall be deemed to be an election to revert to the standard appeals process pursuant to paragraph (2)(D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc613f66e-17c1-491d-af5f-18591caa134e"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Duration; applicability</header><subparagraph id="idc91841e8-b690-430a-b256-cf890d904eeb"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (c), the Secretary may carry out the program during such period as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id10d5dae1-0e15-4d6d-8739-8374c217d951"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall apply only to fully developed appeals that are filed during the period in which the program is carried out pursuant to subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd3b6c866-d38f-4f70-9422-bbbc6407a217"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="id4708a0cb-c2c9-4ab4-aa5a-028f6c81ee2b"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>compensation</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="ida172da8b-8628-4c63-9493-d1706e00facb"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Fully developed appeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fully developed appeal</term> means an appeal of a claim for disability compensation that is—</text><clause id="id9460812f-7182-41ed-91d8-3ef4073d5317"><enum>(i)</enum><text>filed by a claimant in accordance with paragraph (2)(A); and</text></clause><clause id="iddeb87218-f0fc-498e-be1f-df1f1d865a89"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>considered in accordance with this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34fe14df-fc18-4b1f-951e-c4a284e6c3a8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Standard appeal</header><text>The term <term>standard appeal</term> means an appeal of a claim for disability compensation that is not a fully developed appeal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1b937274-813c-4442-b669-2b95a3f17c4d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination of authority</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may not carry out a program under this section after the applicability date set forth in section 2(x)(1).</text></subsection></section><section id="idd22ae243-8d97-4574-ba6f-13f248bbff87"><enum>5.</enum><header>Periodic publication of metrics relating to processing of appeals by Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall periodically publish on an Internet website of the Department of Veterans Affairs the following:</text><paragraph id="id5c28bfb1-b465-42ee-b988-a653776f0c44"><enum>(1)</enum><text>With respect to the processing by the Secretary of appeals under the new appeals system of decisions regarding claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary, the following:</text><subparagraph id="id90cbb498-c904-482e-96e8-870576104bd7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For the Veterans Benefits Administration and, to the extent practicable, each regional office of the Department of Veterans Affairs, the number of—</text><clause id="id7fb8ba5c-af6e-42e6-8d77-27c012cb4fd1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>supplemental claims under section 5108 of title 38, United States Code, as amended by section 2(i), that are pending; and</text></clause><clause id="id60188d16-48bf-4d1a-869f-60592eefe2a2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>requests for higher-level review under section 5104B of such title, as added by section 2(g), that are pending.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3e55839e-e2e0-44e1-bdcd-57c895635fba"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of appeals on any docket maintained under section 7107 of such title, as amended by section 2(t), that are pending.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1ad34a33-d895-4da5-abe3-1fb9eb90656f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The average duration for processing claims and supplemental claims, disaggregated by regional office.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf820cec5-392a-4eed-b81f-43366fc94a9d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The average duration for processing requests for higher-level review under section 5104B of such title, as added by section 2(g), disaggregated by regional office.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7A9D49003F4F49088D3459BB162F1045"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The average number of days that appeals are pending on a docket of the Board of Veterans' Appeals maintained pursuant to section 7107 of such title, as amended by section 2(t), disaggregated by—</text><clause id="id0CBE291819084D40B573DBF24F71F444"><enum>(i)</enum><text>appeals that include a request for a hearing;</text></clause><clause id="id72D24747877A44F3A8557D77422742ED"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>appeals that do not include a request for a hearing and do include submittal of evidence; and</text></clause><clause id="id59603E7BED214EF68EFAA57E83057106"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>appeals that do not include a request for a hearing and do not include submittal of evidence.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id00bd83af-883b-4279-8b3e-229afb58a700"><enum>(F)</enum><text>With respect to the policy developed and implemented under section 7107(e) of such title, as amended by section 2(t)—</text><clause id="idf17ec3e0-5e6a-4de4-9369-33a37b92d983"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of cases moved from one docket to another pursuant to such policy;</text></clause><clause id="ide6b428a8-5066-4134-bd85-e30534339f65"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average time cases were pending prior to moving from one docket to another; and</text></clause><clause id="idd97e8c72-2c39-4ceb-8aef-0b3b3abc64c0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the average time to adjudicate the cases after so moving.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida7984703-a553-46cc-a5e1-58b912e8cbdc"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The total number of remands to obtain advisory medical opinions under section 5109(d) of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 2(j).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2dc535cd-66cc-4380-85c4-f33cfb0eb20c"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The average number of days between the date on which the Board remands a claim to obtain an advisory medical opinion under section 5109(d) of such title, as so added, and the date on which the advisory medical opinion is obtained.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9f029fa8-5c68-47f5-8d02-d265b300bde7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The average number of days between the date on which the Board remands a claim to obtain an advisory medical opinion under section 5109(d) of such title, as so added, and the date on which the agency of original jurisdiction issues a decision taking that advisory opinion into account.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id083643b7-035d-49a2-b001-21184b34f557"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The number of appeals that are granted, the number of appeals that are remanded, and the number of appeals that are denied by the Board disaggregated by docket.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id81263754-d59e-4f40-a8d7-ad302d6cf687"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The number of claimants each year that take action within the period set forth in section 5110(a)(2) of such title, as added by section 2(l), to protect their effective date under such section 5110(a)(2), disaggregated by the status of the claimants taking the actions, such as whether the claimant is represented by a veterans service organization, the claimant is represented by an attorney, or the claimant is taking such action pro se.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb177b599-a89b-4091-b42c-f7da7983a2ac"><enum>(L)</enum><text>The total number of times on average each claimant files under section 5110(a)(2) of such title, as so added, to protect their effective date under such section, disaggregated by the subparagraph of such section under which they file.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id870b1130-e3d5-4265-9398-8afc74d48575"><enum>(M)</enum><text>The average duration, from the filing of an initial claim until the claim is resolved and claimants no longer take any action to protect their effective date under section 5110(a)(2) of such title, as so added—</text><clause id="id351aee60-2022-4903-90d0-75108a32241e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>of claims under the new appeals system, excluding legacy claims that opt in to the new appeals system; and</text></clause><clause id="id6a03934e-8f99-4a17-9e60-b01422c1a1b5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>of legacy claims that opt in to the new appeals system.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddfdeb7b7-cdd7-4370-a2d2-6cf775b333de"><enum>(N)</enum><text>How frequently an action taken within one year to protect an effective date under section 5110(a)(2) of such title, as so added, leads to additional grant of benefits, disaggregated by action taken.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddd74d5f1-b9e1-41b1-80c8-debaf144170c"><enum>(O)</enum><text>The average of how long it takes to complete each segment of the claims process while claimants are protecting the effective date under such section, disaggregated by the time waiting for the claimant to take an action and the time waiting for the Secretary to take an action.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id446db5de-d626-4bf4-891d-c9f62eb8a817"><enum>(P)</enum><text>The number and the average amount of retroactive awards of benefits from the Secretary as a result of protected effective dates under such section, disaggregated by action taken.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3126a31b-c706-4ac3-a33f-57d19c277be3"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>The average number of times claimants submit to the Secretary different claims with respect to the same condition, such as an initial claim and a supplemental claim.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id42c0f4af-eeaa-4d62-b18a-53bba3013879"><enum>(R)</enum><text>The number of cases each year in which a claimant inappropriately tried to take simultaneous actions, such as filing a supplemental claim while a higher-level review is pending, what actions the Secretary took in response, and how long it took on average to take those actions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id65b84b81-c704-43ad-b921-b98dd9ac3953"><enum>(S)</enum><text>In the case that the Secretary develops and implements a policy under section 5104C(a)(2)(D) of such title, as amended by section 2(h)(1), the number of actions withdrawn and new actions taken pursuant to such policy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id78b4f63d-f622-4175-b24d-1be7c9ceef48"><enum>(T)</enum><text>The number of times the Secretary received evidence relating to an appeal or higher-level review at a time not authorized under the new appeals system, disaggregated by actions taken by the Secretary to deal with the evidence and how long on average it took to take those actions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9c8d6da3-413c-45bc-a07a-0f4988555f8b"><enum>(U)</enum><text>The number of errors committed by the Secretary in carrying out the Secretary's duty to assist under section 5103A of title 38, United States Code, that were identified by higher-level review and by the Board, disaggregated by type of error, such as errors relating to private records and inadequate examinations, and a comparison with errors committed by the Secretary in carrying out such duty with respect to appeals of decisions on legacy claims.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id448aea89-6d8f-4acf-b0c7-e7b0a5d466de"><enum>(V)</enum><text>An assessment of the productivity of employees at the regional offices and at the Board, disaggregated by level of experience of the employees.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1C6AC3B7554F431C84494F378501E94F"><enum>(W)</enum><text>The percentage of cases that are decided within the goals established by the Secretary for deciding cases, disaggregated by cases that involve a supplemental claim, cases that involve higher-level review, and by docket maintained under section 7107(a) of such title, as amended by section 2(t), or in the case that the Secretary has not established goals for deciding cases, the percentage of cases which are decided within one year, two years, three years, and more than three years, disaggregated by docket.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1C458780ED664927B0A392B681A23B39"><enum>(X)</enum><text>Of the cases that involve higher-level review, the percentage of decisions that are overturned in whole or in part by the higher-level adjudicator, that are upheld by the higher-level adjudicator, and that are returned for correction of an error.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3E65B3A8E5684967B6FE031903BE86DC"><enum>(Y)</enum><text>The frequency by which the Secretary readjudicates a claim pursuant to section 5108 of such title, as amended by section 2(i), and the frequency by which readjudication pursuant to section 5108 of such title, as so amended, results in an award of benefits.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDCEE467DF587429AB1CDB6AABEC276B5"><enum>(Z)</enum><text>In any case in which the Board decides to screen cases for a purpose described in section 7107(d) of such title, as amended by section 2(t)(1)—</text><clause id="id37969E5BBEFE4C9887D5D3EA5B73395C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the way in which the cases are screened and the purposes for which they are screened;</text></clause><clause id="id02DF8152880F4EDF9A5C085BC434420F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of the effect such screening has had on—</text><subclause id="id008154894F2D4802A25E3EA371ADF777"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the timeliness of the issuance of decisions of the Board; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id63F96A309D5740B8A34D274E852208F0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the inventory of cases before the Board; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id5060A9A220754AB1A973E1364C9DF51C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the type and frequency of development errors detected through such screening.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9f765d76-a871-4118-80ec-df2c622e4a9c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With respect to the processing by the Secretary of appeals of decisions on legacy claims, the following:</text><subparagraph id="id909fe7f6-0782-4651-a6b3-f383ea5c6a91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The average duration of each segment of the appeals process, disaggregated by periods in which the Secretary is waiting for a claimant to take an action and periods in which the claimant is waiting for the Secretary to take an action.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1f12a400-ccdd-4b00-9a1c-d4c3a03eab3f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The frequency by which appeals lead to additional grant of benefits by the Secretary, disaggregated by whether the additional benefits are a result of additional evidence added after the initial decision.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id224369be-c51e-4e8a-98d6-ab3a2c72ba27"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The number and average amount of retroactive awards of benefits resulting from an appeal.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id952a2619-404e-4b58-abb7-dacce87de18f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The average duration from filing a legacy claim with the Secretary until all appeals and remands relating to such legacy claim are completed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idab6d687b-6a85-4b3c-8918-c975de236fc5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The average number of times claimants submit to the Secretary different claims with respect to the same condition, such as an initial claim, new and material evidence, or a claim for an increase in benefits.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5aa4b5fd-9d66-4f27-b6fc-06c8dff11328"><enum>(F)</enum><text>An assessment of the productivity of employees at the regional offices and at the Board, disaggregated by level of experience of the employees.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id79004b03-9bbb-4309-ac68-4e465f00897c"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The average number of days the duration of an appeal is extended because the Secretary secured or attempted to secure an advisory medical opinion under section 5109 of title 38, United States Code, or section 7109 of such title (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7EC462FD1D61474FAF9A03FFB488350A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The frequency by which claims are reopened pursuant to section 5108 of such title and the frequency by which such reopening results in an award of benefits.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida7246936-ba49-4caf-8c5c-68a8d6314af1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>With respect to the processing by the Secretary of appeals of decisions on legacy claims that opt in to the new appeals system, the following:</text><subparagraph id="id5e1d0e26-2702-4cef-8457-f1dde344df8c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The cumulative number of such legacy claims.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id939529a3-a346-4e90-8f8f-cec84bad7ff0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The portion of work in the new appeals system attributable to appeals of decisions on such legacy claims.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id88414341-2e36-4702-8437-5c7dbd4aae83"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The average period such legacy claims were pending before opting in to the new appeals system and the average period required to adjudicate such legacy claims on average after opting in—</text><clause id="ida0327c47-c243-41ea-8305-f06487628e02"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to claims at a regional office of the Department of Veterans Affairs, disaggregated by—</text><subclause id="idee02502d-af81-4af6-8428-f12b80977cf8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>supplemental claims under section 5108 of title 38, United States Code, as amended by section 2(i); and</text></subclause><subclause id="id73d10686-08f8-41b5-b932-d23786a803b3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>requests for higher-level review under section 5104B of such title, as added by section 2(g); and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide4e4325a-a68a-4b74-adb4-02e6d978522a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to appeals, disaggregated by docket of the Board maintained under section 7107 of such title, as amended by section 2(t).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id99e3b958-64cb-4107-b0f0-95138559bc9f"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idb08fbdf0-1d24-4b25-a306-5d85ad4f79d8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Claimant</header><text>The term <term>claimant</term> has the meaning given such term in section 5100 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbd711253-5f20-4950-b1ec-a47160a3b35e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Legacy claims</header><text>The term <term>legacy claim</term> means a claim—</text><subparagraph id="idc9ebe356-5310-4734-831f-ce7427af5603"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that was submitted to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2993cb3d-8bf6-4b11-9145-03a65f972a8c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for which notice of a decision under section 5104 of title 38, United States Code, was provided by the Secretary before the date set forth in section 2(x).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b86a91a-d740-4cbf-8a5c-2b4651273b69"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Opt in</header><text>The term <term>opt in</term> means, with respect to a legacy claim of a claimant, that the claimant elects to subject the claim to the new appeals system pursuant to—</text><subparagraph id="id81ff03b5-9f7d-4a75-8c1d-77a785003cd8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 2(x)(3); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id71e0adef-0ec0-47b7-822f-7d569ec67b92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such other mechanism as the Secretary may prescribe for purposes of carrying out this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id24ba5ff9-e986-4b57-9ab6-26507c31b3f6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>New appeals system</header><text>The term <term>new appeals system</term> means the set of processes and mechanisms by which the Secretary processes, pursuant to the authorities and requirements modified by section 2, claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></section></amendment-block></amendment></engrossed-amendment-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestor></attestor><role>Secretary</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement></endorsement></amendment-doc>


