<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9AC683BACE9749979953D616278ACAC5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3250 IH: 9/11 Immigrant Worker Freedom Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3250</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170714">July 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001038">Mr. Crowley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Vel&#225;zquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide aliens who performed rescue, recovery, demolition, debris cleanup, or other related services after the September 11 terrorist attacks an opportunity to adjust their status to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF25A33752C9A4627BB959AD00E0ED6AD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEDC27B5B29FB4CD5B9B0097FFD54C895" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>9/11 Immigrant Worker Freedom Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H83D1F5EEE373410EAA16AF26DC38B863"><enum>2.</enum><header>Adjustment of status for certain workers after terrorist attacks</header> <subsection id="H2F8997513AB2439B8EF5E358196F9166"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Adjustment of status</header><text>The status of any alien described in subsection (b) may be adjusted by the Secretary of Homeland Security to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, if the alien—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9C2D78C2C0DB41F781D99312D8ED3B19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>applies for such adjustment not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, which may be extended at the discretion of the Secretary in cases with compelling circumstances;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33D86E16480B480C8C2ED13494C49B2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is not inadmissible to the United States under paragraph (2) or (3) of section 212(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)</external-xref>), or deportable under paragraph (2) or (4) of section 237(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1227">8 U.S.C. 1227(a)</external-xref>); except that in determining an alien’s inadmissibility—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5D6995D8346A4281BAD0A5087E953DED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>offenses for which an essential element was the alien’s immigration status shall not apply;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H201F14C0DF894654A9B3150E18C0A32A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>arrests or criminal charges on their own shall not apply; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H906931A755C648389F23D71D0ED50B81"><enum>(C)</enum><text>cases where a judgment has been expunged, set aside, or the equivalent shall not apply; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E1F89030490432A854457D8947B9B1E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not later than the date on which the application under paragraph (1) is submitted, satisfies any applicable Federal tax liability by establishing that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBA0C46E4E88A4212A587025F921DB70F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no such tax liability exists; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3CB99F97309E4A73A5CECDD9F5A0DAB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all outstanding liabilities have been paid.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4AE5CE7A69C64C708DAA0A968813AB9B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Aliens eligible for adjustment of status</header> 
<paragraph id="H3DBD0357EB1643F9AFF7B80C076B1DDA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The benefit provided by subsection (a) shall apply to any alien who—</text> <subparagraph id="HC5064D95BB6648ACB5E49422F6A5AD64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>worked or volunteered onsite in rescue, recovery, debris cleanup, or related support services in lower Manhattan (south of Canal St.), the Staten Island Landfill, or the barge loading piers, for at least 4 hours during the period beginning on September 11, 2001, and ending on September 14, 2001, for at least 24 hours during the period beginning on September 11, 2001, and ending on September 30, 2001, or for at least 80 hours during the period beginning on September 11, 2001, and ending on July 31, 2002; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF4379D0CB223412E84C5114D615A7C64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was a vehicle-maintenance worker who was exposed to debris from the former World Trade Center while retrieving, driving, cleaning, repairing, and maintaining vehicles contaminated by airborne toxins from the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks for any time during the period beginning on September 11, 2001, and ending on July 31, 2002; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9A5E4F2C567B4EC7B3F8A3EDF9BC2419"><enum>(C)</enum><text>was a member of a fire or police department (whether fire or emergency personnel, active or retired), worked for a recovery or cleanup contractor, or was a volunteer; and performed rescue, recovery, demolition, debris cleanup, or other related services at the Pentagon site of the terrorist-related aircraft crash of September 11, 2001, during the period beginning on September 11, 2001, and ending on November 19, 2001; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA78058DD2B4E4A0CAF10473DA71C8555"><enum>(D)</enum><text>was a member of a fire or police department (whether fire or emergency personnel, active or retired), worked for a recovery or cleanup contractor, or was a volunteer; and performed rescue, recovery, demolition, debris cleanup, or other related services at the Shanksville, Pennsylvania, site of the terrorist-related aircraft crash of September 11, 2001, during the period beginning on September 11, 2001, and ending on October 3, 2001.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C446A77BBDB49DB978FE2CEE83FB88D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>An alien shall not be provided any benefit under this section if the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that the alien has willfully made a material misrepresentation or material omission in the proffer of information described in paragraph (1)(C).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB506463C952A4D09B00A9B6C64F1637C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Work authorization</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may authorize an alien who has applied for adjustment of status under subsection (a) to engage in employment in the United States during the pendency of such application.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC89DA45C665B497C99234A06228CB48D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the existing authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security on the date of the enactment of this Act to require any form or other submission of information or to perform any background or security check for the purpose of determining the admissibility, or eligibility under this section, of any alien.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF3ED1ECE9FE440E3BBA138B283DAE24A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Waiver of regulations</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall issue guidance to carry out this section not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, but is not required to promulgate regulations prior to implementing this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H545F48F798BF4184ACA189C51C58F963"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No offset in number of visas available</header><text>When an alien is granted the status of having been lawfully admitted for permanent residence under this section, the Secretary of State shall not be required to reduce the number of immigrant visas authorized to be issued under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> et seq.).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF899894C19A74BBABBF7A2A7843FEFF4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H0445896186284FF2BA4616B12209F0B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>applicable Federal tax liability</quote> means liability for Federal taxes, including penalties and interest, owed for any year for which the statutory period for assessment of any deficiency for such taxes has not expired.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H61E03947DFFD473797C3B5DE1EFCC769"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Except as otherwise specifically provided in this section, the definitions used in the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> et seq.) (excluding the definitions applicable exclusively to title III of such Act) shall apply in the administration of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

