<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H058987FE53004D148ADCD0C0E596D486" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2432 IH: Volunteer Organization Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2432</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170516">May 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000580">Mr. Roskam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000460">Mr. Farenthold</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000582">Mr. Roe of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001056">Ms. Herrera Beutler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000174">Mr. Sam Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001096">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000464">Mr. Faso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001036">Mr. Hensarling</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001293">Mr. Bishop of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000374">Mr. Abraham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000601">Mr. Ratcliffe</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000362">Mr. King of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Volunteer Organization Protection Act of 1997, to provide for liability protection for
			 organizations or entities.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H9C34663655B742ADA26CF33AF7AF9642" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD6FB925C93EE4B5DA59F62AFBBC3B6E5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Volunteer Organization Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H11A128F9DE86450BA095344AE08C9EF5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Liability protection for organization or entity</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Volunteer Protection Act of 1997, <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/19">Public Law 105–19</external-xref>, is amended as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD4053389427A4D66AC27A2F16DE592EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In section 3(a), by inserting after <quote>relating to volunteers</quote> the following: <quote>or volunteer nonprofit organizations</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB4B6078EEC9D4153831B9795B7FB08E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In section 3(b), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting after <quote>against a volunteer</quote> the following: <quote>or a volunteer nonprofit organization</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3EAACB5CA5EC4A3386E376477787AA96"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In section 4, in the heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and volunteer nonprofit organizations</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">volunteers</header-in-text></quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3206E939D54493B96DF44469262D3F4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In section 4, by amending subsection (c) to read as follows:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H674B1FE5F44E40E8AAD951462AAB5C46" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H73948AA5D33444AC992DC7248BD1970E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Liability protection for organization or entity</header>
 <paragraph id="H5E211B102B914656A639BCDB2AEEB19C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No volunteer nonprofit organization shall be liable for harm caused by an act or omission of a volunteer on behalf of the organization unless—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA15F62F239764DDF9FF2C5AE66FEA68C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the organization would be liable for the act or omission under generally applicable laws governing the direct or vicarious liability of organizations; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBD1B137D54C406A8638992218153262"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the organization itself has expressly authorized the specific conduct constituting the act or omission.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2717B678A8054DC08415C5F1A1508A13"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 4(c)(1), no volunteer nonprofit organization shall be liable for harm caused by an act or omission of the organization or of a volunteer acting on behalf of the organization if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE91D1F61B96643AF8C0606152A66FF9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the organization or the volunteer engaged in the act or omission at the request of or pursuant to an authorization by a State or the United States or any agency or subdivision of either; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1FCF23991B64DCE88036437270F6CFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">either—</text> <clause id="H5056CA3635B54AD885B9C085EAEA7386"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the requesting or authorizing governmental entity would have been immune either from suit or from liability in damages if it had engaged in the acts or omissions itself or through employees or independent contractors; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6A03C3A618F94537A25E5C2487CD8494"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the governmental employee, agent, or contractor who engaged in the acts would have been immune either from suit or from liability in damages by virtue of immunity extended to individual governmental actors.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F622D979B1A4ABBAF5CFAEAD6BA6129"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraphs (1) and (2), nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the liability of any nonprofit organization or governmental entity with respect to harm caused to any person.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4157094724B3441DB110156B77EA1102"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In section 4(d), by striking paragraph (2) and redesignating paragraphs (3) and (4) as paragraphs (2) and (3), respectively.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A7131A1DE1348FEA3FF192FE8FA5C7B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In section 4(e), in paragraph (1), by adding the following after the period: <quote>Punitive damages may not be awarded against a volunteer nonprofit organization in an action brought for harm based on the action of a volunteer acting within the scope of the volunteer’s responsibilities to the organization unless the claimant establishes by clear and convincing evidence that the organization itself expressly authorized the volunteer’s action and did so with a conscious, flagrant indifference to the rights or safety of the individual harmed.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7934D24845CC4C1CA29F25DA81544FC7"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In section 4(f), by inserting <quote>or of a volunteer nonprofit organization</quote> after <quote>liability of a volunteer</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7143DB0D7D34DF2B3D39C483811ED7D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In section 5—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD1E75E2C1C314405ADE931B002A79D01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="H1A8B4820ACEB40DEB44D78343F289177"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or a volunteer nonprofit organization</quote> after <quote>action against a volunteer</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H00DF4B4679E14FC4A3E833942D1EB315"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or volunteer nonprofit organization</quote> after <quote>liability of the volunteer</quote>; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21CB81A1452B4ED38CD139C37AE83C7D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <clause id="H0FC0768A94EB4C83BBF61E1BFFD8E551"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>or a volunteer nonprofit organization</quote> after <quote>who is a volunteer</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H0F05566C9A8C4ACE82CAC082A4D9862C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>or volunteer nonprofit organization</quote> after <quote>who is a volunteer</quote>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF076C90B1124FA7A4B323F2A88D85C4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In section 6, by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CE359B078B1451FB65BE6956614508A" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HB525CF611CC94CEEA639B468C0E620DB"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Volunteer nonprofit organization</header><text>An entity is a <quote>volunteer nonprofit organization</quote> if it is any one or more of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8FA7772828AB4770BD7640E684DD7F3B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A nonprofit organization that conducts substantially all of its activities solely through the actions of volunteers or of independent contractors. A nonprofit organization is conclusively presumed to be a <quote>volunteer nonprofit organization</quote> if the organization has no employees.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA477B3C5D97B4A15AB052FE9D2059648"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A nonprofit organization is presumed to be a <quote>volunteer nonprofit organization</quote> if the organization’s primary office and the majority of its employees function primarily to provide support to local affiliated organizations that do not have employees and who act in furtherance of the organization’s nonprofit mission. This presumption can be rebutted only by a clear and convincing showing that the organization’s board expressly authorized its employees to assert active control over the local affiliated organization with respect to the act or omission in question.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1F7F539F6804AC68DB011EB66278904"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A nonprofit organization that has fewer than 50 employees, that has annual gross receipts of less than $200,000, and that is any of the following:</text>
 <clause id="HEF19531F063D487395FA340761F4378E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A public charity that is exempt from taxation under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code.</text> </clause><clause id="H595308E0F9A34174B509EBF6F2AC0FE7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A private foundation that is exempt from taxation under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code but that does not qualify as a public charity.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H83C68FA2C4C140F79296EBA0782C9FC3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A social welfare organization that is exempt from taxation under section 501(c)(4) of the internal revenue code.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H369D79731B784A73BD28041713AB4D5B"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A volunteer nonprofit organization acts <quote>itself</quote> for purposes of this act only when the person or body who is authorized by the organization’s governing documents to act in the name of and on behalf of the organization expressly acts in accordance with those documents. If the organization’s governing documents do not identify the person or body who is authorized to act in the name of and on behalf of the organization, the organization acts <quote>itself</quote> for the purposes of this Act only when the person or body whose action is required under the applicable State law in order to bind the organization acts strictly in accordance with such State law.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


