<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2C92AFF529B44EF4BDAF414D7C23612C" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 665 : Airport Perimeter and Access Control Security Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 665</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20170201">February 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To modernize and enhance airport perimeter and access control security by requiring updated risk
			 assessments and the development of security strategies, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="HB03917B5ECC84FBD8CBF33E96DC09DD5" style="OLC">
 <section id="H8B93DAEC317745ECB83C57324C3C14EB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Airport Perimeter and Access Control Security Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H55883F483431425B8D98F445CE9221AB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Risk assessments of airport security</header> <subsection id="H01940FD889A7450FAC65CCB4C8872C77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCB9A1CB9F2D240C0971E508287ADE586"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, update the Transportation Sector Security Risk Assessment (TSSRA) for the aviation sector; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC151F06C84914A05AE16C311E3BD8975"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 90 days after such date—</text> <subparagraph id="HBF9C06A07F0543CEA1C5CE79A5D3727F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">update with the latest and most currently available intelligence information the Comprehensive Risk Assessment of Perimeter and Access Control Security (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Risk Assessment of Airport Security</quote>) and determine a regular timeframe and schedule for further updates to such Risk Assessment of Airport Security; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75FADD7426534602B46640C0BEBA364A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a system-wide assessment of airport access control points and airport perimeter security.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H221C01BE270C4D7E974A604695A7D420"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The security risk assessments required under subsection (a)(2) shall—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HE9525807CADC4091927C7D8AD7DC9206"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include updates reflected in the TSSRA and Joint Vulnerability Assessment (JVA) findings;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4BB18B88857842C3BB4216E4703F5F0F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reflect changes to the risk environment relating to airport access control points and airport perimeters;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9499F0661A234EE586E972203BDC1616"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use security event data for specific analysis of system-wide trends related to airport access control points and airport perimeter security to better inform risk management decisions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E0A2B27FC064500904F77582E5495D7"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">take into consideration the unique geography of and current best practices used by airports to mitigate potential vulnerabilities.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEF0C19EE9F954EC182CE48F7E9C50523"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall report to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, relevant Federal departments and agencies, and airport operators on the results of the security risk assessments required under subsection (a).</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H0BE28EEC0D0D4AC99CC50B2DF5B8898E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Airport security strategy development</header>
 <subsection id="H297048CDCC9B45CCB3BC4D4731D0CDD7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall update the 2012 National Strategy for Airport Perimeter and Access Control Security (in this section referred to as the <quote>National Strategy</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H541FD88B811F4E88B38258C1A089F714"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The update to the National Strategy required under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H764FD75632CD465EB2494E4667233B78"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information from the Risk Assessment of Airport Security; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA49D9B32E29340BDB9E7B14946993B6A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information on—</text> <subparagraph id="H09EC86B9BC894ACF8283897D93535198"><enum>(A)</enum><text>airport security-related activities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE98D29908684E57A3745A32A279977E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the status of TSA efforts to address the goals and objectives referred to in subsection (a);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEEAB88FDEA543A09BB108F078068793"><enum>(C)</enum><text>finalized outcome-based performance measures and performance levels for each relevant activity and goal and objective under subparagraphs (A) and (B); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6484E042E3BD459DAED01DF8C688C090"><enum>(D)</enum><text>input from airport operators.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE374D70C2DAE44EC8642119E3960D35D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the update is completed under subsection (a), the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall <pagebreak></pagebreak>implement a process for determining when additional updates to the strategy referred to in such subsection are needed.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170131">Passed the House of Representatives January 31, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill>


