<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HE97F4E27FF474D73905AE47AB6A46E58" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4510 IH: No Congressional Vehicle Leases Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4510</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171201">December 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001294">Mr. Blum</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of official funds provided for the operations of a House of Congress for
			 long-term vehicle leases, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H85AD279C84D94DFD912835FF0E065DFE" style="OLC">
 <section id="H16C360E11F024A26A5C42CEC77DAAE25" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Congressional Vehicle Leases Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD0314AE2EB7545F296199A8740C0E6AA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting use of congressional funds for long-term vehicle leases</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds appropriated or otherwise made available during a fiscal year for the operations of a House of Congress, including the official and representational expenses of a Member of Congress or the expenses of a committee or leadership office of a House of Congress, may be used to lease a vehicle for a period of longer than 30 consecutive days, or to lease a vehicle for a period of any length at a daily rate exceeding a maximum rate established by regulation.</text>
 </section><section id="H0ADCDFA10D4B4CDFA5501E891641FA76"><enum>3.</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives (with respect to Representatives in, and Delegates and the Resident Commissioner to, the Congress) and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate (with respect to Senators) shall each promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this Act.</text>
 </section><section id="H775B14CDA28F4ECCA2E9626132C1486B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Member of Congress defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>Member of Congress</term> means a Senator or a Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</text> </section><section id="HBF62767ED764466F9D07F60003277448"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall apply with respect to leases entered into after the expiration of the 1-year period which begins on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


