<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H7552F362722C4D3EB75229014F22FEA7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4676 IH: Expanding Sanctions Against Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4676</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171218">December 18, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Treasury to prescribe regulations to expand sanctions against
			 persons owned or controlled by Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps, and for
			 other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H5EC87AF30C804C9E98AC3A9155878A20" style="OLC">
 <section id="HD50AB32342284D3AB0694B726AA0C8F9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding Sanctions Against Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5B5AFAE46AE34FE1BCD6AD2418366FF5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and sense of Congress</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H0D46065E24244D7DA1AB8C0B93828668"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H68F845D3471B45BD8C575505712FC0FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps has been designated under—</text> <subparagraph id="H4C7D0E3D3CC349C2A55404010657F26F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Executive Order 13224 (September 23, 2001; relating to Blocking Property and Prohibiting Transactions with Persons who Commit, Threaten to Commit, or Support Terrorism);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H820C6FF4F87E4CC1B00029128E52622C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Executive Order 13382 (June 28, 2005; relating to Blocking Property of Weapons of Mass Destruction Proliferators and Their Supporters);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02B88D1FAB304E4181C7C64CB370E9D0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Executive Order 13553 (September 28, 2010; relating to Blocking Property of Certain Persons With Respect to Serious Human Rights Abuses by the Government of Iran and Taking Certain Other Actions); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1B65EBAFB3A406E9891C8D0EE6C7ECC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Executive Order 13606 (April 22, 2012; relating to Blocking the Property and Suspending Entry Into the United States of Certain Persons With Respect to Grave Human Rights Abuses by the Governments of Iran and Syria via Information Technology).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H37BED52F864A4F8CB15D84943E23C7CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps controls a significant portion of Iran’s economy, and whose income makes it one of Iran’s most powerful economic actors.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC08D6BAD12224C7996DBB653CA5373C8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps benefits from limited economic transparency, as demonstrated by Iran’s continued failure to meet its intergovernmental Financial Action Task Force commitments.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H955F06B1560B4DD5B96707C4246D9460"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps carries out Iran’s destabilizing political goals across the Middle East and by proxy worldwide.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H435639B7E3CF4670A85CE0BDFF52D638"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HE07F34B649C646C8921FBAB08C548509"><enum>(1)</enum><text>persons who are owned or controlled by Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps should be subject to a 25-percent beneficial ownership threshold rather than majority ownership threshold with respect to blocking property or interests in property of such persons; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C369F0D56654C8789750A17CE5E06A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such expanded sanctions would generate greater public scrutiny and enhanced due diligence procedures by the private sector and others.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H103D62502F364E9AABADE4D3450BBDC5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Regulations to expand sanctions against persons owned or controlled by Iran’s Revolutionary Guard
			 Corps</header>
 <subsection id="HFD3AF79BAA95494E9253401E18022C80"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe regulations to apply the definition of <quote>own or control</quote> described in subsection (b) for purposes of blocking property or interests in property pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) of persons who are owned or controlled by Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA0DDA4187C6244C3BE0F9DB9A355FF95"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of <quote>own or control</quote></header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>own or control</term> described in this subsection means, with respect to a person—</text> <paragraph id="H63081D691CF64D16A9672AD159281806"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to hold more than 25 percent of the equity interest by vote or value in the person;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H694618B666C7443FB7366938C3D6CEBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to hold a majority of seats on the board of directors of the person; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC0743B6331454072B9513E948EC05232"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to otherwise control the actions, policies, or personnel decisions of the person.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D869998215B4BB2A30B528E258148C3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of subsection (a) or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out subsection (a) shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


