<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H288A6805FD1A4098A489567D6171ECCF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4012 IH: NIE on Iranian Proxy Forces Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4012</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171011">October 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000065">Mr. Yoho</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001202">Mrs. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a National Intelligence Estimate on Iranian proxy forces, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H699F0F3B5C07420DBC4A4C8C252CF306" style="OLC">
 <section id="H31AAD79E6C7541449C520232D70D9464" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>NIE on Iranian Proxy Forces Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H40B9653D95C94FFD887017D8AB32C6A1"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Intelligence Estimate</header> <subsection id="H90E4570EB0B241578899EA8DFD9E658C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H010A2FB2C37A4A0EA0DBBC49E0349624"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Hizballah is active in Syria and its fighters have helped President Bashar Al-Assad maintain regime control.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA6D8227F41C14C43A8F711E5307AC8E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Hizballah fighters are returning to Lebanon more battle-tested and more capable than ever before.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H545FD55A38CB405385E63BD19F034738"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 2006, Hizballah’s rocket and missile arsenal in Lebanon was approximately 15,000; however, by 2017, this figure has grown ten-fold to more than 150,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5139093E5AF4A04B6F1A7DF9FD8B377"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Iran, through various means, illicitly transfers weapons to Hizballah.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA626321F8E5641D7AD2DB8F43515A1BC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Iran is reportedly building missile production facilities in Lebanon to enable an indigenous rocket-producing capability for Hizballah.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H907BB2594F9145B9A306208EA2FAC355"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National Intelligence Estimate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall produce a National Intelligence Estimate—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9F722BE6B2304B498B298B7325D4F20E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on Iranian support of proxy forces in Syria and Lebanon; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1BC34EC67F4492B9DDABFDEDE026B25"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assessing the increased threat posed to Israel, other United States regional allies, and other specified interests of the United States as a result of such support.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8F0210BDDC114EEDBF50EB35ED919155"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Matters To Be included</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Intelligence Estimate required under subsection (b) shall include, at a minimum, information relating to the following matters with respect to both the strategic and tactical implications for the United States and its allies:</text>
 <paragraph id="H5986DD8C63A3417AA4731F831AD364F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of arms or related material transferred by Iran to Hizballah since March 2011, including the number of such arms or related material and whether such transfer was by land, sea, or air, as well as financial and additional technological capabilities transferred by Iran to Hizballah.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8138C98CC2D441E39E8555BFA326CA83"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of Iranian and Iranian-controlled personnel, including Hizballah, Shiite militias, and Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps forces, operating within Syria, including the number and geographic distribution of such personnel operating within 30 kilometers of the Israeli borders with Syria and Lebanon as well as Deir al Zour, Syria.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6EE63B8341F749F29588F9BA1B18DF62"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of Hizballah’s operational lessons learned based on its recent experiences in Syria.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAEE81BFC0CEB445795FE960DA913C609"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of any rocket–producing facilities in Lebanon for non-state actors, including whether such facilities were assessed to be built at the direction of Hizballah leadership, Iranian leadership, or in consultation between Iranian leadership and Hizballah leadership.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H116B44F03D784DE4A6AFF04A4E54208E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An analysis of the foreign and domestic supply chains that significantly facilitate, support, or otherwise aid Hizballah’s acquisition or development of missile production facilities, including the geographic distribution of such foreign and domestic supply chains.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD46D779D6934D7EB5D90BF10F7C29C9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An assessment of the provision of goods, services, or technology transferred by Iran or its affiliates to Hizballah to indigenously manufacture or otherwise produce missiles.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H419FD83AD4704062BFBE63A75B1D0B6B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>An identification of foreign persons that are, based on credible information, facilitating the transfer of significant financial support or arms or related material to Hizballah.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF27BAC67ACFD4EE7BFF316FEFC31DCBC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A description of Russia’s tactical and strategic collaboration with Iranian and Hizballah elements in Syria.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F553DA288BC4EE3926AAC81E39B488E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A description of the threat posed to Israel and other United States partners in the Middle East by the transfer of arms or related material or other support offered to Hizballah from Iran.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCE4355EDBC0F4B4EBF47A03FED93A7E2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text>Upon completion of the National Intelligence Estimate required under subsection (b), the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Development, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate a copy of such estimate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB260CA5793C94CFCB6AD8583ACF17BBA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Arms or related material defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>arms or related material</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H0310601894704F5DB89175D66202146B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>nuclear, biological, chemical, or radiological weapons or materials or components of such weapons;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E31B419FCBF483BA40F15DF5878B630"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ballistic or cruise missile weapons or materials or components of such weapons;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB71E3D03F8E4EBE81C0522C88F6103C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>destabilizing numbers and types of advanced conventional weapons;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB579F7F88E1245AA8BC3A35F317CF58A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>defense articles or defense services, as those terms are defined in paragraphs (3) and (4), respectively, of section 47 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2794">22 U.S.C. 2794</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DD38E7927D04D55A8F7A3CD7180C970"><enum>(5)</enum><text>defense information, as that term is defined in section 644 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2403">22 U.S.C. 2403</external-xref>); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8B8EF4C7AB3B4149B5FDEB88BAA04C74"><enum>(6)</enum><text>items designated by the President for purposes of the United States Munitions List under section 38(a)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2778">22 U.S.C. 2778(a)(1)</external-xref>).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0B9F368D25064B918032D276AEE877E9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Strategy</header>
 <subsection id="HD1D56861356B42288BCFDD7A229A647C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after completion of the National Intelligence Estimate required under section 2(b), the President shall transmit to Congress a strategy to prevent Iran from expanding its power in Syria and Lebanon.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB680F4B0E81E4AD886854656762A4AAA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To Be included</header><text>Such strategy shall include plans to—</text> <paragraph id="HF80B11E54C9E46E895BBBE67DFB12482"><enum>(1)</enum><text>limit Iranian and Iranian-controlled personnel, including Hizballah, Shiite militias, and Iran’s Revolutionary Guard Corps forces, operating within Syria and Lebanon; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H450BF3A53DDF413A9D0BD41BD26464DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work with United States allies to prevent Iranian and Iranian-controlled personnel access to areas in Syria liberated by United States-backed forces.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


