<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2D984FBA60464429B10CAE1295EAC0A7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3178 IH: Medicare Part B Improvement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3178</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170711">July 11, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000755">Mr. Brady of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000791">Mr. Walden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000462">Mr. Tiberi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000263">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve the delivery of home infusion therapy
			 and dialysis and the application of the Stark rule under the Medicare
			 program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1C2CA4AF0C52473880A9405EE3495B4A" style="OLC">
		<section id="H4B10DF60B87B45E6B5832C54C84CDF5A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H31B111CFC11741FE8BECCC1352676BD0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicare Part B Improvement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HD0B74ECA9E5E44B699A8DC0707CAAACF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H4B10DF60B87B45E6B5832C54C84CDF5A" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H89650018336C4253B331B2BB313A0A93" level="title">Title I—Improvements in Provision of Home Infusion Therapy</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H23D1826E3F2640F0BE99548FE0FE90D7" level="section">Sec. 101. Home infusion therapy services temporary transitional payment.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H0A32AE1EA8444F9D929AF7B07FF3AB67" level="section">Sec. 102. Extension of Medicare Patient IVIG Access Demonstration Project.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H4A15474C2A59406187A5098A9358F852" level="section">Sec. 103. Orthotist’s and prosthetist’s clinical notes as part of the patient’s medical record.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H40A545E844104A6DB2D5480010B19A13" level="title">Title II—Improvements in Dialysis Services</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HCD4AD298F80145F3902AB0FE202AF554" level="section">Sec. 201. Independent accreditation for dialysis facilities and assurance of high quality surveys.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF435E2783B034BD0884B955C73D039B5" level="section">Sec. 202. Expanding access to home dialysis therapy.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H89FC399E85A9446F8E8FFB1509B5A429" level="title">Title III—Improvements in Application of Stark Rule</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H0529238368664A10A44959DCE4469F33" level="section">Sec. 301. Modernizing the application of the Stark rule under Medicare.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H29D5F7EEC2D84D9F9ECD4D46A1213D3E" level="section">Sec. 302. Deposit of savings into Medicare Improvement Fund.</toc-entry>
				</toc>
			</subsection></section><title id="H89650018336C4253B331B2BB313A0A93"><enum>I</enum><header>Improvements in Provision of Home Infusion Therapy</header>
			<section id="H23D1826E3F2640F0BE99548FE0FE90D7"><enum>101.</enum><header>Home infusion therapy services temporary transitional payment</header>
 <subsection id="H5F3CA12EACDB4F1B8554DB24A22F5A9B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1834(u) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(u)</external-xref>) is amended, by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H7303B13196A94ACDB109C75BF347894B" style="OLC">
						<paragraph id="H258405DFB99446F497EE70BCDA1F4443"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Home infusion therapy services temporary transitional payment</header>
							<subparagraph id="H7C50EA882764434498BE40BDFF1E8867"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Temporary transitional payment</header>
 <clause id="HE16D4E163CC649D794E87C5812BF6855"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, in accordance with the payment methodology described in subparagraph (B) and subject to the provisions of this paragraph, provide a home infusion therapy services temporary transitional payment under this part to an eligible home infusion supplier (as defined in subparagraph (F)) for items and services described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 1861(iii)(2) furnished during the period specified in clause (ii) by such supplier in coordination with the furnishing of transitional home infusion drugs (as defined in clause (iii)).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H335852CBE8C2495BBF13B2140F222FA8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Period specified</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), the period specified in this clause is the period beginning on January 1, 2019, and ending on the day before the date of the implementation of the payment system under paragraph (1)(A).</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HA7867CA3E0004A88876F5C565AEB56FA"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Transitional home infusion drug defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>transitional home infusion drug</term> has the meaning given to the term <term>home infusion drug</term> under section 1861(iii)(3)(C), except that clause (ii) of such section shall not apply if a drug described in such clause is identified in clause (i), (ii), (iii) or (iv) of subparagraph (C) as of the date of the enactment of this paragraph.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H618CF7F050314770B24B5A6C20EB1112"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Payment methodology</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the Secretary shall establish a payment methodology, with respect to items and services described in subparagraph (A)(i). Under such payment methodology the Secretary shall—</text>
 <clause id="H0B043BF8B4874ED3BE7166C184DFA1F7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>create the three payment categories described in clauses (i), (ii), and (iii) of subparagraph (C);</text> </clause><clause id="HC1D44D1E7CD44ABF9197C1ED0E6033A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assign drugs to such categories, in accordance with such clauses;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9A18231F38114B3BAC5AF7535C0BAC45"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assign appropriate Healthcare Common Procedure Coding System (HCPCS) codes to each payment category; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC207D3B2B7684F3D9AB2ABB6737C0C61"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a single payment amount for each such payment category, in accordance with subparagraph (D), for each infusion drug administration calendar day in the individual’s home for drugs assigned to such category.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCE91850E71744BA8ABBC324A917B008"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Payment categories</header>
 <clause id="H5ACC78F2FD114CA481A55253008E23B6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Payment category 1</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall create a payment category 1 and assign to such category drugs which are covered under the Local Coverage Determination on External Infusion Pumps (LCD number L33794) and billed with the following HCPCS codes (as identified as of July 1, 2017, and as subsequently modified by the Secretary): J0133, J0285, J0287, J0288, J0289, J0895, J1170, J1250, J1265, J1325, J1455, J1457, J1570, J2175, J2260, J2270, J2274, J2278, J3010, or J3285.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA8433585B9CC4EE9870EF361C7114188"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Payment category 2</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall create a payment category 2 and assign to such category drugs which are covered under such local coverage determination and billed with the following HCPCS codes (as identified as of July 1, 2017, and as subsequently modified by the Secretary): J1559 JB, J1561 JB, J1562 JB, J1569 JB, or J1575 JB.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1409C66C277949D3A9BD189785CE3EE2"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Payment category 3</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall create a payment category 3 and assign to such category drugs which are covered under such local coverage determination and billed with the following HCPCS codes (as identified as of July 1, 2017, and as subsequently modified by the Secretary): J9000, J9039, J9040, J9065, J9100, J9190, J9200, J9360, or J9370.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8BA6699A3D82407080B22B87B002AC12"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Infusion drugs not otherwise included</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to drugs that are not included in payment category 1, 2, or 3 under clause (i), (ii), or (iii), respectively, the Secretary shall assign to the most appropriate of such categories, as determined by the Secretary, drugs which are—</text>
 <subclause id="H102BD1CE647248548B33DA73E927649B"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">covered under such local coverage determination and billed under HCPCS code J7799 or J7999 (as identified as of July 1, 2017, and as subsequently modified by the Secretary); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H308E098B9DFE41B4A9590BEE41F7642B"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">billed under any code that is implemented after the date of the enactment of this paragraph and included in such local coverage determination or included in subregulatory guidance as a home infusion drug described in subparagraph (A)(i).</text>
									</subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6ACEEBDF320A4659A0B53DDE01A81629"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Payment amounts</header>
 <clause id="HF176489DA4AD4344834643172160C54E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the payment methodology, the Secretary shall pay eligible home infusion suppliers, with respect to items and services described in subparagraph (A)(i) furnished during the period described in subparagraph (A)(ii) by such supplier to an individual, at amounts equal to the amounts determined under the physician fee schedule established under section 1848 for services furnished during the year for codes and units of such codes described in clauses (ii), (iii), and (iv) with respect to drugs included in the payment category under subparagraph (C) specified in the respective clause, determined without application of any adjustment under such section.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6C5C5E31FFD945D38C93C42FE8830CB7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Payment amount for category 1</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), the codes and units described in this clause, with respect to drugs included in payment category 1 described in subparagraph (C)(i), are one unit of HCPCS code 96365 plus four units of HCPCS code 96366 (as identified as of July 1, 2017, and as subsequently modified by the Secretary).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB760264E811D4A15A01C21E3B6486B4C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Payment amount for category 2</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), the codes and units described in this clause, with respect to drugs included in payment category 2 described in subparagraph (C)(i), are one unit of HCPCS code 96369 plus four units of HCPCS code 96370 (as identified as of July 1, 2017, and as subsequently modified by the Secretary).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5CD7D730768A43688D9261EDAD91EDA2"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Payment amount for category 3</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), the codes and units described in this clause, with respect to drugs included in payment category 3 described in subparagraph (C)(i), are one unit of HCPCS code 96413 plus four units of HCPCS code 96415 (as identified as of July 1, 2017, and as subsequently modified by the Secretary).</text>
								</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CBC49C2F0E045AFA9674339368E5C4E"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Clarifications</header>
 <clause id="HF4D01AF9E1364E5A81D073ABB84675D3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Infusion drug administration day</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, a reference, with respect to the furnishing of transitional home infusion drugs or home infusion drugs to an individual by an eligible home infusion supplier, to payment to such supplier for an infusion drug administration calendar day in the individual’s home shall refer to payment only for the date on which professional services (as described in section 1861(iii)(2)(A)) were furnished to administer such drugs to such individual. For purposes of the previous sentence, an infusion drug administration calendar day shall include all such drugs administered to such individual on such day.</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H652367780BA2457A939BC147ADA4E1FE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Treatment of multiple drugs administered on same infusion drug administration day</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that an eligible home infusion supplier, with respect to an infusion drug administration calendar day in an individual’s home, furnishes to such individual transitional home infusion drugs which are not all assigned to the same payment category under subparagraph (C), payment to such supplier for such infusion drug administration calendar day in the individual’s home shall be a single payment equal to the amount of payment under this paragraph for the drug, among all such drugs so furnished to such individual during such calendar day, for which the highest payment would be made under this paragraph.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4147734717947BEA103DE3463EBD6AE"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Eligible home infusion suppliers</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>eligible home infusion supplier</term> means a supplier that is enrolled under this part as a pharmacy that provides external infusion pumps and external infusion pump supplies and that maintains all pharmacy licensure requirements in the State in which the applicable infusion drugs are administered.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A6E60B83EAF40868363EC6E26310689"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may implement this paragraph by program instruction or otherwise.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA12EFF9410AC4A33B9D150AB8E2BA2E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1842(b)(6)(I) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395u">42 U.S.C. 1395u(b)(6)(I)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or, in the case of items and services described in clause (i) of section 1834(u)(7)(A) furnished to an individual during the period described in clause (ii) of such section, payment shall be made to the eligible home infusion therapy supplier</quote> after <quote>payment shall be made to the qualified home infusion therapy supplier</quote>.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H0A32AE1EA8444F9D929AF7B07FF3AB67"><enum>102.</enum><header>Extension of Medicare Patient IVIG Access Demonstration Project</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 101(b) of the Medicare IVIG Access and Strengthening Medicare and Repaying Taxpayers Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HF8F1113B43F247F3AD25FF7C3DD9B294"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting after <quote>for a period of 3 years</quote> the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8B2987652FFF41719E793472B251AF7F" style="OLC"> <text>and, subject to the availability of funds under subsection (g)—</text><subparagraph id="HA17E9748CC8F421B844682A8291BC076"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the date of enactment of the <short-title>Medicare Part B Improvement Act of 2017</short-title> is on or before September 30, 2017, for the period beginning on October 1, 2017, and ending on December 31, 2020; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB806AEE6635F4CF6869078714CC8D70C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the date of enactment of such Act is after September 30, 2017, for the period beginning on the date of enactment of such Act and ending on December 31, 2020</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC1DBB2AA7C34AC2B60EED8F082CBD8C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Subject to the preceding sentence, a Medicare beneficiary enrolled in the demonstration project on September 30, 2017, shall be automatically enrolled during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Medicare Part B Improvement Act of 2017</short-title> and ending on December 31, 2020, without submission of another application.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H4A15474C2A59406187A5098A9358F852" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>103.</enum><header>Orthotist’s and prosthetist’s clinical notes as part of the patient’s medical record</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834(h) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(h)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3FCFAA99DDD4EADAFD959799171F767" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H251CBA83ABED4F22A7F1C7383A8FADF9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Documentation created by orthotists and prosthetists</header><text>For purposes of determining the reasonableness and medical necessity of orthotics and prosthetics, documentation created by an orthotist or prosthetist shall be considered part of the patient’s medical record to support documentation created by eligible professionals described in section 1848(k)(3)(B).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title id="H40A545E844104A6DB2D5480010B19A13"><enum>II</enum><header>Improvements in Dialysis Services</header>
			<section id="HCD4AD298F80145F3902AB0FE202AF554" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>201.</enum><header>Independent accreditation for dialysis facilities and assurance of high quality surveys</header>
				<subsection id="HC3A22E3ECE1041E99671DAFCD44B2B41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Accreditation and surveys</header>
 <paragraph id="HB697AAE3CCF849339DC51A189C6B0641"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1865 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395bb">42 U.S.C. 1395bb</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HE1D25B833BC44F938C8D7C69DA22B61E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <clause id="H631A7BC366514B68879F11571F8806D5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>or the conditions and requirements under section 1881(b)</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HAA5A65FC778542A3964AAD2AF23FAA07"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by inserting <quote>(including a renal dialysis facility)</quote> after <quote>facility</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A3FFB23A6DC4659A7C59C1930A15FB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5D6A31EDFE3448CACC6A25EF54BB44B" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H28491B45A96B4F81848ACDD244773ACB"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an accreditation body that has received approval from the Secretary under subsection (a)(3)(A) for accreditation of provider entities that are required to meet the conditions and requirements under section 1881(b), in addition to review and oversight authorities otherwise applicable under this title, the Secretary shall (as the Secretary determines appropriate) conduct, with respect to such accreditation body and provider entities, any or all of the following more frequently than is otherwise required to be conducted under this title with respect to other accreditation bodies or other provider entities:</text>
 <paragraph id="H7918ADD88658408697C0D09B400E7871"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Validation surveys referred to in subsection (d).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA63DFC9182044DEE95A8D69E2353D351"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Accreditation program reviews (as defined in section 488.8(c) of title 42 of the Code of Federal Regulations, or a successor regulation).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H622A39AF62C947FB8366BB350C5A42D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Performance reviews (as defined in section 488.8(a) of title 42 of the Code of Federal Regulations, or a successor regulation).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F61389559BA4A96A942ACDDCD55E33D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing for acceptance of requests from accreditation organizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall begin accepting requests from national accreditation bodies for a finding described in section 1865(a)(3)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395bb">42 U.S.C. 1395bb(a)(3)(A)</external-xref>) for purposes of accrediting provider entities that are required to meet the conditions and requirements under section 1881(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395rr">42 U.S.C. 1395rr(b)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6EF3586DA8D54EB697DE9F4D7B13CCC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement for timing of surveys of new dialysis facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1881(b)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395rr">42 U.S.C. 1395rr(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Beginning 180 days after the date of the enactment of this sentence, an initial survey of a provider of services or a renal dialysis facility to determine if the conditions and requirements under this paragraph are met shall be initiated not later than 90 days after such date on which both the provider enrollment form (without regard to whether such form is submitted prior to or after such date of enactment) has been determined by the Secretary to be complete and the provider’s enrollment status indicates approval is pending the results of such survey.</quote>.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HF435E2783B034BD0884B955C73D039B5" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>202.</enum><header>Expanding access to home dialysis therapy</header>
				<subsection id="HA8685FCFC4B2459491C8056046206AE6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowing use of telehealth for monthly end stage renal disease-Related visits</header>
 <paragraph id="H62B0FFF24EEB4E21A5A9AC073D2362C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (3) of section 1881(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395rr">42 U.S.C. 1395rr(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HC1D314841A7B456D9FA4B43A66CD9F76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA95A944F2FE241DE8D8114F6FE5010A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (i), as redesignated by subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>under this subparagraph</quote> and inserting <quote>under this clause</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA6F0ACF28AB4139A19027B38A9D47E9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (ii), as redesignated by subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>subject to subparagraph (B),</quote> before <quote>on a comprehensive</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9894CEFF5CBB4B84B09013578133A103"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking <quote>With respect to</quote> and inserting <quote>(A) With respect to</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H053C6B28BDFA46F7A8EABBE2F36825F3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23E0E993C0484DD6AD5C52FC7F3C214C" style="OLC">
								<subparagraph id="HEE19332DC5BE4D38AEFE73569973B7EA" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H60E8AF1859D8493BA5DD7D5602F90E3A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Subject to clause (ii), an individual who is determined to have end stage renal disease and who is receiving home dialysis may choose to receive monthly end stage renal disease-related visits, furnished on or after January 1, 2019, via telehealth.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAEBFF2E5BF4246C4B8D354BD7C6BF5A8" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Clause (i) shall apply to an individual only if the individual receives a face-to-face visit, without the use of telehealth—</text>
 <subclause id="HA078999B71804CAF9AEDFBDC5BBB6491"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of the initial three months of home dialysis of such individual, at least monthly; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H13EC4299931F4734AAA235226B53324E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>after such initial three months, at least once every three consecutive months.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HABE9EF142E3E46B2879115F58EA87BEF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of such section is amended by striking <quote>paragraph (3)(A)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (3)(A)(i)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H30FD4F9468394BD383268982C3BE6B82"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expanding originating sites for telehealth To include renal dialysis facilities and the home for purposes of monthly end stage renal disease-Related visits</header> <paragraph id="HEFC7DE978F3E44D8B43A7D5AD489BF0F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1834(m) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H256F9DFE969240EEA2D956B9B1C71A93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(C)(ii), by adding at the end the following new subclauses:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9FF38501BA1452EA8DC7165346C2403" style="OLC"> <subclause id="HD5F419BCE0E747FD8F6A833F03D4E706"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>A renal dialysis facility, but only for purposes of section 1881(b)(3)(B).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H02DFF6AA83DA4E689A61310293E230ED"><enum>(X)</enum><text>The home of an individual, but only for purposes of section 1881(b)(3)(B).</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4356879B3CEC4B14B5FCEEA7FFA74A89"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB88D1A4462824B5C8005B80871813BD9" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H92FA7E1392334DA1B959CA86F67D8734"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Treatment of home dialysis monthly ESRD-related visit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The geographic requirements described in paragraph (4)(C)(i) shall not apply with respect to telehealth services furnished on or after January 1, 2019, for purposes of section 1881(b)(3)(B), at an originating site described in subclause (VI), (IX), or (X) of paragraph (4)(C)(ii)), subject to applicable State law requirements, including State licensure requirements.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC82D9EE280DD429FA20BC49CF7F1F143"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No facility fee if originating site for home dialysis therapy is the home</header><text>Section 1834(m)(2)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(m)(2)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HAC9FF89519E644ABA79E958630DAC31E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (i) and (ii) as subclauses (I) and (II), respectively, and by indenting each of such subclauses 2 ems to the right;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04A8E07EF4A14A2DA27F46764E43D41E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subclause (II), as redesignated by subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>clause (i) or this clause</quote> and inserting <quote>subclause (I) or this subclause</quote>;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H381B411FA2704AEFB6309CD496343551"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">site</header-in-text>.—With respect to</quote> and inserting “<header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">site</header-in-text>.—</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1AE796E5328C4A8C9665104CECABF3E6" style="OLC">
 <clause id="H1131986D24254BC7941C13C7E091A7A3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), with respect to</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6A1721DA82748B0B481C578C5A0A5E4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF894B3596D5F457B80E0295545EFD654" style="OLC">
 <clause id="HB2C6967E2E9646B2A2CBE0D56D0AB551"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>No facility fee if originating site for home dialysis therapy is the home</header><text>No facility fee shall be paid under this subparagraph to an originating site described in subclause (X) of paragraph (4)(C)(ii).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF517EB3E2F02475E94B896739DFEC127"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clarification regarding telehealth provided to beneficiaries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1128A(i)(6) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1320a–7a(i)(6)) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE2468AA93E3643808A6A709651590026"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB435681E90E4065AF35DB00E0C9B911"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1284342F50AE47F09476AB10AC49A2F0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFDCE5F6F2F4141419911C9B3FDCF1E80" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H653CD5E6304344A5985D54581CEBEA3A"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the provision of telehealth on or after January 1, 2019, to individuals with end stage renal disease under title XVIII by a health care provider for the purpose of furnishing of telehealth.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB6F56B649EC047DF8DB31C60887076E1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Study and report on further expansion</header>
 <paragraph id="H3FB0E46FF3F44331B71D3B8C6B2061A6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study to examine the benefits and drawbacks of expanding the coverage under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act of renal dialysis services as telehealth services, pursuant to the amendments made by this section, to include coverage of renal dialysis services furnished via telehealth and store-and-forward technologies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDBAB609EFEBE41DF80873700754B5BD8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1).</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H89FC399E85A9446F8E8FFB1509B5A429"><enum>III</enum><header>Improvements in Application of Stark Rule</header>
			<section id="H0529238368664A10A44959DCE4469F33" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>301.</enum><header>Modernizing the application of the Stark rule under Medicare</header>
				<subsection id="H4EE52D9894164A608ED530D10CCED95D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Clarification of the writing requirement and signature requirement for arrangements pursuant to the
			 Stark rule</header>
 <paragraph id="HEACB834D6DD1468E80B30769D0479009"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Writing requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1877(h)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395nn">42 U.S.C. 1395nn(h)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0C8248C1810C463995471CBB61242590" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HE432F582CD9D4C46B894DF33D9477C36" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Written requirement clarified</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any requirement pursuant to this section for a compensation arrangement to be in writing, such requirement shall be satisfied by such means as determined by the Secretary, including by a collection of documents, including contemporaneous documents evidencing the course of conduct between the parties involved.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCBC3758A866B490D8FB5324D841BE155"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Signature requirement</header><text>Section 1877(e) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395nn">42 U.S.C. 1395nn(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HB791316F61A24363AAD68E3D9652D81F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A)(i), by inserting <quote>before or not later than 90 days after the effective date of the lease</quote> after <quote>signed by the parties</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB19E2D510C52404DAFEE3C0C2C966C39"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)(B)(i), by inserting <quote>before or not later than 90 days after the effective date of the lease</quote> after <quote>signed by the parties</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1216A1057154C1998FB85370DEA61BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3)(A)(i), by inserting <quote>before or not later than 90 days after the effective date of the arrangement</quote> after <quote>signed by the parties</quote>.</text>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H571372F6C8BE4B4F9FDA6A3E2554C205"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Indefinite holdover for lease arrangements and personal services arrangements pursuant to the Stark
 rule</header><text>Section 1877 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395nn">42 U.S.C. 1395nn</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB56DF64B18694D2BBFDE09CCCD879EC6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9F7E4D03339F410CA4CCF055723BFE9A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7CA47BB976BE4D19B44ECD05042DB225" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HE9FA0A5C93B740B5B35416FF97B5D290"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Holdover lease arrangements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a holdover lease arrangement for the lease of office space or equipment, which immediately follows a lease arrangement described in subparagraph (A) for the use of such office space or subparagraph (B) for the use of such equipment and that expired after a term of at least one year, payments made by the lessee to the lessor pursuant to such holdover lease arrangement, if—</text>
 <clause id="HB2AE6811571C4764B24199C5EDEDA8CB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the lease arrangement met the conditions of subparagraph (A) for the lease of office space or subparagraph (B) for the use of equipment when the arrangement expired;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF3D841F23B9F420AA5F126BC4B303078"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the holdover lease arrangement is on the same terms and conditions as the immediately preceding arrangement; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5E7A8EAD96D844179250E7448EF16F00"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the holdover arrangement continues to satisfy the conditions of subparagraph (A) for the lease of office space or subparagraph (B) for the use of equipment.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7C508B723974BD0AA9492D80311923F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F34B5C901FA4D5D8A07EBD65DF9DFC5" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HD2D3920405544B34B8500F88A3B8584C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Holdover personal service arrangement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a holdover personal service arrangement, which immediately follows an arrangement described in subparagraph (A) that expired after a term of at least one year, remuneration from an entity pursuant to such holdover personal service arrangement, if—</text>
 <clause id="H0E5AEA4167234CD5AB18F04E9F1D5DC4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the personal service arrangement met the conditions of subparagraph (A) when the arrangement expired;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEDC3755904534B07B89B3190669F5F87"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the holdover personal service arrangement is on the same terms and conditions as the immediately preceding arrangement; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4165C13DCAFD430DB00F37D37DD5AD22"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the holdover arrangement continues to satisfy the conditions of subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70BDC3C6B2DC44129158361A56ECB1F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(1), as amended by subsection (a)(1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF95056518EF44164B69FD021DDF7D36B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">; holdover arrangement</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">remuneration</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDED177251FA748CAAC937E8B2E9AF39A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H232C0D6606F146CBA31410EE5D612353" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H5F10B25DE8E8461689EDE56F5E745757" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Holdover arrangement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>holdover arrangement</term> means an arrangement, with respect to an agreement (including a lease or other arrangement) that has expired but as of the date of such expiration had been in compliance with the applicable requirements of this section, under which the parties to such expired agreement have, since such date of expiration, continued to perform under the terms and conditions of such expired agreement.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H29D5F7EEC2D84D9F9ECD4D46A1213D3E"><enum>302.</enum><header>Deposit of savings into Medicare Improvement Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1898(b)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395iii">42 U.S.C. 1395iii(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>during and after fiscal year 2021, $270,000,000</quote> the following: <quote>minus such dollar amount equal to the amount by which the projected expenditures under this title after application of the provisions of (including amendments made by) the Medicare Part B Improvement Act of 2017 (other than section 302 of such Act) are estimated to exceed the projected expenditures under this title without application of such provisions (other than such section 302)</quote>.</text>
			</section></title></legis-body></bill>


