<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H14B74553407340A8A49D23ACDE21903C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1246 IH: Territory Health Insurance Tax Relief Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1246</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170228">February 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Vel&#225;zquez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To exempt health insurance of residents of United States territories from the annual fee on health insurance providers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA3E8C7AD9C8B40DE8B27F06B83E25B15" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFCA898F3FA6B4E0B921322BD925957F6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Territory Health Insurance Tax Relief Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H44F46CEED5DC4F9782367424C29EB09D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Health insurance of residents of United States territories exempt from annual fee on health insurance providers</header> <subsection id="HCEECB5DE0B1B415F9B03DE41A888F260"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 9010(b) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (26 U.S.C. subtitle D front matter note) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4AFE6A4A2764462B983DCE09C32190E0" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H50CA8D75D1E5430295269FF70BE27ED1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exception for health insurance of residents of United States territories</header> 
<subparagraph id="HCDCB8BFBAA9B439D934C22F395DD2E10"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Solely for purposes of paragraph (1)(A), the term <quote>United States health risk</quote> shall not include the health risk of any individual who is a bona fide resident of Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, Puerto Rico, or the Virgin Islands (as determined under section 937(a)).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA9D88BA5A90A46D184B3ADD50C8BBC6F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception not to increase fee allocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount determined under paragraph (1)(B) shall be determined without regard to subparagraph (A) of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF52C0BB4FF5544EC88B32F7392069828"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 9010(g)(1) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (26 U.S.C. subtitle D front matter note) is amended by inserting <quote>(and the amount of such net premiums to which subsection (b)(4)(A) applies)</quote> before the period at the end.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H60E0566D19204F06B0F54CC4E3B3AD74"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header> <paragraph id="H27212A8C52C04FBF97FF96711504A84D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to calendar years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H66659AAB80FE483DBA5CEA7B8339EA36"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transitional rule for reporting</header><text>For purposes of applying the amendment made by subsection (a) with respect to the first calendar year beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s designee) shall provide a method for covered entities to report the information described in the amendment made by subsection (b) for the calendar year which precedes such first calendar year.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

