<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1AE39CFE46C94309A28B005B118B1831" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3878 IH: Free Credit Freeze Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3878</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170928">September 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000570">Mr. Ben Ray Luján of New Mexico</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to provide access to free credit freezes for all consumers.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H74544B907C5E4E28A49757775728BEF1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H067EB33DC332485ABB7CB80C6223CC8F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Free Credit Freeze Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H3C90C68DF2634350B15A8DB11650ABA4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Provides access to free credit freezes for all consumers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 605A of the Fair Credit Reporting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1681c-1">15 U.S.C. 1681c–1</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCCB759CCC46D4837BF3A8E635873AD60" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H15DF834173FD4F8790E7C60D102BA1EB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Credit freeze fees</header>
 <paragraph id="H26D959F17DE6461BADD8C9291F73BD98"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>credit freeze</term> means a restriction placed at the request of a consumer or a personal representative of the consumer, on the consumer report of the consumer, that prohibits a consumer reporting agency described in section 603(p) from releasing the consumer report for a purpose relating to the extension of credit without the express authorization of the consumer. A credit freeze shall not apply to the use of a consumer report by any of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEE638E3CDA294548AC1705765A36D150"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A person, or the person’s subsidiary, affiliate, agent, subcontractor, or assignee with whom the consumer has, or prior to assignment had, an account, contract, or debtor-creditor relationship for the purposes of reviewing the active account or collecting the financial obligation owed on the account, contract, or debt.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE9752D001394976B85DF1222167A915"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A person, or the person’s subsidiary, affiliate, agent, subcontractor, or assignee, to whom access has been granted pursuant to a request by the consumer for purposes of facilitating the extension of credit or other permissible use.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF78C93326AAC4E7C96C2598E13A36059"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any person acting pursuant to a court order, warrant, or subpoena.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FA7E05142D543278D8B25EC3ACE9270"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A Federal, State, or local government, or an agent or assignee thereof.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FE46AE4A52A450C8090FE27BA8D1168"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any person for the sole purpose of providing a credit monitoring or identity theft protection service to which the consumer has subscribed.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE58539156AA404DBAD89FEDDBC26A4F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any person for the purpose of providing a consumer with a copy of the consumer report, or credit score of the consumer upon the consumer's request.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H194A9252E5AD4A2C8746BA9BF753E078"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any person or entity for insurance purposes, including use in setting or adjusting a rate, adjusting a claim, or underwriting.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H910A461BD13F49348925D2E99F0AB4D6"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Any person acting pursuant to an authorization from a consumer to use their consumer report for employment purposes.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5A1CC003C51410AB9CCC770CA7FFE9B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A consumer reporting agency described in section 603(p) may not charge a consumer a fee to place, temporarily lift, or fully remove a credit freeze.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


