<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1434F95F7E1544DFA07BD06145569A65" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2765 IH: Perpetual POW/MIA Stamp Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2765</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170530">May 30, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001094">Mr. Cook</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the issuance of a forever stamp to honor the sacrifices of the brave men and women of the Armed Forces who are still prisoner, missing, or unaccounted for, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H06621951E0714F0DAA0466ED387D93A3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H16B63B029E7C4D8A9D7B78BACE063131" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Perpetual POW/MIA Stamp Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H29300DB4BAB547689A6E391448CDF4EC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds that—</text>
<paragraph id="H3604267D3614470683948F06EB4AF3B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Department of Defense reports that more than 83,000 service members remain missing since World War II;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE789FBC70ECF486BBF8F9E491FC9B45E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States Government has an obligation to achieve the fullest possible accounting for the Americans who have gone missing while serving the country and to leave no one unaccounted for in future conflicts;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFBA52C0FCFA04C308CF17DD75AD829AC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in 1982, the POW/MIA flag became the first flag other than the Flag of the United States to fly over the White House in Washington, DC;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE00CE637FAF544A1B46B32F6DB9C93A5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>on August 10, 1990, <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/101/355">Public Law 101–355</external-xref> designated the POW/MIA flag as <quote>The Symbol of our Nation’s concern and commitment to resolving as fully as possible the fates of Americans still prisoner, missing, and unaccounted for in Southeast Asia.</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H272104D0B7904AF39C79D67DFE10F63D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the POW/MIA flag should maintain continued visibility as a constant reminder of the plight of America’s Prisoners of War and Missing in Action.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H5C28424D0FE24182B31D05842FE522A3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Perpetual POW/MIA stamp</header> <subsection id="HFC020D4D36A44505B8B7C7C81BF0503E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>In order to continue to honor the sacrifices of the brave men and women of the Armed Forces who have been prisoner, missing, or unaccounted for, the Postmaster General shall provide for the issuance of a forever stamp suitable for that purpose and depicts the National League of Families POW/MIA flag.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H27151B8301CB4A9B8978203B29205F89"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this Act, the term <quote>forever stamp</quote> means a definitive stamp which meets the postage required for first-class mail up to one ounce in weight, and which retains full validity for that purpose even if the rate of that postage is later increased.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H19637B5E356049E08F36AB94FE9E8907"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The stamp described in subsection (a) shall be issued beginning as soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act and shall not thereafter be discontinued.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

