<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H3D7BF9BF8F664F6DB5CFD07B8F387164" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1405 IH: The Veterans Visa and Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1405</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170307">March 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000132">Mr. Vela</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a veterans visa program to permit
			 veterans who have been removed from the United States to return as
			 immigrants, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HDC2AED8A2A3C435D92869C4CA0ECF46E" style="OLC">
 <section id="HBFADCCBD7A644476BD55D8911A436237" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>The Veterans Visa and Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H64EE8074F75B4C88B3EAEEC6F6EDDEBA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2D60A5CE873141E5881931971328C69A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>crime of violence</quote> means an offense defined in section 16 of title 18, United States Code, excluding a purely political offense, for which the noncitizen has served a term of imprisonment of at least 5 years.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H197BAB7889CF4949B41EE710B4A54308"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>deported veteran</quote> means a veteran who is a noncitizen and who—</text> <subparagraph id="HE4084AAB3E2646749F2D857607E99013"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was removed from the United States; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33D664EB36AE4A5C84362953CFFFEB97"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is abroad and is inadmissible under section 212(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD96D2E0024FF4887B93F3E167A3FD98C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>noncitizen</quote> means an individual who is not a national of the United States (as defined in section 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22)</external-xref>)).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6A5E09F504C4C3DA41D1B2BEC2AA3E3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB85121F98BC47FD96E02CFAFE3BCAB2"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>service member</quote> means an individual who is serving as a member of a regular or reserve component of the Armed Forces of the United States on active duty or as a member of a reserve component of the Armed Forces in an active status.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H51635A6689C94CAF836A7C204F0716FF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <quote>veteran</quote> has the meaning given such term under section 101(2) of title 38, United States Code.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H2705DE89DCBA4C7EA6677740942BB24F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Return of noncitizen veterans removed from the United States; status for noncitizen veterans in the United States</header> <subsection id="H0E08F36387BB4D69995F88A36A81E695"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="H29E0B28503BD43F9B865F87CB78915A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Duties of Secretary</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD1B2AEC5761242CCBBFC7DAC6A7C1056"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish a program and application procedure to permit—</text> <clause id="HA713229AA7A648B699EC1DE01C00CA43"><enum>(i)</enum><text>deported veterans who meet the requirements of subsection (b) to enter the United States as a noncitizen lawfully admitted for permanent residence; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H419970FF52AE4845A1628A39BE637842"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">noncitizen veterans in the United States who meet the requirements of subsection (b) to adjust status to that of a noncitizen lawfully admitted for permanent residence; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A900E6F6A00478B9D3597652AD9B483"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cancel the removal of noncitizen veterans ordered removed who meet the requirements of subsection (b) and allow them to adjust status to that of a noncitizen lawfully admitted for permanent residence.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB34FACB9D1F445881B6D06A83DB93D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No numerical limitations</header><text>Nothing in this section or in any other law shall be construed to apply a numerical limitation on the number of veterans who may be eligible to receive benefits under paragraph (1).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C57B9E5B87A4BB1BEF2069911404BE1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header>
 <paragraph id="H9107A766F2C947039A6EC998B023C1F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including sections 212 and 237 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C.1182; 1227), a veteran shall be eligible for the program established under subsection (a)(1)(A), or cancellation of removal under subsection (a)(1)(B), if the Secretary determines that the veteran—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6DF20D86F88542AF9EA42A434FE4284B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was not ordered removed, or removed, from the United States due to a criminal conviction for—</text> <clause id="H2CCA1F224D454998A6A6B44CE257F0A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a crime of violence; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H446E1C7BD35749D6B947A6AD83AC2F92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a crime that endangers the national security of the United States for which the noncitizen has served a term of imprisonment of at least 5 years; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68B1205392C545E5825001CC47445E6E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not inadmissible to, or deportable from, the United States due to such a conviction.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AD6CFF80A764FC29C86092B3BC2F5B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary may waive paragraph (1) for humanitarian purposes, to assure family unity, due to exceptional service in the United States Armed Forces, or if such waiver otherwise is in the public interest.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC976269025E043D0872987EF86B0DA3D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Protecting veterans and service members from removal</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including section 237 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1227">8 U.S.C. 1227</external-xref>), a noncitizen who is a veteran or service member shall not be removed from the United States unless the noncitizen has a criminal conviction for a crime of violence.</text>
 </section><section id="H12D73C8D6C914422B4F3B3EFEADBDF47"><enum>5.</enum><header>Naturalization through service in the Armed Forces of the United States</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a noncitizen who has obtained the status of a noncitizen lawfully admitted for permanent residence pursuant to section 2 shall be eligible for naturalization through service in the Armed Forces of the United States under sections 328 and 329 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1439">8 U.S.C. 1439</external-xref>; 1440), except that—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4988B649A6D3471EA35F8D8F49A02CF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ground or grounds on which the noncitizen was ordered removed, or removed, from the United States, or was rendered inadmissible to, or deportable from, the United States, shall be disregarded when determining whether the noncitizen is a person of good moral character; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1BC0F913EF654531A39C98BAA261867A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any period of absence from the United States due to the noncitizen having been removed, or being inadmissible, shall be disregarded when determining if the noncitizen satisfies any requirement relating to continuous residence or physical presence.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HF9F0F5328F744944BDBFAB19442D67F1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Access to military benefits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A noncitizen who has obtained the status of a noncitizen lawfully admitted for permanent residence pursuant to section 2 shall be eligible for all military and veterans benefits for which the noncitizen would have been eligible if the noncitizen had never been ordered removed, been removed, or voluntarily departed, from the United States.</text>
		</section><section id="H939657EAB48F46549E220C79D7AC3D09"><enum>7.</enum><header>Implementation</header>
 <subsection id="HC2C6C06E73284CCAABA194AFB320B098"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall identify cases involving service members and veterans at risk of removal from the United States by—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6B80E959E86A4C9B9BB8D5700DFB9CD5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inquiring of every noncitizen processed prior to initiating removal proceedings whether the noncitizen is serving, or has served, as a member of a regular or reserve component of the Armed Forces of the United States on active duty or as a member of a reserve component of the Armed Forces in an active status;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4781C6BF800F4ED5981986BA8F2A699B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>requiring personnel to seek supervisory approval prior to initiating removal proceedings against a service member or veteran; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C4BC5365F9B492182B40DEED8E9D33F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>keeping records of service members and veterans who have had removal proceedings against them initiated, been detained, or been removed.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H97981F7A094947D08676E0054617B896"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Record annotation</header><text>When the Secretary has identified a case under subsection (a), the Secretary shall annotate all immigration and naturalization records of the Department of Homeland Security relating to the noncitizen involved so as to reflect that identification and afford an opportunity to track the outcomes for the noncitizen. Such annotation shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB1222CD694B94E2181CEC0888E2767AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the individual’s branch of military service;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD337C7E5C9E74AA78370D5B1D88B2B8C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether or not the individual is serving, or has served, during a period of military hostilities described in section 329 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1440">8 U.S.C. 1440</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC423C2D5AAE2461397120ACBA4D8123C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the individual’s immigration status at the time of enlistment;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H843CCC58E89F4D1E9A5F16A7EA58E793"><enum>(4)</enum><text>whether the individual is serving honorably or was separated under honorable conditions; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD3E12209929F4014B2E5DF7B0604ACB5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the basis for which removal was sought; and, if the basis for removal was a criminal conviction, the crime or crimes for which conviction was obtained.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB4DA308DA8B6454E85CBD3238CCB5164"><enum>8.</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations to implement this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


