<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H03FED947979645AE91D3139FAC9BB060" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 311 IH: Refusing to Assist Paying for United Nations Actions Against Israel Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 311</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170105">January 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To withhold United States assessed and voluntary contributions to the United Nations, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HA2B3A7C41F63423AAB14836D165CBD73" style="OLC">
 <section id="H379253DB0F504463A250AF7AA6902E7B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Refusing to Assist Paying for United Nations Actions Against Israel Act</short-title></quote> .</text> </section><section id="H63846F069B904D9CB18D7BAD41961E98"><enum>2.</enum><header>United States assessed and voluntary contributions to the United Nations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds are authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for assessed or voluntary contributions of the United States to the United Nations or to any organ, specialized agency, commission, treaty or treaty body, or other affiliated body of the United Nations and the United States System, until such time as United Nations Security Council Resolution 2334, regarding Israel’s Settlements in the West Bank and East Jerusalem, is repealed in its entirety.</text>
 </section><section id="HAF4777C7231749A99B277E6C88DB7ACF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Interest on Withheld Payments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds are authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available to pay interest on assessed or voluntary contributions that are withheld under this Act.</text>
 </section><section id="H0099AF2756744404A60B3D55526A8FC2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Effective on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall notify the United Nations of the provisions of this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


