<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H4CEB33FC5CA14B009110411A1A218466" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2850 IH: Military Patron Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2850</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170608">June 8, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Military Resale Patron Benefits Advisory Commission, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H10B7B8187329413892186F59652FB3D1" style="OLC">
 <section id="H513E1A30FE93496F80C6696939CB5791" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Patron Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD48D907AB9D04DCE886AB30FBFCF847C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Military Resale Patron Benefits Advisory Commission</header> <subsection id="HE4E6D55E62894CCE990DF8038769E893"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established a commission to be known as the <quote>Military Resale Patron Benefits Advisory Commission</quote> (in this Act referred to as <quote>the Commission</quote>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H16322BB968284F8A8C0495D42422C952"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Commission shall be to advise the Secretary of Defense regarding—</text> <paragraph id="H796BBE27F0244F14A4432EEB42C19B4C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effects of the operations of military commissaries and exchanges on—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9B3377F95EBF429699F3952EC308C855"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">patrons of military commissaries and exchanges; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FA9F9DF46BB4253B2219BA943ADA1C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">morale, welfare and recreation programs;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5619048ADF024EF897E74976F48D214D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the sources and uses of revenue from military commissaries and exchanges, including surcharge funding;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC5C1704F6294455A9305EA76E0FDD37"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fulfillment of the requirements under Section 661 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/840">Public Law 114–840</external-xref>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6DD39DFA64B3409FA78ADA44D4FF3D8D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">proposed reforms to the operations of military commissaries and exchanges that could effect—</text> <subparagraph id="HFD624065BA9D4A8CA54AA3ABB916EA82"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of revenue from military commissaries and exchanges (including surcharge funding);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD59CC376D98C4C0D852AA20F3E1F496B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the morale, welfare and recreation programs provided for members of the Armed Forces and their dependents; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD431351672F84F4981047A543F10C740"><enum>(C)</enum><text>philanthropic programs that benefit members of the Armed Forces and their families; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDA01E1F52FC423B8536A2CF33C94B38"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the possible effects of such reforms on the morale of members of the Armed Forces and their dependents.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H49D2B67E982045C6A6235753013D1381"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header>
 <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H298BE42ED592403EB165917B1D6D71BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Number and appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall be comprised of seven members, appointed by the Secretary of Defense from military or veterans service organizations to represent the interests of patrons and beneficiaries of military commissaries and exchanges.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H88A0FA13F2664BB781C924FF620179FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2CEC3AF3FDE04E7D81A4E97C460F8165"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each member shall be appointed for a term of one year, subject to renewal by the Secretary of Defense.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F2D262C6B1244D4A338E1B54E3F9D82"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>A vacancy in the Commission shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF56E3E1EAAE42ABA62533B0064E25E9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Pay</header><text>Members of the Commission shall serve without pay.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H578AAE9BCCDF4289B1737498D420CA9B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>Each member shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03B7DC3A21884A80A010F74C95126B0A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Commission shall elect a Chairperson.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBBA30586912340D6832B002EFA74A3AB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Commission shall meet at the call of the Chairperson.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C0DA1455DD840369C7659E87FADBC37"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Director and staff of Commission; experts and consultants</header>
 <paragraph id="HDF7E1ED095294D6A85A9EB352A3168E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall appoint a member of the Armed Forces to serve as the Director of the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94F56EB6979245399BFEBBF993534147"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Experts and consultants</header><text>With the approval of the Commission, the Director may procure temporary and intermittent services under section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D90747A0C6049549CCA910F5271C5A1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Staff of Federal agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon request of the Commission, the head of any Federal department or agency may detail, on a reimbursable basis, any of the personnel of that department or agency to the Commission to assist it in carrying out its duties under this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7D577178D13E4C0B9C543ECB4672E312"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header>
 <paragraph id="H85C2A88AC1C041CC9988670DA654FF9F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hearings and sessions</header><text>The Commission may, for the purpose of carrying out this Act, hold hearings, sit and act at times and places, take testimony, and receive evidence as the Commission considers appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H625EA8ACB3EB4505A298F06173F768BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Obtaining official data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may secure directly from any department or agency of the United States information necessary to enable it to carry out this Act. Upon request of the Chairperson of the Commission, the head of that department or agency shall furnish that information to the Commission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6FAD9479DC4D42A3B792E1AB2C6CF36F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mails</header><text>The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7032C56EB9754B54A7E202D6E7F52A5F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administrative support services</header><text>Upon request of the Commission, the Administrator of General Services shall provide to the Commission, on a reimbursable basis, the administrative support services necessary for the Commission to carry out its responsibilities under this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H55B0A6C54E7A49D4970772A0BBF492B9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <paragraph id="H362CA3C210C0413E9DF897EA1E5CCBB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interim reports</header><text>The Commission may submit to the Secretary of Defense interim reports as the Commission considers appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CE4A4A082E64356A6D5C7B0D8B48AD3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>The Commission shall transmit a final report to the President and the Congress not later than the day on which the Commission terminates under subsection (g). The final report shall contain a detailed statement of the findings and conclusions of the Commission, together with its recommendations for legislation or administrative actions the Commission considers appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5817EAED891849BDA11F798E51F9D349"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 14(a)(2)(B) of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.; relating to the termination of advisory committees) notwithstanding, the Commission shall terminate upon the day that is five years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H682B467A351340C492A0ECB325B2D1DA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reports</header>
 <subsection id="H76FE4ECAC3254C2188CD4211AB486A3A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than March 1, 2018, and annually thereafter for the subsequent four calendar years, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Congress an annual report regarding the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H5438807E250E4BFEBB6B114D2A0A0E96"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The use of funds generated by military commissaries and exchanges other than to—</text> <subparagraph id="H2D4C8C56BAAA49CB85E005B7F84AF681"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cover capital costs of such military commissaries and exchanges;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC263CD5EB23945DFA6F811DD810CB3BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support morale, welfare and recreation programs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2050978F7F474157884514C3B8F383E5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide services directly to members of the Armed Services or their families; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA462F96D558544178D57AA14A40C1EC0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>support operations in a forward deployed or tactical environment.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H71522C04B9A44D7FB43579FA9AA8A45C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The constitution and purpose of the respective boards of directors of the Military Exchanges and Commissary Operations and any determination by any such board to use proceeds covered in a report under paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H94F08A6889C24624A1E1B4A4D172BD38"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Responses of the Secretary to any findings or proposals of the Commission.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6FEB5F4D53BA4D5B9185F81B8BDBDD80"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Actions described in subsection (b), (c), or (d).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6326BEA4ABCE4ABDB6EFA11EB63351D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification before certain expenditures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall notify the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate no later than 90 days before expending any funds generated by a military commissary or exchange for a purpose other than those named in subsection (a)(1).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H2E056CD5645D45908AED2A33F0756EEB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification before actions that reduce certain contracts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall notify the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate no later than 90 days before taking any action that would result in the reduction of a contract awarded by the Defense Commissary Agency that has been awarded to—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HD7FC1D54B66B41B69CA20246C02B7C29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a small, veteran-owned, woman-owned, or disadvantaged business concern;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C1805724BA24520BB755CCADDE9AC5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a qualified nonprofit agency for the blind under section 8501(7) of title 41, United States Code; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H577AAFDD4FF2456E86416ADA2942863A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a qualified nonprofit agency for other severely disabled under section 8501(6) of title 41, United States Code.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


