<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H20230E3121FC4C2996A62B232D2B63E7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4512 IH: Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4512</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171201">December 1, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001294">Mr. Blum</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide that the rates of pay for Members of Congress shall be reduced following any fiscal year
			 in which there is a Federal deficit.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H74A9E098E6964D6AB525A5801BCD036A" style="OLC">
 <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA9E2E84F7B7408D9CC44AE3FA1DB68D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short Title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HB30DFD12FCD54D34A0C3737EE33780F7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purpose of this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="H44785EE52D6C47D7B0F2210FCDB3141F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a <term>deficit</term> shall be considered to exist in a fiscal year if total budget outlays of the Government for such fiscal year exceed total revenues of the Government for such fiscal year (as determined under <internal-xref idref="H460D596027244C1C82F1271EA2C86761" legis-path="3.(d)">section 3(d)</internal-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E0EF2CE30C141C88A6A1CBDBD5C362E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Member of Congress</term> or <term>Member</term> means an individual serving in a position referred to in section 601(a)(1) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501(1)</external-xref>).</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H6B905D04B0B64502A41CD4FAB86B6929"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effect of a deficit</header>
 <subsection id="H59FDF1E59B8942DEA73187050AEC2649"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if there is a deficit in a fiscal year, then—</text> <paragraph id="H168A4DB760B94D4DB2D19383F4AC596B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any pay adjustment for Members of Congress scheduled to take effect under section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>) in the succeeding calendar year shall be null and void; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC05A31FEFC24258A9BA96E6FF7B9067"><enum>(2)</enum><text>effective as of the first day of the first pay period beginning in that succeeding calendar year, rates of basic pay for Members of Congress shall be reduced (from the rate in effect as of the day before the start of such succeeding calendar year) by the amount determined under <internal-xref idref="H8D9883C48F544EC8B4D34F0386AED4A4" legis-path="3.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>, but not below zero.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8D9883C48F544EC8B4D34F0386AED4A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reductions required</header><text>The reduction required under this subsection is as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H13DCC374C84044A6B814AE786C6AC6D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If the reduction is to take effect in a calendar year that does not immediately follow another calendar year in which a reduction under this section was made, the reduction amount shall be equal to 5 percent of the rate of basic pay last in effect before such reduction is made.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H67A020A288354045B613562A1CF17155"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If the reduction is to take effect in a calendar year that immediately follows another calendar year in which a reduction under this section was made, the reduction amount shall be equal to 10 percent of the rate of basic pay last in effect before the most recent reduction under <internal-xref idref="H13DCC374C84044A6B814AE786C6AC6D5" legis-path="3.(b)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> was made.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H02B296E2BD9E48FFA37309A147754405"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conditions for restoration</header><text>If, following one or more years in which Members’ pay is reduced under this Act, there occurs a fiscal year in which there is no deficit, then, effective as of the first day of the first pay period in the succeeding calendar year (and until another deficit triggering the preceding provisions of this section occurs)—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8ECEA06FC19C44F89802C2FFCC8A0A95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>rates of basic pay for Members shall be restored to the highest rate that was at any time previously payable for the office involved; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4076D3F1F30D45C6923320EDD58B241C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>pay adjustments scheduled to take effect on or after such first day under the provision of law referred to in <internal-xref idref="H168A4DB760B94D4DB2D19383F4AC596B" legis-path="3.(a)(1)">subsection (a)(1)</internal-xref> shall be effective.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H460D596027244C1C82F1271EA2C86761"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Determinations</header><text>Determinations of whether or not a deficit exists in any fiscal year shall, for purposes of this Act, be made by the Director of the Congressional Budget Office. In making any such determination, the Director shall exclude any budget outlays resulting from a formal declaration of war by Congress.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H9A14EB00780F48F38D36BF0697D72730"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act, except that no determination under <internal-xref idref="H460D596027244C1C82F1271EA2C86761" legis-path="3.(d)">section 3(d)</internal-xref> shall be made with respect to any fiscal year before fiscal year 2018.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


