<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC8B3E9F4E7DD427C80EE691BCCBE8204" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1075 IH: Freedom for Refugees Escaping Enmity (FREE) Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1075</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170215">February 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000390">Mr. Kihuen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000455">Ms. Fudge</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000537">Mr. Clyburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000586">Mr. Lawson of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide that the Executive Order entitled <quote>Protecting the Nation from Foreign Terrorist Entry into the United States</quote> (January 27, 2017) shall have no force or effect, to prohibit the use of Federal funds to enforce
			 the Executive Order, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H92A7E897173043F2B603A167DEDCCE00" style="OLC">
 <section id="HFB757FCA8FEB4C488ACB010647EB0B83" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Freedom for Refugees Escaping Enmity (FREE) Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDCBB16DA5454445E8BDF90B1865C5CFC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Nullification of effect of executive order</header> <subsection id="HA58377F94AA44EEB8AC9D166897EA0B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Executive Order entitled <quote>Protecting the Nation from Foreign Terrorist Entry into the United States</quote> (January 27, 2017) (<quote>the Executive Order</quote>), is null and void, shall have no force or effect, and may not be implemented, administered, enforced, or carried out.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1B1E1A77EBE7438689DFC3E9822805B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall take effect as if enacted concurrent with the execution of the Executive Order.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H09F6B1DC5684446D8167BFD15DDFCD7F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No funds available</header><text>No amounts (including fees) made available to the Secretary of Homeland Security, or to any other official of a Federal agency, by any Act for any fiscal year, may be used to implement, administer, enforce, or carry out (including through the issuance of any regulations) any of the policy changes set forth in the Executive Order.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6324D6F8E1474A7F85F56859E2F47A8A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Release of aliens in custody</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall release any alien in custody under the authority of the Executive Order.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H46198AAF843F4945BCC2B1156F37B113"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Revoked visas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall ensure that any visa or other documentation issued to an alien and revoked, or provisionally revoked, under the authority of the Executive Order is reinstated, reissued, or replaced, as appropriate, unless a consular officer knows, or has reason to believe, that the alien is ineligible to receive the visa or documentation under section 212 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</external-xref>) or any other provision of the immigration laws (as defined in section 101(a)(17) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(17)</external-xref>)). The Secretary of State shall ensure that, in the case of an alien who was unable to apply for admission before the expiration of the validity of the alien’s visa by reason of the Executive Order, the visa is timely renewed or replaced, as appropriate, in order to afford the alien an opportunity to apply for admission, unless a consular officer knows, or has reason to believe, that the alien is ineligible to receive the visa or documentation under section 212 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</external-xref>) or any other provision of the immigration laws (as defined in section 101(a)(17) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(17)</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE6F1721E494E41848EACB49161D54BFD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Visa refusal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall ensure that any decision by a consular officer to refuse a visa or other documentation under the authority of the Executive Order is reconsidered by the consular officer in order to determine whether the consular officer knows, or has reason to believe, that the alien is ineligible to receive the visa or documentation under section 212 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</external-xref>) or any other provision of the immigration laws (as defined in section 101(a)(17) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(17)</external-xref>)).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H40C04560628F4A6AB9FCC6439AB6F72F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>No effect on immigration status or benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Executive Order, and any action taken under the authority of the Executive Order, shall not be considered to have modified or otherwise affected the immigration status, or eligibility for any immigration benefit, under the immigration laws (as defined in section 101(a)(17) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(17)</external-xref>)) of any person. Section 206 the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1156">8 U.S.C. 1156</external-xref>), section 212(a)(9)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(9)(A)</external-xref>), and section 276 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1326">8 U.S.C. 1326</external-xref>) shall not be construed to apply to any denial of admission, removal, or departure from the United States under the authority of the Executive Order. No alien may be adversely affected for any withdrawal of an application for admission or other voluntary departure from the United States initiated due to the Executive Order. The registration of any alien may not be terminated under section 203(g) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(g)</external-xref>) if the alien fails timely to apply for an immigrant visa by reason of the Executive Order.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HCE60B5191F2E4279A72AF40435B87796"><enum>3.</enum><header>Nondiscrimination in the issuance of immigrant visas based on religion</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 202(a)(1)(A) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1152">8 U.S.C. 1152(a)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>religion or lack of religious beliefs,</quote> after <quote>sex,</quote>.</text>
		</section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H950B7A3B89DD4CBF9EF5317784361D81"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on denying admission or entry because of religion</header>
 <subsection id="H5EE351A8ECE4400D84028D8345B57849"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 2 of title I of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1181">8 U.S.C. 1181</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 219 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2EA76FD43B714CA5911ECB61D314D6DF" style="OLC">
 <section id="HE92C4C773EA845608AA901C5907F9131"><enum>220.</enum><header>Prohibition on denying admission or entry because of religion</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of the immigration laws, an alien may not be denied entry, reentry, or admission to the United States because of the alien’s religion or lack of religious beliefs.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8ADD5C94D0004FBFA909D74DE630236D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 219 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H35E620C1D45043CF88ECE8F9EFED15C5" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 220. Prohibition on denying admission or entry because of religion.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="HC33BF92132864BC69A1220CEA876F070"><enum>5.</enum><header>Limitation on Presidential authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 212(f) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H78F42E93142A4C5099A8717BD88DBF27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="traditional"><enum-in-header>(f)</enum-in-header></header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="traditional"><enum-in-header>(f)(1)</enum-in-header></header-in-text></quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC74E05DDE2104238A9556C010A779C0B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E2D1FD559DF42CEB1B83EF9A933CD71" style="traditional"> <paragraph id="H6ACF1954BAC54FD59B80870702A8B209" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H696013F81C88486A80AF26BEACB34411"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the President, notwithstanding paragraph (1) and section 215(a)(1), may not exercise the President’s authority under such provisions so as to modify the requirements under the immigration laws for entry, reentry, or admission, as applied to an alien having, on the date of such exercise of authority—</text>
 <clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC58734157A3243B8AB4A2990B9D6D81F" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a valid and unexpired immigrant or nonimmigrant visa; or</text> </clause><clause id="H8546CA75C91548E29FF373A18BC775C7" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>valid and unexpired status as—</text>
 <subclause id="H2710A4EAAFF047489861A814B7DA8FBA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HA207A988C8B54E80A7A545F87728CBF8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a refugee who qualifies for admission, or who has been admitted, under section 207(c)(1); or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3C804A43D1A440759EE1E81C1D051F53"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an alien granted asylum.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54C8E2BF2E4F4BEFB43E73412CEA1F59" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Nothing in subparagraph (A) shall be construed to affect the authorities under subsections (h) and (i) of section 221.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


