<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2D13B140DD394999A16E0D690E6BF902" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2965 IH: Gas Pump Access Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2965</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170620">June 20, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000593">Mr. Ross</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require all gas stations offering self-service to meet certain accessibility standards for individuals with disabilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H49231FA4D84B4C02BA34ACBB54787B98" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBB6E756932CB4C3594BF21BD02679FAC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gas Pump Access Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9DE4E4491E1245368405218A9CE7DC5E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H74049948A89241BA9FA2C5A04D7CE486"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The technical assistance materials for the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 of the Department of Justice requires gas stations, including those offering self-service, to provide equal access for their customers with disabilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H702FDAEA688E49B5BEC32E15879A2F99"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Customers with disabilities are advised that they can obtain refueling assistance by either honking or otherwise signaling an employee.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB255BD85E197442BA3B1CDA438840FC0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 requires self-service gas stations to provide refueling assistance upon the request of a qualified person with a disability if there is more than one attendant on duty at the station. Such service is provided without any charge beyond the self-service price.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBE72B6BEFAC442BFB1AE53DA7B407845"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A qualified person with a disability is described as a person to whom an accessible or disabled parking permit has been issued or a person who is in legal possession of a specialized motor vehicle license plate indicating that the owner is a person with a disability.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD773D04DD7BF4FB0818D8B7BD3C64CAC"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">History has shown that these methods to attract refueling assistance are not effective. Throughout the United States, individuals with disabilities who need gas pumping assistance at gas stations or convenience stores do not generally receive such assistance when they honk their horns, flash their headlights, or otherwise signal to attract the attention of an attendant inside the facility. This is not considered equal access under the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F7A31C29D67432490D99A440E308B43"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2014, the State of Florida enacted House Bill 7005, which requires phone numbers to be placed on all gas pumps not later than two years after July 1, 2014. This requirement allows qualified individuals with disabilities to call on their cell phones for free gas pumping assistance. However, should such refueling assistance be requested during times when a second attendant is not present at a self-service gasoline station, the Florida gas station retailer is not required to provide the requested assistance and will inform the caller. History has proven this to be a simple, inexpensive, common sense, effective solution that is favored by both customers with disabilities and the petroleum and convenience store industries.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H92B68FB90B6B45088D1725D9C74F756E"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Today, unlike in 1990, almost everyone owns a cell phone. Owning a cell phone is a safety measure for drivers with disabilities in case their vehicle breaks down on the road.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HC5D12F2E325A40DB8A0269BFFCF31ED9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to provide accessibility to gas stations by ensuring that it will be considered discrimination under the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101</external-xref> et seq.) for a gas station to fail to display a phone number to call for assistance on each self-service gas pump of the gas station.</text></section>
<section id="H1C3C7C9090024AD9AD33BC8715779547"><enum>4.</enum><header>Accessibility</header>
<subsection id="H164004FB31DE4425A5AA676C63D32E8E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notification Requirement</header>
<paragraph id="H0DA05BA816774E779421A480761336F2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall be considered discrimination for purposes of section 302 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12182">42 U.S.C. 12182</external-xref>) for a gas station or convenience store to fail to clearly display at each self-service gas pump a decal that—</text> <subparagraph id="HBB39902532CA4F08A8BA7CAE6F6EEFDB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is at least 15 square inches in size;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2217FB185FB3413BA073224DB8BE0D7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has a blue background;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H732C0B071B224EB09B6F6FAAB6110D7D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes the telephone number of the gas station or convenience store at which such pump is located and the words <quote>Call for Assistance</quote> in printed white text; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H278E9A464D8144069144DC68475C655E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>includes the International Symbol of Accessibility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H947372A5005240CBA08B189B2ED1044D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Operational telephone</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the telephone number indicated on the decal, it shall be considered discrimination for purposes of section 302 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12182">42 U.S.C. 12182</external-xref>) if the phone connected to such number is not operational and answered directly by an employee of the gas station retailer during the hours the gas station retailer is open for business to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF5817638666B4F85BEC7EC360DE30B33"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assistance</header>
<paragraph id="HC75C09E350B344F590B4870F1FFA9380"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Two or more attendants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be considered discrimination for purposes of section 302 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12182">42 U.S.C. 12182</external-xref>) for a gas station or convenience store that is open for business to the public with two or more attendants on duty to fail to provide gas pumping assistance to a qualified individual with a disability who makes a request for such assistance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38DECE10F70D4474870B817DFB279EF4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>One attendant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall not be considered discrimination for purposes of section 302 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12182">42 U.S.C. 12182</external-xref>) for a gas station or convenience store that is open for business to the public with one attendant on duty to fail to provide gas pumping assistance to a qualified individual with a disability who makes a request for such assistance, if such attendant notifies the individual that assistance cannot be provided because there is only one attendant on duty.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD7331B8E299C43EDA2A7C4B5C044BA91"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Further accessibility standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall prohibit a unit of local government from adopting an ordinance, or enforcing an existing ordinance, that expands the accessibility, safety, or availability of fueling assistance to a motor vehicle operator with a qualified disability.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H373DCB854E214D3981127D41D69A7A21"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation and the Attorney General shall each promulgate such regulations as are necessary to ensure compliance with this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H9A7D2671B6A5464482216D8C176A6D86"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Example of decal made publicly available</header><text>Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation and the Attorney General shall make a graphic example of a decal described in subsection (a) publicly available at no cost, in downloadable format, on the websites of the Department of Transportation and the Department of Justice, respectively. Such decal shall have a blank area in which a telephone number may be inserted.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

