<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2C6FCD9236894D62820A8018E78BD994" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3166 IH: To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide under the Medicare program for independent accreditation for dialysis facilities and assurance of high quality surveys with respect to such facilities.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3166</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170706">July 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide under the Medicare program for independent accreditation for dialysis facilities and assurance of high quality surveys with respect to such facilities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBD21AF29E06341EEB6AB40F15D3E8D38" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8154AC1FD29A46E5A4946FC3C39E2378" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Independent accreditation for dialysis facilities and assurance of high quality surveys</header> 
<subsection id="H383044B71EC540F1B5245A64F0D38E86"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Accreditation and surveys</header> 
<paragraph id="H4E7403F91EF14B41BA242B0A164F8595"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1865 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395bb">42 U.S.C. 1395bb</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H7F2C02079BEA4E898FD8B4D34034619F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> 
<clause id="H3BE3F037A3FA48449D11899DEF345930"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>or the conditions and requirements under section 1881(b)</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HBA9FF83AA1BA4D8389657B593A62C846"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by inserting <quote>(including a renal dialysis facility)</quote> after <quote>facility</quote>; and </text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFA4535B13C0248EF9823EE1AD6992733"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8255872680714E8D839B60B62390E67C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HABA538BE7D124D4ABDC6942977E6507E"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an accreditation body that has received approval from the Secretary under subsection (a)(3)(A) for accreditation of provider entities that are required to meet the conditions and requirements under section 1881(b), in addition to review and oversight authorities otherwise applicable under this title, the Secretary shall (as the Secretary determines appropriate) conduct, with respect to such accreditation body and provider entities, any or all of the following more frequently than is otherwise required to be conducted under this title with respect to other accreditation bodies or other provider entities:</text> 
<paragraph id="H41312847E2A049E59D1C2B3E1A4E1D4A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Validation surveys referred to in subsection (d). </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD11A4093577B48C59BDE6DB18A84F33D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Accreditation program reviews (as defined in section 488.8(c) of title 42 of the Code of Federal Regulations, or a successor regulation).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3EEF974D7B9D40C6A4E7D1C1523DF3A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Performance reviews (as defined in section 488.8(a) of title 42 of the Code of Federal Regulations, or a successor regulation).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE650C1702BE48EA8716A44A3DB3DB7E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing for acceptance of requests from accreditation organizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall begin accepting requests from national accreditation bodies for a finding described in section 1865(a)(3)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395bb">42 U.S.C. 1395bb(a)(3)(A)</external-xref>) for purposes of accrediting provider entities that are required to meet the conditions and requirements under section 1881(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395rr">42 U.S.C. 1395rr(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H42A08D087D584EB4B2D13AB2C87D831F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement for timing of surveys of new dialysis facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1881(b)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395rr">42 U.S.C. 1395rr(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Beginning 180 days after the date of the enactment of this sentence, an initial survey of a provider of services or a renal dialysis facility to determine if the conditions and requirements under this paragraph are met shall be initiated not later than 90 days after such date on which both the provider enrollment form (without regard to whether such form is submitted prior to or after such date of enactment) has been determined by the Secretary to be complete and the provider’s enrollment status indicates approval is pending the results of such survey.</quote>. </text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

