<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8E1DE6B179C5435A97466248C53315C2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1915 IH: To amend the Small Business Act to provide the Administrator of the Small Business Administration authority to increase amount for general business loans, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1915</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170405">April 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Vel&#225;zquez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Small Business Act to provide the Administrator of the Small Business Administration authority to increase amount for general business loans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8761F87DCFC0439D8E23A1A883FAB3AE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAA2DF93E589D4EE5AF70774FA9AAB429" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Authority for Administrator to increase amount for general business loans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 20 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6E63937A012D4F93B25096F38FCBAA6A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (j) as subsection (f); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB32BD2A67F094541AF06F021D17213CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8A83800A7DE64E1E94286385AB88CB6D" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HE5A3F24EF5D54476A3937A7B863E3A6B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authority To increase amount of general business loans</header> <paragraph id="H60BAF0BA9A074D4082FB00169B54141E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2018 and each fiscal year thereafter, if the Administrator determines that the amount of commitments by the Administrator for general business loans authorized under section 7(a) for a fiscal year exceeds the limit on the total amount of commitments the Administrator may make for such loans under this Act, appropriation Acts, or any other provision of law, the Administrator may make commitments for such loans for such fiscal year in total amount equal to not more than 120 percent of such limit.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H755CE23DD7C743EC8C0CBDB89487B92B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approval required before exercising authority</header> 
<subparagraph id="HEEC82A0BF8FA478CBE795EF7FB34CE33"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days before the date on which the Administrator intends to exercise the authority under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall submit notice of the intent of the Administrator to exercise the authority to—</text> <clause id="H18FE0D5FC5DE445EA0FD998A5A758EEE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship and the Subcommittee on Financial Services and General Government of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9D799B28BB65443A950F7B25BB5082BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Small Business and the Subcommittee on Financial Services and General Government of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H065DD929B1404D969DD2BE4A31138BAF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>The Administrator may not exercise the authority under paragraph (1) unless the exercise of authority has been approved by the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

