<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF67E8E59B3AD4B05AC1751A79C7FB32E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1859 IH: To amend the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 to designate a portion of United States Route 15 in Pennsylvania as part of the Interstate System, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1859</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170403">April 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001179">Mr. Marino</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 to designate a portion of
			 United States Route 15 in Pennsylvania as part of the Interstate System,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H48D1DE6783E14FB694360E5BC39BEDD0" style="OLC">
		<section id="HB1F8907FDB3F4B03BE3B506E160579CE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Designation of high priority corridor on National Highway System</header>
 <subsection id="H6C3BC487BBEE40F28753D7822320535A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1105(c)(9) of the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/240">Public Law 102–240</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>and including United States Route 15 in Pennsylvania from its intersection with Interstate Route 180 to the New York border</quote>.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H851F0C191B4A4D509FF2A971AB1AE7BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation; signs</header>
 <paragraph id="HFC9C13FFCF144F48B8BC44FBA8AF34B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1105(e)(5)(C)(i) of such Act is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H959ED52ADCEA483B91F735C7CE8D15EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the first sentence by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, including United States Route 15 in Pennsylvania from its intersection with Interstate Route 180 to the New York border</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD40D159DDD3D4A62915A6CAAAC8477F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after the first sentence the following: <quote>The Commonwealth of Pennsylvania shall erect signs identifying the route referred to in subsection (c)(9) as Interstate Route 99, including United States Route 15 in Pennsylvania from its intersection with Interstate Route 180 to the New York border.</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H59455E9739D74743BB67E75903B34950"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The Commonwealth of Pennsylvania shall erect signs in accordance with the amendment made by paragraph (1) not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H29AAD3A70C254B13B9B43C05015EA365"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grants</header>
 <subparagraph id="H14ADB7F0FE5F4E22A46C1066742DD798"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation may make grants to the State of Pennsylvania for projects—</text> <clause id="H2454B4E9CD574981A30EB7A451268247"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to erect signs along United States Route 15 in Pennsylvania from its intersection with Interstate Route 180 to the New York border identifying that highway segment as part of the Interstate System; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H83C639FD72E14B619C69819163A13074"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to make such improvements as may be necessary for that highway segment to conform with standards applicable to the Interstate System.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB1B9EDA51724404ACFCF7DFAD0520E2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated out of the Highway Trust Fund (other than the Mass Transit Account) such sums as may be necessary to carry out this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE33021D1CF0446CAB8B8FB0AB5918B1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Vehicle weight limitations on Interstate System</header><text>Section 127 of title 23, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H559C9C538A7E431692DCAEA8DE7DEAED" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H9F163FE939484EABA3688D9EE956486E"><enum>(u)</enum><header>Vehicles on highway segment in Pennsylvania</header> <paragraph id="HFA3523AF75B74CBFAF8F88D4B663DC9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a vehicle could operate legally on the highway segment described in paragraph (2) on the day before the segment was designated as part of the Interstate System, the vehicle may continue to operate on that segment without regard to any requirement under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC33AE745C484DEBAB52253258107AC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Description</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The highway segment described in this paragraph is the portion of Interstate Route 99 in Pennsylvania between Interstate Route 180 and the New York border, formerly known as United States Route 15.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


