<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HBDADB40AD4BA4E7BA8001BFD4B632510" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1864 IH: Chronic Absenteeism Reduction Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1864</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170403">April 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001056">Ms. Herrera Beutler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to allow local educational agencies to
			 use Federal funds for programs and activities that address chronic
			 absenteeism.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3E1EFCF2BD844B0D883FAEF7CBA4FE2E" style="OLC">
 <section id="H29A415FEDCF54AE7BE5D0A05B6953BDB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Chronic Absenteeism Reduction Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H14EAA67F388B44B8A6E48242A0D11FAE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H53606719AF1040D1881570F28EF8B43B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Students who are chronically absent—meaning they miss 10 percent or more of the school year—are more likely to experience hardships later in life and 68 percent less likely than their peers to graduate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0D1363B0138747DDBD5E2B5DDBC7D678"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Department of Education’s Office of Civil Rights Data Collection found that over 6.8 million students were chronically absent during the 2013–2014 school year. This makes up 14 percent of all students.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H20747A10705C4BC5BC1D8FD4363CAC2D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Chronically absent students are more likely to become high school drop outs. This leaves them prone to living in poverty, suffering from diminished health, and being involved in the criminal justice system later in life. Nineteen percent of high school students are chronically absent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB98797E672EF490DB66EA5E695C82AF9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Department of Education has found that, <quote>Chronic absenteeism is widespread</quote> and <quote>Research suggests the reasons for chronic absenteeism are as varied as the challenges our students and families face—including poor health, limited transportation, and a lack of safety—which can be particularly acute in disadvantaged communities and areas of poverty.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB574FFD4753410BB55FD117BCB12532"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A report by the Everyone Graduates Center found that chronic absenteeism can stem from a wide range of often overlapping internal and external factors. External factors include homelessness, family dysfunction, and transportation; while internal factors include health, fear of bullying, concern for safety, and not valuing daily school attendance. Therefore, it is critical to have cross-sector collaborations and multifaceted strategies that incorporate parents, public-private partnerships, and community partners.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5C4BFD9265343F9B32C0EBB603C693D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Students of color are disproportionately chronically absent compared to their White peers. Latino students are 11 percent more likely to be chronically absent, African-American students are 36 percent more likely, and American Indian and Pacific Islander students are over 65 percent more likely according to the Department of Education’s Office of Civil Rights Data Collection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C88CA054B164E1F88E2E6CF6718E8AE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Studies have shown that mentors can help reduce chronic absenteeism. Students who regularly meet with mentors are 52 percent less likely than their peers to skip a day of school and 37 percent less likely to skip a class. In one program, previously chronically absent students in 2012–13 with <quote>Success Mentors</quote> gained 51,562 additional days of school compared to previously chronically absent students without mentors at comparison schools; and 92,277 additional days compared to comparison school students without mentors during the 3-year initiative.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3E1C9A184774E95ABF66A1D0BC05F9B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A report on the impact of one mentoring program found that it reduced school absenteeism by half. In another study, youth showed a gain of more than a week of class attendance.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FE6BAB350DC496FA5527F17F5371B3E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Studies estimate that 9.4 million young people who are at risk need a mentor.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="HF2615E6D04B6491AA2BF1008F158D5C2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Interventions to address chronic absenteeism</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4108(5) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7118">20 U.S.C. 7118(5)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDA441D9212B0444BA6EDADC5683EAFE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H)(iii) by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5A64AEDA319E445599A4A0BA66BC50AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA99B4E8C64EA49A8BB57729BA251654F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9265F660D47F4A41B9A2ED0790E5AB30" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HEA1EAACFDE1A455DBCAE662101642AB2"><enum>(J)</enum><text>interventions for students who miss 10 percent or more of school days (as determined at any time during a school year), which may include—</text>
 <clause id="HBF65EBDBE6D94C86BCB9718A7AF7067F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implementing data collection systems that assist schools in collecting and tracking attendance data;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEE103BCDAD3A41D9975898C81BCE9D1B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">creating data-sharing and confidentiality agreements between schools and partner agencies or community organizations working with students;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2A34E2C95D424FF9A1E630FD9C57ABB9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>partnering with local health, transportation, and service providers;</text> </clause><clause id="H1D8A48D4B06E4D4897C69287C40461E2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>integrating school personnel for mentoring;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5A608CC27B7F407DB32B113C59D3D057"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carrying out mentoring programs that—</text> <subclause id="H3D525CC769CA46BEB3B42658BA3DFEE1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are structured, managed, and appropriately match students with screened and well-trained adult volunteers for group and one-on-one mentoring relationships;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H63247AB8C3C74B83A29E0744D7DD1767"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourage mentors and students to meet frequently;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HC21D32E23DDC4BFF93B21BCBAE6DC648"><enum>(III)</enum><text>are intended to satisfy a student’s need for involvement with a caring and supportive adult who serves as a positive role model;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H18CDA9EA632F47F08A9DBB001BDDCC2B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>emphasize the importance of regular school attendance; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H7EE6301961344AEB8FE7325C048EBCE2"><enum>(V)</enum><text>provide and facilitate the necessary student support services;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H3A4CA2F65E214852A6210E93D5CBCD01"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">partnering with community organizations that offer mentoring services that consist of—</text> <subclause id="H105FDBBB337743D6B42044F780952BE5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>screening and training of adult volunteers;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H03BA15BFEEDA4D6887BBCB026813C07D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>matching children and youth with the appropriate adult volunteer mentors;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H2EBE1BD1867646EEAF9837146151E1D0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>support and oversight of the mentoring relationship;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H3F8FE767DEF74CE194DFBE2844F7DAC2"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>establishing goals and evaluation of outcomes for mentored children; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H40D96369579B4A58BAB3F5E2D414473E"><enum>(V)</enum><text>planned and ongoing coordination between mentors and school personnel to identify individual student challenges causing chronic absenteeism in an effort to connect mentees to appropriate school personnel or resources such as access to transportation or medical care;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H9654612E45C04B14B88306DD908961D2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cross-age peer mentoring programs under which an older youth serves a mentor for a younger student for the purpose of guiding and supporting the student’s academic, social, and emotional development;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAB3A03DD0D93474CBCCD399DDCAC753F"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>school reorganization aimed at improving relationships between students and staff, including strategies for recognizing and modeling good attendance, such as mentors greeting students each day and promptly contacting a parent or mentor if the student is absent;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H047B1499ED6D4157A8E2EC7258DAE621"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>identifying issues that lead to school absences;</text> </clause><clause id="H8ABBA3E66B234E558F31B0115AA09B07"><enum>(x)</enum><text>meeting with students and parents to engage students and improve performance;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0C1840FB89B541B398281D3DD202AF8D"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>arranging for teacher home visits to develop relationships among students, parents and schools;</text> </clause><clause id="H605F34BA75B2407A800C01B78D82FC71"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>connecting students to existing school resources and activities, including school counseling services and existing community-based organizations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H573E54E38646405287756FCE44A1A605"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">using mentors to serve as a bridge between students, parents, and schools;</text> </clause><clause id="H8343B02D0E9C41EAB9E16832FAD663CE"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implementing evidence-based restorative justice strategies aimed at reducing suspensions in order to keep students in school; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4455F45AA215436CA162822F3656AFDC"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>providing personnel training to build positive school climates and promote social-emotional learning.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


