<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H158DAED581814FB4B42CE26268CF20DB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1461 IH: Veterans, Employees, and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1461</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20170309">March 9, 2017</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to submit an annual report to Congress relating to the use of official time by employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to limit the instances in which official time may be granted for certain purposes to employees of the Department, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HE9318350C91E44FB98499EA4245A2C28" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCCD607E0FDD846C48F9792762DEC9B89" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans, Employees, and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>VET Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9C6DEC93311942C5B63ED77847F95624" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Labor management in Department of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="H7147918E59414BA5A03E994A213CEA32"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/7">Chapter 7</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subchapter:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H902E62E2D0F646C7B79740692CF5D684" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subchapter id="H59F9398D8C6D414E855918954ABF6863"><enum>III</enum><header>Labor management</header> 
<section id="H382DCD685124418F8C97DB146AC9D5FD"><enum>741.</enum><header>Records on use of official time</header> 
<subsection id="H3C348A265DE34279AA707445C42D676B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Tracking of official time</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall track the use of official time by employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs in a manner that accounts for such time accurately and to a specific degree without the use of estimates or ranges of time.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8947CA292D7546FFAE9045EE7EA79052"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7EBC6BDFF7B842A8885112C88D7ACAC0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than October 1 of each fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to the Office of Personnel Management and the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on the use of official time by employees of the Department during the most recently ended fiscal year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD63E99279FE640D8A96230EBD5439182" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Each report under paragraph (1) shall include, with respect to the fiscal year covered by the report, the following information:</text> <subparagraph id="HF721B89BFC6848CAAC5C15473CFC40DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The total amount of official time granted to employees.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8E9830031F2F4DAFB98F124EC840B485"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The average amount of official time expended per bargaining unit employee.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1FDA5CB4457648A4BB052330991B9D75"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The specific types of activities or purposes for which official time was granted, and the impact which the granting of such official time for such activities or purposes had on the operations of the Department.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HECC08194AA8045DCAE80BF5DCE5A8994"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The total number of employees to whom official time was granted, and, of that total, the number who were not engaged in any activities or purposes except activities or purposes involving the use of official time.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B0D31BD616C40F2B4DBD70D76C82116"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The total amount of compensation (including fringe benefits) afforded to employees in connection with activities or purposes for which they were granted official time.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD16DD96664E74BF785662504AC6DCF89"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of any room or space designated at the Department where official time activities will be conducted, including the square footage of any such room or space.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDE307A9E3B5647C68CDFC637F7618DF7"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>official time</term> means any period of time—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5982C8BFF1744A738CCD30DC7A540302"><enum>(1)</enum><text>which may be granted to an employee under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/71">chapter 71</external-xref> of title 5 (including a collective bargaining agreement entered into under such chapter) or chapter 74 of this title to perform representational or consultative functions; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H29F56865D1F84618B063CD3BE8F255A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>during which the employee would otherwise be in a duty status.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF57BFDF60C2A4BE19C887351F1E0395C" commented="no"><enum>742.</enum><header>Limitations on use of official time for certain purposes and individuals</header> 
<subsection id="H2178C176D8054959ABA58DA0C0C7D957"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Political activities and lobbying</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 7131 of title 5, an employee of the Department may not use official time to carry out political activities or activities relating to lobbying.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H26FC103EAF35460682D366845D905125" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of official time by certain employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A physician, dentist, podiatrist, chiropractor, or optometrist employed by the Department may not use official time for any purpose.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9B1EC01858414CE8B2C2358D7C4518FC" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Direct patient care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employee of the Department not covered by subsection (b) may spend no more than 25 percent of the time such employee would otherwise be in a duty status on official time if such employee—</text> <paragraph id="H9E01062D6020493CAA3CD1DFDA0EA667" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is involved with direct patient care; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14DDE46467DC42D28C6484EF523492FE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>occupies a position with a rate of basic pay equal to or higher than the rate of basic pay for GS–13 of the General Schedule.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H43753D0533804DFF93B16C5721FE4F77"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on all employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employee of the Department not covered by subsection (b) or (c) may spend no more than 50 percent of the time such employee would otherwise be in a duty status on official time.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H6C5F6D584AE34FEE88B580643BF85BC1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Official time defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>official time</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 741(c). </text> </subsection></section> <section id="H2FF605F61EFD4E23BE270DAC8A5BD31C" commented="no"><enum>743.</enum><header>Termination of collection of dues</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any exclusive bargaining agreement entered into pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/71">chapter 71</external-xref> of title 5 by the Department shall provide that an employee of the Department may terminate a voluntary allotment for the payment of dues at any time. Any deductions for dues made pursuant to such allotment shall cease beginning on the first pay period after the termination is made.</text></section> </subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8C5D8AB28BBA46428056AA23B8722450"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Sections 743 and 742 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall apply with respect to any collective bargaining agreement entered into after the date of enactment of this Act. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H78C67A5F0A5C4835AAA8E362B260DEE0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H674477AB8AAB42FA8C275B77A17A22AC" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="subchapter">Subchapter III—Labor management</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE9318350C91E44FB98499EA4245A2C28" level="section">741. Records on use of official time.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HE9318350C91E44FB98499EA4245A2C28" level="section">742. Prohibition on use of official time for certain purposes.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">743. Termination of collection of dues.</toc-entry> </toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3491FADA155248F98CA6ED8CABD60921" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Required probationary period for new employees of Department of Veterans Affairs</header> 
<subsection id="HCD277A6C240441FCBD28D9448FD79FFE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Probationary period</header> 
<paragraph id="H87ECC772A6FB4E989FB9EE4D23F65EB9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/7">Chapter 7</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is further amended by inserting after section 717 the following new section:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBFCAB0F66D194614BF3E3F3B2586F320" style="USC"> <section id="HBF9AB1BF61214EC385853E8B2872BDF6"><enum>719.</enum><header>Probationary period for employees </header> <subsection id="H95EEC2424D974DED9B070E0026DB5212"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding sections 3321 and 3393(d) of title 5, the appointment of a covered employee shall become final only after such employee has served a probationary period of 18 months. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD91797BBE1B64E01BF83FAA55F190A24"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered employee</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>covered employee</quote>—</text> <paragraph id="H7F991D3A40A744ADA65CB35C35D02213"><enum>(1)</enum><text>means any individual—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H52D8B06A558647A09683F0FD1CFE1DA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>appointed to a permanent position within the competitive service at the Department; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1606F664561A4F56A2C6EBAEF19241AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>appointed as a career appointee (as that term is defined in section 3132(a)(4) of title 5) within the Senior Executive Service at the Department; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4660052F0F6C4264B7FEC5E9CBA1FA08"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include any individual with a probationary period prescribed by section 7403 of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H27B6DD7A2CF9423D98DA3DA87B79F745"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Permanent hires</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days before the expiration of a covered employee’s probationary period under subsection (a), the supervisor of the employee shall determine whether the appointment becomes final based on regulations prescribed for such purpose by the Secretary.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAD3DCD1DF8C441DE86A26E485F60D1CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical and conforming amendments</header> 
<subparagraph id="H1543A45F18E54C4DBED4AF1D9794DDC7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Clerical</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter, as amended by section 2, is further amended by inserting after the item relating to section 717 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1ECB7C1FB3A54856A1D7CCA678531714" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">719. Probationary period for employees.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB450C553D8114744B723ABE9DAADEC37"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conforming</header><text>Title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<clause id="H61FE00818356449CB7CE0EC492D9B775"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in section 3321(c)—</text> <subclause id="HE3EA91D7FA114CD3BB5EA61F5CF1F541"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Service or</quote> and inserting <quote>Service,</quote>; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE8448B4307424016884A1D7F717265C3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by inserting at the end before the period the following: <quote>, or any individual covered by section 719 of title 38</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H9F732B0CFCA04C448E8A9D50C5BE2C0C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in section 3393(d), by adding at the end after the period the following: <quote>The preceding sentence shall not apply to any individual covered by section 719 of title 38.</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD1736C3E6AE643C0B87F8E3B2AF39456"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Section 719 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(1), shall apply to any covered employee (as that term is defined in subsection (b) of such section 719, as so added) appointed after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

