<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC184048AFFBE4CBF8A1A6EDA672568A3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><form><distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1006</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170213">February 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Guti&#233;rrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000580">Ms. Michelle Lujan Grisham of New Mexico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000248">Mr. Serrano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Vel&#225;zquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Ted Lieu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To clarify the rights of all persons who are held or detained at a port of entry or at any detention facility overseen by U.S. Customs and Border Protection or U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HED85F85CCD3C48F78E097E28015D67B7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H62D54006512647C7B85488FD4923E4ED" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Clarification of right to counsel</header> 
<subsection id="HC7421C49892341DC8791A69A7F30F1AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Right to counsel in immigration proceedings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 292 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1362">8 U.S.C. 1362</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59D5A4F0659946B7997C90980F6F3855" style="OLC"> <section id="HD5E1320636934A6787BE28AFCC9E3759"><enum>292.</enum><header>Right to counsel</header> <subsection id="H4BACFAC4CF3A486D8946214DDB7B7389"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any removal, exclusion, deportation proceeding, or inspection under section 235(a), 235(b), 236, 238, 240, or 241, the person subject to such proceeding shall be entitled to representation (at no expense to the Government) by such authorized counsel as the person may choose.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB843501E47BD4225BE710F3234D17A88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Redress options</header><text>If counsel cannot personally meet with a person subject to holding, detention, or inspection at a port of entry, U.S. Customs and Border Protection or U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, as appropriate, shall provide redress options through which counsel may communicate remotely with the held or detained person during the first hour and thereafter of such holding or detention, regardless of the day or time when such holding or detention began.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6B327957CB12417C94657A2434DDDF18"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Record of abandonment of lawful permanent resident status or withdrawal of application for admission</header><text>A person held or detained at a port of entry may not submit a valid Record of Abandonment of Lawful Permanent Resident Status or Withdrawal of Application for Admission if such person has been denied access to counsel in accordance with this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2226516256F44EBFBB2384453ED69EFD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HC7E9C2E1928F46909C63C33235FA1E55"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inspection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>inspection</quote> does not include primary inspection (as defined in the policies of the Department of Homeland Security).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4D22D73FFCB540CAB3230D74AF612EE0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>person</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 101(b)(3).</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H6BCAB5AA7F9146A8BE500DA1FE321CB0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Right to counsel or representation</header><text>Section 555(b) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>The right to be accompanied, represented, and advised by counsel or other qualified representative under this subsection shall extend to any person subject to a proceeding, examination, holding, or detention described in section 292 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1362">8 U.S.C. 1362</external-xref>).</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H630F1303D09C45C398903627AD24742C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section, or in any amendment made by this section, may be construed to limit any preexisting right to counsel under section 292 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1362">8 U.S.C. 1362</external-xref>), as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act, or under any other law.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H43204DB5053B4D18BAA843B292709DD6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of individuals held or detained at ports of entry or any CBP or ICE detention facility</header> <subsection id="HB99E1444849D464282318B68BBB135CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The holding or detention of individuals at a port of entry or at any holding or detention facility overseen by U.S. Customs and Border Protection or U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8A6BB8253DBF408F851EAE5A83C0535B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be limited to the briefest term and the least restrictive conditions practicable and consistent with the rationale for such holding or detention; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20B366D541C94702B3B956DA655D8CEB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include access to food, water, and restroom facilities.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H59F20B84DC9B43FAB4963F33569A8BC8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Section may be construed to limit agencies from complying with other legal authorities, policies, or standards with respect to treatment of individuals held or detained at ports of entry or at any holding or detention facility overseen by U.S. Customs and Border Protection or U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

