<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFC49959BCD794DD7A74425C04EF411FE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3119 IH: 21st Century STEM for Girls and Underrepresented Minorities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3119</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170629">June 29, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000293">Ms. Esty of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001049">Mr. Clay</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000608">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide grants to local educational agencies to encourage girls and underrepresented minorities to pursue studies and careers in science, mathematics, engineering, and technology.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4ABFC4FFB5044670932FBAF740EA2275" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1B8CBFBB4ECB498A839B3566F600AE1A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>21st Century STEM for Girls and Underrepresented Minorities Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1DFA8EC18B4B4C59B20F0AE94F77060D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants to prepare girls and underrepresented minorities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title IV of the <act-name parsable-cite="ESEA">Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7101">20 U.S.C. 7101</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block act-name="Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965" id="H8883DC623AC947AF852EC4105D3649DA" style="OLC"> 
<part id="H0C76F730499A4E8793A58CA410D146BA"><enum>G</enum><header>Preparing girls and underrepresented minorities for the 21st century</header> 
<section id="H16EF359B1C694F6A968B611014513495"><enum>4701.</enum><header>Program authority</header> 
<subsection id="H9C089E2BA7714EC5AF44E8D8D1A36996"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From funds provided under section 4702, the Secretary is authorized to provide grants to local educational agencies on behalf of elementary and secondary schools to establish and implement a program to encourage the ongoing development of programs and curriculum for girls and underrepresented minorities in science, mathematics, engineering, and technology and to prepare girls and underrepresented minorities to pursue undergraduate and graduate degrees and careers in science, mathematics, engineering, or technology.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD6FB2C3D56FF4732B60EC61A2970D5E1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header> <paragraph id="H3B52734D2217430F9D0C29322E4BEEB9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant, or enter into a contract or cooperative agreement, under this part, a local educational agency shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HACB0ECE62E8D4D1AB2859B55F74BB491"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The application shall contain, at a minimum, the following:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H6E512E0A884840A1BCCB8AB12D07A0F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A program description, including the content of the program and the research and models used to design the program.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H2B96F8EBA7414997A9B7B26F9D59F582"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the collaboration between elementary and secondary schools to fulfill goals of the program and how the applicant will ensure that there is a comprehensive plan to improve science, mathematics, engineering, and technology education for girls and underrepresented minorities in grades kindergarten through 12.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H93155D1B09EB47DC8D30047F70995BDD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of the process for recruitment and selection of participants.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H13800403CDC6418E99CEFA37F6686D01"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the planned instructional and motivational activities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39B449D815844502891C7B7B2BE746F9"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of any collaboration among local, regional, or national institutions and organizations that will occur in order to fulfill the goals of the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HD6327B4B55AA4489B94A21F9D5EB8063"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting among applications, the Secretary shall give priority to applicants that partner or coordinate, to the extent possible, with local, regional, or national institutions and organizations who have extensive experience, expertise and research on increasing the participation of girls or underrepresented minorities in science, mathematics, engineering and technology.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H214943DDC24E4AA192B03BE4CED22DC9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds provided under this section shall be used for the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H003E96D341634ABDAEE351F7508A8274"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Preparing girls and underrepresented minorities with careers in science, mathematics, engineering, and technology, and the advantages of pursuing careers in these areas.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8BBAF9CDC1E74C5FBCDF40621DCDA9A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Educating the parents of girls and underrepresented minorities about the opportunities and advantages of science, mathematics, engineering, and technology careers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H12D930AE0D4844C48F87333D50466B73"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enlisting the help of the parents of girls and underrepresented minorities in overcoming the obstacles these groups face and encouraging their child’s continued interest and involvement in science, mathematics, engineering, and technology.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8642F0896BF4F18A5D9D100B0E2EA44"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing tutoring and mentoring programs in science, mathematics, engineering, and technology.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0D457CF63BE4CD09CEB9B135F1A5300"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Establishing partnerships and other opportunities that expose girls and underrepresented minorities to role models in the fields of science, mathematics, engineering and technology.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H530CA61A2F6A41949DAFBDD0C4010599"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enabling female and underrepresented minority students and their teachers to attend events and academic programs in science, mathematics, engineering, and technology.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC7BE3D4D705F4CCCA91C13FC0DB49CF3"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing after-school activities designed to encourage interest, and develop skills of girls and underrepresented minorities, in science, mathematics, engineering, and technology.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H93BF0666499841128AC21035B9EDBB76"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Summer programs designed in order that girls and underrepresented minorities develop an interest in, develop skills in, and understand the relevance and significance of, science, mathematics, engineering, and technology.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA7A1FDCEA8D041C386854D3CEC5B8B60"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Purchasing—</text> <subparagraph id="HB1362851AE8546BBAD68E1776600D079"><enum>(A)</enum><text>educational instructional materials or software designed to encourage interest of girls and underrepresented minorities in science, mathematics, engineering, and technology; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H74C4F0149D1148A683579EF285D7340E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>equipment, instrumentation, or hardware used for teaching and to encourage interest of girls and underrepresented minorities in science, mathematics, engineering, and technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88457D4E78814994A61A23590949B47F"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Field trips to locations, including institutions of higher education, to educate and encourage girls’ and underrepresented minorities’ interest in science, mathematics, engineering, and technology and acquaint them with careers in these fields.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8481DE03506649B981BA467E80DD4ED7"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Providing academic advice and assistance in high school course selection that encourages girls and underrepresented minorities to take advanced courses in areas of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FFF9FA07FE34478A50C4DE8262D0E93"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Paying up to 50 percent of the cost of an internship in science, mathematics, engineering, or technology for female and underrepresented minority students.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA5E56E9DD0D24019B9BB25A7A5547638"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing professional development for teachers and other school personnel, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H4E39E967A12E454BB18AC1D06CABD1EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how to eliminate gender and racial bias in the classroom;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCF45D031D6BC408891675634203C3B94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how to be sensitive to gender and racial differences;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9368B7BD1F594331BC83DA255B1DADE0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how to engage students in the face of gender-based and racial peer pressure and parental expectations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC1CDBC1B70B1493394E0090859C11CD8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>how to create and maintain a positive environment; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7A9FF37861274B6ABA95A546CAA640FC"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how to encourage girls and underserved minorities through academic advice and assistance to pursue advanced classes and careers in science, mathematics, engineering, and technology fields.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2061FF163D4448A082CE2453F436EEDE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require each local educational agency to use the assistance provided under this section only to supplement, and not to supplant, any other assistance or funds made available from non-Federal sources for the activities assisted under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H67EAC8EC818744AF9CFF5B03243B5526"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evaluations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each local educational agency that receives funds under this section shall provide the Secretary, at the conclusion of every school year during which the funds are received, with an evaluation, in a form prescribed by the Secretary. This evaluation shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAF0357A03178495FA50EBA07F71AC0D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the programs and activities conducted by the local educational agency using the funds;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A23C98506B448DEBBF07E15C8E8B895"><enum>(2)</enum><text>data on curriculum and partnerships developed using the funds;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE88CB17B09624A6E9016EE8811A92496"><enum>(3)</enum><text>data on the amount of time spent on subjects allowed for under the grant; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06CDF3E8C2154763B0E9E9707F824F58"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such other information as may be required by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5BB00AE0D880426B90EE616089956257"><enum>4702.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this part $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2018 and such sums as may be necessary for each of the 4 succeeding fiscal years.</text></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

