<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H44948C2FB712454393AD77004E0B2630" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1760 IH: To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to eliminate the authority of the Secretary of Agriculture to grant a waiver from the work requirements for participation in the supplemental nutrition assistance program on account of an area’s high unemployment rate or limited employment availability for individuals who reside in the area.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1760</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170328">March 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to eliminate the authority of the Secretary of
			 Agriculture to grant a waiver from the work requirements for participation
			 in the supplemental nutrition assistance program on account of an area’s
			 high unemployment rate or limited employment availability for individuals
			 who reside in the area.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H879A06665C7044039DCC0ED1FDB1D0BA" style="OLC">
		<section id="H42A59F201A754BF0AE63C88A5D91CCEA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Elimination of authority to waive supplemental nutrition assistance program work requirements based
			 on unemployment rate or job availability</header>
 <subsection id="H91A8E25C4A4449308ADB7BFCB0D3A008"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Elimination of waiver authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6(o) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2015">7 U.S.C. 2015(o)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (4).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0988EC082C5E409CB79E0946D7AA4325"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming regulatory change</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall implement the amendment made by subsection (a) by revising section 273.24 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations, to remove subsection (f).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


