<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0C5EBD1C5D504F41B2022D522BCCB343" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1062 IH: Geolocational Privacy and Surveillance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1062</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170215">February 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001076">Mr. Chaffetz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000573">Mr. Labrador</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000289">Mr. Jordan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Permanent Select Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to specify the circumstances in which a person may acquire
			 geolocation information, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE653886A8EAD4B24B51AE7DC657FABC8" style="OLC">
 <section id="H69742365DAC948EBB4E2F0A8A93B08A7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Geolocational Privacy and Surveillance Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GPS Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7BBAF75433CB4718AB17622BC0A16651"><enum>2.</enum><header>Protection of geolocation information</header> <subsection id="H9D7CEE6663CA42709EC9F5BCD55B1953"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part 1 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after chapter 119 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93D79B8655D845009F9D5130CFFEC223" style="USC">
					<chapter id="H1A59C8B76F304E6091DDF6FCFE7F7FEB"><enum>120</enum><header>Geolocation information</header>
						<toc>
							<toc-entry level="section">Sec. </toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H0A3EF50780D3496F893B107EFDD8F209" level="section">2601. Definitions.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H6AB08B6947F2491EA5529A19BA04E35A" level="section">2602. Interception and disclosure of geolocation information.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H6ACF3EA7164843B7BFFAA7380CE0B4BD" level="section">2603. Prohibition of use as evidence of acquired geolocation information.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H4AE666782D584D7CBE55C29C0A8F17AC" level="section">2604. Emergency situation exception.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="HF2250371CBAE452FB72F034EEBAC658C" level="section">2605. Recovery of civil damages authorized.</toc-entry></toc>
 <section id="H0A3EF50780D3496F893B107EFDD8F209"><enum>2601.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this chapter:</text> <paragraph id="H3E1BF4E1A1FC429B9D5B76511CD178E0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Electronic communication service</header><text>The term <term>electronic communication service</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2510.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H26DEB191BA814129A40399DB6689F15D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Electronic surveillance</header><text>The term <term>electronic surveillance</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5032CBD3AE674288B7353C9F9B0B9411"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Geolocation information</header><text>The term <term>geolocation information</term> means, with respect to a person, any information that is not the content of a communication, concerning the location of a wireless communication device or tracking device (as that term is defined section 3117) that, in whole or in part, is generated by or derived from the operation of that device and that could be used to determine or infer information regarding the location of the person.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H64D63E701D404C7F8AB3ECD2DCEB5086"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Geolocation information service</header><text>The term <term>geolocation information service</term> means the provision of a global positioning service or other mapping, locational, or directional information service to the public, or to such class of users as to be effectively available to the public, by or through the operation of any wireless communication device, including any mobile telephone, global positioning system receiving device, mobile computer, or other similar or successor device.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4168EA5A32814FE08080421F3E769B73"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Intercept</header><text>The term <term>intercept</term> means the acquisition of geolocation information through the use of any electronic, mechanical, or other device.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H094FD28A00A94B0A800BF72F743CFF85"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Investigative or law enforcement officer</header><text>The term <term>investigative or law enforcement officer</term> means any officer of the United States or of a State or political subdivision thereof, who is empowered by law to conduct investigations of, or to make arrests for, offenses enumerated in this chapter, and any attorney authorized by law to prosecute or participate in the prosecution of such offenses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8764922ABA94C1BBD32FC6A3C5338DC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means any employee or agent of the United States, or any State or political subdivision thereof, and any individual, partnership, association, joint stock company, trust, or corporation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H85A0F9974A6C4636BF4E27689CECEBCA"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Remote computing service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>remote computing service</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2711.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC30558B5E26C49DC96872F39242D6FBF"><enum>(9)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA0097EEA926A479598B35A50ED3DC2D0"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Wireless communication device</header><text>The term <term>wireless communication device</term> means any device that enables access to, or use of, an electronic communication system or service, remote computing service, or geolocation information service, if that device utilizes a radio or other wireless connection to access such system or service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2FBC6D551C8248BDAE2B82DE889781ED"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Covered service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered services</term> means electronic communication service, remote computing service, or geolocation information service.</text>
							</paragraph></section><section id="H6AB08B6947F2491EA5529A19BA04E35A"><enum>2602.</enum><header>Interception and disclosure of geolocation information</header>
							<subsection id="H4C032D1DA38C4E899D452FD5240AC58B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
 <paragraph id="H9675A8BFE9D249A490D16DBF243C3E6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition on disclosure or use</header><text>Except as otherwise specifically provided in this chapter, it shall be unlawful for any person to—</text> <subparagraph id="HFFCA7DC9E9EA4CEFB36182420D287EA2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>intentionally intercept, endeavor to intercept, or procure any other person to intercept or endeavor to intercept, geolocation information pertaining to another person;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA9668BBC7014AC4A7A6075E38DEFE6E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>intentionally disclose, or endeavor to disclose, to any other person geolocation information pertaining to another person, knowing or having reason to know that the information was obtained through the interception of such information in violation of this paragraph;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5690E01EC3A0487980A5E3672B8BD064"><enum>(C)</enum><text>intentionally use, or endeavor to use, any geolocation information, knowing or having reason to know that the information was obtained through the interception of such information in violation of this paragraph; or</text>
									</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4CC946AF3904788BE75F4DDAC26463C"><enum>(D)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H04F7379736C745C5A460C37B982A40FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>intentionally disclose, or endeavor to disclose, to any other person the geolocation information pertaining to another person intercepted by means authorized by subsections (b) through (h), except as provided in such subsections;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEFACE8F498DE407D85B0F2A524F84D96" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>knowing or having reason to know that the information was obtained through the interception of such information in connection with a criminal investigation;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF96648E4BADB4C219BF8524FBD68932E" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>having obtained or received the information in connection with a criminal investigation; and</text> </clause><clause id="HD514E3E827A3468C950A0ACD90431160" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>with intent to improperly obstruct, impede, or interfere with a duly authorized criminal investigation.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H66B993487D95412CBEB7E1C18CBFF7D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Any person who violates paragraph (1) shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3721125FB4014B88B43343C28BFE6EA1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception for information acquired in the normal course of business</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall not be unlawful under this chapter for an officer, employee, or agent of a provider of covered services, whose facilities are used in the transmission of geolocation information, to intercept, disclose, or use that information in the normal course of the officer, employee, or agent's employment while engaged in any activity which is a necessary incident to the rendition of service or to the protection of the rights or property of the provider of that service, except that a provider of a geolocation information service to the public shall not utilize service observing or random monitoring except for mechanical or service quality control checks.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H00F2AFFCFE9741A49C74FAC599483F32"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception for conducting foreign intelligence surveillance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, it shall not be unlawful for an officer, employee, or agent of the United States in the normal course of the official duty of the officer, employee, or agent to conduct electronic surveillance, as authorized by the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HAA6DEE2DE6A54FE8AFDE82DE663B50A4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exception for consent</header>
 <paragraph id="H586656F8AD234F9883CB0D99A13F0D05"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall not be unlawful under this chapter for a person to intercept geolocation information pertaining to another person if such other person has given prior consent to such interception unless such information is intercepted for the purpose of committing any criminal or tortious act in violation of the Constitution or laws of the United States or of any State.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C36CF21B70041029D5C9FF1249BB068"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Children</header><text>The exception in paragraph (1) permits a parent or legal guardian of a child to intercept geolocation information pertaining to that child or to give consent for another person to intercept such information.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H08127B6753BA4808A379F0683524FBE1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exception for public information</header><text>It shall not be unlawful under this chapter for any person to intercept or access geolocation information relating to another person through any system that is configured so that such information is readily accessible to the general public.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB8198BA8AD354E4093F3BC159ADF0D5B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exception for emergency information</header><text>It shall not be unlawful under this chapter for any investigative or law enforcement officer or other emergency responder to intercept or access geolocation information relating to a person if such information is used—</text>
 <paragraph id="H612353ED35CE449CA95C51B540FFAFAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to respond to a request made by such person for assistance; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3B0CA2CEDCC34A2ABE824703127EB629"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in circumstances in which it is reasonable to believe that the life or safety of the person is threatened, to assist the person.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36A8BBF3A08C45C09825BF81F22A6423"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exception for theft or fraud</header><text>It shall not be unlawful under this chapter for a person acting under color of law to intercept geolocation information pertaining to the location of another person who has unlawfully taken the device sending the geolocation information if—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAE11E4237D114F729229D4122397F8C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the owner or operator of such device authorizes the interception of the person's geolocation information;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC265206F10E74D97B5FC843252A3DD24"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the person acting under color of law is lawfully engaged in an investigation; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7E3ED1AC62E4594BF963039C7E9FCC5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the person acting under color of law has reasonable grounds to believe that the geolocation information of the other person will be relevant to the investigation.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H07C07A9C2CA84731A8F1744557D7FD12"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Exception for warrant</header>
 <paragraph id="HDC1B44FD5E0746E588B0E7E4D071F8D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H41DCCD0F324344129528A0DBBBAF990E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Court of competent jurisdiction</header><text>The term <term>court of competent jurisdiction</term> includes—</text>
 <clause id="H675053B94A1D491BA6EC1B0C2404A063"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any district court of the United States (including a magistrate judge of such a court) or any United States court of appeals that—</text>
 <subclause id="H89EA53C434FC489FA6E222D5E60EB0D1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has jurisdiction over the offense being investigated;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HE7821DC5952D41B2AAC717C648A1FD07"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is in or for a district in which the provider of a geolocation information service is located or in which the geolocation information is stored; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HCA3C115D723E490C90D503EB05165669"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is acting on a request for foreign assistance pursuant to section 3512 of this title; or</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H6E163E3CFF9241B193294CAFF2BCB80D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a court of general criminal jurisdiction of a State authorized by the law of that State to issue search warrants.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50EB77B636B2461B99D132BD286D6F45"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Governmental entity</header><text>The term <term>governmental entity</term> means a department or agency of the United States or any State or political subdivision thereof.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC758EED2E6DA407DB6A43A56B730B55C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Warrant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A governmental entity may intercept geolocation information or require the disclosure by a provider of covered services of geolocation information only pursuant to a warrant issued using the procedures described in the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure (or, in the case of a State court, issued using State warrant procedures) by a court of competent jurisdiction, or as otherwise provided in this chapter or the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HABE6B76037704D9C9758D1C7A8BE4254"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Prohibition on divulging geolocation information</header>
 <paragraph id="H8CCFF3B2BD57454F888DFB27A4B78C72"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), a person providing covered services shall not intentionally divulge geolocation information pertaining to another person.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F7C9439680043FAB012A31206B29E52"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person providing covered services may divulge geolocation information—</text> <subparagraph id="H4342DB4CB0614B7A9E2F2829CF644578"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as otherwise authorized in subsections (b) through (h);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68244B556A5747568B27E686510E492E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with the lawful consent of such other person;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA88E525E1C8F4A5F86D67199EADBE9EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to another person employed or authorized, or whose facilities are used, to forward such geolocation information to its destination; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57EB37CAF36B484EBAB75B44F804DFCF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>which was inadvertently obtained by the service provider and which appears to pertain to the commission of a crime, if such divulgence is made to a law enforcement agency.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6ACF3EA7164843B7BFFAA7380CE0B4BD"><enum>2603.</enum><header>Prohibition of use as evidence of acquired geolocation information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Whenever any geolocation information has been acquired, no part of such information and no evidence derived therefrom may be received in evidence in any trial, hearing, or other proceeding in or before any court, grand jury, department, officer, agency, regulatory body, legislative committee, or other authority of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision thereof if the disclosure of that information would be in violation of this chapter.</text>
						</section><section id="H4AE666782D584D7CBE55C29C0A8F17AC"><enum>2604.</enum><header>Emergency situation exception</header>
 <subsection id="H23591D81A9904C23B6E8AFC7CE68EC23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Emergency situation exception</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, any investigative or law enforcement officer, specially designated by the Attorney General, the Deputy Attorney General, the Associate Attorney General, or by the principal prosecuting attorney of any State or subdivision thereof acting pursuant to a statute of that State, may intercept geolocation information if—</text>
 <paragraph id="H43B55B2CA48D40B2B6E1829147B876AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such officer reasonably determines that an emergency situation exists that—</text> <subparagraph id="HF4DEE396FA73484EB70ECFF10E007A59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>involves—</text>
 <clause id="HF4F91382978947FF92B3474D2C80C58D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any person;</text> </clause><clause id="HBAEC377E5FC54BA3ADDF9402F70406BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>conspiratorial activities threatening the national security interest; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCC465F2796194F79A457EF5195BA6936"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>conspiratorial activities characteristic of organized crime; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC7F2A16AC454B348D8EBADC25452BA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requires geolocation information be intercepted before an order authorizing such interception can, with due diligence, be obtained;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H84D3C2B5ABC74E49B5164DA698132484"><enum>(2)</enum><text>there are grounds upon which an order could be entered to authorize such interception; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3862EB06B2F7447383996C3D10F7ACBF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an application for an order approving such interception is made within 48 hours after the interception has occurred or begins to occur.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2EB2E33CE72A49F5A64BD119088D2C3F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Failure To obtain court order</header>
 <paragraph id="H431BB2473BF848B8A2F64075DF59F839"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Termination of acquisition</header><text>In the absence of an order, an interception of geolocation information carried out under subsection (a) shall immediately terminate when the information sought is obtained or when the application for the order is denied, whichever is earlier.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H685609025C904728A38E29574CE60133"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on use as evidence</header><text>In the event such application for approval is denied, the geolocation information shall be treated as having been obtained in violation of this chapter and an inventory shall be served on the person named in the application.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF2250371CBAE452FB72F034EEBAC658C"><enum>2605.</enum><header>Recovery of civil damages authorized</header>
 <subsection id="H0F76F647AF794CACA58DB045D957AF7A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person whose geolocation information is intercepted, disclosed, or intentionally used in violation of this chapter may in a civil action recover from the person, other than the United States, which engaged in that violation such relief as may be appropriate.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAE321C0BF56C4848807270FD1EE475A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relief</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In an action under this section, appropriate relief includes—</text> <paragraph id="H5B6277F197CF438585A52B567DD40F36"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such preliminary and other equitable or declaratory relief as may be appropriate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H031B03CE362F4AF9A4D55E1419EA6950"><enum>(2)</enum><text>damages under subsection (c) and punitive damages in appropriate cases; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE0FD7A0D012499CB43F62901A35692A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a reasonable attorney's fee and other litigation costs reasonably incurred.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8BEA997F07C44B3BB9FB42DFFC75D0FE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Computation of damages</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court may assess as damages under this section whichever is the greater of—</text> <paragraph id="HE77B553CDCA543A2AE74B07FBB33BEE1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the sum of the actual damages suffered by the plaintiff and any profits made by the violator as a result of the violation; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H083480BF48064F1B9C14376946D0DB6B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>statutory damages of whichever is the greater of $100 a day for each day of violation or $10,000.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA6397E09D92142FF929404A937956D52"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Defense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is a complete defense against any civil or criminal action brought against an individual for conduct in violation of this chapter if such individual acted in a good faith reliance on—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9A1619EEA84D4290A42947BD48A0A613"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a court warrant or order, a grand jury subpoena, a legislative authorization, or a statutory authorization;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H14BC8280A0614C0383DBFA59078EC42D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a request of an investigative or law enforcement officer under section 2604; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4CBC8FA40592468494B73A55E9F03165"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a good-faith determination that an exception under section 2602 permitted the conduct complained of.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6D3E0B3FA38D41C3A92E2329B6B7D84D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A civil action under this section may not be commenced later than two years after the date upon which the claimant first has a reasonable opportunity to discover the violation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8FC95577FE4F4C9DB9774AA6FC7F424B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administrative discipline</header><text>If a court or appropriate department or agency determines that the United States or any of its departments or agencies has violated any provision of this chapter, and the court or appropriate department or agency finds that the circumstances surrounding the violation raise serious questions about whether or not an officer or employee of the United States acted willfully or intentionally with respect to the violation, the department or agency shall, upon receipt of a true and correct copy of the decision and findings of the court or appropriate department or agency promptly initiate a proceeding to determine whether disciplinary action against the officer or employee is warranted. If the head of the department or agency involved determines that disciplinary action is not warranted, such head shall notify the Inspector General with jurisdiction over the department or agency concerned and shall provide the Inspector General with the reasons for such determination.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDDAE33D415AD4DF4A43C253AF8555B8C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Improper disclosure is violation</header><text>Any willful disclosure or use by an investigative or law enforcement officer or governmental entity of information beyond the extent permitted by this chapter is a violation of this chapter for purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC4A0ADA4A06F401E9179E94B8A114A43"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of chapters for part 1 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to chapter 119 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC16087B833249B6908EACB2F79134E6" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<multi-column-toc-entry bold="off" level="section"><toc-enum>120. </toc-enum><level-header level="section">Geolocation information</level-header><target>2601</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H55C4B08834D94AC88D5BDC671ABEAA0E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 3512(a) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4077396063834371A79085F9E1C50398"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H10B130748AD241928DE30D1526B0704D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (B), (C), and (D) as subparagraphs (C), (D), and (E), respectively; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90556700B0994767A2572066B7AB238D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEFF00647680142F78A6531E233D031F1" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H82E26B5E061C424F95EB2338D82D64C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a warrant or order for geolocation information or records related thereto, as provided under section 2602 of this title;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H952E1E7EF81A445E82BF169BA91C7468"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requirement for search warrants to acquire geolocation information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Rule 41(a) of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H426FA1AE211B4896B9A513343022FB27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A), by striking the period at the end and inserting a comma and <quote>including geolocation information.</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA3E7BB7A40C140BA8A4975DF8D1CC124"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BE175264A8243ACAEC3321A08EBDE67" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H427E4484C9C34F1D904592D6C6BAA1ED"><enum>(F)</enum><text><term>Geolocation information</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2601 of title 18, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H1F7DC0FD1CF945669A95298F14814472"><enum>4.</enum><header>Fraud and related activity in connection with obtaining geolocation information</header>
 <subsection id="H7FF54D8F0CB24BE7953F4E7FECA3CE8C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Criminal violation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1039(h) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H5BBA781D524B44FDB030EE179ED9B7D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H59E2516856E040268B6223317E2E56D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC41EDB02F43F4C2CB413B69BF51AACEB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon and <quote>and</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8329B1184ED1490D8FEA047913730988"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B4900CDB7994B0183CE42DB66908AB1" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H94187C1F51064291BF2181EA8A8AA44A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes any geolocation information service.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H77A6D227618541B6A22489C6E93EDD04"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9415AC41973040A18E6EF03287D80025"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90D98E9FADDB428EB6084693E43E4170" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HAD222C4802C541599C205836DE027449"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Geolocation information service</header><text>The term <term>geolocation information service</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2601.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE0CE422D769B474AB7E1BB16B17AACF2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <paragraph id="HF59E9E455EBC4E7A877369099C2EEEEA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition amendments</header><text>Section 1039(h)(1) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAF9441D03B8F43A4BAE589530171E4D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">or GPS</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">phone</header-in-text></quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1542F949F324BA5BF458396042DBBF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or GPS</quote> after <quote>phone</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFA522C69A6D48E68B303DB7983A8CB2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 1039 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H4DE81D2357064401B4B7F968A4C36593"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the section heading by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">or GPS</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">phone</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0EC8306714B47D08C18923DA77A4C4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="H20F9DF9F3AD24ECAA8838604C5FADDFE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>or GPS</quote> after <quote>phone</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC5DCB7A200BC4405A14E4046431D5EC1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by inserting <quote>or GPS</quote> after <quote>phone</quote>;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF00413A249949AB8404AF5E8ABA4D29"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <clause id="H1B5647B856D145A89F1FBD4EE42E318E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">or GPS</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">phone</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="HC1F7309468CB427C835FCA0C26685BF9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>or GPS</quote> after <quote>phone</quote> both places that term appears; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H85E99CB9FAC64E51965D298D064A51FC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>or GPS</quote> after <quote>phone</quote>; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2ACB8D969674EDB85935E3F7691D054"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
 <clause id="HD5AE75E8E3724221AA3C5158E3CCF431"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">or GPS</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">phone</header-in-text></quote>;</text> </clause><clause id="HD2CFE64B8B5C4F3CA17CDDF40A9434F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>or GPS</quote> after <quote>phone</quote> both places that term appears; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11B47DA0B72F4037AF481378659141FB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>or GPS</quote> after <quote>phone</quote>.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAC2EC1EBBBB4DA6A36CAFEF61232A55"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chapter analysis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/47">chapter 47</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 1039 and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3CE1441A89F64B23B36389FF2F123DCA" style="USC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">1039. Fraud and related activity in connection with obtaining confidential phone or GPS records
			 information of a covered entity.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H815649128B864BABA3712E65A15BF4A5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sentencing guidelines</header>
 <paragraph id="HD82285ED9FBF49CBBC6EA64AF56217DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Review and Amendment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the United States Sentencing Commission, pursuant to its authority under section 994 of title 28, United States Code, and in accordance with this section, shall review and, if appropriate, amend the Federal sentencing guidelines and policy statements applicable to persons convicted of any offense under section 1039 of title 18, United States Code, as amended by this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FD4B4D95BB74B5B90F6F31E16ABEEE8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>The United States Sentencing Commission may amend the Federal sentencing guidelines in accordance with the procedures set forth in section 21(a) of the Sentencing Act of 1987 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/994">28 U.S.C. 994</external-xref> note) as though the authority under that section had not expired.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H826522BB4AA54E769878E78AE6CA3F5B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Statement of exclusive means of acquiring geolocation information</header>
 <subsection id="H6A501E5DFF814FB7BA51B5F68641C714"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person may acquire the geolocation information of a person for protective activities or law enforcement or intelligence purposes except pursuant to a warrant issued pursuant to rule 41 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure, as amended by section 3, or the amendments made by this Act, or the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref>).</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83C78023808E4E4F8E1536BE8F4B828C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Geolocation information defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>geolocation information</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2601 of title 18, United States Code, as amended by section 2.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


