<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9074CF7E34AB4960B2209D6509EA2022" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 523 IH: Debt Transparency and Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 523</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170113">January 13, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001158">Mr. Marchant</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide further means of accountability of the United States debt and promote fiscal
			 responsibility.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF8101C1BE20845B8AE06DE6823F9EF68" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7AF1B43E6819460787FF0393977BFD77" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Debt Transparency and Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H88BA76AEF99049CC8E01F37881438A6E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Secretary of the Treasury report to Congress before reaching debt limit</header> <subsection id="HEAEB4DDA9AD84952A925418CB2D537EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6517C74BAC684861A6D4983F4FE9DF19" style="USC">
					<section id="H35A5F1F8A40D458792001B1870DD5AE2"><enum>3131.</enum><header>Report before reaching debt limit</header>
 <subsection id="H90ED0B6968D7491B8F7BA89952AD1017"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than sixty days and not less than twenty-one days prior to any date on which the Secretary of the Treasury anticipates the public debt will reach the limit specified under section 3101, as modified by section 3101A, the Secretary shall appear before the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate, to submit the information described under subsection (b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H86C057E3ECAB48CE9A3614FBD21F8274"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information required To be presented</header><text>In an appearance described under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit the following:</text> <paragraph id="H46464271DC3B47C3AC725CCC90B7322B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Debt Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A report on the state of the public debt, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HD9A781D308FA4AB896850EE493167B80"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the historical levels of the debt, current amount and composition of the debt, and future projections of the debt;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63669275B11A4F15AA990FA9CBFDD977"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the drivers and composition of future debt; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H098062F662DD4C4D9AFF69F45D8247EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how, if the debt limit is raised, the United States will meet debt obligations, including principal and interest.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H39277060C9544E0F8F55B8DB7ED0B4CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Statement of intent</header><text>A detailed explanation of—</text> <subparagraph id="H10B0DC8583C04EDBB4F359C19D366E51"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">proposals of the President to reduce the public debt in the short term (the current and following three fiscal years), medium term (approximately five to nine fiscal years), and long term (approximately ten to twenty-five fiscal years), and proposals of the President to adjust the debt-to-gross domestic product ratio;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AFEECA5B0B844C1957087BDB6AB1633"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact an increased debt limit will have on future Government spending, debt service, and the position of the United States dollar as the international reserve currency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93489EC6761541DDBF3347EBB69ED522"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">projections of fiscal health and sustainability of major direct-spending entitlement programs (including Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89707F8E33DD42EC8040849375CEFB93"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any extraordinary measures the Secretary intends to take to fund Federal Government obligations if the debt limit is not raised, a projection of how long such extraordinary measures will fund the Federal Government, and a projection of the administrative cost of taking such extraordinary measures.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F2B4F7A944F4D3DBADB50BA681F5AEE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Progress report</header>
 <subparagraph id="H5FF3A7C6B868492FAFA6903755829567"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A detailed report on the progress of implementing all proposals of the President described under subparagraph (A) of paragraph (2).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE840452CBAB4A1D8B17E1B79C97E2AE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The report described under this paragraph shall only be submitted if a Secretary has already appeared at least once pursuant to this section during any term of office for a particular President.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H02793232B202470AA164ED041522B6F9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public access to information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall place on the homepage of the Department of the Treasury a link to a webpage that shall serve as a repository of information made available to the public for at least 6 months following the date of release of the relevant information, including:</text>
 <paragraph id="HCA758669337C457E8007203F170451E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The debt report submitted under subsection (b)(1).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H832B6448BE9B48C8B6A186A66E23E014"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The detailed explanation submitted under subsection (b)(2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3D067CA7F6A54AA0B9C0D53B5B26A1BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The progress report submitted under subsection (b)(3).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H31F4917D967241F08B12A3D20DA1FA74"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Extraordinary measures defined</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>extraordinary measures</quote> means each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HBE55972272D14605B679D8BBB2362ECC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Directing or approving the issuance of debt by the Federal Financing Bank for the purpose of entering into an exchange transaction for debt that is subject to the limit under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1BC5529AF16D464EBC95BC5FD154E299"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Suspending investments in the Government Securities Investment Fund of the Thrift Savings Fund.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD7A67C6355F74D65B0202BACC032D815"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Suspending investments in the stabilization fund established under section 5302.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H891FC653F2234D368AEA0D5FB30D0F09"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Suspending new investments in the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund or the Postal Service Retiree Health Benefits Fund.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2053A5C6DAFE47178A6B931491187D9D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Selling or redeeming securities, obligations, or other invested assets of the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund or the Postal Service Retiree Health Benefits Fund before maturity.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE29BF7055C884DF9A7258301D1972FD1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Suspending sales of State and Local Government Series Treasury securities.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7AF2536FB584A7DA8952535CA87CA44"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Such other measures as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEF16D9CD284D49128F0F85F87949E906"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3130">section 3130</external-xref> the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62D254144DFD47D1B13EED5A03692E94" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">3131. Report before reaching debt limit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3FB17EB69E8D42DDBCE273BC79704661" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Access to certain Treasury Department data</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than thirty days after receipt of a written request from the Chairman of the Committee on Finance of the Senate or of the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, but no more than four times per fiscal year for each, the Secretary of the Treasury shall provide to the requesting Chairman financial and economic data relevant to determining the amount of the public debt of the United States, including—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE2FBC81211B047B6958D52CBCDE0CE89"><enum>(1)</enum><text>cash flow and debt transaction information used in preparing the Daily Treasury Statement, including current balances, receipts, and payments;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H34DA4747057C45949CAB8B52CAD3EA2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>operating cash balance projections; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H62FEE6636BEE4D5E86A8B5FB48EA0F71"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">relevant information regarding any extraordinary measures (as defined under section 3131(d) of title 31, United States Code) taken to prevent the public debt from exceeding the limitation imposed by section 3101 of title 31, United States Code, as modified by section 3101A of such title.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


