<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCAFE8B295AA34BBF92DD9F1573279B96" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4667 IH: Further Additional Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements, 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4667</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20171218">December 18, 2017</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000372">Mr. Frelinghuysen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Making further supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018, for disaster assistance for Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, and calendar year 2017 wildfires, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HBF7BBBAE3CEA4F898FBBBB12AFAFAF3D" style="OLC"> 
<division id="HFA895678AF784C1893560B26EFEBB9D8" style="appropriations"><enum>A</enum><header>Disaster Assistance</header> 
<section id="H9926F56DF39E46B4A96351CA19C6C36C" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> The following sums are appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018, and for other purposes, namely:</text></section> <title id="HB0A163AC40FA4E3BA93922EB4348E7F6"><enum>I</enum><appropriations-major id="HD58F8B10D75F42F18B7D698A01AFC739"><header>Department of Agriculture</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H2C80AD8A04D24B58864040783284DBE3"><header>Office of the Secretary</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for the <quote>Office of the Secretary</quote>, $2,600,000,000, which shall remain available until September 30, 2019, for necessary expenses related to crops, trees, bushes, vines, and livestock losses resulting from Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, Maria, and other hurricanes and wildfires occurring in calendar year 2017 under such terms and conditions as determined by the Secretary: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the Secretary may provide assistance for such losses in the form of block grants to eligible states and territories: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the total amount of payments received under this heading and applicable policies of crop insurance under the Federal Crop Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1501">7 U.S.C. 1501</external-xref> et seq.) or the Noninsured Crop Disaster Assistance Program (NAP) under section 196 of the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7333">7 U.S.C. 7333</external-xref>) shall not exceed 85 percent of the loss as determined by the Secretary: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the total amount of payments received under this heading for producers who did not obtain a policy or plan of insurance for an insurable commodity for the 2017 crop year, or 2018 crop year in the case of citrus, under the Federal Crop Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1501">7 U.S.C. 1501</external-xref> et seq.) for the crop incurring the losses or did not file the required paperwork and pay the service fee by the applicable State filing deadline for a noninsurable commodity for the 2017 crop year under NAP for the crop incurring the losses shall not exceed 65 percent of the loss as determined by the Secretary: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That producers receiving payments under this heading, as determined by the Secretary, shall be required to purchase crop insurance where crop insurance is available for the next two available crop years, and producers receiving payments under this heading shall be required to purchase coverage under NAP where crop insurance is not available in the next two available crop years, as determined by the Secretary: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That, not later than 90 days after the end of fiscal year 2018, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Congress specifying the type, amount, and method of such assistance by state and territory and the status of the amounts obligated and plans for further expenditure and include improvements that can be made to Federal Crop Insurance policies, either administratively or legislatively, to increase participation, particularly among underserved producers, in higher levels of coverage in future years for crops qualifying for assistance under this heading: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. </text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H1F2596908EA641AFBFCE30E15AC9AAE0"><header>Office of Inspector General</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Office of Inspector General</quote>, $2,500,000, to remain available until expended, for oversight and audit of programs, grants, and activities funded by this division and administered by the Department of Agriculture: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H781BE70E10D24ECAAAABD65382F3CDAB"><header>Agricultural research service</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H92F3738FA7D049348DCAE8E256D0A9EE"><header>buildings and facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Buildings and Facilities</quote>, $22,000,000, to remain available until expended, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma and Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H2608F42FA46046A9899E324E2190807B"><header>Farm service agency</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HDE07B4647163448CBF7AB7C3C07F7B87"><header>emergency conservation program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for the <quote>Emergency Conservation Program</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria and of wildfires occurring in calendar year 2017, and other natural disasters, $400,000,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That not less than $300,000,000 of the amount made available in the previous proviso shall be for necessary expenses resulting from a major disaster declared pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HD82D5C808C234A7B8D30AA955AD2353C"><header>Natural resources conservation service</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H9D9EF7C9F6604D2BBB6B428165B8FE4C"><header>watershed and flood prevention operations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount, for <quote>Watershed and Flood Prevention Operations</quote>, for necessary expenses for the Emergency Watershed Protection Program related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria and of wildfires occurring in calendar year 2017, and other natural disasters, $541,000,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That not less than $400,000,000 of the amount made available in the previous proviso shall be for necessary expenses resulting from a major disaster declared pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="H234217F2F0154D7CB0453362C22A3FEA"><header>Rural Development Programs</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H2AC05D3812564252B6C5AEADE9AE5196"><header>Rural Housing Service</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HBDF094BFCF924AA38BA8167D5242F3B2"><header>Rural Housing Insurance Fund Program Account</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for costs of direct loans, including costs relating to modification of such loans, as those terms are defined in section 502 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/661a">2 U.S.C. 661a</external-xref>), $18,672,000 shall be for direct loans for the rehabilitation of section 515 rental housing (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1485">42 U.S.C. 1485</external-xref>) in locations where owners were not required to carry national flood insurance, to remain available until September 30, 2019: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such funds shall be for areas impacted by Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HA086D76D601B448CB378543382C06B34"><header>Rural Utilities Service</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H60CA6DEB6E43497F96E93FD99596B30E"><header>Rural Water and Waste Disposal Program Account</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for the <quote>Rural Water and Waste Disposal Program Account</quote>, $165,475,000, to remain available until expended, for grants to repair drinking water systems and sewer and solid waste disposal systems impacted by Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That not to exceed $2,000,000 of the amount appropriated under this heading shall be for technical assistance grants for rural water and waste systems pursuant to section 306(a)(14) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H8EF697E591514BE6B20F69E4BF3E16A3"><header>Food and nutrition service</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H54B2221F7A8047838A5EDFDB3AA5E6B4"><header>commodity assistance program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Commodity Assistance Program</quote> for the emergency food assistance program as authorized by section 27(a) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2036">7 U.S.C. 2036(a)</external-xref>) and section 204(a)(1) of the Emergency Food Assistance Act of 1983 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7508">7 U.S.C. 7508(a)(1)</external-xref>), $24,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019: <italic>Provided</italic>, That notwithstanding any other provisions of the Emergency Food Assistance Act of 1983, the Secretary of Agriculture may allocate additional foods and funds for administrative expenses from resources specifically appropriated, transferred, or reprogrammed to provide resources to Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, and States affected by wildfires occurring in calendar year 2017 or Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, as determined by the Secretary, without regard to sections 204 and 214 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7508">7 U.S.C. 7508</external-xref>, 7515): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such funds will be designated for States impacted by Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, or wildfire and subject to a federal major disaster or emergency declaration: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="H49E072EC8B114BB0AD9429D636A9893D"><header>Department Of Health And Human Services</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="HF7914BA04F994B3CBA101DB6C9C07648"><header>Food and Drug Administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H975D3582B2FD4C39812F0E8AF8C977EC"><header>buildings and facilities</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H4A7E5159FF6446518B178F1DA0EF4F17"><header>(Including Transfer of Funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Buildings and Facilities</quote>, $7,600,000, to remain available until expended, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount may be transferred to <quote>Department of Health and Human Services—Food and Drug Administration Salaries and Expenses</quote> for costs related to repair of facilities, for replacement of equipment, and for other increases in facility-related costs: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That obligations incurred for the purposes provided herein prior to the date of enactment of this Act may be charged to funds appropriated by this paragraph: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="H6663C6AF32E44ED6B0715EC6A667C860" commented="no"><header>General Provision—This Title</header></appropriations-major> <section id="H99A7793B8FAC4883BB3864385B150107" commented="no"><enum>101.</enum> <subsection id="H0F07572589814CF49171D0F9A7F21DEB" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1501(d)(1) of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/9081">7 U.S.C. 9081(d)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>not more than $20,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>not more than $40,000,000</quote>.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF8DA7003678D4AEF93D377E2109727E4" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The amount provided by subsection (a) for fiscal year 2018 is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></subsection></section></title> <title id="H692A23874197436B8113E679DD9F992D"><enum>II</enum><appropriations-major id="H827C53D9430347A8BC5024172A3B43FB"><header>Department of Commerce</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H0E0A4F903684442E831E4FE16ADD14B1"><header>Economic development administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H017596DB89AA49BCAF7D13E8D9076992"><header>Economic development assistance programs</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HC79A7B80CD74414298BA12E49B966038"><header>(Including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Pursuant to section 703 of the Public Works and Economic Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3233">42 U.S.C. 3233</external-xref>), for an additional amount for <quote>Economic Development Assistance Programs</quote> for necessary expenses related to flood mitigation, disaster relief, long-term recovery, and restoration of infrastructure in areas that received a major disaster designation as a result of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, and the calendar year 2017 wildfires, under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.), $600,000,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the amount provided under this heading is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That within the amount appropriated, up to 2 percent of funds may be transferred to the <quote>Salaries and Expenses</quote> account for administration and oversight activities: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That within the amount appropriated, $1,000,000 shall be transferred to the <quote>Office of Inspector General</quote> account for carrying out investigations and audits related to the funding provided under this heading. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H3C083CC17B6940208382530A4F88B905"><header>National Oceanic And Atmospheric Administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HE3B7D9F9686C419098C8FB62A108E794"><header>Operations, Research, and Facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Operations, Research, and Facilities</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $120,904,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019, as follows: (1) $12,904,000 for repair and replacement of observing assets, Federal real property, and equipment; (2) $18,000,000 for marine debris assessment and removal; (3) $40,000,000 for mapping, charting, and geodesy services; and (4) $50,000,000 to improve weather forecasting, hurricane intensity forecasting and flood forecasting and mitigation capabilities, including data assimilation from ocean observing platforms and satellites: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the amount provided under this heading is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H06244E8DA4AC48739A580C8E6021830B"><header>Procurement, acquisition and construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Procurement, Acquisition and Construction</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $79,232,000, to remain available until September 30, 2020, as follows: (1) $29,232,000 for repair and replacement of Federal real property and observing assets; and (2) $50,000,000 for improvements to operational and research weather supercomputing infrastructure and for improvement of satellite ground services used in hurricane intensity and track prediction: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the amount provided under this heading is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="HCEBA2317C5BE404AA6420852CAE256A5"><header>Department of Justice</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H8A4EF8821F424796B0751400708AF5C3"><header>United states marshals service</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H523EA151C8B84BA79236D21EA6001D12"><header>salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Salaries and Expenses</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $2,500,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the amount provided under this heading is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H53D86018D88D4F319CDFCC93740161B3"><header>Federal bureau of investigation</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HAEB017593AB2498995A0B5308FA61AB6"><header>salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Salaries and Expenses</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $21,200,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the amount provided under this heading is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H4238AADACEFC4D8B82F8F6E806257519"><header>Drug enforcement administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H896A1E2E53334574A5FAA4A2DB32E05B"><header>salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Salaries and Expenses</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $11,500,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the amount provided under this heading is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H0FBEDAE21E40497795C47640CBFBA495"><header>Federal prison system</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H45BF1CC22D844C26BC4D0D6CC0D11DF8"><header>salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Salaries and Expenses</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $16,000,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the amount provided under this heading is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HB90B8899C40C4471A05910C2B1ED1148"><header>buildings and facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Buildings and Facilities</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $34,000,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the amount provided under this heading is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="H92C1489D9AD640CCB5BD61AA700A9DCA"><header>Science</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H88B5ED6E354C432BBC8E5BE5E68A23EB"><header>National aeronautics and space administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H596AE65DF78740DF8A17EDE0828FAEE5"><header>construction and environmental compliance and restoration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Construction and Environmental Compliance and Restoration</quote> for repairs at National Aeronautics and Space Administration facilities damaged by hurricanes during 2017, $81,300,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the amount provided under this heading is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H3AC23EF3B0F2418DB78B639EFA56983D"><header>National science foundation</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H4E5EF709C6314E94B3FAB84460566B8A"><header>research and related activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Research and Related Activities</quote> for necessary expenses to repair National Science Foundation radio observatory facilities damaged by hurricanes that occurred during 2017, $16,300,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the amount provided under this heading is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the National Science Foundation shall submit a spending plan to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate within 45 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="HC816F39FEB954CE7B035014E7B224C60"><header>Related Agencies</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H257A8C5C5BA64C87B43F6503B74C5389"><header>Legal Services Corporation</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H0A8C40B84C1A4A0B817A6C848FDA5310"><header>Payment to the Legal Services Corporation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> For an additional amount for <quote>Payment to the Legal Services Corporation</quote> to carry out the purposes of the Legal Services Corporation Act by providing for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $1,000,000: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the amount made available under this heading shall be used only to provide the mobile resources, technology, and disaster coordinators necessary to provide storm-related services to the Legal Services Corporation client population and only in the areas significantly affected by Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That none of the funds appropriated in this division to the Legal Services Corporation shall be expended for any purpose prohibited or limited by, or contrary to any of the provisions of, sections 501, 502, 503, 504, 505, and 506 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/119">Public Law 105–119</external-xref>, and all funds appropriated in this division to the Legal Services Corporation shall be subject to the same terms and conditions set forth in such sections, except that all references in sections 502 and 503 to 1997 and 1998 shall be deemed to refer instead to 2017 and 2018, respectively, and except that sections 501 and 503 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/134">Public Law 104–134</external-xref> (referenced by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/119">Public Law 105–119</external-xref>) shall not apply to the amount made available under this heading: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That, for the purposes of this division, the Legal Services Corporation shall be considered an agency of the United States Government.</text></appropriations-small></title> <title id="H7E46C20F9FDB468E95208B9656271988"><enum>III</enum><appropriations-major id="H3B456A1395F048F093767CCB785F4C98"><header>DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-major id="HBEA679467A7E4C6FBF98105B3FFFB244"><header> DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE—MILITARY</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H29A99AB272204A0E8696ECB7C9B1A52C"><header>OPERATION AND MAINTENANCE</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H682563E5D58445818F76BD5F16C75CA9"><header>Operation and Maintenance, Army</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> For an additional amount for <quote>Operation and Maintenance, Army</quote>, $20,110,000, to remain available until September 30, 2018, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma or Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H2BBFABD140BE4D45B9FE4EF742DD91EE"><header>Operation and Maintenance, Navy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> For an additional amount for <quote>Operation and Maintenance, Navy</quote>, $267,796,000, to remain available until September 30, 2018, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma or Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H49E24FA9CD4D42B4B1978CE0805BBADE"><header>Operation and Maintenance, Marine Corps</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> For an additional amount for <quote>Operation and Maintenance, Marine Corps</quote>, $17,920,000, to remain available until September 30, 2018, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma or Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HA8E1891A0C08494783D6154ECCE3344D"><header>Operation and Maintenance, Air Force</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> For an additional amount for <quote>Operation and Maintenance, Air Force</quote>, $20,916,000, to remain available until September 30, 2018, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma or Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H71C0A0762DC8464E99FC178CC9D8EFF8" commented="no"><header>Operation and Maintenance, Defense-Wide</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> For an additional amount for <quote>Operation and Maintenance, Defense-Wide</quote>, $2,650,000, to remain available until September 30, 2018, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma or Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HAEB1AC35AFDD4579BC7EE3099D19CE9B"><header>Operation and Maintenance, Army Reserve</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> For an additional amount for <quote>Operation and Maintenance, Army Reserve</quote>, $12,500,000, to remain available until September 30, 2018, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma or Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H7603D93CDBCA4B0E8826CF915317DE1C"><header>Operation and Maintenance, Navy Reserve</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> For an additional amount for <quote>Operation and Maintenance, Navy Reserve</quote>, $2,922,000, to remain available until September 30, 2018, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma or Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H0ECA9B07C19A43E8B384FD9470A1A079"><header>Operation and Maintenance, Air Force Reserve</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> For an additional amount for <quote>Operation and Maintenance, Air Force Reserve</quote>, $5,770,000, to remain available until September 30, 2018, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma or Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HE620110306C145288A5503141C0C7CD7"><header>Operation and Maintenance, Army National Guard</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> For an additional amount for <quote>Operation and Maintenance, Army National Guard</quote>, $55,471,000, to remain available until September 30, 2018, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma or Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H3FC9A75DD16D421692FF5B33EECE8E08"><header>PROCUREMENT</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H14B936CCEE2E42BC8B8EDE53214827AF"><header>Other Procurement, Navy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> For an additional amount for <quote>Other Procurement, Navy</quote> $18,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2020, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma or Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H5EE3EBC261304DACB924E4057714B926"><header>Revolving and management funds</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HC4FDE0FA4D0B4802AC909E48E4149F04"><header>Defense Working Capital Funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> For an additional amount for <quote>Defense Working Capital Funds</quote> for the Navy Working Capital Fund, $9,486,000, to remain available until September 30, 2018, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma or Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HA458C6FEF374415CB9CCE1F7A069492B"><header>Other department of defense programs</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H4CB97B05D496464EA9FF241B8D0AD518"><header>Defense Health Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for operation and maintenance for <quote>Defense Health Program</quote>, $704,000, to remain available until September 30, 2018, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma or Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small></title> <title id="HAB0BBB20620941BE9EC6388832F5E52E"><enum>IV</enum><appropriations-major id="H2B2DE01B1B854C599B66DEB1E9F52C99"><header>CORPS OF ENGINEERS—CIVIL</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-major id="HA685CC15E82E4F8E9EC50E4C282C4F51"><header>DEPARTMENT OF THE ARMY</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="HFFF580EC673848058C72F0163AD0148A"><header>Corps of Engineers—Civil</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H0703F7E45868431FB151BC1460401E34"><header>Investigations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Investigations</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $75,000,000, to remain available until expended to expedite and complete at full Federal expense studies, including Preconstruction Engineering and Design, for flood and storm damage reduction, including shore protection, in areas that were affected by Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, or Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the Secretary may use funding provided under this heading to complete ongoing studies, to initiate and complete up to two authorized studies for assessing regional flood and storm risks, and to initiate and complete up to six authorized feasibility studies: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the Secretary shall consider giving priority to studies in areas that suffered the most damage from these hurricanes and to studies in areas that have had multiple major disaster declarations in recent years: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That a report identifying all ongoing studies, authorized studies for assessing regional flood and storm risks in the impacted areas, and authorized feasibility studies eligible for funding under this heading, including identification of whether each study is in a category to be considered for priority, shall be submitted to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That no allocation shall be made to initiate any new study until the Secretary submits to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a list of all new studies selected to be initiated using funds provided under this heading: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That beginning not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works shall provide monthly reports to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate detailing the allocation and obligation of these funds.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H45A1259FBEC74DA7B997B0D19648C03D" commented="no"><header>CONSTRUCTION</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Construction</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of natural disasters, including Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $10,480,000,000, to remain available until expended to rehabilitate, repair, and construct United States Army Corps of Engineers projects: <italic>Provided</italic>, That $55,000,000 of the funds provided under this heading shall be used to address emergency situations at Corps of Engineers projects, and to rehabilitate and repair damages to Corps of Engineers projects, caused by natural disasters: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That $10,425,000,000 of the funds provided under this heading shall be used to expedite construction of projects for flood and storm damage reduction, including shore protection, in areas that were affected by Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, or Maria: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the Secretary shall consider giving priority to projects located in areas that suffered the most damage from these hurricanes and to projects located in areas that have had multiple major disaster declarations in recent years: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That funding utilized for authorized shore protection projects shall restore such projects from the design level of protection to the full project profile at full Federal expense: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the completion of ongoing construction projects receiving funds provided under this heading shall be at full Federal expense with respect to such funds: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That upon approval of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate funds provided under this heading may be used to construct any project studied using funds provided under the heading <quote>Investigations</quote> or any project with a completed Chief’s Report that has not yet been authorized if the Secretary determines that the project is technically feasible, economically justified, and environmentally acceptable: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That, using these funds, the non-Federal cash contribution for authorized but unconstructed projects, projects with completed Chief’s Reports that have not yet been authorized, or projects that are funded as ongoing studies under the heading <quote>Investigations</quote> shall be financed in accordance with the provisions of section 103(k) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/99/662">Public Law 99–662</external-xref> over a period of 30 years from the date of completion of the project or separable element: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That a report identifying all ongoing construction projects, authorized but unconstructed projects, and projects with completed Chief’s Reports that have not yet been authorized, including project cost estimates and identification of whether each project is in a category to be considered for priority, shall be submitted to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate not later than 45 days after the date of enactment of this Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That not more than $500,000,000 of the funds provided to expedite construction shall be available until such report is submitted: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That for projects funded under this heading, the provisions of section 902 of the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 shall not apply to these funds: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That up to $50,000,000 of the funds provided to expedite construction shall be used to expedite continuing authorities projects to reduce the risk of flooding and storm damage in areas impacted by Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, or Maria: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That any projects using funds appropriated under this heading shall be initiated only after non-Federal interests have entered into binding agreements with the Secretary requiring the non-Federal interests to pay 100 percent of the operation, maintenance, repair, replacement, and rehabilitation costs of the project and to hold and save the United States free from damages due to the construction or operation and maintenance of the project, except for damages due to the fault or negligence of the United States or its contractors: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That beginning not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works shall provide monthly reports to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate detailing the allocation and obligation of these funds.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H2EC7BB29C6A340389D2E701F3808C372" commented="no"><header>MISSISSIPPI RIVER AND TRIBUTARIES</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Mississippi River and Tributaries</quote>, $370,000,000, to remain available until expended, for necessary expenses to dredge navigation projects in response to, and repair damages to Corps of Engineers projects caused by, natural disasters: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That beginning not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works shall provide monthly reports to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate detailing the allocation and obligation of these funds.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H3AB2A317643241A8B5EACB242BE9BB3D"><header>OPERATION AND MAINTENANCE</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Operation and Maintenance</quote> for necessary expenses to dredge navigation projects in response to, and repair damages to Corps of Engineers projects caused by, natural disasters, $608,000,000, to remain available until expended, of which such sums as are necessary to cover the Federal share of eligible operation and maintenance costs for coastal harbors and channels, and for inland harbors shall be derived from the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That beginning not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works shall provide monthly reports to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate detailing the allocation and obligation of these funds.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HBEBA0D84216847CDBD000EB448FC53B3" commented="no"><header>FLOOD CONTROL AND COASTAL EMERGENCIES</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Flood Control and Coastal Emergencies</quote>, as authorized by section 5 of the Act of August 18, 1941 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/701n">33 U.S.C. 701n</external-xref>), for necessary expenses to prepare for flood, hurricane and other natural disasters and support emergency operations, repairs, and other activities in response to such disasters, as authorized by law, $537,000,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That beginning not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works shall provide monthly reports to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate detailing the allocation and obligation of these funds.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HFD0CBD7D8DA349D781C4AFE1F5293337"><header>Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Expenses</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $20,000,000, to remain available until expended to oversee emergency response and recovery activities: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That beginning not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works shall provide monthly reports to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate detailing the allocation and obligation of these funds.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="HC3EB3B942D1B4EA399CFD5AE5285D523"><header>Department of Energy</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-major id="HC45545317FD04A27B0E9154BC7438E4B"><header>Energy programs</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="HBF97234543F1456E9057361EE00DEDB9"><header>Electricity delivery and energy reliability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability</quote>, $13,000,000, to remain available until expended, for necessary expenses related to natural disasters, including technical assistance related to electric grids: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H301CF59E9BE24C1CB6A6EF76C5427742"><header>Strategic petroleum reserve</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Strategic Petroleum Reserve</quote>, $8,716,000, to remain available until expended, for necessary expenses related to damages caused by natural disasters: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-major id="HB65EEFC8A4754D27A719AB15ECFF9F06"><header>General Provision—This Title</header></appropriations-major> <section id="HD2202DEBE61542D4B027DED2E9CABD39"><enum>401.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In fiscal year 2018 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Chief of Engineers of the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers shall transmit to the Congress, after reasonable opportunity for comment, but without change, by the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works, a monthly report, the first of which shall be transmitted to Congress not later than 2 days after the date of enactment of this Act and monthly thereafter, which includes detailed estimates of damages to each Corps of Engineers project, caused by natural disasters or otherwise.</text></section></title> 
<title id="HAEE1EBFCD7FC477D83325937EEA7D6F2"><enum>V</enum><appropriations-intermediate id="H84536E2459974A639A608045D761F620"><header>General services administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H6EDFD6C7A2124184B6BCAC6CD2374C75"><header>Federal buildings fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount to be deposited in the <quote>Federal Buildings Fund</quote>, $126,951,000, to remain available until expended, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Maria, and Irma, for repair and alteration of buildings under the custody and control of the Administrator of General Services, and real property management and related activities not otherwise provided for: <italic>Provided</italic>, That funds may be used to reimburse the <quote>Federal Buildings Fund</quote> for obligations incurred for this purpose prior to enactment of this Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That not more than $15,000,000 shall be available for tenant improvements in damaged U.S. courthouses: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HAF5280983AD24E2F8160B5F3E4F6B6BE"><header>Small business administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HE52DABF330E2497FA13C1D4669561D30"><header>disaster loans program account</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HCDDA8EEF7C9F4D19B0EA0FBA63B1BCD8"><header>(Including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for the <quote>Small Business Administration—Disaster Loans Program Account</quote> for the cost of direct loans authorized by section 7(b) of the Small Business Act, $1,652,000,000, to remain available until expended:<italic> Provided</italic>, That up to $618,000,000 may be transferred to and merged with <quote>Salaries and Expenses</quote> for administrative expenses to carry out the disaster loan program authorized by section 7(b) of the Small Business Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That none of the funds provided under this heading may be used for indirect administrative expenses: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the amount provided under this heading is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HB1701FB2F1054E06AD05D753E2EB01F9"><header>Office of inspector general</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for the <quote>Small Business Administration—Office of Inspector General</quote>, $7,000,000, to remain available until expended:<italic> Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-intermediate></title> <title id="H36C46A5094F048D8BCA5B91A6E60C77C"><enum>VI</enum><appropriations-major id="H2DA980EE2D0C4B73B72CF5B5EA746402"><header>DEPARTMENT OF HOMELAND SECURITY</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="HD722D6B36F044977A970AA3A562FBD86"><header>Office of Inspector General</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HCD29727B72FB4BD88765A657D6D5C15D"><header>Operations and Support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Operations and Support</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $25,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2020, for audits and investigations of activities funded by this title: <italic> Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HA856B3CA1A164FA385CB906BAAC2C551"><header>U.S. Customs and Border Protection</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H4A14F227CF884E6BB8FB2664457F402A"><header>Operations and Support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Operations and Support</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $104,494,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019: <italic> Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That not more than $39,400,000 may be used to carry out U.S. Customs and Border Protection activities in fiscal year 2018 in Puerto Rico and the United States Virgin Islands, in addition to any other amounts available for such purposes.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HFDD71D16D0FC4D4E9A670A40C10594A5"><header>procurement, construction, and improvements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Procurement, Construction, and Improvements</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $3,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2022: <italic> Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That funds are provided to carry out U.S. Customs and Border Protection activities in Puerto Rico and the United States Virgin Islands, in addition to any other amounts available for such purposes.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H301F20F8977F4B04821AB24297C84995"><header>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H39A205ABF44E4D5D83790175EDDCBE80"><header>Operations and Support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> For an additional amount for <quote>Operations and Support</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $30,905,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019: <italic> Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H1F3AD69A05FC4344B0F4BD0333CC4DC1"><header>procurement, construction, and improvements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Procurement, Construction, and Improvements</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $33,052,000, to remain available until September 30, 2022: <italic> Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HFB340BDF6C8747AE86D317A56D407FD9"><header>Transportation Security Administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H24F6982E6BE34A34BD9BB3061FD74810"><header>Operations and Support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Operations and Support</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $10,322,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019: <italic> Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H193C226E1F1D4048AB74D5413529EB92"><header>Coast Guard</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HF778A4E3653E4BF4B5760302D10EC92B"><header>Operating Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Operating Expenses</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $112,136,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019: <italic> Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H84F9105C651E480689408E92BFFCA453"><header>Environmental Compliance and Restoration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Environmental Compliance and Restoration</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $4,038,000, to remain available until September 30, 2022: <italic> Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HC435F722E63041DA8138F22B2288FF02"><header>Acquisition, Construction, and Improvements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Acquisition, Construction, and Improvements</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, Maria, and Matthew, $718,919,000, to remain available until September 30, 2022: <italic> Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HF8AC8FEFFDD74915B17E5CB277FC9810"><header>Federal Emergency Management Agency</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HD82C223DEF4A48F2B50475661A22099E"><header>Operations and Support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Operations and Support</quote> for necessary expenses, $58,800,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019: <italic> Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H513A3FD851334B19A829247B5FE7C186"><header>Procurement, Construction, and Improvements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Procurement, Construction, and Improvements</quote> for necessary expenses, $1,200,000, to remain available until September 30, 2020: <italic> Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H872C881903884817AF1A2D1DAA04C3FE"><header>Disaster Relief Fund</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H67197E5AE1D74ABEB682274779B94500"><header>(Including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Disaster Relief Fund</quote> for major disasters declared pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.), $27,500,000,000, to remain available until expended: <italic> Provided</italic>, That the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall publish on the Agency’s website not later than 5 days after an award of a public assistance grant under section 406 or 428 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172</external-xref> or 5189f) that is in excess of $1,000,000, the specifics of each such grant award: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That for any mission assignment or mission assignment task order to another Federal department or agency regarding a major disaster in excess of $1,000,000, not later than 5 days after the issuance of such mission assignment or mission assignment task order, the Administrator shall publish on the Agency’s website the following: the name of the impacted State, the disaster declaration for such State, the assigned agency, the assistance requested, a description of the disaster, the total cost estimate, and the amount obligated: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That not later than 10 days after the last day of each month until a mission assignment or mission assignment task order described in the preceding proviso is completed and closed out, the Administrator shall update any changes to the total cost estimate and the amount obligated: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That for a disaster declaration related to Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, or Maria, the Administrator shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, not later than 5 days after the first day of each month beginning after the date of enactment of this Act, and shall publish on the Agency’s website, not later than 10 days after the first day of each such month, an estimate or actual amount, if available, for the current fiscal year of the cost of the following categories of spending: public assistance, individual assistance, operations, mitigation, administrative, and any other relevant category (including emergency measures and disaster resources): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That not later than 10 days after the first day of each month, the Administrator shall publish on the Agency’s website the report (referred to as the Disaster Relief Monthly Report) as required by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/4">Public Law 114–4</external-xref>. </text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Of the amounts provided under this heading for the Disaster Relief Fund, up to $4,000,000,000 may be transferred to the Disaster Assistance Direct Loan Program Account for the cost of direct loans as authorized under section 417 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5184">42 U.S.C. 5184</external-xref>) to be used to assist local governments in providing essential services as a result of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, or Maria: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amounts may subsidize gross obligations for the principal amount of direct loans not to exceed $4,000,000,000 under section 417 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5184">42 U.S.C. 5184</external-xref>): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That notwithstanding section 417 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5184">42 U.S.C. 5184</external-xref>), a territory or possession, and instrumentalities and local governments thereof, of the United States shall be deemed to be a local government for purposes of this paragraph: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That notwithstanding section 417(b) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5184">42 U.S.C. 5184(b)</external-xref>), the amount of any such loan issued to a territory or possession, and instrumentalities and local governments thereof, may be based on the projected loss of tax and other revenues and on projected cash outlays not previously budgeted for a period not to exceed 180 days from the date of the major disaster, and may exceed $5,000,000: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That notwithstanding any other provision of law or the constitution of a territory or possession that limits the issuance of debt, a territory or possession, and instrumentalities and local governments thereof, may each receive more than one loan with repayment provisions and other terms specific to the type of lost tax and other revenues and on projected unbudgeted cash outlays for which the loan is provided: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That notwithstanding section 417(c)(1) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5184">42 U.S.C. 5184(c)(1)</external-xref>), loans to a territory or possession, and instrumentalities and local governments thereof, may be cancelled in whole or in part only at the discretion of the Secretary of Homeland Security in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall determine the terms, conditions, eligible uses, and timing and amount of Federal disbursements of loans issued to a territory or possession, and instrumentalities and local governments thereof: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such costs, including the cost of modifying such loans, shall be as defined in section 502 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/661a">2 U.S.C. 661a</external-xref>): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the Federal Emergency Management Agency may transfer up to 1.5 percent of the amount under this paragraph to the Disaster Assistance Direct Loan Program Account for administrative expenses to carry out under this paragraph the direct loan program, as authorized by section 417 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5184">42 U.S.C. 5184</external-xref>): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the amount provided under this paragraph for transfer, up to $150,000,000 may be transferred to the Disaster Assistance Direct Loan Program Account for the cost to lend a territory or possession of the United States that portion of assistance for which the territory or possession is responsible under the cost-sharing provisions of the major disaster declaration for Hurricanes Irma or Maria, as authorized under section 319 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5162">42 U.S.C. 5162</external-xref>): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the amount provided under this paragraph for transfer, up to $1,000,000 may be transferred to the Disaster Assistance Direct Loan Program Account for administrative expenses to carry out the Advance of Non-Federal Share program, as authorized by section 319 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5162">42 U.S.C. 5162</external-xref>):<italic> Provided further</italic>, That the amount provided under this heading is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H0EDF6652B4F2408687DDB69C02DF687C"><header>Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HDE565828164F42D3B81018FDDBABF6A5"><header>Operations and Support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Operations and Support</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $5,374,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H228F4893379E440BA73968B46B8A22BD"><header>Procurement, Construction, and Improvements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Procurement, Construction, and Improvements</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $5,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2022: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="HF9EE9B48273B453D958DCD4158B789A7"><header>General Provisions—This Title</header></appropriations-major> <section id="H9274E2DE706E437BB0E30B54DB6D2E30"><enum>601.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency may provide assistance, pursuant to section 428 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.), for critical services as defined in section 406 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act for the duration of the recovery for incidents DR–4336–PR, DR–4339–PR, DR–4340–USVI, and DR–4335–USVI to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1354029FB8F14A4AAAC93B3129B9AE00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>replace or restore the function of a facility or system to industry standards without regard to the pre-disaster condition of the facility or system; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB195CF694F448AEBD1FF68754B2EBD2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>replace or restore components of the facility or system not damaged by the disaster where necessary to fully effectuate the replacement or restoration of disaster-damaged components to restore the function of the facility or system to industry standards.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HF05EF2EEF571428DAAC8A7FBAA574AFC"><enum>602.</enum> 
<subsection id="H59C8FB7D619542DF9D42A0E8FA28A483" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of assistance, including direct Federal assistance, provided under section 407 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5173">42 U.S.C. 5173</external-xref>), with respect to a major disaster declared pursuant to such Act for damages resulting from a wildfire in calendar year 2017, shall be 90 percent of the eligible costs under such section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF844AC5A93CD4603A33CD47D8829CC58"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share provided by subsection (a) shall apply to assistance provided before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></title> 
<title id="H195184F2556D49258E0FD04F4347E14B"><enum>VII</enum><appropriations-major id="HA6D743401C364BA6BC9CFE4B89CB11C6"><header>Department of the Interior</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H72A968ADDA7B4DBAA10EFF789947E428"><header>Fish and wildlife service</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HAC345E5DA2374B12AE3AD6883AEC3D34"><header>construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Construction</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $210,629,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H517CFEC7D4B6498CA9EBBD1C349CA8D5"><header>National park service</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H329B9C4549E14D77AC9E061D3D601998"><header>Historic preservation fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for the <quote>Historic Preservation Fund</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $17,500,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019, including costs to States necessary to complete compliance activities required by section 306108 of title 54, United States Code (formerly section 106 of the National Historic Preservation Act), and costs needed to administer the program: <italic>Provided</italic>, That grants shall only be available for areas that have received a major disaster declaration pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That individual grants shall not be subject to a non-Federal matching requirement: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HDCCB690E1CE24CF1B5665808D02D0028"><header>Construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Construction</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $207,600,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H177685D3DF334D3A815F41349B408593"><header>United states geological survey</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H4015FD14D2AA4EB1AF56490FB4EECF3D"><header>Surveys, investigations, and research</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Surveys, Investigations, and Research</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, and in those areas impacted by a major disaster declared pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.) with respect to wildfires in 2017, $42,246,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H1E5352AF73664E68A41BD151598126B5"><header>Departmental offices</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HCCF893C6646249C9A9955FE10FAE44C8"><header>Insular affairs</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H5D328A2A51DB49C295F078622A38C05D"><header>Assistance to territories</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Technical Assistance</quote> for financial management expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Irma and Maria, $3,000,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H6DD91526F71B4A0C984A3208BB23E122"><header>Office of inspector general</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H613FC59DF4F14832A6D79137C56D94DA"><header>Salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Salaries and Expenses</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $2,500,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="H89C80D6866C048DDA8284AA0323F4EA5"><header>Environmental Protection Agency</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="HCBE1FC7166314F17A5A6519E127CF5B3"><header>Hazardous Substance Superfund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Hazardous Substance Superfund</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $6,200,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H22C21408B5454607BBC2F18FE821FD20"><header>Leaking underground storage tank fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Leaking Underground Storage Tank Fund</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $7,000,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-major id="HD2B763F96FE1400C8F8EB482BC162BB0"><header>Department of Agriculture</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="HE639772596544E3BB6064F79EC611574"><header>FOREST SERVICE</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H3D0666ED72A54C1789E39DDE3739D8F0"><header>State and private forestry</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>State and Private Forestry</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $7,500,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H4A1574B0D4594449BE3571FF56218464"><header>National forest system</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>National Forest System</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, $20,652,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H235E66D75B5B4D41BF9DB22CBEBB48E2"><header>Capital improvement and maintenance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Capital Improvement and Maintenance</quote> for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, and the 2017 fire season, $91,600,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="HDDF6625A2C4E44BE9E4DDF52D0E94870"><header>General Provision—This Title</header></appropriations-major> <section id="H210E90BA2146401E9512F141980E5502" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>701.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Agencies receiving funds appropriated by this title shall each provide a monthly report to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate detailing the allocation and obligation of these funds by account, beginning not later than 90 days after enactment of this Act.</text> </section></title> 
<title id="H399116908DA340FCB19F344DEB4178C0"><enum>VIII</enum><appropriations-major id="H87266AD0C09E4EDD9F33EB9796A4DCC1"><header>Department of Labor</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H0C617122796646B4A164B1F1FE9553C9"><header>Employment and Training Administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HEFEA931C40F84B4BA11B3C60658D0230"><header>Training and Employment Services</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H2C16B2D2087C41438BA7AC0821092484"><header>(Including Transfers of Funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Training and Employment Services</quote>, $30,000,000, for the dislocated workers assistance national reserve for necessary expenses directly related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Maria, and Irma or the calendar year 2017 wildfires with major disaster or emergency declarations under titles IV or V of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act in calendar year 2017, which shall remain available until September 30, 2019: <italic>Provided</italic>, That these sums may be used to replace grant funds previously obligated to the impacted areas: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H6F8DA0A24F004719B2D25D5A37215061"><header>Job Corps</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Job Corps</quote> for construction, rehabilitation and acquisition for Job Corps Centers in Puerto Rico, $30,900,000, which shall be available through June 30, 2021: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="HCCB5C26B1FD64B77A1837BB3285D3218"><header>Department of Health and Human Services</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H0312A1AB1EF64AAEA19ADF92959F328C"><header>Centers for disease control and prevention</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H16AE313DA5614BA0BEE97CBF8D226635"><header>Cdc-wide activities and program support</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H73943ADAB36F490285DB9FEC1F898E0C"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>CDC-Wide Activities and Program Support</quote>, $200,000,000, to remain available until expended, for response, recovery, preparation, mitigation, and other expenses directly related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, or Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That obligations incurred for the purposes provided herein prior to the date of enactment of this Act may be charged to funds appropriated by this paragraph: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the amount provided, not less than $6,000,000 shall be transferred to the <quote>Buildings and Facilities</quote> account for the purposes provided herein: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H33B410F392B74E899748CAC6DD2B6A5C"><header>Office of the secretary</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H103AC7BAEA2E487B9F7FCD17D7B0DC6D"><header>Public health and social services emergency fund</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HF16A25E6AB904E42B5B9137F5D6D76A9"><header>(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for the <quote>Public Health and Social Services Emergency Fund</quote>, $177,000,000, to remain available until expended, for response, recovery, preparation, mitigation and other expenses directly related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, or Maria, including activities authorized under section 319(a) of the Public Health Service Act (referred to in this title as the <quote>PHS Act</quote>):<italic> Provided</italic>, That $60,000,000 shall be transferred to <quote>Health Resources and Services Administration—Primary Health Care</quote>, for expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, or Maria for disaster response and recovery, for the Health Centers Program under section 330 of the PHS Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That not less than $50,000,000, of amounts transferred under the preceding proviso, shall be available for alteration, renovation, construction, equipment, and other capital improvement costs as necessary to meet the needs of areas affected by Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, or Maria: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the time limitation in section 330(e)(3) of the PHS Act shall not apply to funds made available under the preceding proviso: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That not less than $20,000,000 shall be transferred to <quote>Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration—Health Surveillance and Program Support</quote> for grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements for behavioral health treatment, crisis counseling, and other related helplines, and for other similar programs to provide support to individuals impacted by Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, or Maria: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That up to $2,000,000 shall be transferred to <quote>Office of the Secretary—Office of Inspector General</quote> for oversight of activities responding to such hurricanes: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That obligations incurred for the purposes provided herein prior to the date of enactment of this Act may be charged to funds appropriated under this heading: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the funds appropriated in this paragraph, $15,000,000 shall be transferred to the <quote>National Institutes of Health—Office of the Director</quote> for the purposes provided in this paragraph: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That funds transferred to the National Institutes of Health for the purpose of supporting the repair or rebuilding of non-Federal biomedical or behavioral research facilities damaged as a result of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, or Maria shall be used to award grants or contracts for such purpose under section 404I of the Public Health Service Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That section 404I(c)(2) of such Act does not apply to the use of funds described in the preceding proviso: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That funds appropriated in this paragraph shall not be available for costs that are reimbursed by the Federal Emergency Management Agency, under a contract for insurance, or by self-insurance: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such additional amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HFA5F53220E5D4EA1BE98824DC7E54858"><header>Administration for children and families</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HBC846CC986AA4C9F986FA9D3B111A760"><header>Children and families services programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Children and Families Services Programs</quote>, $650,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2021, for Head Start programs, for necessary expenses directly related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, or Maria, including making payments under the Head Start Act: <italic> Provided</italic>, That none of the funds appropriated in this paragraph shall be included in the calculation of the <quote>base grant</quote> in subsequent fiscal years, as such term is defined in sections 640(a)(7)(A), 641A(h)(1)(B), or 645(d)(3) of the Head Start Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That funds appropriated in this paragraph are not subject to the allocation requirements of section 640(a) of the Head Start Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That funds appropriated in this paragraph shall not be available for costs that are reimbursed by the Federal Emergency Management Agency, under a contract for insurance, or by self-insurance: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That up to $10,000,000 shall be available for Federal administrative expenses: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That obligations incurred for the purposes provided herein prior to the date of enactment of this Act may be charged to funds appropriated under this heading: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such additional amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="HA80A524008B547A782A1A0B949FDCE4F"><header>Department of education</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H338417FD7E244BB4BDB2F8DAC8051ED9" commented="no"><header>Hurricane education recovery</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H9DF77302D79E4BCB878E1CD799E08995"><header>(Including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Hurricane Education Recovery</quote> for assisting in meeting the educational needs of individuals affected by Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, or Maria, or calendar year 2017 wildfires for which the President declared a major disaster or emergency under section 401 or 501 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5191">42 U.S.C. 5191</external-xref>) (referred to herein as a <quote>covered disaster or emergency</quote>), $2,900,000,000, to remain available through September 30, 2021:<italic> Provided</italic>, That such additional amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That—</text> <paragraph id="H1AC824480BC348AB81097603763621A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such funds shall be used—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA48BECD32540434383E20A2EC18EA35B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to make awards, which shall be available until expended, to eligible entities for immediate aid to restart school operations, in accordance with paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B778F6A76944475927249C30365E119"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for temporary emergency impact aid for displaced students, in accordance with paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAB1848E57C604869A3AD40EFC988FDE8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for emergency assistance to institutions of higher education and students attending institutions of higher education in an area directly affected by a covered disaster or emergency in accordance with paragraph (3);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCA11CE8C07F34C76A91DC4AC87BE1A55"><enum>(D)</enum><text>for payments to institutions of higher education to help defray the unexpected expenses associated with enrolling displaced students from institutions of higher education directly affected by a covered disaster or emergency, in accordance with paragraph (4); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFE4DD22512A64950B52869EA0A8AC309"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to provide assistance to local educational agencies serving homeless children and youth in accordance with paragraph (5);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF91F5F6E0D0E4C149949FC5AFFFB183F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">immediate aid to restart school operations and temporary emergency impact aid for displaced students described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1) shall be provided under the statutory terms and conditions that applied to assistance under sections 102 and 107 of title IV of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/148">Public Law 109–148</external-xref>, respectively, including the nondiscrimination provisions under section 107(m), except that such sections shall be applied so that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD61372F9DEAE46DEA049E4459FC70F8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each reference to a major disaster declared in accordance with section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>) shall be to a major disaster or emergency declared by the President in accordance with section 401 or 501, respectively, of such Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9DB5E45637D64B778F0F13B0C58E53BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each reference to Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita shall be a reference to a covered disaster or emergency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC7583B00C41E4F0C8530E101FA88B0FD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>each reference to August 22, 2005, when used in relation to a covered disaster or emergency, shall be to the date that is one week prior to the date on which the major disaster or emergency was declared for the area;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H356A655DFE964BEC8031680F204A3610"><enum>(D)</enum><text>each reference to the States of Louisiana, Mississippi, Alabama, and Texas shall be to the States or territories affected by a covered disaster or emergency, and each reference to the State educational agencies of Louisiana, Mississippi, Alabama, or Texas shall be a reference to the State educational agencies that serve the states or territories affected by a covered disaster or emergency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2FB012E5C234406BA711C7A1C7F4A4A9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>each reference to the 2005–2006 school year shall be to the 2017–2018 school year;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBE986375861A49A38FA4EEB54EC4E56C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the references in section 102(h)(1) of title IV of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/148">Public Law 109–148</external-xref> to the number of non-public elementary schools and secondary schools in the State shall be to the number of students in non-public elementary schools and secondary schools in the State, and the reference in such section to the 2003–2004 school year shall be to the most recent data set for the 2016–2017 school year;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE150C614D30A46CEBBA1522DCAE47B9F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>in determining the amount of immediate aid provided to restart school operations as described in section 102(b) of title IV of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/148">Public Law 109–148</external-xref>, the Secretary shall consider the number of students enrolled, during the 2016–2017 school year, in elementary schools and secondary schools that were closed as a result of a covered disaster or emergency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDC08B209C1D34C1BBDADFE24EB9C7B54"><enum>(H)</enum><text>in determining the amount of emergency impact aid that a State educational agency is eligible to receive under paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary shall, subject to section 107(d)(1)(B) of such title, provide—</text> 
<clause id="HA233B41514A84A3284A00EE2E5ABB585"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$9,000 for each displaced student who is an English learner, as that term is defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>);</text></clause> <clause id="H215AF205606B4C1F9401537372D19902"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$10,000 for each displaced student who is a child with disability (regardless of whether the child is an English learner); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6B3E2E71E8AA4572BC3570C54BB8C1B1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>$8,500 for each displaced student who is not a child with a disability or an English learner; and</text> <subclause id="H1025287C56874D19AA5BA82765C69D3A" indent="up2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>with respect to the emergency impact aid provided under paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary may modify the State educational agency and local educational agency application timelines in section 107(c) of such title;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H66BBD6C175A84E8881DC1B037DB72D13"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">up to $200,000,000 of the funds made available under this heading shall be for programs authorized under subpart 3 of part A and part C of title IV and part B of title VII of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087-51">20 U.S.C. 1087–51</external-xref> et seq., 1138 et seq.) for institutions located in an area affected by a covered disaster or emergency, and students enrolled in such institutions, except that—</text> <subparagraph id="H5F28BBD0F0D84BE1AF767DEC327AA06E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any requirements relating to matching, Federal share, reservation of funds, or maintenance of effort under such parts that would otherwise be applicable to that assistance shall not apply;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H98BCBC803E0746CFB79F1075333A94E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such assistance may be used for student financial assistance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59E6FF3703D64DF88C50AD9043D4176D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such assistance may also be used for faculty and staff salaries, equipment, student supplies and instruments, or any purpose authorized under the Higher Education Act of 1965, by institutions of higher education that are located in areas affected by a covered disaster or emergency; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB2A29DCA48D2452F91D51A868A05A18D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Secretary shall prioritize, to the extent possible, students who are homeless or at risk of becoming homeless as a result of displacement, and institutions that have sustained extensive damage, by a covered disaster or emergency;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC1C0081656C4E2986FE1D4CF5ADF206"><enum>(4)</enum><text>up to $120,000,000 of the funds made available under this heading shall be for payments to institutions of higher education to help defray the unexpected expenses associated with enrolling displaced students from institutions of higher education at which operations have been disrupted by a covered disaster or emergency, in accordance with criteria established by the Secretary and made publicly available;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H32A779E359B144A6AE954E3CCC28325D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$25,000,000 of the funds made available under this heading shall be available to provide assistance to local educational agencies serving homeless children and youths displaced by a covered disaster or emergency, consistent with section 723 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11431">42 U.S.C. 11431–11435</external-xref>) and with section 106 of title IV of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/148">Public Law 109–148</external-xref>, except that funds shall be disbursed based on demonstrated need and the number of homeless children and youth enrolled as a result of displacement by a covered disaster or emergency;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19B4B7E557E747C89B477351410C078A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>section 437 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232">20 U.S.C. 1232</external-xref>) and section 553 of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to activities under this heading;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H309FA300442E47B883A1BE6DBD572F76"><enum>(7)</enum><text>$4,000,000 of the funds made available under this heading, to remain available through September 30, 2021, shall be transferred to the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Education for oversight of activities supported with funds appropriated under this heading, and up to $3,000,000 of the funds made available under this heading, to remain available through September 30, 2019, shall be for program administration;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC1238E9414134FF8B13276E7A69E798A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>up to $35,000,000 of the funds made available under this heading shall be to carry out activities authorized under section 4631(b) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7281">20 U.S.C. 7281(b)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8B0C1A203E84B2CB4B6ED6F4F6E5B1C"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary may waive, modify, or provide extensions for certain requirements of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref> et seq.) for affected individuals, affected students, and affected institutions in covered disaster or emergency areas in the same manner as the Secretary was authorized to waive, modify, or provide extensions for certain requirements of such Act under provisions of subtitle B of title IV of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/148">Public Law 109–148</external-xref> for affected individuals, affected students, and affected institutions in areas affected by Hurricane Katrina and Hurricane Rita, except that the cost associated with any action taken by the Secretary under this paragraph is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></paragraph></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="HF58CE4C96D3840968C38D191311C557B"><header>General Provisions—This Title</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-small id="HC15E9600FE5D46D9B193C946AD89413C"><header>(Including Transfers of Funds)</header></appropriations-small> <section id="H81624231D06B496E94D09D8E1686F4CE"><enum>801.</enum> <subsection id="HF86748776AEE4DFFAA99FDE7A6C7BE90" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 133(b)(4) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, in States, as defined by section 3(56) of such Act, affected by Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria, a local board, as defined by section 3(33) of such Act, in a local area, as defined by section 3(32) of such Act, affected by such Hurricanes may transfer, if such transfer is approved by the Governor, up to 100 percent of the funds allocated to the local area for Program Years 2016 and 2017 for Youth Workforce Investment activities under paragraphs (2) or (3) of section 128(b) of such Act, for Adult employment and training activities under paragraphs (2)(A) or (3) of section 133(b) of such Act, or for Dislocated Worker employment and training activities under paragraph (2)(B) of section 133(b) of such Act among—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE1FC0FF2E99D4F1491CC9E31170B97D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>adult employment and training activities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB3462E896804852872939222D86C05F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>dislocated worker employment and training activities; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H923ADFB7943C4ED9BD27B60BB1B6EAC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>youth workforce investment activities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0CE6250E168F45748F949152113F1AB5" indent="up1"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Except for the funds reserved to carry out required statewide activities under sections 127(b) and 134(a)(2) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, the Governor of the United States Virgin Islands may authorize the transfer of up to 100 percent of the remaining funds provided to the United States Virgin Islands for Program Years 2016 and 2017 for Youth Workforce Investment activities under section 127(b)(1)(B) of such Act, for Adult employment and training activities under section 132(b)(1)(A) of such Act, or for Dislocated Worker employment and training activities under section 133(b)(2)(A)) of such Act among—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE88AE0B974CF413BAF850598257D1C16"><enum>(1)</enum><text>adult employment and training activities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A1A956C118C455995C79AA26BCE0AA4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>dislocated worker employment and training activities; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H22B1488BCDCC4DF8B022A682E786DC6D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>youth workforce investment activities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HBC806A9E00354836B0F2CC7FC35D005F"><enum>802.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds appropriated by this title may be transferred to, and merged with, other appropriation accounts under the headings <quote>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</quote> and <quote>Public Health and Social Services Emergency Fund</quote> for the purposes specified in this title following consultation with the Office of Management and Budget: <italic>Provided</italic>, That the Committees on Appropriations in the House of Representatives and the Senate shall be notified 10 days in advance of any such transfer: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That, upon a determination that all or part of the funds transferred from an appropriation are not necessary, such amounts may be transferred back to that appropriation: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That none of the funds made available by this title may be transferred pursuant to the authority in section 205 of division H of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/31">Public Law 115–31</external-xref> or section 241(a) of the PHS Act.</text></section> 
<section id="H79C1C80A0326424D93E007942423E4F0"><enum>803.</enum> 
<subsection id="HD09B4CF6BC314E47BB6BD089CBB46AEB" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines necessary to respond to a critical hiring need for emergency response positions, after providing public notice and without regard to the provisions of sections 3309 through 3319 of title 5, United States Code, the Secretary may appoint candidates directly to the following positions to perform critical work directly relating to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, or Maria:</text> <paragraph id="H17DB1AB65DA24056A309FE48D0BDDE44"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Intermittent disaster-response personnel in the National Disaster Medical System, under section 2812 of the PHS Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300hh-11">42 U.S.C. 300hh–11</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H363B555416E84A14A6D5E0509FFD4D85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Term or temporary appointments at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC580ED088BDD4A3EBB740540D27D54FA"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The authority under subsection (a) shall expire 270 days after the date of enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H15E6DB5474974A23872B899EB646CF6B"><enum>804.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the interest payment of the United States Virgin Islands that was due under section 1202(b)(1) of the Social Security Act on September 29, 2017, shall not be due until September 28, 2018, and no interest shall accrue on such amount through September 28, 2018. </text></section> <section id="HB61E9B9961CB4BFC9EEE1C8A033C7F9E"><enum>805.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Agencies receiving funds appropriated by this title shall each provide a monthly report to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate detailing the allocation and obligation of these funds by account, beginning not later than 90 days after enactment of this Act.</text> </section></title> 
<title id="HF222A2A1184E4509A0BE9802D04DC9AB"><enum>IX</enum><appropriations-intermediate id="HA84624ED3AF94811B5C2B13ABB4ECF69"><header>Government accountability office</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H6F5F138D6D8D4BF3B9CBD8B7C8AD2F3A"><header>Salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for the Government Accountability Office for <quote>Salaries and Expenses</quote>, $14,000,000, to remain available until expended, for audits and investigations relating to Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria and the calendar year 2017 wildfires: <italic>Provided</italic>, That not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, GAO shall submit to Congress a report describing the United States Virgin Island’s economic and disaster recovery plan that defines the priorities, goals, and expected outcomes of the recovery effort based on damage assessments prepared pursuant to Federal law: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That GAO shall report on the internal control plans that are in place to provide oversight of Federal disaster funds to be used in recovery activities in the United States Virgin Islands, identify any deficiencies in such plans, and provide recommendations to address noted deficiencies: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small> </title> <title id="HA41DA038E8384D059DB52D3B13942C93"><enum>X</enum><appropriations-major id="H418CB05023C4450FBDB8B3382DFC8EB2"><header>Department of Defense</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-major id="H5E55716094A64D95882B0ADB04640F45"><header>Military Construction</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H1E7A8B3D117146CFA58CF70AFC64F85F"><header>Military Construction, Navy and Marine Corps</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Military Construction, Navy and Marine Corps</quote>, $201,636,000, to remain available until September 30, 2022, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That none of the funds made available to the Navy and Marine Corps for recovery efforts related to Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria in this division shall be available for obligation until the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate receive form 1391 for each specific request: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That, not later than 60 days after enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Navy, or his designee, shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of House of Representatives and the Senate a detailed expenditure plan for funds provided under this heading: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such funds may be obligated or expended for planning and design and military construction projects not otherwise authorized by law: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H74F1927910C448C497B25CF7A6CC5B37"><header>Military Construction, Army National Guard</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Military Construction, Army National Guard</quote>, $519,345,000, to remain available until September 30, 2022, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That none of the funds made available to the Army National Guard for recovery efforts related to Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria in this division shall be available for obligation until the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate receive form 1391 for each specific request: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That, not later than 60 days after enactment of this Act, the Director of the Army National Guard, or his designee, shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a detailed expenditure plan for funds provided under this heading: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such funds may be obligated or expended for planning and design and military construction projects not otherwise authorized by law: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-major id="H363B24DDB0F148AE9FA4F00E36AD92C1"><header>Department of Veterans Affairs</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-major id="H43D870C147BE461A9483453775C1C5E9"><header>Veterans Health Administration</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H29BFFE4F537147DB93A6CD3B2CD4C51C"><header>Medical Services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Medical Services</quote>, $11,075,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H317473E3F8D64EA18118C717D416F7BD"><header>Medical Support and Compliance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> For an additional amount for <quote>Medical Support and Compliance</quote>, $3,209,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H0207E30A3B7C49648903A7090FBE4390"><header>Medical Facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> For an additional amount for <quote>Medical Facilities</quote>, $75,108,000, to remain available until September 30, 2022, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That none of these funds shall be available for obligation until the Secretary of Veterans Affairs submits to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a detailed expenditure plan for funds provided under this heading: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HBD26BE4E532A463C857B94F20F3CA7F2"><header>Departmental Administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HE0F2CA99487E41CA8283D2C261474729"><header>Construction, Minor Projects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Construction, Minor Projects</quote>, $4,088,000, to remain available until September 30, 2022, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-major id="HB940C0D1CC6E46A0994B3DB98F0B3A95"><header>General Provision—This Title</header></appropriations-major> <section id="HFD8BC018846E402CAB9E6730724AF06F"><enum>1001.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 18236(b) of title 10, United States Code, the Secretary of Defense shall contribute to Puerto Rico 100 percent of the total cost of construction (including the cost of architectural, engineering and design services) for the acquisition, construction, expansion, rehabilitation, or conversion of the Arroyo readiness center under paragraph (5) of section 18233(a) of title 10, United States Code.</text> </section></title> 
<title id="H8CB274B36D4246FE8273939AC1627FF2"><enum>XI</enum><appropriations-major id="H649A0727C3D7470398FDC8044D8C98ED"><header>Department of Transportation</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H6148E485ACF34AF3A106E47EFCADA3CF"><header>Federal aviation administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H661E77F1044A4BE39E6C02DAF987B6EC"><header>Operations</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H92047EE3DF6D445D97D9EAD31BC83DB4"><header>(airport and airway trust fund) </header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Operations</quote>, $35,000,000, to be derived from the Airport and Airway Trust Fund and to remain available until expended, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of hurricanes occurring in calendar year 2017: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HBCB8E1C32A5A429BAFE111027CDBA436"><header>Facilities and equipment</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H25C546C0296F49B2A4FE4D2CC3E1EC8C"><header>(airport and airway trust fund) </header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Facilities and Equipment</quote>, $79,589,000, to be derived from the Airport and Airway Trust Fund and to remain available until expended, for necessary expenses related to the consequences of hurricanes occurring in calendar year 2017: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H5EFA2E4A8D864374B4BFD1B9B6A1EF4C"><header>Federal highway administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HA403A14596C1426086B9377BB0FE8295"><header>Federal-aid highways</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H1BA55E2034CA41369B286A6E864D9E54"><header>Emergency relief program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for the Emergency Relief Program as authorized under section 125 of title 23, United States Code, $1,374,000,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That notwithstanding section 125(d)(4) of title 23, United States Code, no limitation on the total obligations for projects under section 125 of such title shall apply to the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands for fiscal year 2018 and fiscal year 2019: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That notwithstanding section 120(i)(1) of title 23, United States Code, for fiscal year 2018 and each fiscal year thereafter, Puerto Rico may use toll credits toward the non-Federal share requirement for emergency relief funds made available under section 125 of such title to respond to damage caused by Hurricanes Irma and Maria: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amounts are designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H71B1FAD8686046FE9F95F86891DAA68C"><header>Federal transit administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H078A73C3813C427BB40A4167853D945E"><header>Public transportation emergency relief program </header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the <quote>Public Transportation Emergency Relief Program</quote> as authorized under section 5324 of title 49, United States Code, $269,000,000 to remain available until expended, for transit systems affected by Hurricanes Harvey, Irma, and Maria with major disaster declarations in 2017: <italic>Provided</italic>, That not more than three-quarters of one percent of the funds for public transportation emergency relief shall be available for administrative expenses and ongoing program management oversight as authorized under sections 5334 and 5338(f)(2) of such title and shall be in addition to any other appropriations for such purpose: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amounts are designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H5EC74AF409B847108F1AA25542D3E299"><header>Maritime administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H6B57118B1F1B44B28ACFF0AE0BB42BA2"><header>Operations and training</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Operations and Training</quote>, $10,000,000, to remain available until expended, for necessary expenses, including for dredging, related to damage to Maritime Administration facilities resulting from Hurricane Harvey: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="H3ACA6E5D19EF41358D6F7F0CD5AA35C2"><header>Department of Housing and Urban Development</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H2F9DD99875954E6AA224CC9332EC5DBE"><header>Community planning and development</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HBFF5C2BF4C1445BCA50CEF7167022011"><header>Community development fund</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HCC0E39ADB18948CDB92B1206943CC737"><header>(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for <quote>Community Development Fund</quote>, $26,060,000,000, to remain available until expended, for necessary expenses for activities authorized under title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5301">42 U.S.C. 5301</external-xref> et seq.) related to disaster relief, long-term recovery, restoration of infrastructure and housing, economic revitalization, and mitigation in the most impacted and distressed areas resulting from a major disaster declared in 2017 (except as otherwise provided under this heading) pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.): <italic>Provided</italic>, That funds shall be awarded directly to the State, unit of general local government, or Indian tribe (as such term is defined in section 102 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974) at the discretion of the Secretary: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the amounts made available under this heading, up to $13,560,000,000 shall be allocated to meet unmet needs for grantees that have received or will receive allocations for major disasters declared in 2017, and that such allocations shall include the States and units of local government affected by Hurricane Maria: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the amounts made available under this heading, no less than $12,500,000,000 shall be allocated for mitigation activities to all grantees of funding provided under this heading, the same heading in chapter 9 of title X of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/2">Public Law 113–2</external-xref>, section 420 of division L of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref>, section 145 of division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/223">Public Law 114–223</external-xref>, section 192 of division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/223">Public Law 114–223</external-xref> (as added by section 101(3) of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/254">Public Law 114–254</external-xref>), section 421 of division K of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/31">Public Law 115–31</external-xref>, and the same heading in division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/56">Public Law 115–56</external-xref>, and that such mitigation activities shall be subject to the same terms and conditions of this heading, as determined by the Secretary: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That all such grantees shall receive an allocation of funds under the preceding proviso in the same proportion that the amount of funds each grantee received or will receive under the second proviso of this heading or the headings and sections specified in the previous proviso bears to the amount of all funds provided to all grantees specified in the previous proviso: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the amounts made available under the second and third provisos of this heading, the Secretary shall allocate to all such grantees an aggregate amount of not less than 33 percent of each such amount of funds provided under this heading within 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act based on the best available data: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the Secretary shall not prohibit the use of funds made available under this heading and the same heading in division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/56">Public Law 115–56</external-xref> for non-federal share as authorized by section 105(a)(9) of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5305">42 U.S.C. 5305(a)(9)</external-xref>): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the amounts made available under this heading, grantees may establish grant programs to assist small businesses to recover from economic losses: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That as a condition of making any grant, the Secretary shall certify in advance that such grantee has in place proficient financial controls and procurement processes and has established adequate procedures to prevent any duplication of benefits as defined by section 312 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5155">42 U.S.C. 5155</external-xref>), to ensure timely expenditure of funds, to maintain comprehensive websites regarding all disaster recovery activities assisted with these funds, and to detect and prevent waste, fraud, and abuse of funds: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the Secretary shall require grantees to maintain on a public website information containing common reporting criteria established by the Department that permits individuals and entities awaiting assistance and the general public to see how all grant funds are used, including copies of all relevant procurement documents, grantee administrative contracts and details of ongoing procurement processes, as determined by the Secretary: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That prior to the obligation of funds a grantee shall submit a plan to the Secretary for approval detailing the proposed use of all funds, including criteria for eligibility and how the use of these funds will address long-term recovery, restoration of infrastructure and housing, economic revitalization, and mitigation in the most impacted and distressed areas: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such funds may not be used for activities reimbursable by, or for which funds are made available by, the Federal Emergency Management Agency or the Army Corps of Engineers: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That funds allocated under this heading shall not be considered relevant to the non-disaster formula allocations made pursuant to section 106 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5306">42 U.S.C. 5306</external-xref>): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That a State, unit of general local government, or Indian tribe may use up to 5 percent of its allocation for administrative costs: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the sixth proviso under this heading in the Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements, 2017 (division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/56">Public Law 115–56</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>State or subdivision thereof</quote> and inserting <quote>State, unit of general local government, or Indian tribe (as such term is defined in section 102 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5302">42 U.S.C. 5302</external-xref>))</quote>: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That in administering the funds under this heading, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may waive, or specify alternative requirements for, any provision of any statute or regulation that the Secretary administers in connection with the obligation by the Secretary or the use by the recipient of these funds (except for requirements related to fair housing, nondiscrimination, labor standards, and the environment), if the Secretary finds that good cause exists for the waiver or alternative requirement and such waiver or alternative requirement would not be inconsistent with the overall purpose of title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That, notwithstanding the preceding proviso, recipients of funds provided under this heading that use such funds to supplement Federal assistance provided under section 402, 403, 404, 406, 407, 408(c)(4), or 502 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.) may adopt, without review or public comment, any environmental review, approval, or permit performed by a Federal agency, and such adoption shall satisfy the responsibilities of the recipient with respect to such environmental review, approval or permit: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That, notwithstanding section 104(g)(2) of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5304">42 U.S.C. 5304(g)(2)</external-xref>), the Secretary may, upon receipt of a request for release of funds and certification, immediately approve the release of funds for an activity or project assisted under this heading if the recipient has adopted an environmental review, approval or permit under the preceding proviso or the activity or project is categorically excluded from review under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the Secretary shall publish via notice in the Federal Register any waiver, or alternative requirement, to any statute or regulation that the Secretary administers pursuant to title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 no later than 5 days before the effective date of such waiver or alternative requirement: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the eighth proviso under this heading in the Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements, 2017 (division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/56">Public Law 115–56</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>408(c)(4),</quote> after <quote>407,</quote>: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the amounts made available under this heading, up to $10,000,000 shall be made available for capacity building and technical assistance, including assistance on contracting and procurement processes, to support States, units of general local government, or Indian tribes (and their subrecipients) that receive allocations pursuant to this heading, received disaster recovery allocations under the same heading in <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/56">Public Law 115–56</external-xref>, or may receive similar allocations for disaster recovery in future appropriations Acts: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the amounts made available under this heading, up to $10,000,000 shall be transferred, in aggregate, to <quote>Department of Housing and Urban Development—Program Office Salaries and Expenses—Community Planning and Development</quote> for necessary costs, including information technology costs, of administering and overseeing the obligation and expenditure of amounts under this heading: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the amount specified in the preceding proviso shall be combined with funds appropriated under the same heading and for the same purpose in <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/56">Public Law 115–56</external-xref> and the aggregate of such amounts shall be available for any of the purposes specified under this heading or the same heading in <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/56">Public Law 115–56</external-xref> without limitation: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the funds made available under this heading, $10,000,000 shall be transferred to the Office of the Inspector General for necessary costs of overseeing and auditing funds made available under this heading:<italic> Provided further</italic>, That any funds made available under this heading that remain available, after the other funds under such heading have been allocated for necessary expenses for activities authorized under such heading, shall be used for additional activities, including mitigation, in the most impacted and distressed areas resulting from major disasters declared in 2011 and subsequent years:<italic>Provided further</italic>, That such remaining funds shall be awarded to grantees of funding provided for disaster relief under this heading, the same heading in chapter 9 of title X of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/2">Public Law 113–2</external-xref>, section 420 of division L of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref>, section 145 of division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/223">Public Law 114–223</external-xref>, section 192 of division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/223">Public Law 114–223</external-xref> (as added by section 101(3) of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/254">Public Law 114–254</external-xref>), section 421 of division K of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/31">Public Law 115–31</external-xref>, and the same heading in division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/56">Public Law 115–56</external-xref>, subject to the same terms and conditions under this heading and such headings and sections respectively: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That each such grantee shall receive an allocation from such remaining funds in the same proportion that the amount of funds such grantee received under the second proviso under this heading and under the Acts specified in the previous proviso bears to the amount of all funds provided to all grantees specified in the previous proviso: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such amount is designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</text></appropriations-small> </title> <title id="HD700B058BD894048A71C5563D6B80021" style="appropriations"><enum>XII</enum><appropriations-major id="H210A9D34A0A348BF82761000C0EFC529"><header>General Provisions—This Division</header></appropriations-major> <section id="HA607CAA5A2D24CA78D1AB0D930F60A92"><enum>1201.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each amount appropriated or made available by this division is in addition to amounts otherwise appropriated for the fiscal year involved.</text></section> 
<section id="H68195D046A264EB0BAE3BE6509EB6B4D"><enum>1202.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No part of any appropriation contained in this division shall remain available for obligation beyond the current fiscal year unless expressly so provided herein.</text></section> <section id="HDC6327555CDE4DC284CA4CBC1F109A78"><enum>1203.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Unless otherwise provided for by this division, the additional amounts appropriated by this division to appropriations accounts shall be available under the authorities and conditions applicable to such appropriations accounts for fiscal year 2018.</text></section> 
<section id="H4827FB448669461EB07AF51B60CF5610"><enum>1204.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms and conditions applicable to the funds provided in this division, including those provided by this title, shall also apply to the funds made available in division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/56">Public Law 115–56</external-xref> and in division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/72">Public Law 115–72</external-xref>.</text></section> <section id="H0D94442702E947129EABABD5535F82A6"><enum>1205.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each amount designated in this division by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 shall be available only if the President subsequently so designates all such amounts and transmits such designations to the Congress.</text></section> 
<section id="H09B06696804C4B02A653FA247B1E08B4" commented="no"><enum>1206.</enum> 
<subsection id="H31D7E2AEEF31415FAA4C41CC4016D554" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 305 of division A of the Additional Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements Act, 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/72">Public Law 115–72</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H717966B59D434827AC8E9D28C5BAE1EB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDF3132AC785E40C4A55DA50B858FB15A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(1) Not later than December 31, 2017,</quote> and inserting <quote>Not later than March 31, 2018,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBBB8455BCFC14532917A64BEDA865D37" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A69D5A1D7CE4FA9830F24C2E2A19645" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>receiving funds under this division</quote> and inserting <quote>expending more than $10,000,000 of funds provided by this division and division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/56">Public Law 115–56</external-xref> in any one fiscal year</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF493D7751B4B481D8AC922BFEE7CFE84" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Section 305 of division A of the Additional Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements Act, 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/72">Public Law 115–72</external-xref>), as amended by this section, shall apply to funds appropriated by this division as if they had been appropriated by that division.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCBD16DC6F1FC469AB353F337C94602A0" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><text>In order to proactively prepare for oversight of future disaster relief funding, not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall issue standard guidance for Federal agencies to use in designing internal control plans for disaster relief funding. This guidance shall leverage existing internal control review processes and shall include, at a minimum, the following elements:</text> <paragraph id="H2F8E290B2D3C4D788F297735BD5E311B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Robust criteria for identifying and documenting incremental risks and mitigating controls related to the funding.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C01048D0A284D3F82C2B24F12DECE45" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Guidance for documenting the linkage between the incremental risks related to disaster funding and efforts to address known internal control risks.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H0C16FBF29E1945508BE5C9A5D4AFED74"><enum>1207.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any agency or department provided funding in excess of $3,000,000,000 by this division, including the Federal Emergency Management Agency, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and the Corps of Engineers, is directed to provide a report to the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives regarding its efforts to provide adequate resources and technical assistance for small, low-income communities affected by natural disasters.</text></section> 
<section id="HB04A0CFADF7941768D11BF15094830AA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>1208.</enum> 
<subsection id="H1F9232F2F3364AB6879E229E95C7A64E" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act and in coordination with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, with support and contributions from the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Energy, and other Federal agencies having responsibilities defined under the National Disaster Recovery Framework, the Governor of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico shall submit to Congress a report describing the Commonwealth's 12- and 24-month economic and disaster recovery plan that—</text> <paragraph id="HB767C4EF1201437A9144DB643915199E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>defines the priorities, goals, and expected outcomes of the recovery effort for the Commonwealth, based on damage assessments prepared pursuant to Federal law, if applicable, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0B3E71BC144548699FF549DCF2DF1804"><enum>(A)</enum><text>housing;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4DF5E9CE4F3E40AD96F15038E991DFB2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>economic issues, including workforce development and industry expansion and cultivation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H045D1A19CD504080A854DA88F2A1E9D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>health and social services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9688F7265C8541E49478D22DE7D2F79A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>natural and cultural resources;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE2E40C2DBE1F46279610976604183FB8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>governance and civic institutions;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C2590E977EC4FF787B96B42C07FD0CB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>electric power systems and grid restoration;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H211E45D75DB545279E5FD4F21595ECD4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>environmental issues, including solid waste facilities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2C9E5F2A4EA344A3B359814E26EF8609"><enum>(H)</enum><text>other infrastructure systems, including repair, restoration, replacement, and improvement of public infrastructure such water and wastewater treatment facilities, communications networks, and transportation infrastructure;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0AAE6DD7B6C243BBB48282A7FE484346"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is consistent with—</text> <subparagraph id="HB99752FE4CF044B6849DDE00FDFF725B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Commonwealth’s fiscal capacity to provide long-term operation and maintenance of rebuilt or replaced assets;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9AA1A9944D5540ED9E4E389D7D48FDA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>alternative procedures and associated programmatic guidance adopted by the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Administration pursuant to section 428 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5189f">42 U.S.C. 5189f</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8701C74A627A4A1C9073B0CBAE1E76F5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>actions as may be necessary to mitigate vulnerabilities to future extreme weather events and natural disasters and increase community resilience, including encouraging the adoption and enforcement of the latest published editions of relevant consensus-based codes, specifications, and standards that incorporate the latest hazard-resistant designs and establish minimum acceptable criteria for the design, construction, and maintenance of residential structures and facilities for the purpose of protecting the health, safety, and general welfare of the buildings’ users against disasters;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54F06EEEDD2C467C8D26A62075863213"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promotes transparency and accountability through appropriate public notification, outreach, and hearings;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEFA9D3743E0E424EAB355A0D5DB8383E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identifies performance metrics for assessing and reporting on the progress toward achieving the Commonwealth’s recovery goals, as identified under paragraph (1); </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H623CEBDA31CB4472BB9AA032F03BB4FE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>is developed in coordination with the Oversight Board established under PROMESA; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDDCF2444349B428B87AE0C8AE947D421"><enum>(6)</enum><text>is certified by that Oversight Board to be consistent with the purpose set forth in section 101(a) of PROMESA (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/2121">48 U.S.C. 2121(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8CE6EB39A2544DC087B6EDF5A3C877FC"><enum>(b)</enum><text>At the end of every 30-day period before the submission of the report described in subsection (a), the Governor of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, in coordination with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, shall provide to Congress interim status updates on progress developing such report.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H98AACEB848BF4A2683C2AA1506B84032"><enum>(c)</enum><text>At the end of every 180-day period after the submission of the report described in subsection (a), the Governor of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, in coordination with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, shall make public a report on progress achieving the goals set forth in such report.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA2CFA67EE119454DA82F07BAD3745937"><enum>(d)</enum><text>During the development, and after the submission, of the report require by in subsection (a), the Oversight Board may provide to Congress reports on the status of coordination with the Governor of Puerto Rico.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBCE978644CBE4C0A8B10BF86057EAD23" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><text>Amounts made available by this division to a covered territory for response to or recovery from Hurricane Irma or Hurricane Maria in an aggregate amount greater than $10,000,000 may be reviewed by the Oversight Board under the Oversight Board’s authority under 204(b)(2) of PROMESA (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/2144">48 U.S.C. 2144(b)(2)</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H75067C22383E460FBD34C26F870B2EC9"><enum>(f)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When developing a Fiscal Plan while the recovery plan required under subsection (a) is in development and in effect, the Oversight Board shall use and incorporate, to the greatest extent feasible, damage assessments prepared pursuant to Federal law.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD38169321D0B4020B8A42623CC16FBB9"><enum>(g)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the terms <term>covered territory</term> and <quote>Oversight Board</quote> have the meaning given those term in section 5 of PROMESA (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/2104">48 U.S.C. 2104</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB5281898F3B14F72AAD0043CA7EF63CB" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This division may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Further Additional Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Requirements, 2017</short-title></quote>. </text></section> </title></division> <division id="HAA21D9B13B5144FA854EA9A3EFB5F30E" style="OLC"><enum>B</enum><header>Disaster Recovery Reform Act</header> <section id="HEEEF36E173294A5FA3CF5D035890DCC2" section-type="undesignated-section"> <toc container-level="division-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="HAA21D9B13B5144FA854EA9A3EFB5F30E" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> <toc-entry idref="H45D2FD1AA7634A8EB8B0F1E538A60131" level="section">Sec. 2001. Applicability.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H5F23A84B54A54B839756E3FF1597CA09" level="section">Sec. 2002. State defined.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H2B2270009E2F478A82D7FE76A9D1A72F" level="section">Sec. 2003. Wildfire prevention.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H667DFC325CF146F5972DF008D4680043" level="section">Sec. 2004. Additional activities.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H5691A7E4173A4F6FB6B18251D31CF39B" level="section">Sec. 2005. Eligibility for code implementation and enforcement.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H07ADA206633E4338A6F4205FEE782A8C" level="section">Sec. 2006. Program improvements.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H88851D5304D54F25894E25C05D55F0DA" level="section">Sec. 2007. Prioritization of facilities.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HA99328DFEE5B4F9DB1A9BB4BCF352821" level="section">Sec. 2008. Guidance on evacuation routes.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H18FBFF7AA7CC4919BD1B344AED8C32F6" level="section">Sec. 2009. Duplication of benefits.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H57B7828BFA004EB4B8AB762BFD6F62ED" level="section">Sec. 2010. State administration of assistance for direct temporary housing and permanent housing construction.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H8372D15F71EE4F089F2FD37D833CBE2F" level="section">Sec. 2011. Assistance to individuals and households.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HCB7A707DF2674E31BD8258E9DB8E9F3E" level="section">Sec. 2012. Multifamily lease and repair assistance.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HBAB8CE053CAE4889B7307EEB671CFC27" level="section">Sec. 2013. Federal disaster assistance nonprofit fairness.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H8E4107247FE4432A9ABB57494E040A1D" level="section">Sec. 2014. Management costs.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H643C1FDD8BEB4799A3D69A208B8E708A" level="section">Sec. 2015. Flexibility.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HD425898474704C0CAB1BC0D53E57D661" level="section">Sec. 2016. Additional disaster assistance.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H65C37C0A5292446E9EC950E9D49D2988" level="section">Sec. 2017. National veterinary emergency teams.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HA8A1D0E5FB2D43D6B579ECF1D9CF152C" level="section">Sec. 2018. Dispute resolution pilot program.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H32199A6E64514A5DB3092DDA84175581" level="section">Sec. 2019. Emergency relief.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HD6424A6BBEB64570A840D12D9AB63B6C" level="section">Sec. 2020. Unified Federal environmental and historic preservation review.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H4DC1BF933BDB42AC918602628C944DD8" level="section">Sec. 2021. Closeout incentives.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HF5F2EBD6C8EF4A60AC665D3EB2F9DC2D" level="section">Sec. 2022. Performance of services.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H5115CA4405714B15ADAE0B893EAF3A71" level="section">Sec. 2023. Study to streamline and consolidate information collection.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H97426D372ABE4635B8C27AB1D0DC487A" level="section">Sec. 2024. Agency accountability.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H84C64E1F3CF74051A43C3A4B3A478B1C" level="section">Sec. 2025. Audit of contracts.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H915073D78C1F46349F2538EEC7F0E1C5" level="section">Sec. 2026. Inspector general audit of FEMA contracts for tarps and plastic sheeting.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HEA81EED769734BFD9FF0F1B76D3AD4EC" level="section">Sec. 2027. Relief organizations.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H682AC0DA7D9644608EF211D9B2558C5A" level="section">Sec. 2028. Guidance on inundated and submerged roads.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H5F3B12481D404A4BA0DF4F8A3F54CBAF" level="section">Sec. 2029. Authorities.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H8719B9C3AF694D28B2643A83F9079884" level="section">Sec. 2030. Recoupment of certain assistance prohibited.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HB1A3075C94724185921FE1BF62AA871F" level="section">Sec. 2031. Statute of limitations.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H1A5D92F76AA944DF88B8D4918199A4AB" level="section">Sec. 2032. Technical assistance and recommendations.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HEADCB51272E74E94B399BF8D5B296E77" level="section">Sec. 2033. Guidance on hazard mitigation assistance.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H42ED6DAEE35A48BBB2549D07214CDEBD" level="section">Sec. 2034. Local impact.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H60A31C5E507D45238B3AFA3EA32084A9" level="section">Sec. 2035. Additional hazard mitigation activities.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H2E2F92F70B7D42D3A38945217D9D45DD" level="section">Sec. 2036. National public infrastructure predisaster hazard mitigation.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HC1E722035C2F4F3290814A2B5148C1BE" level="section">Sec. 2037. Additional mitigation activities.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H76BE487260B34034BBE3E9F402FF7EA3" level="section">Sec. 2038. Federal cost-share adjustments for repair, restoration, and replacement of damaged facilities.</toc-entry> </toc></section> <section id="H45D2FD1AA7634A8EB8B0F1E538A60131" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2001.</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided, the amendments in this division to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.) apply to each major disaster and emergency declared by the President on or after August 1, 2017, under such Act.</text></section> 
<section id="H5F23A84B54A54B839756E3FF1597CA09"><enum>2002.</enum><header>State defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this division, the term <quote>State</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 102(4) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122(4)</external-xref>). </text></section> <section id="H2B2270009E2F478A82D7FE76A9D1A72F"><enum>2003.</enum><header>Wildfire prevention</header> <subsection id="H5773FA9054FA4E0AA7343DD41209F296"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mitigation assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 420 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5187">42 U.S.C. 5187</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBEFCA3ABA47243D8819793F7B3C3B168"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (e); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB4EEE2A9DA349518953647C545ECFB5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC82DB23557C246F3BFF5CE8586CDF25A" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H68A7741ACE5A4B03B47481D24EC454E4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Hazard mitigation assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether or not a major disaster is declared, the President may provide hazard mitigation assistance in accordance with section 404 in any area affected by a fire for which assistance was provided under this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3F1612B4F7B947919F3934C80F989D84"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>The Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H871E1462D6864E9382E1281A559E496D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 404(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170c">42 U.S.C. 5170c(a)</external-xref>) (as amended by section 37(a) of this Act)—</text> <subparagraph id="H535FD57BF02E4E5FBBFEFEE5FAEECE80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting before the first period <quote>, or any area affected by a fire for which assistance was provided under section 420</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2431EED3576146268416F2449F54AE45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the third sentence by inserting <quote>or event under section 420</quote> after <quote>major disaster</quote> each place it appears; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4878EE0D71304D1280BDABED23B320BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 322(e)(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5165">42 U.S.C. 5165(e)(1)</external-xref>), by inserting <quote>or event under section 420</quote> after <quote>major disaster</quote> each place it appears.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6F9BD66F5C3346C2BC8C30924BBE5441"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, and the Appropriations Committees of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report containing a summary of any projects carried out, and any funding provided to those projects, under subsection (d) of section 420 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5187">42 U.S.C. 5187</external-xref>) (as amended by this section).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H667DFC325CF146F5972DF008D4680043"><enum>2004.</enum><header>Additional activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 404 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170c">42 U.S.C. 5170c</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HEC9FA4C242B14CDB925B2598B9EEEB52" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H43AA0DBA0D934CE18D37A974677A7C05"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of assistance</header><text>Recipients of hazard mitigation assistance provided under this section and section 203 may use the assistance to conduct activities to help reduce the risk of future damage, hardship, loss, or suffering in any area affected by a wildfire or windstorm, including—</text> <paragraph id="H9A6054EF1FA34B049DCA85941C2FEB0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reseeding ground cover with quick-growing or native species;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H28A6B0C8B9854EECA144850D919B042A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>mulching with straw or chipped wood;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C967651550E4810BE89083B06FDBBF1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>constructing straw, rock, or log dams in small tributaries to prevent flooding;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A51D6898A3941B5A125DBB0194FD02F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>placing logs and other erosion barriers to catch sediment on hill slopes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3484259A50C34B0BA5C80B5D7D9660F0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>installing debris traps to modify road and trail drainage mechanisms;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC937A905F5CB46F4B83CA24259B3B1F7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>modifying or removing culverts to allow drainage to flow freely;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6FC18D04A1C54FF78BB5F84815A44BF7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>adding drainage dips and constructing emergency spillways to keep roads and bridges from washing out during floods;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9921335A71247669BF9384361DCF485"><enum>(8)</enum><text>planting grass to prevent the spread of noxious weeds;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H283EEEBA79D94BBAA6FE7B59986CE261"><enum>(9)</enum><text>installing warning signs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H30E9B97300914B188CDAF5CC56001534"><enum>(10)</enum><text>establishing defensible space measures; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6C0805C73F44F3D9E48C1B2DADBD24C"><enum>(11)</enum><text>reducing hazardous fuels; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF926F36425194115BBFAA349E120E171"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">windstorm damage, including replacing or installing electrical transmission or distribution utility pole structures with poles that are resilient to extreme wind and combined ice and wind loadings for the basic wind speeds and ice conditions associated with the relevant location.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H5691A7E4173A4F6FB6B18251D31CF39B"><enum>2005.</enum><header>Eligibility for code implementation and enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 406(a)(2) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H56C2BAF1D8234A38A0F2F566501E25C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (B);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02D89C4569D841D8AA7A7E02474B778F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (C) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H398C1338A42348029E1AA4BC1FD15203"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57FD448F7CD64B8D9E860079040A6691" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H2EA6D5A1AEB049A6A13CB060003213C9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">base and overtime wages for extra hires to facilitate the implementation and enforcement of adopted building codes for a period of not more than 180 days after the major disaster is declared.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H07ADA206633E4338A6F4205FEE782A8C"><enum>2006.</enum><header>Program improvements</header> 
<subsection id="H04EFD22966B246C4BBBE1F6CB4D5C0DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Hazard Mitigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 406(c) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H1AAEB4065C0F46B4B47D6962027A676A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>90 percent of</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HC052B870ACB84D21A568952DCD450D76"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)(A), by striking <quote>75 percent of</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HD19B5AAB9AAF4D2CBB4C7BFC5A9F05AE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Participation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 428(d) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5189f">42 U.S.C. 5189f</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3034ED282AD240D8932343AA2733C633"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(1) <header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">In general.—</header-in-text></quote> before <quote>Participation in</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H79AAFF662C3F45C183329651CE2ADFCD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE210DE3FE6D4AF9BAB9E3C0BEFBA301" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H22A72C552FD940B3A2FB506BD587E2E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may not condition the provision of Federal assistance under this Act on the election by a State, Tribal, or local government, or owner or operator of a private nonprofit facility to participate in the alternative procedures adopted under this section.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HC8CC853999704FC98D968562A68C4B4D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 428(e)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5189f">42 U.S.C. 5189f(e)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB9259A1B292F4BE698B21FECD04FE6E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6A9CA5F861A42858BD3292D1364353B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H97419A6E9A744808AD276DF9BF2CFF31"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAEB0FB79ED1449D7857C5DE361BD273F" style="OLC"> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H60C58FA696ED4058953A98C93DD2EC05"><enum>(G)</enum><text>once certified by a professionally licensed engineer and accepted by the Administrator, the estimates on which grants made pursuant to this section are based shall be presumed to be reasonable and eligible costs, as long as there is no evidence of fraud.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H88851D5304D54F25894E25C05D55F0DA"><enum>2007.</enum><header>Prioritization of facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall provide guidance and training on an annual basis to State, Tribal, and local governments, first responders, and utility companies on—</text> <paragraph id="H53D7283AFCC948C78CEFBCBF879BD950"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the need to prioritize assistance to hospitals, nursing homes, and other long-term care facilities to ensure that such health care facilities remain functioning or return to functioning as soon as practicable during power outages caused by natural hazards, including severe weather events; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H282A545EB3594A0F8389FAE40FA699F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how hospitals, nursing homes and other long-term care facilities should adequately prepare for power outages during a major disaster or emergency.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HA99328DFEE5B4F9DB1A9BB4BCF352821"><enum>2008.</enum><header>Guidance on evacuation routes</header> <subsection id="HBEC36866AFE94804A80F49B9861E85D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="HCE28035F9B7B4BA28FD28EB98EDF0891"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Identification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, in coordination with the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration, shall develop and issue guidance for State, local, and Tribal governments regarding the identification of evacuation routes.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A7EFC1F5B3D4D4CB5995F2F5156D48F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration, in coordination with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, shall revise existing guidance or issue new guidance as appropriate for State, local, and Tribal governments regarding the design, construction, maintenance, and repair of evacuation routes.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFFF89A5B8C7C484983C0F9844AFB49DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header> <paragraph id="H4BCF3D98497448CE98245DD2A23BC925"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Identification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the guidance under subsection (a)(1), the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall consider—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFF670883673E4E45B7CE8A368998A7C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether evacuation routes have resisted impacts and recovered quickly from disasters, regardless of cause;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4416BCC4824A4E569BD62B22DBFCF6C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the need to evacuate special needs populations, including—</text> 
<clause id="H52CF3332FCC04776ACEEC4A2E0A0E3A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals with a physical or mental disability;</text></clause> <clause id="H2B29E64627B34D33BD6CD30DFF339384"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>individuals in schools, daycare centers, mobile home parks, prisons, nursing homes and other long-term care facilities, and detention centers;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFDCC9D97772C4B018169CE6B38284F2F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>individuals with limited-English proficiency;</text></clause> <clause id="HFBD8A18D8CA942409FFAA3FA1EE24BBC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the elderly; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF82002907F3A40AC89681B996FEE4A24"><enum>(v)</enum><text>individuals who are tourists, seasonal workers, or homeless;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDC75E2EE3F8C43F996CD20955E72F971"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the sharing of information and other public communications with evacuees during evacuations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H599345EC96574991ADEFD97D930670DA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the sheltering of evacuees, including the care, protection, and sheltering of animals;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H90FF88835E30447C8AA1B07E72B76D3D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the return of evacuees to their homes; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF6B45F461E204D109A5F201BB23F3EB2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>such other items the Administrator considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2334354C712F46B4AAE0D46046794B8C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Design, construction, maintenance, and repair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In revising or issuing guidance under (a)(2), the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration shall consider—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1E703E2FC3ED4D4C94128E3CBF83B05F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">methods that assist evacuation routes to—</text> <clause id="H521F98431BF24B6186B35DBD5BBB4967"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">withstand likely risks to viability, including flammability and hydrostatic forces;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3A491BEE7D1F4DFE85745A39D3331722"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improve durability, strength (including the ability to withstand tensile stresses and compressive stresses), and sustainability; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF37062B5913E490B963A84934DD5EB5F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide for long-term cost savings;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF41A7664AB004B1BAEBBC9DB19EBBF4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ability of evacuation routes to effectively manage contraflow operations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1D891BBB68C54F66815FF4BA44FD1C68"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for evacuation routes on public lands, the viewpoints of the applicable Federal land management agency regarding emergency operations, sustainability, and resource protection; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3F01E287203C4F19902CFFA67CAE2DC7"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other items the Administrator considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section commented="no" id="H18FBFF7AA7CC4919BD1B344AED8C32F6" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2009.</enum><header>Duplication of benefits</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H52C5F7988104435A9E461BF96B0249CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 312(b) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5155">42 U.S.C. 5155(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDEFD97EF9084437A9F1F54DDE3DF6632" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H322BEDCC673F4334B995DE80A2810F24"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Waiver of general prohibition</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H077322F2A5E14E819FFA86A30BB80BF8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may waive the general prohibition provided in subsection (a) upon request of a Governor on behalf of the State or on behalf of a person, business concern, or any other entity suffering losses as a result of a major disaster or emergency, if the President finds such waiver is in the public interest and will not result in waste, fraud, or abuse. In making this decision, the President may consider the following:</text> <clause commented="no" id="H2C25C4806BAF4D799829B28115F3F92C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The recommendations of the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency made in consultation with the Federal agency or agencies administering the duplicative program.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H6F8195056D29430E8F8BEE0599A1B17B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If a waiver is granted, the assistance to be funded is cost effective.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HA089E4235BE14709AF16AD897F3A878A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Equity and good conscience.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H8DE097EDF30A48959A757C71EAA92CF0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Other matters of public policy considered appropriate by the President.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H1F63A05177A340A3BA07F4E3F2B4F008"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Grant or denial of waiver</header><text>A request under subparagraph (A) shall be granted or denied not later than 45 days after submission of such request.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H7A77E00F338249DE83FCF5923E27346E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Prohibition on determination that loan is a duplication</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (c), in carrying out subparagraph (A), the President may not determine that a loan is a duplication of assistance, provided that all Federal assistance is used toward a loss suffered as a result of the major disaster or emergency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HE1B00C56A41D431F86DD35C89BA86906"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding of a federally authorized water resources development project</header> <paragraph id="H83F67559A1784FAF85402A3E10CA0438" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible activities</header><text>Notwithstanding section 312 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5155">42 U.S.C. 5155</external-xref>) and its implementing regulations, assistance provided pursuant to section 404 of such Act may be used to fund activities authorized for construction within the scope of a federally authorized water resources development project of the Army Corps of Engineers if such activities are also eligible activities under such section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H150D9F2A8AD744689F39D6F5F7639966" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal funding</header><text>All Federal funding provided under section 404 pursuant to this section shall be applied toward the Federal share of such project.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F47296149154569AA65384323A0590D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Non-Federal match</header><text>All non-Federal matching funds required under section 404 pursuant to this section shall be applied toward the non-Federal share of such project.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE115B1E39AB347DBAC45E6B836DEAD52" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Total Federal share</header><text>Funding provided under section 404 pursuant to this section may not exceed the total Federal share for such project.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0EA6F190420B47FD9E730B793E22FA1E" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>No effect</header><text>Nothing in this section shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC20D3BF6EA70480CAF6FC7FD41C5B414" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>affect the cost-share requirement of a hazard mitigation measure under section 404;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF77925D6DA247C4853E729249BCB119" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>affect the eligibility criteria for a hazard mitigation measure under section 404;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6748E0B4EB8443258553D98B9E27999D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>affect the cost share requirements of a federally authorized water resources development project; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H132FE0F897E240DFBFAC6933E09B37CE" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>affect the responsibilities of a non-Federal interest with respect to the project, including those related to the provision of lands, easements, rights-of-way, dredge material disposal areas, and necessary relocations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H57B7828BFA004EB4B8AB762BFD6F62ED"><enum>2010.</enum><header>State administration of assistance for direct temporary housing and permanent housing construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 408(f) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6E16B057C6A14DC4A08249E580AD7B2A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking the paragraph heading and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">State- or Tribal-administered assistance and other needs assistance.—</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1BFDDDC66F2C412DBCF7689EA96FD719"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A)—</text> <subparagraph id="H17A82E14C15D403CA1B4BB66B3837310"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>financial</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H68BACD50B36C46F19E504B4484491078"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (e)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (c)(1)(B), (c)(4), and (e) if the President and the State or Tribal government comply, as determined by the Administrator, with paragraph (3)</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF9389E9B367465D9BAC5B86CB2ED8D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9CABEB22B6AF47F9B87E0518723BFFDF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>financial</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE153E2A1B1FC4B508612CDED262C3D17"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>subsection (e)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (c)(1)(B), (c)(4), and (e)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8734809AE9C40B6A7FFDA0C4CF45BF7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB614DAB55F34E0192CEAE0ADE700413" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HABC8CB814D994A77B1661080A799FF85"><enum>(3)</enum><header>In general</header> <subparagraph id="H1AEC9C0C270D48A29C09182187F710BA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or Tribal government desiring to provide assistance under subsection (c)(1)(B), (c)(4), or (e) shall submit to the President an application for a grant to provide financial assistance under the program.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFC6519D545B04F7DBEBF791C97A661A9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President, in consultation and coordination with State, Tribal, and local governments, shall establish criteria for the approval of applications submitted under subparagraph (A). The criteria shall include, at a minimum—</text> <clause id="H6BB703C3567B43BCBEB78B7488AE2892"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the demonstrated ability of the State or Tribal government to manage the program under this section;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H632EA71363EF42C2B1B0427500104C9D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>there being in effect a plan approved by the President as to how the State or Tribal government will comply with applicable Federal laws and regulations and how the State or Tribal government will provide assistance under its plan;</text></clause> <clause id="H5BF26A26BEB149C7B56A90545ED28D96"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a requirement that the State, Tribal, or local government comply with rules and regulations established pursuant to subsection (j); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H96A5C0FCF355474DABCA815067A932FC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a requirement that the President, or the designee of the President, comply with subsection (i).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDFC51059F5B44FF892BB9C04EE95985F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Quality assurance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before approving an application submitted under this section, the President, or the designee of the President, shall institute adequate policies, procedures, and internal controls to prevent waste, fraud, abuse, and program mismanagement for this program and for programs under subsections (c)(1)(B), (c)(4), and (e). The President shall monitor and conduct quality assurance activities on a State or Tribal government’s implementation of programs under subsections (c)(1)(B), (c)(4), and (e). If, after approving an application of a State or Tribal government submitted under this section, the President determines that the State or Tribal government is not administering the program established by this section in a manner satisfactory to the President, the President shall withdraw the approval.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H133CE00767874D7791671008889A2327"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Audits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office of the inspector general shall provide for periodic audits of the programs administered by States and Tribal governments under this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0EB903DA8C1A455F92876CF1943E89C9"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Applicable laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All Federal laws applicable to the management, administration, or contracting of the programs by the Federal Emergency Management Agency under this section shall be applicable to the management, administration, or contracting by a non-Federal entity under this section.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCA17CCE10928450D90C0719EE008A248"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the inspector general of the Department of Homeland Security shall submit a report to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives on the State or Tribal government’s role to provide assistance under this section. The report shall contain an assessment of the effectiveness of the State or Tribal government’s role to provide assistance under this section, including—</text> <clause id="H63022B3A67FD45AA8437DBD753DE9715"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the State or Tribal government’s role helped to improve the general speed of disaster recovery;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H94F4524CCE6645DB9187196EA1762800"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the State or Tribal government providing assistance under this section had the capacity to administer this section; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0E2D3FA424634D2B8AD7055D3D258A14"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for changes to improve the program if the State or Tribal government’s role to administer the programs should be continued.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF9F0776DB83C4A028D34AC7511F7C93F"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may not condition the provision of Federal assistance under this Act by a State or Tribal government requesting a grant under this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6FFA0DF655614E619E597AADAB32AFB3"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Miscellaneous</header> <clause id="H39F750EDA42D4EB9889B4CCBBDB5B0FF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Notice and comment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may waive notice and comment rulemaking, if the Administrator determines doing so is necessary to expeditiously implement this section, and may carry out this section as a pilot program until such regulations are promulgated.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H029CEE2062054DAC9F3AA442F144A6CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Final Rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Administrator shall issue final regulations to implement this subsection as amended by the Disaster Recovery Reform Act.</text></clause> <clause id="HF81055A971594A1E869BFF707A9E032E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Waiver and expiration</header><text>The authority under clause (i) and any pilot program implemented pursuant to such clause shall expire 2 years after the date of enactment of this paragraph or upon issuance of final regulations pursuant to clause (ii), whichever occurs sooner.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H8372D15F71EE4F089F2FD37D833CBE2F"><enum>2011.</enum><header>Assistance to individuals and households</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 408(h) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174(h)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HED14A69ED5CA4629A6E44FF653D2B003"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>, excluding financial assistance to rent alternate housing accommodations under subsection (c)(1)(A)(i) and financial assistance to address other needs under subsection (e)</quote> after <quote>disaster</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H453460C684384D06A6605F2A24C56E73"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (2) as paragraph (3);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6925387857FF436D9B3CDC839B6B00E5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H3CDD430FCBA740AFB8580973197B9F82" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HC2755D95ABA842EE865ACFB710B9F7EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other needs assistance</header><text>The maximum financial assistance any individual or household may receive under subsection (e) shall be equivalent to the amount set forth in paragraph (1) with respect to a single major disaster.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC884003EF334C28AFE31E224BB9C712"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (3) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>paragraph (1)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (1) and (2)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB25D96E0D8640BA846D181E8A5CF136"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) (as so redesignated) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HBD0ABBFC4D9B44579E5EDB7240A8E91F" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H5DD1A2DCC18D4446AD21EB8EE317B729"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exclusion of necessary expenses for individuals with disabilities</header> <subparagraph id="H968A1196D5E54C01A8309BCEB0818933"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The maximum amount of assistance established under paragraph (1) shall exclude expenses to repair or replace damaged accessibility-related improvements under paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of subsection (c) for individuals with disabilities.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6302F7D9D5F04ED7A61E7B460A061930"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The maximum amount of assistance established under paragraph (2) shall exclude expenses to repair or replace accessibility-related personal property under subsection (e)(2) for individuals with disabilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="HCB7A707DF2674E31BD8258E9DB8E9F3E"><enum>2012.</enum><header>Multifamily lease and repair assistance</header> <subsection id="HDEADBCB8F117445CA13CE607244F1342"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Lease and repair of rental units for temporary housing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 408(c)(1)(B)(ii)(II) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174(c)(1)(B)(ii)(II)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7AA467957BF2497D88914B4518F418EB" style="OLC"> 
<subclause id="H46ECB446D1484E5E835AF74ABF13D4DB"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Improvements or repairs</header><text>Under the terms of any lease agreement for property entered into under this subsection, the value of the improvements or repairs shall be deducted from the value of the lease agreement.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HDC1606DDC1D749CEAD6BDB5A74D3CDE9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rental properties impacted</header><text>Section 408(c)(1)(B)(ii)(I)(aa) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C. 5174(c)(1)(B)(ii)(I)(aa)) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H719229C3E89445BCB4F5BB7CA2A0EEA7" style="OLC"> 
<item id="HD30806AB580B406C8938EDFB8CB66A27"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>enter into lease agreements with owners of multifamily rental property impacted by a major disaster or located in areas covered by a major disaster declaration to house individuals and households eligible for assistance under this section; and</text></item><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H142F33C89B084586B58C7CBFBE3FE0D9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inspector general report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the inspector general of the Department of Homeland Security shall assess the use of the authority provided under section 408(c)(1)(B) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174(c)(1)(B)</external-xref>), including the adequacy of any benefit-cost analysis done to justify the use of this alternative, and submit a report on the results of that review to the appropriate committees of Congress.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HBAB8CE053CAE4889B7307EEB671CFC27"><enum>2013.</enum><header>Federal disaster assistance nonprofit fairness</header> 
<subsection id="H91330E01E81E467DB082E322F9937467"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of private nonprofit facility</header><text>Section 102(11)(B) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122(11)(B)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A5D790CA72B46ACAAFEB7CCF72FC743" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HD5E7FB86447043C98DA586077F396943"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the facilities described in subparagraph (A), the term <quote>private nonprofit facility</quote> includes any private nonprofit facility that provides essential services of a governmental nature to the general public (including museums, zoos, performing arts facilities, community arts centers, community centers, houses of worship exempt from taxation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, libraries, homeless shelters, senior citizen centers, rehabilitation facilities, shelter workshops, food banks, broadcasting facilities, and facilities that provide health and safety services of a governmental nature), as defined by the President.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD493946DBA9845739F3AFAE6A6D3CC9E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repair, restoration, and replacement of damaged facilities</header><text>Section 406(a)(3) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H72D39F66171B4F46B56208E5869B2C0C" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H6A8D86B8C6204E5FA9DB7BAB27816454"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Houses of worship</header> <clause id="HE90A945384FF413E9F4124FC99A5F2E2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A church, synagogue, mosque, temple, or other house of worship, and a private nonprofit facility operated by a religious organization, shall be eligible for contributions under paragraph (1)(B) (subject to paragraph (3)(A)), without regard to the religious character of the facility or the primary religious use of the facility.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEE69DDFD17E2485CBF596B2ED6EBBD4F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding clause (i), in spaces dedicated to or primarily used for religious purposes, contributions under paragraph (1)(B) shall only be used to cover costs of purchasing or replacing, without limitation, the building structure, building enclosure components, building envelope, vertical and horizontal circulation, physical plant support spaces, electrical, plumbing, and mechanical systems (including heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and fire and life safety systems), and related site improvements.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H4C0305C1364A415D9E4DD7E03788CDF6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section and the amendments made by this section shall apply to the provision of assistance in response to a major disaster or emergency declared on or after October 28, 2012.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8E4107247FE4432A9ABB57494E040A1D"><enum>2014.</enum><header>Management costs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 324 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5165b">42 U.S.C. 5165b</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H62BEC76BA2B54604A86FB7C56FBC2CCA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a) by striking <quote>any administrative expense, and any other expense not directly chargeable to</quote> and inserting <quote>direct administrative cost, and any other administrative expense associated with</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6BF693F6641544DC9AF6D96D6E0EFE85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H1C0FCC6E67364640807093AFAC73641A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Notwithstanding</quote> and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H37D520AE304B4CE39C48BBF083B4AA62" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H8E027850EC3B49AF908401058370820F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H67554247365042BEB676D5F24E68E405"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>establish</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>implement</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB6FA6488AFD243F499BCC703C1E7EC4C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H963B104605054914A9CCD511E5ACA7F7" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H3856D49DAA014A5EAF7928908731526F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specific Management Costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall provide the following percentage rates, in addition to the eligible project costs, to cover direct and indirect costs of administering the following programs:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA72F446C19794DD49041191E1BCB83A1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Hazard mitigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grantee under section 404 may be reimbursed not more than 15 percent of the total amount of the grant award under such section of which not more than 10 percent may be used by the grantee and 5 percent by the subgrantee for such costs.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H91EB529F892D4F48A40CD771BD1910A1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public Assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grantee under sections 403, 406, 407, and 502 may be reimbursed not more than 12 percent of the total award amount under such sections, of which not more than 7 percent may be used by the grantee and 5 percent by the subgrantee for such costs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H643C1FDD8BEB4799A3D69A208B8E708A"><enum>2015.</enum><header>Flexibility</header> 
<subsection id="HBAC74354C7C54622BC68AD8ACEED8CBF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>covered assistance</quote> means assistance provided—</text> <paragraph id="H627D8D29A7E94D3F8449EE3F6CA28745"><enum>(1)</enum><text>under section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4206DD2B14134396BC3EF8C8A9E979F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in relation to a major disaster or emergency declared by the President under section 401 or 501 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5191">42 U.S.C. 5191</external-xref>) on or after October 28, 2012.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H605B8C06B9FC4F3A91EA498B5C8A4E6E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver authority</header><text>Notwithstanding section 3716(e) of title 31, United States Code, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency—</text> 
<paragraph id="HABEFEB71D91E4A3C8CEB6F0D8704F679"><enum>(1)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (2), may waive a debt owed to the United States related to covered assistance provided to an individual or household if—</text> <subparagraph id="H1B244F57B50C4721813D321843D884EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the covered assistance was distributed based on an error by the Federal Emergency Management Agency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2CA0892FDB714A578AAB687DAB5A932B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>there was no fault on behalf of the debtor; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HABE3A50777124399B012A9CF2344E82B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the collection of the debt would be against equity and good conscience; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C9C8E443DEC47CFA0A10E0691558C3E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may not waive a debt under paragraph (1) if the debt involves fraud, the presentation of a false claim, or misrepresentation by the debtor or any party having an interest in the claim.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB0CD2AFE80A4C6695F9A2C1CC17AB7A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Monitoring of covered assistance distributed based on error</header> <paragraph id="HDB875824A24644D894D7C7BE31F53B7D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The inspector general of the Department of Homeland Security shall monitor the distribution of covered assistance to individuals and households to determine the percentage of such assistance distributed based on an error.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB8940A304BC6481DA57EA44346F17F77"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Removal of waiver authority based on excessive error rate</header><text>If the inspector general determines, with respect to any 12-month period, that the amount of covered assistance distributed based on an error by the Federal Emergency Management Agency exceeds 4 percent of the total amount of covered assistance distributed—</text> <subparagraph id="H0146F42BA87E4A41907F010CFDD9F895"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the inspector general shall notify the Administrator and publish the determination in the Federal Register; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H88D31102F1D74803B2465B5F2F73D947"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to any major disaster or emergency declared by the President under section 401 or section 501, respectively, of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5191">42 U.S.C. 5191</external-xref>) after the date on which the determination is published under subparagraph (A), the authority of the Administrator to waive debt under subsection (b) shall no longer be effective.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HD425898474704C0CAB1BC0D53E57D661"><enum>2016.</enum><header>Additional disaster assistance</header> <subsection id="H2F58FD0B822242ABB44BAAA294D58234"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disaster mitigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 209 of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3149">42 U.S.C. 3149</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C7026C33F7E47419F7568D8E3D9BD83" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H371E5A3B28684B5BA4807263E4819BA3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Disaster mitigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In providing assistance pursuant to subsection (c)(2), if appropriate and as applicable, the Secretary may encourage hazard mitigation in assistance provided pursuant to such subsection.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H12DC16CDD3CD4903B72C4D7B43245DD6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Emergency management assistance compact grants</header><text>Section 661(d) of the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/761">6 U.S.C. 761(d)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>for fiscal year 2008</quote> and inserting <quote>for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H659B639D5ED94401AF1CD0FCCE5479AB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Emergency management performance grants program</header><text>Section 662(f) of the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/762">6 U.S.C. 762(f)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the program</quote> and all that follows through <quote>2012</quote> and inserting <quote>the program, for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD560DCDA04F946DBB182F0CBF4C4F262"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text>Section 403(a)(3) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170b">42 U.S.C. 5170b(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the second subparagraph (J).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H65C37C0A5292446E9EC950E9D49D2988"><enum>2017.</enum><header>National veterinary emergency teams</header> 
<subsection id="HE405E227A9D941A3AD81CA50BF47A076"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency may establish one or more national veterinary emergency teams at accredited colleges of veterinary medicine.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4A9EE6562CC846F4B9AA087A950C071F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>A national veterinary emergency team shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H44ED3FB6194541288716B75BD6E15360"><enum>(1)</enum><text>deploy with a team of the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System to assist with—</text> <subparagraph id="H7B25A56EC8E34A55A2A375501F186EBB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>veterinary care of canine search teams;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H99B8F29E45974FD4AB754A78CC2B31C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>locating and treating companion animals, service animals, livestock, and other animals; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C0901B18D4543DEA1C0F3F3EE5E025A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>surveillance and treatment of zoonotic diseases;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF5C8BB0650E41DE9134F7FB2D3F31F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recruit, train, and certify veterinary professionals, including veterinary students, in accordance with an established set of plans and standard operating guidelines to carry out the duties associated with planning for and responding to emergencies as described in paragraph (1);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9B6436D37854BE6851132F1809B2E05"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assist State, Tribal, and local governments and nonprofit organizations in developing emergency management and evacuation plans that account for the care and rescue of animals and in improving local readiness for providing veterinary medical response during a disaster; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF5B300F64C14A06B8EF0FD57026E76A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>coordinate with the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Agriculture, State, Tribal, and local governments (including departments of animal and human health), veterinary and health care professionals, and volunteers.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HA8A1D0E5FB2D43D6B579ECF1D9CF152C"><enum>2018.</enum><header>Dispute resolution pilot program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1105(c) of the Sandy Recovery Improvement Act of 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5189a">42 U.S.C. 5189a</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>2015</quote> and inserting <quote>2022</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H32199A6E64514A5DB3092DDA84175581"><enum>2019.</enum><header>Emergency relief</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for each of fiscal years 2018 and 2019, obligations for projects undertaken to respond to damages caused by Hurricanes Irma and Maria shall be excluded from any calculation of total obligations for purposes of section 125(d)(4) of title 23, United States Code.</text></section> <section id="HD6424A6BBEB64570A840D12D9AB63B6C"><enum>2020.</enum><header>Unified Federal environmental and historic preservation review</header> <subsection id="H47FAF6A2095F4709914BED53D12D6A38"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review and analysis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall review the Unified Federal Environmental and Historic Preservation review process established pursuant to section 429 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5189g">42 U.S.C. 5189g</external-xref>), and submit a report to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate that includes the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HDC3382C9013D421082C580F7317B2FD4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An analysis of whether and how the unified process has expedited the interagency review process to ensure compliance with the environmental and historic requirements under Federal law relating to disaster recovery projects.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H426EC4E5A3084A45B70C7B74E86AD91C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A survey and analysis of categorical exclusions used by other Federal agencies that may be applicable to any activity related to a Presidentially declared major disaster or emergency under such Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA741AAAAB34B49DB828EA4BA10B5BB38"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recommendations on any further actions, including any legislative proposals, needed to expedite and streamline the review process.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H23D74DBA4A7F4F8FBE0F09B66E75FF60"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After completing the review, survey, and analyses under subsection (a), but not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and after providing notice and opportunity for public comment, the Administrator shall issue regulations to implement any regulatory recommendations, including any categorical exclusions identified under subsection (a), to the extent that the categorical exclusions meet the criteria for a categorical exclusion under section 1508.4 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, and section II of DHS Instruction Manual 023–01–001–01.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H4DC1BF933BDB42AC918602628C944DD8"><enum>2021.</enum><header>Closeout incentives</header> 
<subsection id="H8CD6CA81DFC344D8957F006C6BFD00FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Facilitating closeout</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 705 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5205">42 U.S.C. 5205</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HFD68323ED68B4D5F8655E0D13E917F72" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HE8A787FBA3844F41B02EA846E14E3057"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Facilitating closeout</header> <paragraph id="H11EF3460474D47C5856F96B887A747C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Incentives</header><text>The Administrator may develop incentives and penalties that encourage State, Tribal, or local governments to close out expenditures and activities on a timely basis related to disaster or emergency assistance.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEB24589DCABA41F29AB2FB6195D1A2B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Agency shall, consistent with applicable regulations and required procedures, meet its responsibilities to improve closeout practices and reduce the time to close disaster program awards.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HC655AF38978A45F4B3C47FF56560D36E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Administrator shall issue regulations to implement this section.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF5F2EBD6C8EF4A60AC665D3EB2F9DC2D"><enum>2022.</enum><header>Performance of services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 306 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5149">42 U.S.C. 5149</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H87CA0166EFE340108F956D90717215A8" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H891690912E4C454690BD1C2E192B30C5"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency is authorized to appoint temporary personnel, after serving continuously for 3 years, to positions in the Agency in the same manner that competitive service employees with competitive status are considered for transfer, reassignment, or promotion to such positions. An individual appointed under this subsection shall become a career-conditional employee, unless the employee has already completed the service requirements for career tenure.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H5115CA4405714B15ADAE0B893EAF3A71"><enum>2023.</enum><header>Study to streamline and consolidate information collection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall—</text> <paragraph id="H681D2A7DBA1F4F29821FCD4E36064CCA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in coordination with the Small Business Administration, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and other appropriate agencies, conduct a study and develop a plan, consistent with law, under which the collection of information from disaster assistance applicants and grantees will be modified, streamlined, expedited, efficient, flexible, consolidated, and simplified to be less burdensome, duplicative, and time consuming for applicants and grantees; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD77D999F8FA845FA845A494FB698D5A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in coordination with the Small Business Administration, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and other appropriate agencies, develop a plan for the regular collection and reporting of information on Federal disaster assistance awarded, including the establishment and maintenance of a website for presenting the information to the public; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD189EDD6E0B44F288D45E9BC9B160A22"><enum>(3)</enum><text>submit the plans to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H97426D372ABE4635B8C27AB1D0DC487A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2024.</enum><header>Agency accountability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title IV of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H61D831CEB2C64931808D5FC46896AECC" style="OLC"> <section id="H2A930451141040E08FBA0D5613DE9C8E"><enum>430.</enum><header>Agency accountability</header> <subsection id="HB4BF8E83A31147648906C78B19A0AC8C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public Assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 days after an award of a public assistance grant is made under section 406 that is in excess of $1,000,000, the Administrator shall publish on the Agency’s website the specifics of each such grant award, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAEC133357C1B43EDB3AE2C30B6F79F83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifying the Federal Emergency Management Agency Region;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83AD5AACFCA24246B7E10E5F48CC8F46"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the disaster or emergency declaration number;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA2BC64D02E1F445DBA6206E623FB833F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the State, county, and applicant name;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H67AA6371B3AB4AF38BB618B9A123606A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>if the applicant is a private nonprofit organization;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2831C5B5FD024558BD22A10800694331"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the damage category code;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3AC5A965C03649BB94BCD307C1F41098"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the amount of the Federal share obligated; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB80F31D59AD94178973A06A83E70D808"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the date of the award.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H64F7E799A1314BABB478F7B3D86B7B52"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mission Assignments</header> <paragraph id="H28FEFA6C423445F3952B9FB35E2C438D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 5 days after the issuance of a mission assignment or mission assignment task order, the Administrator shall publish on the Agency’s website any mission assignment or mission assignment task order to another Federal department or agency regarding a major disaster in excess of $1,000,000, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H99F229139F8F4775B07DAC833EA6F253"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name of the impacted State or Tribe;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H169824A2B8A542A0B08D6FDDCC10815E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the disaster declaration for such State or Tribe;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBE7026F5107C4B9F9EC04C4DEEF7430A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the assigned agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H831C1A9189A24408A1C3F7B8F3BF20A1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the assistance requested;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1C4D4C2180D24705BE21C99D0FA4CA09"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of the disaster;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H69EC9D6992BB4C52825FB29E57F36171"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the total cost estimate;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4D11C3664F7041B78D1EA5E0949E28A6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the amount obligated;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H34B98AD6243A4CC3A3290F7A9A256B12"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the State or Tribal cost share, if applicable;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6095AAA5FF8C4FD4BB8381DD52D04E85"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the authority under which the mission assignment or mission assignment task order was directed; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H33CF4536C28A4593AE876A88E6291240"><enum>(J)</enum><text>if applicable, the date a State or Tribe requested the mission assignment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2ACE22280CE44E99AE2A6320DFD92E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recording changes</header><text>Not later than 10 days after the last day of each month until a mission assignment or mission assignment task order described in paragraph (1) is completed and closed out, the Administrator shall update any changes to the total cost estimate and the amount obligated.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCC12961D56704F5CADA2AAF313DD57B3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disaster Relief Monthly Report</header><text>Not later than 10 days after the first day of each month, the Administrator shall publish on the Agency’s website reports, including a specific description of the methodology and the source data used in developing such reports, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC74E99990ED24A5BAEBE1A813E2CF366"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an estimate of the amounts for the fiscal year covered by the President’s most recent budget pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HB84E65814E91481FA37885ED250C11AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the unobligated balance of funds to be carried over from the prior fiscal year to the budget year;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H41B291FD085F40718360A646092EFC0B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the unobligated balance of funds to be carried over from the budget year to the budget year plus 1;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBFF72EE992764C3E83041F6D3E09E21D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the amount of obligations for noncatastrophic events for the budget year;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H76C363400BD1430CB746184A7D1B29C2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the amount of obligations for the budget year for catastrophic events delineated by event and by State;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCA83F1A0506044F8A8A10BC0A23A0F2D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the total amount that has been previously obligated or will be required for catastrophic events delineated by event and by State for all prior years, the current fiscal year, the budget year, and each fiscal year thereafter;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3575C1BB188F4BD0BC56E412B38F10DF"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the amount of previously obligated funds that will be recovered for the budget year;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H303280B860FB46CBB9DA1489A7BF6C5F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the amount that will be required for obligations for emergencies, as described in section 102(1), major disasters, as described in section 102(2), fire management assistance grants, as described in section 420, surge activities, and disaster readiness and support activities; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H08E0765863DF4FBC9D4FC6DF5E1A2683"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the amount required for activities not covered under section 251(b)(2)(D)(iii) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/901">2 U.S.C. 901(b)(2)(D)(iii)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83F31EE0F48A441BB51A63CA6260E127"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an estimate or actual amounts, if available, of the following for the current fiscal year shall be submitted not later than the fifth day of each month, published by the Administrator on the Agency’s website not later than the fifth day of each month:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H48F053762E414A889A473FE012BD502A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A summary of the amount of appropriations made available by source, the transfers executed, the previously allocated funds recovered, and the commitments, allocations, and obligations made.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H78F20D9FB1D14ABEBDE42CD6A7502428"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A table of disaster relief activity delineated by month, including—</text> 
<clause id="HE5C155ECEBDB4719B76E86F9652DCAFA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the beginning and ending balances;</text></clause> <clause id="HAB1DB2BDC8164A258C21210F1F99DB82"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total obligations to include amounts obligated for fire assistance, emergencies, surge, and disaster support activities;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H730A9404B977414392AEA044CA6CE786"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the obligations for catastrophic events delineated by event and by State; and</text></clause> <clause id="H2DD1227877A743F18916B14A7F2A5464"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the amount of previously obligated funds that are recovered.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF4A6F47F80E64B5E90EF4A3728432A2F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A summary of allocations, obligations, and expenditures for catastrophic events delineated by event.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H937A613706F7447DB8660D6DD7033D2A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The cost of the following categories of spending:</text> 
<clause id="H96444292AFBF4E989A11999A5CED94F5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Public assistance.</text></clause> <clause id="H308BEFAC934C408C897C64732FC979CF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Individual assistance.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H84BDC447D4444258BAFC376CB9C5C089"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Mitigation.</text></clause> <clause id="HB724A75A512C4CAC947AA95D60FD74C2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Administrative.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEB209D930B854CD59F973F3BC704241A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Operations.</text></clause> <clause id="HE831E5A8E24742C08ED91CCD34A21B35"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Any other relevant category (including emergency measures and disaster resources) delineated by disaster.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7B2AA4F39AB24DA3AD3A2B8593E4A4C2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The date on which funds appropriated will be exhausted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9D915A79DB054FDE942F5F1C38A47DD3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Contracts</header> <paragraph id="H26B063DB623E40D5924692901D483269"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information</header><text>Not later than 10 days after the first day of each month, the Administrator shall publish on the Agency’s website the specifics of each contract in excess of $1,000,000 that the Agency enters into, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3D077AE453974F8197A85B448A496CF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name of the party;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H88C1C87C79744F5A9B3A57D8538ACFA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date the contract was awarded;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDC227FC5F23448098D4A233A5C75940E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the amount and scope of the contract;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2A878D37CDC641E7ADAD6D20A7A63E3C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>if the contract was awarded through competitive bidding process;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H13164DD99282442FACC95F315B1E6C5C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>if no competitive bidding process was used, the reason why competitive bidding was not used; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9504CE15E0DC45508869C5C5B2EF47A1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the authority used to bypass the competitive bidding process.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The information shall be delineated by disaster, if applicable, and specify the damage category code, if applicable.</continuation-text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H04B67CFD96964DA7B2B4A2D6C5CA3B51"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 10 days after the last day of the fiscal year, the Administrator shall provide a report to the appropriate committees of Congress summarizing the following information for the preceding fiscal year:</text> <subparagraph id="H2186E72AA40D448F8056C3F29F0DAEE5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of contracts awarded without competitive bidding.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBA3ABE6258974BE6A250C945D1A4E643"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The reasons why a competitive bidding process was not used.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA14BAD9C272944849D023D5662749AEC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The total amount of contracts awarded with no competitive bidding.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H908F32C30B9043959820691894EC5F76"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The damage category codes, if applicable, for contracts awarded without competitive bidding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section commented="no" id="H84C64E1F3CF74051A43C3A4B3A478B1C"><enum>2025.</enum><header>Audit of contracts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall not reimburse a State, Tribe, or local government or the owner or operator of a private nonprofit facility for any activities made pursuant to a contract entered into after August 1, 2017, that prohibits the Administrator or the Comptroller General of the United States from auditing or otherwise reviewing all aspects relating to the contract.</text></section> 
<section id="H915073D78C1F46349F2538EEC7F0E1C5"><enum>2026.</enum><header>Inspector general audit of FEMA contracts for tarps and plastic sheeting</header> 
<subsection id="H21EA0E34521E4D0987F89C4F6E770466"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the inspector general of the Department of Homeland Security shall initiate an audit of the contracts awarded by the Federal Emergency Management Agency (in this section referred to as <quote>FEMA</quote>) for tarps and plastic sheeting for the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the United States Virgin Islands in response to Hurricane Irma and Hurricane Maria.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7CE5DFA17D504021BC9A1DE986D5B98C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the audit under subsection (a), the inspector general shall review—</text> 
<paragraph id="H062FF55C2B2F44918CE3B1562E974ECB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the contracting process used by FEMA to evaluate offerors and award the relevant contracts to contractors;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5625AAC4BC484DC0BBFCE3660229B99E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>FEMA’s assessment of the past performance of the contractors, including any historical information showing that the contractors had supported large-scale delivery quantities in the past;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H48EC768CCBAF435C8F81032B546F88F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">FEMA’s assessment of the capacity of the contractors to carry out the relevant contracts, including with respect to inventory, production, and financial capabilities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8FC7FDCF1B9247929A8CF1D9CE137DE6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how FEMA ensured that the contractors met the terms of the relevant contracts; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2960694A93B947AEAAEE7D60E3050152"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the failure of the contractors to meet the terms of the relevant contracts and FEMA’s subsequent cancellation of the relevant contracts affected the provision of tarps and plastic sheeting to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the United States Virgin Islands.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF21D25F570B4436B882793410AA03D61"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of initiation of the audit under subsection (a), the inspector general shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the results of the audit, including findings and recommendations.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HEA81EED769734BFD9FF0F1B76D3AD4EC"><enum>2027.</enum><header>Relief organizations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 309 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5152">42 U.S.C. 5152</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H9C1AD7B9C899483596D6CB67FC3CEF35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>and other relief or</quote> and inserting <quote>long-term recovery groups, domestic hunger relief, and other relief, or</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2CF446AB2A1A45D3A30B0FE78483B3EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b), by striking <quote>and other relief or</quote> and inserting <quote>long-term recovery groups, domestic hunger relief, and other relief, or</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H682AC0DA7D9644608EF211D9B2558C5A"><enum>2028.</enum><header>Guidance on inundated and submerged roads</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, in coordination with the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration, shall develop and issue guidance for State, local, and Tribal governments regarding repair, restoration, and replacement of inundated and submerged roads damaged or destroyed by a major disaster, and for associated expenses incurred by the Government, with respect to roads eligible for assistance under section 406 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172</external-xref>).</text></section> 
<section id="H5F3B12481D404A4BA0DF4F8A3F54CBAF"><enum>2029.</enum><header>Authorities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the non-federally funded actions of private parties and State, local, or Tribal governments, on State, local, Tribal, and private land, and the effects of those actions, shall not be attributed to the Federal Emergency Management Agency's actions under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4001">42 U.S.C. 4001</external-xref> et seq.), the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4002">42 U.S.C. 4002</external-xref> et seq.), the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 (subtitle A of title II of division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/141">Public Law 112–141</external-xref>; 126 Stat. 916), and the Homeowner Flood Insurance Affordability Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/89">Public Law 113–89</external-xref>; 128 Stat. 1020) for the purposes of section 7 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536</external-xref>) and section 9 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1538">16 U.S.C. 1538</external-xref>) of the Endangered Species Act. Actions taken under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973, the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012, and the Homeowner Flood Insurance Affordability Act of 2014, that may influence private actions do not create a Federal nexus for the purpose of applying the requirements of section 7 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536</external-xref>).</text></section> <section commented="no" id="H8719B9C3AF694D28B2643A83F9079884"><enum>2030.</enum><header>Recoupment of certain assistance prohibited</header> <subsection id="H5C7E537CAD1F479BB5D11E2C5C0F558E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 3716(e) of title 31, United States Code, and unless there is evidence of civil or criminal fraud, the Federal Emergency Management Agency may not take any action to recoup covered assistance from the recipient of such assistance if the receipt of such assistance occurred on a date that is more than 3 years before the date on which the Federal Emergency Management Agency first provides to the recipient written notification of an intent to recoup.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2AA3411F867C47F9AB9A3FE904AFF429"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered assistance defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>covered assistance</term> means assistance provided—</text> <paragraph id="H4B3C12AA0D9E45C2829BC1FF6085F925"><enum>(1)</enum><text>under section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H675696C591FF4B31BF8ECD7881326077"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in relation to a major disaster or emergency declared by the President under section 401 or 501 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5191">42 U.S.C. 5191</external-xref>) on or after January 1, 2012.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HB1A3075C94724185921FE1BF62AA871F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2031.</enum><header> Statute of limitations</header> <subsection id="HE19F72C03AD54E49B2BC179043108DE6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 705 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5205">42 U.S.C. 5205</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7323E7FE78A24DA096EB74E9CF6EB206"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H4F6E0C36E20941AF8BA2E4D126CD7AA5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Except</quote> and inserting <quote>Notwithstanding section 3716(e) of title 31, United States Code, and except</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAFF21C0EE14A4624AE98817827EC9A16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>report for the disaster or emergency</quote> and inserting <quote>report for project completion as certified by the grantee</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1EABCD095B794EDFBAD8BCE7FDA050B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6EC9BAB8334843F6B19AEC814B43968D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) by striking <quote>report for the disaster or emergency</quote> and inserting <quote>report for project completion as certified by the grantee</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF94C5E29C5FD4867BFD2C0390AE29E6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3) by inserting <quote>for project completion as certified by the grantee</quote> after <quote>final expenditure report</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H151895FBF7D1432EA8997B5C32F75EB3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header> 
<paragraph id="H7783ACE7D64D42FA9B553EB92997CFAA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to disaster or emergency assistance provided to a State or local government on or after January 1, 2004—</text> <subparagraph id="H08BAE66E38C649CEB039456430605F34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no administrative action may be taken to recover a payment of such assistance after the date of enactment of this Act if the action is prohibited under section 705(a)(1) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5205">42 U.S.C. 5205(a)(1)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8A19013D92604B9CA886E16C155B7320"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any administrative action to recover a payment of such assistance that is pending on such date of enactment shall be terminated if the action is prohibited under section 705(a)(1) of that Act, as amended by subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC8B519CEE8284C06A19A9DA83D7DF7D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>This section, including the amendments made by this section, may not be construed to invalidate or otherwise affect any administration action completed before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H1A5D92F76AA944DF88B8D4918199A4AB"><enum>2032.</enum><header>Technical assistance and recommendations</header> 
<subsection id="H3F92FD44CAC545238A5F0B9D0ABE0E65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall provide technical assistance to a common interest community that provides essential services of a governmental nature on actions that a common interest community may take in order to be eligible to receive reimbursement from a grantee that receives funds from the Agency for certain activities performed after an event that results in a disaster declaration.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4F2CCD594E544FAB9510F197D646EC61"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall provide to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a legislative proposal on how to provide eligibility for disaster assistance with respect to common areas of condominiums and housing cooperatives.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HEADCB51272E74E94B399BF8D5B296E77" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2033.</enum><header> Guidance on hazard mitigation assistance</header> 
<subsection id="H4120601B590A43E68894DDA8D783A945"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall issue guidance regarding the acquisition of property for open space as a mitigation measure under section 404 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170c">42 U.S.C. 5170c</external-xref>) that includes—</text> <paragraph id="HAC6517D936CF4A34B412DD034879023C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a process by which the State hazard mitigation officer appointed for such an acquisition shall, not later than 60 days after the applicant for assistance enters into an agreement with the Administrator regarding the acquisition, provide written notification to each affected unit of local government for such acquisition that includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H36C1A033B63649AEA4AE8E5455E5D0D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the location of the acquisition;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9340818C27134D109EDF91318582B54D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the State-local assistance agreement for the hazard mitigation grant program;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H687623E1E4BD4C358E0FB5D8628F3605"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the acquisition; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC51FCD2FDBFE4E01BF7961AF6D9DCECB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a copy of the deed restriction; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H715FE748B40F48DEA4333FB3E0D60B9D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations for entering into and implementing a memorandum of understanding between units of local government and covered entities that includes provisions to allow an affected unit of local government notified under paragraph (1) to—</text> <subparagraph id="H26FB612085134991996BAAC2D22FC4D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use and maintain the open space created by such a project, consistent with section 404 (including related regulations, standards, and guidance) and consistent with all adjoining property, subject to the notification of the adjoining property, so long as the cost of the maintenance is borne by the local government; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H4E686D6020C441B48BDEA42F667354D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain the open space pursuant to standards exceeding any local government standards defined in the agreement with the Administrator described under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H460E4A9714E84D51ABE9E7C15F626986"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section the following definitions apply:</text> 
<paragraph id="H589604029CD84C3590502EC25F46DBE3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affected unit of local government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>affected unit of local government</quote> means any entity covered by the definition of local government in section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122</external-xref>), that has jurisdiction over the property subject to the acquisition described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9BD423A64DB140B1974853207F332FD1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <quote>covered entity</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB49AD5D3E95041519E0B6ACCCF42D6B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the grantee or subgrantee receiving assistance for an open space project described in subsection (a);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6AB9D98D45C84111ADAEB3A8BF299522"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the State in which such project is located; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5F44095A3CFD4BF8BF1EA0D48BE0635D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicable Regional Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H42ED6DAEE35A48BBB2549D07214CDEBD"><enum>2034.</enum><header> Local impact</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In making recommendations to the President regarding a major disaster declaration, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall give greater weight and consideration to severe local impact or recent multiple disasters. Further, the Administrator shall make corresponding adjustments to the Agency’s policies and regulations regarding such consideration. Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall report to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate on the changes made to regulations and policies and the number of declarations that have been declared based on the new criteria.</text></section> 
<section id="H60A31C5E507D45238B3AFA3EA32084A9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2035.</enum><header>Additional hazard mitigation activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 404 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170c">42 U.S.C. 5170c</external-xref>) is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8B758C4B4A564EDD8CFF487FBAC02834" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HFB824900C1CA491FAA94A1697E2D9014"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Use of assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recipients of hazard mitigation assistance provided under this section and section 203 may use the assistance to conduct activities to help reduce the risk of future damage, hardship, loss, or suffering in any area affected by earthquake hazards, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0F420B1497784FEBABB264F812FDBB9F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improvements to regional seismic networks in support of building a capability for earthquake early warning;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6763322C7E3410CB01733783A0D451E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improvements to geodetic networks in support of building a capability for earthquake early warning; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3C9D581E475F4FBAA7C5FCA6037E3BD0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improvements to seismometers, Global Positioning System receivers, and associated infrastructure in support of building a capability for earthquake early warning.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H2E2F92F70B7D42D3A38945217D9D45DD" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2036.</enum><header>National public infrastructure predisaster hazard mitigation</header> <subsection id="HEEA05889368440218BE778B283C730B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Predisaster hazard mitigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 203 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5133">42 U.S.C. 5133</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H429B68D1F08D4EA8BAFE552764B6A480"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c) by inserting <quote>Public Infrastructure</quote> after <quote>the National</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H008B5A09B667459F8B936A2D78269920"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (e)(1)(B)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7EF0A3C2C04C4760BB6BB126E5576DAB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (ii);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA130C494C9974B018DE2DE43A3165ADB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking the period at the end of clause (iii) and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCA4FBDB635B14C49AC099EAEE1BF6976"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2B791935E6F24EA7840EEBB02740CD96"> <clause id="H6936102285914354AB16353684D081E6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to establish and carry out enforcement activities to implement the latest published editions of relevant consensus-based codes, specifications, and standards that incorporate the latest hazard-resistant designs and establish minimum acceptable criteria for the design, construction, and maintenance of residential structures and facilities that may be eligible for assistance under this Act for the purpose of protecting the health, safety, and general welfare of the buildings’ users against disasters.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H869EED6F09B0424FA1A08EACAEBCD58C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (f)—</text> <subparagraph id="H5D3377A71B4942C7A6C11A472740EF73"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) by inserting <quote>for mitigation activities that are cost effective</quote> after <quote>competitive basis</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2FD5502D0E2D46AFAE00F1A577A16ECE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6AFE9E70238D4A9DB8698000D6BBBDD0"> <paragraph id="H0278F1BE1E134C3F9DA47C192A632DBE" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Redistribution of unobligated amounts</header><text>The President may—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H24062B275E7943809AF3043A23D3F55D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>withdraw amounts of financial assistance made available to a State (including amounts made available to local governments of a State) under this subsection that remain unobligated by the end of the third fiscal year after the fiscal year for which the amounts were allocated; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D60AE8433334275875623099974103B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the fiscal year following a fiscal year in which amounts were withdrawn under subparagraph (A), add the amounts to any other amounts available to be awarded on a competitive basis pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H22610A0ACF084A96A45762F27D249B1F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (g)—</text> <subparagraph id="HEEE6D4A1BAC949C4B7A613DA59AB7ABC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (9) by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE6397CFB0E7D4FC599CD02382018982F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (10) as paragraph (12); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39AB213899294E4F9ED0C1FE95345E0A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding after paragraph (9) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFDFE0C4C388A412A8D789A05F2AA0894"> 
<paragraph id="H4E102A24AEB543E08D474EC9C0C90721"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which the State or local government has facilitated the adoption and enforcement of the latest published editions of relevant consensus-based codes, specifications, and standards that incorporate the latest hazard-resistant designs and establish criteria for the design, construction, and maintenance of residential structures and facilities that may be eligible for assistance under this Act for the purpose of protecting the health, safety, and general welfare of the buildings’ users against disasters;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDCE44E5D763D409CA10EB69E0E1CF4B7"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the extent to which the assistance will fund activities that increase the level of resiliency; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD50344A573C845988B4BB9594FD035B0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by striking subsection (i) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4BC6ACCA2FE4A5EBF6F27BD28A88E25"> <subsection id="H06265C6CCFFA4B1AAF934B2E5E0EAEE2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>National public infrastructure predisaster mitigation assistance</header> <paragraph id="HC6C8735E20E848C79D5D0400509082A1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may set aside from the Disaster Relief Fund, with respect to each major disaster, an amount equal to 6 percent of the estimated aggregate amount of the grants to be made pursuant to sections 403, 406, 407, 408, 410, and 416 for the major disaster in order to provide technical and financial assistance under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9C40ACC38344481AB72ACB0225822624"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Estimated aggregate amount</header><text>Not later than 180 days after each major disaster declaration pursuant to this Act, the estimated aggregate amount of grants for purposes of paragraph (1) shall be determined by the President and such estimated amount need not be reduced, increased, or changed due to variations in estimates.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H519EC43537344609BC009066F671723C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No reduction in amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount set aside pursuant to paragraph (1) shall not reduce the amounts otherwise made available for sections 403, 404, 406, 407, 408, 410, and 416 under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBBDFBD7FBB9A41F98B12C6A368B2A654"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by striking subsections (j) and (m) and redesignating subsections (k), (l), and (n) as subsections (j), (k), and (l), respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HECE7665FD71141508BFB68C005560F26"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendments made to section 203 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5133">42 U.S.C. 5133</external-xref>) by paragraphs (3) and (5) of subsection (a) shall apply to funds appropriated after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC1E722035C2F4F3290814A2B5148C1BE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2037.</enum><header>Additional mitigation activities</header> 
<subsection id="H7950B37D337A49BB9EE7CE25D659A792"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Hazard mitigation clarification</header><text>Section 404(a) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170c">42 U.S.C. 5170c(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the first sentence and inserting the following: <quote>The President may contribute up to 75 percent of the cost of hazard mitigation measures which the President has determined are cost effective and which substantially reduce the risk of, or increase resilience to, future damage, hardship, loss, or suffering in any area affected by a major disaster.</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDBAF224478744316B5EBBD8D8A7522B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible cost</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 406(e)(1)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172(e)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEEB94FA9EF374F15938788B380E0D5DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting after <quote>section,</quote> the following: <quote>for disasters declared on or after August 1, 2017, or a disaster in which a cost estimate has not yet been finalized for a project,</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C8D63C8540A4BD9AB1EA8D59BC91ECA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>and</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58B7A98744764F71A0B21D581E870CF7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text> <subparagraph id="HF7B330955B9644408E276EF5749F822A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>codes, specifications, and standards</quote> and inserting <quote>the latest published editions of relevant consensus-based codes, specifications, and standards that incorporate the latest hazard-resistant designs and establish minimum acceptable criteria for the design, construction, and maintenance of residential structures and facilities that may be eligible for assistance under this Act for the purposes of protecting the health, safety, and general welfare of a facility’s users against disasters</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9F04F8638CDA4F929200A167B97E5406"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>applicable at the time at which the disaster occurred</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H567CF0C3F99846B9958CAB1D3A69D391"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE75567DFFE6E416BACD4EAEE25054876"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HADF868FD7CB6433F8599A76D7535E446" style="OLC"> <clause id="HE1AE72326E3A4CE68E3B9BCCF76E86EA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in a manner that allows the facility to meet the definition of resilient developed pursuant to this subsection.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAFF9C034EC0247F2BC917401D1D38DE2" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other eligible cost</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 406(e)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172(e)(1)</external-xref>) is further amended by inserting at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1CDC1352B4984ACE969EAAFAA0AED6BB" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H1CFFF1FE01354AD8B72F0BC26E2EA80D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Contributions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Contributions for the eligible cost made under this section may be provided on an actual cost basis or on cost-estimation procedures.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1B9AD5A2416D446AA169F2DE0A2A7B89"><enum>(d)</enum><header>New rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 406(e) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172(e)</external-xref>) is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H1422CED8B19F47379E558750086B521C" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H698596AEF0C241D583D671CA18F9298B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>New rules</header> <subparagraph id="H9547EC08475645FEA4F50717E150563B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the President, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, shall issue a final rulemaking that defines the terms <term>resilient</term> and <term>resiliency</term> for purposes of this subsection.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0FC12D3ECE604D498EE700B37C6A6A98"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Interim guidance</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Administrator shall issue interim guidance to implement this subsection. Such interim guidance shall expire 18 months after the date of enactment of this paragraph or upon issuance of final regulations pursuant to subparagraph (A), whichever occurs first.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF11F3AB272D54B47A777FCA1DE03AC29"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which the Administrator issues the final rulemaking under this paragraph, the Administrator shall issue any necessary guidance related to the rulemaking.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB46B224FDA8B4A07B07C2E96FAA609C1"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report summarizing the regulations and guidance issued pursuant to this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HDBBEBC0018A7487CA90E05028F2EF718"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 205(d)(2) of the Disaster Mitigation Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/390">Public Law 106–390</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(C)</quote> after <quote>except that paragraph (1)</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H76BE487260B34034BBE3E9F402FF7EA3"><enum>2038.</enum><header>Federal cost-share adjustments for repair, restoration, and replacement of damaged facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 406(b) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172(b)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93FFE02C82D64BEEBE5F3EFC361F7622" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H3D13DB3E6AE049289601C1DCF376E35F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Increased Federal share</header> <subparagraph id="H7ECDF99BD7E24D4FA47CAC420CA164AA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Incentive measures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may provide incentives to a State or Tribal government to invest in measures that increase readiness for, and resilience from, a major disaster by recognizing such investments through a sliding scale that increases the minimum Federal share to 85 percent. Such measures may include—</text> 
<clause id="H84AEC0C27B5C4220B774D9BDB8809AB9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the adoption of a mitigation plan approved under section 322;</text></clause> <clause id="HC7B6BAFC3A684D83847629497073FAE9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>investments in disaster relief, insurance, and emergency management programs;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9B5DB71E8219405A937AE10569312A46"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encouraging the adoption and enforcement of the latest published editions of relevant consensus-based codes, specifications, and standards that incorporate the latest hazard-resistant designs and establish minimum acceptable criteria for the design, construction, and maintenance of residential structures and facilities that may be eligible for assistance under this Act for the purpose of protecting the health, safety, and general welfare of the buildings’ users against disasters;</text></clause> <clause id="H343A0DC1C27140EF951A834264B52775"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>facilitating participation in the community rating system; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4C7CB1CD79764FEB9B163D45F9546443"><enum>(v)</enum><text>funding mitigation projects or granting tax incentives for projects that reduce risk.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7908309F645A43BD9491216C656AD5AA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Comprehensive Guidance</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the President, acting through the Administrator, shall issue comprehensive guidance to State and Tribal governments regarding the measures and investments, weighted appropriately based on actuarial assessments of eligible actions, that will be recognized for the purpose of increasing the Federal share under this section. Guidance shall ensure that the agency’s review of eligible measures and investments does not unduly delay determining the appropriate Federal cost share. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6A025FCE45A04CD591029A4339578F9F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Report</header><text>One year after the issuance of the guidance required by subparagraph (B), the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report regarding the analysis of the Federal cost shares paid under this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H67D7CB6D3CFD4D7ABC1AEB754002D6C9"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Savings Clause</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph prevents the President from increasing the Federal cost share above 85 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></division> 
<division id="HBED6B3739D0B4D78836311338B8CCFA3"><enum>C</enum><header>Other Matters</header> 
<section id="H26FED51AF2E5488CB159C64C22918198" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3001.</enum><header>Treatment of seed cotton</header> 
<subsection id="H5F02CED28AA94A679AB787795942544F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1111 of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/9011">7 U.S.C. 9011</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBE388A77CCC1478BA77255B21ACEC2E9" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HF4AD37BF6BA8421AB398F7E38FCA0427"><enum>(25)</enum><header>Seed cotton</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>seed cotton</quote> means unginned upland cotton that includes both lint and seed.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H910613FA3C2A47F8BC65F5BB7C3E9D1E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation as covered commodity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1111(6) of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/9011">7 U.S.C. 9011(6)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Effective beginning with the 2018 crop year, the term includes seed cotton.</quote>. </text></subsection> <subsection id="HD4913AEDE2E348B4A72757F57587A892"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reference price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1111(18) of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/9011">7 U.S.C. 9011(18)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFD1EFFF13ACD44408BC6A7B172CB7E43" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="HE07619CE0D284BED88AA9D6C5487B689"><enum>(O)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For seed cotton, $0.367 per pound.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H7A0F86742CF04DD2955618D59C46F089"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Payment yield</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1113(d) of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/9013">7 U.S.C. 9013(d)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H384885EB6FFD499AACFFA3C365F8CC0F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HD7BBA879AA1D4201B9E13808BAEA07CF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Payment yield for seed cotton</header> 
<subparagraph id="H50C652F07F954FB89E1B3C41BFAF8230"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Payment yield</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (B), the payment yield for seed cotton for a farm shall be equal to 2.4 times the payment yield for upland cotton for the farm established for purposes of subsection (e)(3) of section 1104 of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/246">Public Law 110–246</external-xref>; 122 Stat. 1672), as in effect immediately before the repeal of such section by section 1102(a) of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/79">Public Law 113–79</external-xref>; 128 Stat. 658).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H592FEF80D784473CB5BFE2F15AF98227"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Update</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the sole discretion of the owner of a farm with a yield described in subparagraph (A), the owner of the farm shall have a 1-time opportunity to update the payment yield for upland cotton for the farm, as provided in subsection (d), for the purpose of calculating the payment yield for seed cotton under such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEB3F999F38CC40C7813208873855D023" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Payment acres</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1114(b) of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/9014">7 U.S.C. 9014(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F57485EFBEC4678BE8039C38F832FAB"> <paragraph id="HBCB57FEFAF274A2BB70F295E9DC569F0" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Seed cotton rule</header> <subparagraph id="H87A3400E7FEA400D953FA3BCCA0317F7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary shall require the owner of a farm to allocate all generic base acres on the farm under subparagraph (B) or (C), or both.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC7D8E72DFFAE4DA8BAD484704C7F9A73"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No recent history of covered commodities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a farm where no covered commodities (including seed cotton) were planted or were prevented from being planted at any time during the 2009 through 2016 crop years, the owner of such farm shall allocate generic base acres on the farm to unassigned crop base for which no payments may be made under section 1116 or 1117.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H81DD618825DF426C83C83E68A4A23081"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Recent history of covered commodities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a farm not described in subparagraph (B), the owner of such farm shall allocate generic base acres on the farm—</text> 
<clause id="H1FF4E4569A2F4E5A9873349E53621CC1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph (D), to seed cotton base acres in an amount equal to the greater of—</text> <subclause id="HD6A312023A774609878C3A0474A978D6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>80 percent of the generic base acres on the farm; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HBA7E1BE0413E4385A18E1400C0AE4D9C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the average seed cotton acres planted or prevented from being planted on the farm during the 2009 through 2012 crop years (not to exceed the total generic base acres on the farm); or</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HCDA768F7E5354DF08646FDDE95287458"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to covered commodities (including seed cotton), by applying subparagraphs (B), (D), (E), and (F) of section 1112(a)(3).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H58CE7DC805BE4A9FB5C07C285CE39096"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Treatment of residual generic base acres</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a farm where generic base acres are allocated under subparagraph (C)(i), the residual generic base acres shall be allocated to unassigned crop base for which no payments may be made under section 1116 or 1117.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H22ED903E9C03403BB7B9B8579723B4CA"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Effect of failure to allocate</header><text>If the owner of a farm fails to allocate generic base acres on the farm, the owner of the farm shall be deemed to have allocated all generic base acres in accordance with subparagraph (C)(i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H57082CFFB6C64CDFB18F18309FF66ACD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Recordkeeping regarding unassigned crop base</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1114 of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/9014">7 U.S.C. 9014</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCBB4619CF0134FA69C07FA7FB2F498E8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HEB89255896CC4D42B01CD93E2D04BE99"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Unassigned crop base</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall maintain information on generic base acres on a farm allocated as unassigned crop base pursuant to subsection (b)(4).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H972D5683FFD646219D2E6C26412F8F35"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Special election period for price loss coverage or agriculture risk coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1115 of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/9014">7 U.S.C. 9014(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF8341B50779148E3ABA86749F37E5844"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>For</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subsection (g), for</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD4D49B89017E49CCB86B945639C49761"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7C6C46C6D0DD45A5857A6DDDD39AA07E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H56E20CF2F1E2471899EED683F420FECC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Special election</header> <paragraph id="H5E3324FDB1C543CE81210306F9A59CFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Election required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of acres allocated on a farm to seed cotton, all of the producers on the farm shall be given the opportunity to make a new 1-time election under subsection (a) to reflect the designation of seed cotton as a covered commodity for that crop year under section 1111(6).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H74648C7E753341CC815002A1C25616A9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of failure to make unanimous election</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If all of the producers on a farm fail to make a unanimous election under paragraph (1), the producers on the farm shall be deemed to have elected price loss coverage under section 1116 for all acres allocated on the farm to seed cotton.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBF69E1D5BF244AC5AC2DE5D57471F331"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effective price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1116 of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/9016">7 U.S.C. 9016(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAC3111B093714126BC213D0EDB11150A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HB758B1D5DC3946E6A355B465EB75949D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effective price for seed cotton</header> 
<paragraph id="HEB5BFA095F2041C79B1503687510724E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The effective price for seed cotton under subsection (b) shall be equal to the marketing year average price for seed cotton, as calculated under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0C18F624BC44E09BA17D6458A9266F1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Calculation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The marketing year average price for seed cotton for a crop year shall be equal to the quotient of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HABAE3208BA2A4E16AF6DB17EE2DC7846"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a dividend that is equal to the sum of—</text> <clause id="H302BF23D6CEA4402B6D8490615567C90"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the product obtained when the upland cotton lint marketing year average price is multiplied by total United States upland cotton lint production measured in pounds; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1017657F496647E0B7DD9C9F73B93505"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the product obtained when the cottonseed marketing year average price is multiplied by total United States cottonseed production measured in pounds; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3EF588A985BB4A3BB9FEF4A2F2BC40F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a divisor that is equal to the sum of—</text> 
<clause id="H90A3593D579E4F5284E26803BD34DA5C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>total United States upland cotton lint production measured in pounds; and </text></clause> <clause id="HE2AA1838507E414F8CB73D8FC487FA9A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>total United States cottonseed production measured in pounds.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4F5ECD30F7534101B33D6CA5ABFADA8F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Deemed loan rate for seed cotton</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1202 of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/9032">7 U.S.C. 9032</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFA11EC624A3B4A03A238A187369449CE" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HD80AD36FD6474843ADE52A93CA2D28BF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule for seed cotton</header> <paragraph id="HC5F156763BA6448BBEF48780A058042B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of section 1116(b)(2) and paragraphs (1)(B)(ii) and (2)(A)(ii)(II) of section 1117(b) only, seed cotton shall be deemed to have a loan rate equal to $0.25 per pound.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0CFD63B16127491B9FFBE9C511128F0B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to authorize nonrecourse marketing assistance loans under this part for seed cotton.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H7D718FD5CBF7430EBD5E3AB8B54394B4" commented="no"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Limitation on stacked income protection plan for producers of upland cotton</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 508B of the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1508b">7 U.S.C. 1508b</external-xref>) is amended by adding the following new subsection: </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE062E64A020C412D8765A473803195E2" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H1F8499D6EA324A92A6B2DDB5CE98E27A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning with the 2018 crop year, in the case of a farm that is enrolled for a crop year in price loss coverage under section 1116 of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/9016">7 U.S.C. 9016</external-xref>) or agriculture risk coverage under section 1117 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/9017">7 U.S.C. 9017</external-xref>) and the coverage on the farm includes seed cotton, the farm shall not be eligible for a Stacked Income Protection Plan for upland cotton for that crop year.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HA6D67F4F1173495EA241BA13543DD5FE"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Technical correction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1114(b)(2) of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/9014">7 U.S.C. 9014(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>paragraphs (1)(B) and (2)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (1) and (2)</quote>. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA09155CA55EC447EB17455AE81BA5AAA"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture shall carry out the amendments made by this section in the manner provided under section 1601 of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/9091">7 U.S.C. 9091</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8BFBB3D1BC0D437CB1CC0887E1A7E509"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply beginning with the 2018 crop year.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HBF55A10FE7974C12947B5D05D2495D6F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3002.</enum><header>Limitation on crop insurance livestock-related expenditures</header> 
<subsection id="HE7154CEF54424C2C9A9CEAEB66115EE2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (10) of section 523(b) of the Federal Crop Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1523">7 U.S.C. 1523</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H96808C3C3A04449A8E809D56EDB86370"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 516 of the Federal Crop Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1516">7 U.S.C. 1516</external-xref>) is amended in subsections (a)(2)(C) and (b)(1)(D) by striking <quote>subsections (a)(3)(E)(ii) and (b)(10) of section 523</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)(3)(E)(ii) of such section</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H1B5CFA113DA84FDA8340C9F68716181B"><enum>3003.</enum><header>National accuracy clearinghouse</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011</external-xref> et seq.) is amended at the end by adding the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HBC55D177D22D40CB84CBE4FB112CDB2C" style="OLC"> <section id="H500376764489487D93F4E4793B084266"><enum>30.</enum><header>National accuracy clearinghouse</header> <subsection id="H6FA6F0C09EBA4953A14D4C5B81F52045"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish an interstate database, or system of databases, of supplemental nutrition assistance program information to be known as the National Accuracy Clearinghouse.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H773A007928E64C9487BCCF49B724777E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any database or system of databases established pursuant to subsection (a) shall be used by States when making eligibility determinations to prevent supplemental nutrition assistance program participants from receiving duplicative benefits in multiple States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H896B51EBFAA84DB09D87989713D97FE1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header> <paragraph id="HF8978CB5BA814265963FCBE606BE75B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Issuance of interim final regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the effective date of this section, the Secretary shall issue interim final regulations to carry out this section that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H10BC410B315D416DAA83DF08C0F21BF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>incorporate best practices and lessons learned from the regional pilot project referenced in section 4032(c) of the Agricultural Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2036c">7 U.S.C. 2036c(c)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6177A34E680141F09D78A2E859B1EE88"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">safeguard the security of the data stored in the National Accuracy Clearinghouse and protect the privacy of supplemental nutrition assistance program participants and applicants; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H590F780F8C5F40F980E306D3573F7A6B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>detail the process States will be required to follow for—</text> <clause id="H3740EE28B54B47B8A62F0084E0C9CF15"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conducting initial and ongoing matches of participant and applicant data;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC9C0E54976AA4420ACF55CF8ADFE54EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identifying and acting on all apparent instances of duplicative participation by participants or applicants in multiple States; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB14406FC311D4AB49C5D157088B9F297"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">complying with such other rules and standards the Secretary determines appropriate to carry out this section. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A050EC65FB54ACFB364F08EFDB44B74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The initial match and corresponding actions required by paragraph (1)(C) shall occur within 3 years after the effective date of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></division> <division id="HA2CBB81C7DD942C68C6F68ADDAA016EA"><enum>D</enum><header>Budgetary Effects</header> <section id="H927331F8CC6045A986F533063F4BB821"><enum>4001.</enum><header>Budgetary effects</header> <subsection id="HCD4476B428B34A8285F81E69E3A9534B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The budgetary effects of division B and each succeeding division shall not be entered on either PAYGO scorecard maintained pursuant to section 4(d) of the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF61CD7A4C3B147478F9D0A318EC7C1DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Senate PAYGO scorecards</header><text>The budgetary effects of division B and each succeeding division shall not be entered on any PAYGO scorecard maintained for purposes of section 4106 of H. Con. Res. 71 (115th Congress).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0FC4D8B4B32B4E9B99639486E574A9F1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Classification of budgetary effects</header><text>Notwithstanding Rule 3 of the Budget Scorekeeping Guidelines set forth in the joint explanatory statement of the committee of conference accompanying Conference Report 105–217 and section 250(c)(8) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985, the budgetary effects of division B and each succeeding division shall not be estimated—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA2E18B7484554B779B4230DC1AFD2A50"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for purposes of section 251 of such Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2793472E3CFC432795BD92992DE10FA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for purposes of paragraph (4)(C) of section 3 of the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 as being included in an appropriation Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></division> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


