<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H71577F4250124C4C8BCEE6048652FC3B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3168 IH: To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide continued access to specialized Medicare Advantage plans for special needs individuals, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3168</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170706">July 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000462">Mr. Tiberi</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000263">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide continued access to specialized Medicare
			 Advantage plans for special needs individuals, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HEA546C58EB6748B185E4579EF667BA0F" style="OLC">
		<section id="HCD023E0B02B6443B8FB30F9F69FDBA6B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Specialized Medicare Advantage plans for special needs individuals</header>
 <subsection id="H079DB9C3FAEC49239A200DEEED2A9824"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1859(f)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-28">42 U.S.C. 1395w–28(f)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H90D9924E011E47D49CB795D00DB1A6B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and for periods before January 1, 2019</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01A44D8372514D3EAF8F1C53CEAC86D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>In the case of a specialized MA plan for special needs individuals described in clause (ii) or (iii) of subsection (b)(6)(B), the previous sentence shall apply for periods before January 1, 2024.</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H19BC506DF70440DC901A9593B1157AE4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Increased integration of dual SNPs</header>
 <paragraph id="HDBD75610EEDF4232B0C38A16B1B1A974"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1859(f) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-28">42 U.S.C. 1395w–28(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HF4909F51C37E4C2B8D21BACA9288308E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H728A61DD7D0447E48827B15F82963B01" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H0DD1BCF77B534E5FA26284F175B3270F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The plan meets the requirements applicable under paragraph (8).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE5F5852EF9B44FAB325C424BEA00567"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E531F763A924F14983AE8FC6ECDA83E" style="OLC">
							<paragraph id="H792AC83BE2A84C1BA072BBFA1DF409C7"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Increased integration of dual SNPs</header>
 <subparagraph id="HFB3B83B71C674A2785DD866E13B887BD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Designated contact</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Federal Coordinated Health Care Office established under section 2602 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>, shall serve as a dedicated point of contact for States to address misalignments that arise with the integration of specialized MA plans for special needs individuals described in subsection (b)(6)(B)(ii) under this paragraph and, consistent with such role, shall—</text>
 <clause id="HC95F29B42FC4454EAB857B5BF039FA4B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish a uniform process for disseminating to State Medicaid agencies information under this title impacting contracts between such agencies and such plans under this subsection; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBB87A36E08B044909D9D5EF53365E651"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish basic resources for States interested in exploring such plans as a platform for integration, such as a model contract or other tools to achieve those goals.</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7B47945F44E41FAB293D2AD545DE154"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Unified grievances and appeals process</header>
 <clause id="H8D96F7143D0C4C83BA2BE084C90ECD6E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than April 1, 2020, the Secretary shall establish procedures, to the extent feasible as determined by the Secretary, unifying grievances and appeals procedures under sections 1852(f), 1852(g), 1902(a)(3), 1902(a)(5), and 1932(b)(4) for items and services provided by specialized MA plans for special needs individuals described in subsection (b)(6)(B)(ii) under this title and title XIX. The Secretary shall solicit comment in developing such procedures from States, plans, beneficiaries and their representatives, and other relevant stakeholders. With respect to items and services described in the previous sentence, appeals procedures established under this clause shall apply in place of otherwise applicable appeals procedures.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HCFA9A442ACDE4D5E9F68C3CA64C76DDD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>The procedures established under clause (i) shall be included in the plan contract under paragraph (3)(D) and shall—</text>
 <subclause id="HE7BDEB0C264B4C59887952317630A069"><enum>(I)</enum><text>adopt the provisions for the enrollee that are most protective for the enrollee and, to the extent feasible as determined by the Secretary, are compatible with unified timeframes and consolidated access to external review under an integrated process;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4D49236079E94A39BD320CD0D2DF03E1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>take into account differences in State plans under title XIX to the extent necessary;</text> </subclause><subclause id="H5782C5E5BE93424A819B12A7E14CB6D0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>be easily navigable by an enrollee; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H43C98C8F4DFC4ADEA72B8E0B358E4BBC"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>include the elements described in clause (iii), as applicable.</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HB83F33B4E51B4841835DF4EDA851B2BA"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Elements described</header><text>Both unified appeals and unified grievance procedures shall include, as applicable, the following elements described in this clause:</text>
 <subclause id="H9D24CC3BB6D843A2AB977992A7DFA728"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Single written notification of all applicable grievances and appeal rights under this title and title XIX. For purposes of this subparagraph, the Secretary may waive the requirements under section 1852(g)(1)(B) when the specialized MA plan covers items or services under this part or under title XIX.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HED774A795AEE4C44999FD6924A3D7A3D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Single pathways for resolution of any grievance or appeal related to a particular item or service provided by specialized MA plans for special needs individuals described in subsection (b)(6)(B)(ii) under this title and title XIX.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8D06D48EC0F24C8490477652B5110C45"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Notices written in plain language and available in a language and format that is accessible to the enrollee, including in non-English languages that are prevalent in the service area of the specialized MA plan.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE6280A3A52CE456D8C41756286010146"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Unified timeframes for grievances and appeals processes, such as an individual’s filing of a grievance or appeal, a plan’s acknowledgment and resolution of a grievance or appeal, and notification of decisions with respect to a grievance or appeal.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H444208A26CD0436D97FF0036AF3861E5"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Requirements for how the plan must process, track, and resolve grievances and appeals, to ensure beneficiaries are notified on a timely basis of decisions that are made throughout the grievance or appeals process and are able to easily determine the status of a grievance or appeal.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H08B5BA6A14224D59B4261855D52BCAB6"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Continuation of benefits pending appeal</header><text>The unified procedures under clause (i) shall, with respect to all benefits under parts A and B and title XIX subject to appeal under such procedures, incorporate provisions under current law and implementing regulations that provide continuation of benefits pending appeal under this title and title XIX.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CE0E98409E7420F86456E3CBD65AB75"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirement for unified grievances and appeals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For 2022 and subsequent years, the contract of a specialized MA plan for special needs individuals described in subsection (b)(6)(B)(ii) with a State Medicaid agency under paragraph (3)(D) shall require the use of unified grievances and appeals procedures as described in subparagraph (B).</text>
								</subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H24F0C035976C47EDB86973DFEDE825BE"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Requirements for full integration for certain dual SNPs</header>
 <clause id="H4075006B4B59437D8D75B827A6BD266D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For 2022 and subsequent years, a specialized MA plan for special needs individuals described in subsection (b)(6)(B)(ii) shall meet one or more of the following requirements, to the extent allowed by the State, for integration of benefits under this title and title XIX:</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H7DF26DBFFD184AEBAF9574D9EF0587C0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Meet the requirements of a fully integrated plan described in section 1853(a)(1)(B)(iv)(II) (other than the requirement that the plan have similar average levels of frailty, as determined by the Secretary, as the PACE program).</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HA3DCC27FB4B7440691F19311B1BF3801"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Enter into a capitated contract with the State Medicaid agency to provide long-term services and supports or behavioral health services, or both.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H745CBCD5ABA641A1B383D32DD79C7382"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Enter into any other type of arrangement, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text> </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H0C9ACED0E06F47C88CF94B9DD3A8CA28"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Sanctions</header><text>For 2022 and subsequent years, if the Secretary determines that a specialized MA plan fails to comply with clause (i), the Secretary may provide for the application against the Medicare Advantage organization offering the plan any of the remedies described in section 1857(g)(2).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H364E82F814404C8D85128D40B382CED6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment to responsibilities of Federal Coordinated Health Care Office</header><text>Section 2602(d) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315b">42 U.S.C. 1315b(d)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA81007E4845549258B5C6E6DAE186289" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H957AC786EF654F99884E138FD9B02148"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To act as a designated contact for States under subsection (f)(8)(A) of section 1859 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-28">42 U.S.C. 1395w–28</external-xref>) with respect to the integration of specialized MA plans for special needs individuals described in subsection (b)(6)(B)(ii) of such section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58B62D0BE9F64B17BCDEED85A8E16560"><enum>(7)</enum><text>To be responsible for developing regulations and guidance related to the implementation of a unified grievance and appeals process as described in subparagraphs (B) and (C) of section 1859(f)(8) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-28">42 U.S.C. 1395w–28(f)(8)</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1F4D18AD26924BECB9E0AB64842221A5"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be responsible for developing regulations and guidance related to the integration or alignment of policy and oversight under the Medicare program under title XVIII of such Act and Medicaid program under title XIX of such Act regarding specialized MA plans for special needs individuals described in subsection (b)(6)(B)(ii) of such section 1859.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8633B0A94CFA44CA96B205E403C8EC5E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Improvements to severe or disabling chronic condition SNPs</header>
 <paragraph id="HB5C4B619A2504CB695BACAE32F9454C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Care management requirements</header><text>Section 1859(f)(5) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-28">42 U.S.C. 1395w–28(f)(5)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H3E0EBEAB644C4D83A6F34981AD74CA99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively, and indenting appropriately;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D6D7D6F3E5D40F4A3C621FE10E2544A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), as redesignated by subparagraph (B), by redesignating clauses (i) through (iii) as subclauses (I) through (III), respectively, and indenting appropriately;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6CE0B0C75BB491A8444793E962C625F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">all SNPs</header-in-text>.—The requirements</quote> and inserting “<header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">all SNPs</header-in-text>.—</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H60CDE9D6C1CE40DA898AD4AA406AF570" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H850BEA908E294321BBEFA821C26926A9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the requirements</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EAB3A40F10046FF917D84EF2F12D006"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4BF88DD60DF94BC3AA2A4022A1B515E7" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H127B43D7D9844931A9D0D6CEA13DE702"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Improvements to care management requirements for severe or disabling chronic condition SNPs</header><text>For 2020 and subsequent years, in the case of a specialized MA plan for special needs individuals described in subsection (b)(6)(B)(iii), the requirements described in this paragraph include the following:</text>
 <clause id="HC1CF0D12BE9A49C7B69B12F5277E0227"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The interdisciplinary team under subparagraph (A)(ii)(III) includes a team of providers with demonstrated expertise, including training in an applicable specialty, in treating individuals similar to the targeted population of the plan.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB1099C3148584EB481A249B30561401D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Requirements developed by the Secretary to provide face-to-face encounters with individuals enrolled in the plan not less frequently than on an annual basis.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0BFDE64CA7264385A2FD1D21EECB3F60"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>As part of the model of care under clause (i) of subparagraph (A), the results of the initial assessment and annual reassessment under clause (ii)(I) of such subparagraph of each individual enrolled in the plan are addressed in the individual’s individualized care plan under clause (ii)(II) of such subparagraph.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9AF930C77190437789391B1AD1D42B33"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>As part of the annual evaluation and approval of such model of care, the Secretary shall take into account whether the plan fulfilled the previous year’s goals (as required under the model of care).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H1E0C2386777F435980D1C4C48735E85A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Secretary shall establish a minimum benchmark for each element of the model of care of a plan. The Secretary shall only approve a plan's model of care under this paragraph if each element of the model of care meets the minimum benchmark applicable under the preceding sentence.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1FFB6BAA7CC46FD8D6D196FFFC4971B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Revisions to the definition of a severe or disabling chronic conditions specialized needs
			 individual</header>
 <subparagraph id="HC9719374CE7F4B46A7046C27B81FD6A7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1859(b)(6)(B)(iii) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-28">42 U.S.C. 1395w–28(b)(6)(B)(iii)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <clause id="H43AF93462C844EA787D063A09CBF7B2D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>who have</quote> and inserting “who—</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2212AE26D364524AB76AF38C41809A6" style="OLC"> <subclause id="HC4918FBA1FD541169C53F7CE68C78FE5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>before January 1, 2022, have</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause id="HFE7BA020079B4056A8FEE2BEE671DD89"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subclause (I), as added by clause (i), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H22CAC126645E4F449048463757AFA50B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A74DE097FC44F678444CC6BF2791431" style="OLC">
 <subclause id="HF64D6A6563314AE4B077115C3750899F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>on or after January 1, 2022, have one or more comorbid and medically complex chronic conditions that is life threatening or significantly limits overall health or function, have a high risk of hospitalization or other adverse health outcomes, and require intensive care coordination and that is listed under subsection (f)(9)(A).</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05BE5E2E6621471AA39CBBFA4BB7EB35"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Panel of clinical advisors</header><text>Section 1859(f) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-28">42 U.S.C. 1395w–28(f)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (b), is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2127416AA3714331BEC7999D361472FF" style="OLC">
							<paragraph id="HB8B29A3B2ABD43DD9FABAB1CE1D79B3F"><enum>(9)</enum><header>List of conditions for clarification of the definition of a severe or disabling chronic conditions
			 specialized needs individual</header>
 <subparagraph id="H0CEEC69467F34C3CBC8B6BC6F76C2942"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2020, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary shall convene a panel of clinical advisors to establish and update a list of conditions that meet each of the following criteria:</text>
 <clause id="HF1F35FC1AE5747DD9C66589C66F0079A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Conditions that meet the definition of a severe or disabling chronic condition under subsection (b)(6)(B)(iii) on or after January 1, 2022.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFDD92A530AB444559DA23818ED8285AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Conditions that require prescription drugs, providers, and models of care that are unique to the specific population of enrollees in a specialized MA plan for special needs individuals described in such subsection on or after such date and—</text>
 <subclause id="HDD36D771255B463C94B6FD47DAEE289C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as a result of such special needs individuals with such a condition having access to and being enrolled in such a plan, as compared to access to and enrollment in other Medicare Advantage plans under this part, it is projected that such individuals would improve health outcomes with respect to such condition, that such individuals would have reduced overall costs under this title, and that there would not be any increase in expenditures under this title for such individuals; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HD2EFE5B11295463D866C45914CB0D290"><enum>(II)</enum><text>have a low prevalence in the general population of beneficiaries under this title or a disproportionally high per-beneficiary cost under this title.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H778C4AEDED3D4B15A959EA21ED468F9F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>GAO Study on Health Outcomes of Individuals Enrolled in Specialized MA plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the date that is 3 years after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study and submit to Congress a report on the extent to which health outcomes can be compared across specialized MA plans for special needs individuals (as defined in section 1859(b)(6)) and other Medicare Advantage plans under this part across similar populations, using existing measures and that identifies any potential limitations where new measures may need to be developed for such population.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HAE04C7DDCED34184B35DF1EAA806F21C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Quality measurement at the plan level for SNPs and determination of feasability of quality
 measurement at the plan level for all MA plans</header><text>Section 1853(o) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-23">42 U.S.C. 1395w–23(o)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H97F7BBEFCD1F4537963AC61E63B80EE3" style="OLC">
					<paragraph commented="no" id="HBB0D5A2F0C6241EABC50085EC20FF452"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Quality measurement at the plan level for SNPs</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HD3CF99194ABF47D69528E284E6644224"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary may require reporting of data under section 1852(e) for, and apply under this subsection, quality measures at the plan level for specialized MA plans for special needs individuals instead of at the contract level.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB2A88E954F1C4A28B1FBD1001ECC0098"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>Prior to applying quality measurement at the plan level under this paragraph, the Secretary shall—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H83D0345FD0044DCFA08E5AFEB9F77229"><enum>(i)</enum><text>take into consideration the minimum number of enrollees in a specialized MA plan for special needs individuals in order to determine if a statistically significant or valid measurement of quality at the plan level is possible under this paragraph;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H2DFD627F345A41CDBF29934ECB6EE7FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if quality measures are reported at the plan level, ensure that MA plans are not required to provide duplicative information; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HB2C2695AB75241A18A5811D6D99E3927"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ensure that such reporting does not interfere with the collection of encounter data submitted by MA organizations or the administration of any changes to the program under this part as a result of the collection of such data.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4F05CD28A0CD4E12B0CCD21B4E361178"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application</header><text>If the Secretary applies quality measurement at the plan level under this paragraph—</text> <clause id="HA64D1C57880347D9958FDC8016DC405C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such quality measurement may include Medicare Health Outcomes Survey (HOS), Healthcare Effectiveness Data and Information Set (HEDIS), Consumer Assessment of Healthcare Providers and Systems (CAHPS) measures and quality measures under part D; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFDFC8D18DF6F4C49B4C4DEE4CF5BDF2D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary shall consider applying administrative actions, such as remedies described in section 1857(g)(2), to the plan level.</text>
							</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H812A71E05EDA4FE6AA2FD1CD07E14617"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Determination of feasibility of quality measurement at the plan level for all MA plans</header>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H69EB991094EA40B1BE7AC0E6BD396161"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Determination of feasibility</header><text>The Secretary shall determine the feasibility of requiring reporting of data under section 1852(e) for, and applying under this subsection, quality measures at the plan level for all MA plans under this part.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7C8F08609CD4D32A2717F9B816A4C27"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consideration of change</header><text>After making a determination under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall consider requiring such reporting and applying such quality measures at the plan level as described in such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H3B9861DEEB694C4CAF6929B9699A1AA4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>GAO study and report on State-Level integration between dual SNPs and Medicaid</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H5CD0087A75B64D86AFF962F12063DF31"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States (in this paragraph referred to as the <quote>Comptroller General</quote>) shall conduct a study on State-level integration between specialized MA plans for special needs individuals described in subsection (b)(6)(B)(ii) of section 1859 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-28">42 U.S.C. 1395w–28</external-xref>) and the Medicaid program under title XIX of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</external-xref> et seq.). Such study shall include an analysis of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H1D06E5F69DE0411AABFB68FA40B1A427"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The characteristics of States in which the State agency responsible for administering the State plan under such title XIX has a contract with such a specialized MA plan and that delivers long-term services and supports under the State plan under such title XIX through a managed care program, including the requirements under such State plan with respect to long-term services and supports.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H06377AB8E8374DD1A44841FB3FEC35A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The types of such specialized MA plans, which may include the following:</text> <clause commented="no" id="H539A56612973431E99D3C8F92AB7C718"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A plan described in section 1853(a)(1)(B)(iv)(II) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-23">42 U.S.C. 1395w–23(a)(1)(B)(iv)(II)</external-xref>).</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HF49E3FC2A58D49C2812CDF4EE0B4B06C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A plan that meets the requirements described in subsection (f)(3)(D) of such section 1859.</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H8942D305E86A4A6A89DBD2681995F103"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A plan described in clause (ii) that also meets additional requirements established by the State.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HABEE86047D994D9EB227C019E3D92560"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The characteristics of individuals enrolled in such specialized MA plans.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3FF734FB5A454AABA7B9FFFE9546F566"><enum>(D)</enum><text>As practicable, the following with respect to State programs for the delivery of long-term services and supports under such title XIX through a managed care program:</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HBC53AFEA603A43E48A134F337FC80A2B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Which populations of individuals are eligible to receive such services and supports.</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H76D7F77B178D4E38B6CF5681138084AC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Whether all such services and supports are provided on a capitated basis or if any of such services and supports are carved out and provided through fee-for-service.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H43DB8A15294E49619E5A4E1C9EA40B1A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>As, practicable, how the availability and variation of integration arrangements of such specialized MA plans offered in States affects spending, service delivery options, access to community-based care, and utilization of care.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H36EA3AF170ED448B82BD3F3656E2A45B"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Barriers and opportunities for making further progress on dual integration, as well as recommend legislation to expedite or refine pathways toward fully integrated care.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H141C82EADB9947549300C1BE3036AA24"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Comptroller General determines appropriate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HF27A756874F949FABFFD175E9035444F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expanding supplemental benefits to meet the needs of chronically ill medicare advantage enrollees</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="HE1EA87D203064732AB6A34D9F81F09BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1852(a)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-22">42 U.S.C. 1395w–22(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H03DF7EE771664B25B656F26F61012A0D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Each</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subparagraph (D), each</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD5EC2F30A6724E5D8216D485D84DA5A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H64EC04267BF541BCACBC5ED8512ABCC3" style="OLC"> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HF6FD9AF2006F4339A78157CB37453A35"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Expanding supplemental benefits to meet the needs of chronically ill enrollees</header> <clause commented="no" id="H4ACC457B55A34D1E974DCCFB2FDAEB0F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For plan year 2020 and subsequent plan years, in addition to any supplemental health care benefits otherwise provided under this paragraph, an MA plan, including a specialized MA plan for special needs individuals described in subsection (b)(6) of section 1859, may provide supplemental benefits described in clause (ii) to a chronically ill enrollee (as defined in clause (iii)).</text>
							</clause><clause commented="no" id="H5CC9E350A0514217AD093E6CAC82FC75"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Supplemental benefits described</header>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H7C85D1A482DF40A1B965B4DBAA3690D2"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Supplemental benefits described in this clause are supplemental benefits that, with respect to a chronically ill enrollee, have a reasonable expectation of improving or maintaining the health or overall function of the chronically ill enrollee and may not be limited to being primarily health related benefits.</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HC1A08D3658394A0286A71B4A70C13E17"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Authority to waive uniformity requirements</header><text>The Secretary may, with respect to supplemental benefits provided to a chronically ill enrollee under this subparagraph, waive the uniformity requirement, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HD58C5DB604884885BF32B0DCE972AD70"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Chronically ill enrollee defined</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>chronically ill enrollee</term> means an enrollee in an MA plan that the Secretary determines—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H09B91CB175764FC6A0DBA6370015D878"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has one or more comorbid and medically complex chronic conditions that is life threatening or significantly limits the overall health or function of the enrollee;</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H48D6618B48B04A368DA2D7250AE84432"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has a high risk of hospitalization or other adverse health outcomes; or</text> </subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H33E9878D4CBE4E7E8D1DB675BA330F57"><enum>(III)</enum><text>requires intensive care coordination.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H38CE0356CA6040CD88D05A0D755D8B8B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO Study and Report</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HF32DB5DC19CE47C7AC1EE3F90ED4EFCE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Comptroller General</quote>) shall conduct a study on supplemental benefits provided to enrollees in Medicare Advantage plans under part C of title XVIII of the Social Security Act, including specialized MA plans for special needs individuals described in section 1859(b)(6) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-28">42 U.S.C. 1395w–28(b)(6)</external-xref>). Such study shall be conducted in consultation with the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services and Medicare Advantage plans as necessary and, to the extent data is available, shall include an analysis of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="H910AE127174C460B99D48FFA405673C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The type of supplemental benefits provided to such enrollees, the total number of enrollees receiving each supplemental benefit, and whether the supplemental benefit is covered by the standard benchmark cost of the benefit or with an additional premium.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5F0B141DEAA047328115EFFD3F1E81A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The frequency in which supplemental benefits are utilized by such enrollees.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H694EC0ACDB3D4CEBA9D4507E5D174CEC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The impact supplemental benefits have on—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H15728F7C28D54059B73A7451D9764F2D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>indicators of the quality of care received by such enrollees, including overall health and function of the enrollees;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HEF5DF330ADF44AE197A191C953D53A51"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the utilization of items and services for which benefits are available under the original Medicare fee-for-service program option under parts A and B of such title XVIII by such enrollees; and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H9175219E0E5343F19C9964425E28AC38"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the amount of the bids submitted by Medicare Advantage Organizations for Medicare Advantage plans under such part C.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H80A07B3F3B9B4FA1B30A799D1139DEC1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of the study conducted under paragraph (1), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Comptroller General determines appropriate.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


