<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFC7D234497AC4CC285D843937E5D1E01" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2250 IH: Standard Data And Technology Advancement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2250</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170428">April 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001293">Mr. Bishop of Michigan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish consistent requirements for the electronic content and format of data used in the
			 administration of certain human services programs under the Social
			 Security Act.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H3451124A04FF49DD91160836CF092501" style="OLC">
 <section id="H7D2B057468F94895AAC5088E01E6FEA5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Standard Data And Technology Advancement Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Standard DATA Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HDB1F2626F26B43068B456F3AEB08BA96"><enum>2.</enum><header>Data standardization for improved data matching</header> <subsection id="HB0E9D125A3E74C2285A89E410B1EEAD0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part A of title XI of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1301—1320b–5) is amended by inserting after section 1121 the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H7C213661C54D430293E2890302E646E1" style="OLC">
					<section id="HFBBAA7CB2E5B4000B3055247326BC958"><enum>1121A.</enum><header>Data exchange standardization for improved interoperability</header>
						<subsection id="H05D1D9269F6544B1B9E773E434CFAC0B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation and use of data exchange standards</header>
 <paragraph id="H35D92A2321FC49FE8CA962DB1321AE90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The head of the department or agency responsible for administering a program funded under title III, IV, IX, XII, XVI, or subtitle A of title XX, or section 511, shall, in consultation with an interagency work group established by the Office of Management and Budget and considering State perspectives, designate data exchange standards for necessary categories of information that a State agency operating the program is required to electronically exchange with another State agency under applicable Federal law.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F19301628E7463A8580CD257BFC5829"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Data exchange standards must be nonproprietary and interoperable</header><text>The data exchange standards designated under paragraph (1) shall, to the extent practicable, be nonproprietary and interoperable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B72D2CC40C147F2BDB61B95B0DB16A7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other requirements</header><text>In designating data exchange standards under this subsection, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, incorporate—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFF5D9E9832CF4A91A21EE1C8BC3AD0B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>interoperable standards developed and maintained by an international voluntary consensus standards body, as defined by the Office of Management and Budget;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H815236BD09534F8D8B6965358B496B73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>interoperable standards developed and maintained by intergovernmental partnerships, such as the National Information Exchange Model; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE7D2322E3FF432195A1EA617753848D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>interoperable standards developed and maintained by Federal entities with authority over contracting and financial assistance.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6FE6238D42C44F77BE5C9417547A2BD1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Data exchange standards for Federal reporting</header>
 <paragraph id="H59F6408EAD5E4BB19086B4BF9E18AC3E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The head of the department or agency responsible for administering a program referred to in subsection (a)(1) shall, in consultation with an interagency work group established by the Office of Management and Budget, and considering State government perspectives, designate data exchange standards to govern Federal reporting and exchange requirements under applicable Federal law.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC288652C0799464AA8B6365CA392443E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The data exchange reporting standards required by paragraph (1) shall, to the extent practicable—</text> <subparagraph id="H960A4459C22749DAA1B60380220A7251"><enum>(A)</enum><text>incorporate a widely accepted, non-proprietary, searchable, computer-readable format;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB45A7BD4B96B40B79EC73DFCE96A0C3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be consistent with and implement applicable accounting principles;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE49C7439CB0A4901A96EFDCCE2884414"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be implemented in a manner that is cost-effective and improves program efficiency and effectiveness; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14B5544541C5472CB1D32E5C41F37F5C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>be capable of being continually upgraded as necessary.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE59E90B651E4339918D4E7D054002AB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Incorporation of nonproprietary standards</header><text>In designating data exchange standards under this subsection, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, incorporate existing nonproprietary standards, such as the eXtensible Markup Language.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H091F4774F9C146A7B671080B5F0F7DC4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require a change to existing data exchange standards for Federal reporting about a program referred to in subsection (a)(1), if the head of the department or agency responsible for administering the program finds the standards to be effective and efficient.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="H08094A79D5784960A57DF229BC321438"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming repeals and amendment</header>
 <paragraph id="H887BB6BE807243D3A7DB486F7993C315"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Conforming repeals</header><text>Section 105 of the Child and Family Services Improvement and Innovation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/34">Public Law 112–34</external-xref>), sections 2104 and 4003 of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/96">Public Law 112–96</external-xref>), and subpart 3 of part B of title IV, and section 911, of the Social Security Act are each repealed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA442E7D5549849AC8013AB9363851713"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 411 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/611">42 U.S.C. 611</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (d).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H57395370AA534B8B879D6E76A9F445AA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act and the amendments and repeals made by this Act shall take effect 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


