<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H15E5CA3492E843B99959E099E8F6F545" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 772 IH: Common Sense Nutrition Disclosure Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 772</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170131">January 31, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. McMorris Rodgers</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001269">Mr. Barletta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001294">Mr. Blum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001092">Mr. Collins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001093">Mr. Collins of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000290">Ms. Jenkins of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000588">Mr. Pearce</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000598">Mr. Rothfus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000820">Mrs. Mimi Walters of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000799">Mr. Walz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Y000066">Mr. Young of Iowa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to improve and clarify certain disclosure
			 requirements for restaurants and similar retail food establishments, and
			 to amend the authority to bring proceedings under section 403A.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1001425699904CCBA2FAFC6FE78323EC" style="OLC">
 <section id="H100F72D1B7A7433E89AA38A5C918949A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Common Sense Nutrition Disclosure Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HD6F6105725FA4CEC8755C66620BB8372"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amending certain disclosure requirements for restaurants and similar retail food establishments</header> <subsection id="HAB7E4813593A4525B1D4F0E1DB431FC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 403(q)(5)(H) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/343">21 U.S.C. 343(q)(5)(H)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC3365D28263F4438B31586DF0A2A690D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subclause (ii)—</text> <subparagraph id="HCBED99ED615D40549BE81BC8262A83D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in item (I)(aa), by striking <quote>the number of calories contained in the standard menu item, as usually prepared and offered for sale</quote> and inserting <quote>the number of calories contained in the whole standard menu item, or the number of servings (as reasonably determined by the restaurant or similar retail food establishment) and number of calories per serving, or the number of calories per the common unit division of the standard menu item, such as for a multiserving item that is typically divided before presentation to the consumer</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8562D69EF1A5419BB8A069E475FC86C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in item (II)(aa), by striking <quote>the number of calories contained in the standard menu item, as usually prepared and offered for sale</quote> and inserting <quote>the number of calories contained in the whole standard menu item, or the number of servings (as reasonably determined by the restaurant or similar retail food establishment) and number of calories per serving, or the number of calories per the common unit division of the standard menu item, such as for a multiserving item that is typically divided before presentation to the consumer</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB1BD33700DA4D168AEFE155DFF3FE17"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following flush text:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30EA112F25884FC8BC1DA9893D56B06B" style="OLC"> <quoted-block-continuation-text indent="paragraph" quoted-block-continuation-text-level="clause">In the case of restaurants or similar retail food establishments where the majority of orders are placed by customers who are off-premises at the time such order is placed, the information required to be disclosed under items (I) through (IV) may be provided by a remote-access menu (such as a menu available on the Internet) as the sole method of disclosure instead of on-premises writings.</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6603280B76E14EA2930D37471C2DA480"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subclause (iii)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB6AACCBADCA3466DBF1D2A1DBCAE25F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>either</quote> after <quote>a restaurant or similar retail food establishment shall</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB29535EA5E3D45B2B1B108E137192B21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or comply with subclause (ii)</quote> after <quote>per serving</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2216E2C5B2D44FD48621F893140EB17A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subclause (iv)—</text> <subparagraph id="H693CA399848D40679906B9DC32348752"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>For the purposes of this clause</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H78A26BAA055E4219BD154FAEEBC165A0" style="OLC">
 <subclause id="H66694C3663744D9589B3DB5DBA286A42" indent="up2"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this clause</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H991D069DC249476A904C7A68EF44BFA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and other reasonable means</quote> and inserting <quote>or other reasonable means</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92BEAC082EEA4488BE2A2A310319C7A4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB61DDA27CAFA48678ACAF1161E5B215D" style="OLC"> <subclause id="H3C9236920E154F73B761AC8FB0AB481F" indent="up2"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Permissible variation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the restaurant or similar food establishment uses such means as the basis for its nutrient content disclosures, such disclosures shall be treated as having a reasonable basis even if such disclosures vary from actual nutrient content, including but not limited to variations in serving size, inadvertent human error in formulation or preparation of menu items, variations in ingredients, or other reasonable variations.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7394C289E55143919E9239AE9CE42C30"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by amending subclause (v) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H44C583CF51B045F78AFF44AA88826D7B" style="OLC"> <clause commented="no" id="HA4509BE757AD45298A55409ED7354A1E" indent="up2"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Menu variability and combination meals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish by regulation standards for determining and disclosing the nutrient content for standard menu items that come in different flavors, varieties, or combinations, but which are listed as a single menu item, such as soft drinks, ice cream, pizza, doughnuts, or children's combination meals. Such standards shall allow a restaurant or similar retail food establishment to choose whether to determine and disclose such content for the whole standard menu item, for a serving or common unit division thereof, or for a serving or common unit division thereof accompanied by the number of servings or common unit divisions in the whole standard menu item. Such standards shall allow a restaurant or similar retail food establishment to determine and disclose such content by using any of the following methods: ranges, averages, individual labeling of flavors or components, or labeling of one preset standard build. In addition to such methods, the Secretary may allow the use of other methods, to be determined by the Secretary, for which there is a reasonable basis (as such term is defined in subclause (iv)(II)).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD816A653CBE54D18B28F03CF6911C544"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subclause (x)—</text> <subparagraph id="H3C1FAC3D91804FA484378E92F82C8951"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this clause, the Secretary shall promulgate proposed regulations to carry out this clause.</quote> and inserting <quote>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Common Sense Nutrition Disclosure Act of 2017</short-title>, the Secretary shall issue proposed regulations to carry out this clause, as amended by such Act. Any final regulations that are promulgated pursuant to the <short-title>Common Sense Nutrition Disclosure Act of 2017</short-title>, and any final regulations that were promulgated pursuant to this clause before the date of enactment of the Common Sense Nutrition Disclosure Act of 2017, shall not take effect earlier than 2 years after the promulgation of final regulations pursuant to the Common Sense Nutrition Disclosure Act of 2017.</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BDFBC58BD904EC6B585CBB232E2C3B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H5E87380E40FB46A7BEA7078602197344" style="OLC"> <subclause id="H6C8FDA71A74043D392E8841F887EA6A4" indent="up2"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Certifications</header><text>Restaurants and similar retail food establishments shall not be required to provide certifications or similar signed statements relating to compliance with the requirements of this clause.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1165CE3631B74AA39E240D40094C5A7C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by amending subclause (xi) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B230422C5AF4578B18BAF53E9A9A3A7" style="OLC"> <clause id="H87A58C98D0A24740A284D8F9C3945CEF" indent="up2"><enum>(xi)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this clause:</text>
 <subclause commented="no" id="H4F37BB8FFEA74CF4880B166C0658FA51"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Menu; menu board</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>menu</quote> or <quote>menu board</quote> means the one listing of items which the restaurant or similar retail food establishment reasonably believes to be, and designates as, the primary listing from which customers make a selection in placing an order. The ability to order from an advertisement, coupon, flyer, window display, packaging, social media, or other similar writing does not make the writing a menu or menu board.</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H8829DEB95E8D4FE0B984539748E9CEA0"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Preset standard build</header><text>The term <quote>preset standard build</quote> means the finished version of a menu item most commonly ordered by consumers.</text> </subclause><subclause id="H595FDA3C8A204E98BC17D81704139E0F"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Standard menu item</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>standard menu item</quote> means a food item of the type described in subclause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (5)(A) with the same recipe prepared in substantially the same way with substantially the same food components that—</text>
 <item id="H3A4867EA7D3D48E38227D731E780E245"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is routinely included on a menu or menu board or routinely offered as a self-service food or food on display at 20 or more locations doing business under the same name; and</text>
 </item><item id="H078C632B389C4F6181498FDAABFA1429"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is not a food referenced in subclause (vii).</text></item></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8F2F61C5FE304935AF7DA23CDDE5621B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block id="H0C5BBEFE67D444C0B761A5C52387D299" style="OLC">
 <clause commented="no" id="H87827D0E64F94D57B29DBCB6D32FFCF5" indent="up2"><enum>(xii)</enum><header>Opportunity to correct violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any restaurant or similar retail food establishment that the Secretary determines is in violation of this clause shall have 90 days after receiving notification of the violation to correct the violation. The Secretary shall take no enforcement action, including the issuance of any public letter, for violations that are corrected within such 90-day period.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H40CD097C520A4729805501957528A9B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National uniformity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 403A(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/343-1">21 U.S.C. 343–1(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>may exempt from subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>may exempt from subsection (a) (other than subsection (a)(4))</quote>.</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H049E2DCA38CD4DDE92EB7327D234E4FF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation on liability for damages arising from noncompliance with nutrition labeling requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 403(q)(5)(H) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/343">21 U.S.C. 343(q)(5)(H)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9828667ADB9146BDAEFC7D697110E54D" style="OLC">
 <clause commented="no" id="H95E397E1145740F29F75CC838D782848" indent="up2"><enum>(xiii)</enum><header>Limitation on liability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A restaurant or similar retail food establishment shall not be liable in any civil action in Federal or State court (other than an action brought by the United States or a State) for any claims arising out of an alleged violation of—</text>
 <subclause id="HE7EE7C38B1E2424A99AA8E5FC941A59C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>this clause; or</text> </subclause><subclause id="HD04213BA1AE94A979005AFF6FF7F5AC5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any State law permitted under section 403A(a)(4).</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


