<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB42FD0D3D2C341208A831348E76E1CAA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2176 IH: Asia-Pacific Defense Commission Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2176</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170426">April 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001202">Mrs. Murphy of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001245">Ms. Bordallo</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the establishment of an Asia-Pacific Defense Commission to enhance defense cooperation between the United States and allies in the Asia-Pacific region, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4E8E656D492342E4A3BAB8A9B570B43E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H649FE7AC0F16458EA61C71652A147D64" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Asia-Pacific Defense Commission Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H35F93125AD454CCCAE4CC82429085259"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HDFB9B267ABBF48B88E2C95A1662F33FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States has worked cooperatively with its allies and partners in the Asia-Pacific region for decades on issues of mutual concern having regional and global strategic and economic importance, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H23F304D6306E4D61B0BC6641A7C61078"><enum>(A)</enum><text>deterring and confronting external aggression against allies and partners;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E4B8FF3A92C486994837F48C7A5C79D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensuring the free flow of energy and commerce, and freedom of navigation in international waters;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBFFFB9CC50C7494CAF7BC3DB077BF391"><enum>(C)</enum><text>dismantling terrorist networks that threaten the safety of the region; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC3F721B7EAC247FF9DD9FA7DBE195235"><enum>(D)</enum><text>preventing the development, use, and proliferation of weapons of mass destruction;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H55EDD5E1D7A94F1CA68292ABC3D7894D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>adapting to climate change and severe weather events, including cooperation on humanitarian assistance and disaster response; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4B08AB258766441C890D4C08CBD91F55"><enum>(F)</enum><text>promoting respect for the international liberal order based on commonly respected norms and values.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4103BC49FDC04287B0C68969C144EBB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The close security relationships between the United States and its five treaty allies in the Asia-Pacific region—Australia, Japan, the Philippines, South Korea and Thailand—as well as the security relationships between the United States and its non-alliance security partners in the region remain vital to the United States national interest and a cornerstone of regional stability.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA1290A3B1E2D47E3A5DDB89D8920835C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States opposes North Korea’s illegal and reckless pursuit of nuclear weapons.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H242F8CE0F0CE467A84DD4A83A87B0288"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Countering North Korea’s destabilizing activities in the region by diplomatic, economic, and defensive means is a top national security issue for the United States as the threat posed by North Korea endangers United States allies, threatens to destabilize the Asia-Pacific region, and if unchecked, poses a grave nuclear proliferation challenge to the world.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H9766F6EB327C4225BC7797FEBD2BB89F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of Asia-Pacific Defense Commission</header> 
<subsection id="HE26D2C372E514671BE8E142D6B981339" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header> 
<paragraph id="H58FD7819537D45E88B21635E011E67EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It is the policy of the United States to continue to maintain a strong military posture in the Asia-Pacific region in order to reassure United States allies, deter aggression, and respond swiftly to crises.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6951CAEC72A04154B8F2ADDC1B4AC6D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enhanced military training and exercises</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall seek opportunities to enhance military training and exercises with United States allies in the Asia-Pacific region to deepen cooperation between the militaries of the United States and such allies, to expand operational capabilities, and to encourage respect for human rights and the rule of law.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB877D0E873904E1EA893841B5D87FA75"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Joint defense commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may establish a regional joint defense commission to be known as the Asia-Pacific Defense Commission. The purpose of the commission shall be to strengthen cooperation between the United States and its allies in the Asia-Pacific region to combat joint threats. The commission may undertake the following activities:</text> <paragraph id="H476985CF2CB84054972E2D07F7D2C652"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Strengthening counterterrorism operations and building capacity to track, investigate, and prosecute individuals engaged in terrorist activities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE0706DC13F1E4460B104F8AF1E0529F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Improving regional maritime security and capabilities to interdict illegal arms shipments.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD14429A50E7B4C899A2C46F34FE57C28"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Bolstering regional cybersecurity initiatives and protecting critical infrastructure.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC482046CF6964C179D5A604052D64929"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Strengthening military preparedness.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3838E8427A314D068DF276FE954B2A84"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Facilitating defense-related transfers, subject to the requirements of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2751">22 U.S.C. 2751</external-xref> et seq.).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H661CE6172B264FE9AED9011F1FEDCA34"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Facilitating efforts to enhance training, preparedness, and operations by allies to address North Korean maritime weapons transfers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE02A8D682C754149B1481EBB40779939"><enum>(7)</enum><text> Coordinating intelligence collected by the intelligence services of the countries participating in the commission, identify the most immediate threats to inform the security services of such countries, and create guidelines for the coordination of multilateral direct action against shared threats.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCA271909AA864296832041BF64D3EF7D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Asia-Pacific Region</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>Asia-Pacific region</term> means the region corresponding to the area of responsibility of the United States Pacific Command, as defined by the Department of Defense unified command plan.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3F212974C08943218D867B133453378F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the United States Navy should regularize freedom of navigation operations, in accordance with international law, in the Japanese-administered Senkaku Islands, in the South China Sea, and in regular ports of call at strategic ports in the Asia-Pacific region.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

