<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB600DA99186A417D9B861B0853CEA523" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 830 IH: STAND for Ukraine Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 830</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170202">February 2, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000179">Mr. Engel</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000620">Mr. Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000263">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001181">Mr. Meehan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000364">Mr. Shimkus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To contain, reverse, and deter Russian aggression in Ukraine, to assist Ukraine’s democratic
			 transition, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H761C7D403F1B47BB99DD9C530BEA8BBA" style="OLC">
		<section id="H093F81D9312A452DA0BAD06B91DCC41F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title and table of contents</header>
 <subsection id="H27248B04FB3E48F5A93515E8B2A57DEF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stability and Democracy for Ukraine Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>STAND for Ukraine Act</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H6AD929D5E802467D9FFCEEE2B7ADCF95"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
				<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
					<toc-entry idref="H093F81D9312A452DA0BAD06B91DCC41F" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and table of contents.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5C28D2C1B4BD4CF885021126C86CF0D1" level="section">Sec. 2. Statements of policy.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H04841326B79F422BB2A860F4E0D6FAF0" level="title">Title I—Crimea Annexation Non-Recognition</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HB3F5DCC24A7A41EDA80FAF3790D194C6" level="section">Sec. 101. United States policy against recognition of territorial changes effected by force alone.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H6AAED46C350744CB99F2105A0091B3D6" level="section">Sec. 102. Prohibitions against United States recognition of the Russian Federation’s annexation of
			 Crimea.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H5FDB1E9989A048F79D2DCB9D5F1E1A34" level="section">Sec. 103. Determinations and codification of sanctions under Executive Order No. 13685.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HF7CD06D5FB2A439191C1E62FD432A2EF" level="title">Title II—Sanctions provisions</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H0A9B45E40C254BE2B65BC9054D261C54" level="section">Sec. 201. Prohibiting certain transactions with foreign sanctions evaders and serious human rights
			 abusers with respect to the Russian Federation.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="HCE94FDD2123A4856A31E6471762B40F7" level="section">Sec. 202. Report on certain foreign financial institutions.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H0F4A53ECA97C4A098993BB1C566F9CEA" level="section">Sec. 203. Requirements relating to transfers of defense articles and defense services to the
			 Russian Federation.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H744F1AB07E734D2AA0E1782391B36A99" level="title">Title III—Other matters</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H2E5DF370E2B744DC9B9607D8A3534FB6" level="section">Sec. 301. Strategy to respond to Russian Federation-supported information and propaganda efforts
			 directed toward Russian-speaking communities in countries bordering the
			 Russian Federation.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H1D8153B993404AAEA966E8453FCA3F6A" level="section">Sec. 302. Cost limitation.</toc-entry>
					<toc-entry idref="H04308B920D6D487DAAAE72488EB13120" level="section">Sec. 303. Sunset.</toc-entry></toc>
			</subsection></section><section id="H5C28D2C1B4BD4CF885021126C86CF0D1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statements of policy</header>
 <subsection id="H39CD452959A14F5BB0039E39218F272F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It is the policy of the United States to further assist the Government of Ukraine in restoring its sovereignty and territorial integrity to contain, reverse, and deter Russian aggression in Ukraine. That policy shall be carried into effect, among other things, through a comprehensive effort, in coordination with allies and partners of the United States where appropriate, that includes sanctions, diplomacy, and assistance, including lethal defensive weapons systems, for the people of Ukraine intended to enhance their ability to consolidate a rule of law-based democracy with a free market economy and to exercise their right under international law to self-defense.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4692E8565D354FCE9D2EB52C2E451217"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional statement of policy</header><text>It is further the policy of the United States—</text> <paragraph id="H18A0004547844A9B821F7B4DE74A5AE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to use its voice, vote, and influence in international fora to encourage others to provide assistance that is similar to assistance described in subsection (a) to Ukraine; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H536E9D2DC3094A508306CA556A16E1F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to ensure that any relevant sanctions relief for the Russian Federation is contingent on timely, complete, and verifiable implementation of the Minsk Agreements, especially the restoration of Ukraine’s control of the entirety of its eastern border with the Russian Federation in the conflict zone.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><title id="H04841326B79F422BB2A860F4E0D6FAF0"><enum>I</enum><header>Crimea Annexation Non-Recognition</header>
 <section id="HB3F5DCC24A7A41EDA80FAF3790D194C6"><enum>101.</enum><header>United States policy against recognition of territorial changes effected by force alone</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Between the years of 1940 and 1991, the United States did not recognize the forcible incorporation and annexation of the three Baltic States of Lithuania, Latvia, and Estonia into the Soviet Union under a policy known as the <quote>Stimson Doctrine</quote>.</text>
			</section><section id="H6AAED46C350744CB99F2105A0091B3D6"><enum>102.</enum><header>Prohibitions against United States recognition of the Russian Federation’s annexation of Crimea</header>
 <subsection id="H388639CCB45543449F6DB1C2D6623428"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with United States policy enumerated in section 101, no Federal department or agency should take any action or extend any assistance that recognizes or implies any recognition of the de jure or de facto sovereignty of the Russian Federation over Crimea, its airspace, or its territorial waters.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H05237C51EAF14A97809EE36249B2FA6C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Documents portraying crimea as part of russian federation</header><text>In accordance with United States policy enumerated in section 101, the Government Publishing Office should not print any map, document, record, or other paper of the United States portraying or otherwise indicating Crimea as part of the territory of the Russian Federation.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="H5FDB1E9989A048F79D2DCB9D5F1E1A34"><enum>103.</enum><header>Determinations and codification of sanctions under Executive Order No. 13685</header>
				<subsection id="HEE26E0CC49BB47B68A6232E690428678"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Determinations</header>
 <paragraph id="HCB241F7D269D4D2686B4B0D328FE8ABE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains the assessment described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H352641391EC74702A42F5D6036445F7C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assessment described</header><text>The assessment described in this paragraph is—</text> <subparagraph id="HC2641345E6564878972D1977003D53AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a review of each person designated pursuant to Executive Order No. 13660 (March 6, 2014; 79 Fed. Reg. 13493; relating to blocking property of certain persons contributing to the situation in Ukraine) or Executive Order No. 13661 (March 16, 2014; 79 Fed. Reg. 15535; relating to blocking property of additional persons contributing to the situation in Ukraine); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E843CA693404141887FC05F39BE7861"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a determination as to whether any such person meets the criteria for designation pursuant to Executive Order No. 13685 (December 19, 2014; 79 Fed. Reg. 77357; relating to blocking property of certain persons and prohibiting certain transactions with respect to the Crimea region of Ukraine).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B73FC8DF4C142B8B4C84750E8CD52AB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The assessment required by paragraph (2) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5762847393F54983A78176B4B73C8D4E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Codification</header><text>United States sanctions provided for in Executive Order No. 13685, as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act, shall remain in effect until the date on which the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees a certification described in subsection (c).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H09C5AB745643443F8B9266C2BCB59FCD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>A certification described in this subsection is a certification of the President that Ukraine’s sovereignty over Crimea has been restored.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB0248672D2354E1E90937DE018039694"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to restrict the authority of the President to impose additional United States sanctions with specific respect to the Russian Federation’s occupation of Crimea pursuant to Executive Order No. 13685.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0E013C2B0CEC4E1F84583395CF071692"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="HBF25BBABC52F410EA8D1A08A6D09535B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBF36032E22724B5CB685008C988C7C3A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="HF7CD06D5FB2A439191C1E62FD432A2EF"><enum>II</enum><header>Sanctions provisions</header>
			<section id="H0A9B45E40C254BE2B65BC9054D261C54"><enum>201.</enum><header>Prohibiting certain transactions with foreign sanctions evaders and serious human rights abusers
 with respect to the Russian Federation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Support for the Sovereignty, Integrity, Democracy, and Economic Stability of Ukraine Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/95">Public Law 113–95</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8901">22 U.S.C. 8901</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new sections:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H3028084199094694B27CEF93A1F30622" style="OLC">
					<section id="H54C860B7659743C49B7CBBAB56DC6A73"><enum>10.</enum><header>Prohibiting certain transactions with foreign sanctions evaders with respect to the Russian
			 Federation</header>
 <subsection id="H6317FCDD18EF40D3A7E7A0A44BE87EAF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President is authorized to impose with respect to a foreign person the sanctions described in subsection (b) if the President determines that the foreign person knowingly—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9DBBC69F6B4B44B893DD41435D15E144"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has materially violated, attempted to violate, conspired to violate, or caused a violation of any license, order, regulation, or prohibition contained in, or issued pursuant to any covered Executive order; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD38FE28B2B924667A11942620F86756F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has facilitated significant deceptive or structured transactions for or on behalf of any person subject to United States sanctions concerning the Russian Federation.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H69CC8B575B64472F9B6EEB1AC0C5911D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header>
 <paragraph id="H0A45C72F093C42A594874B34779638E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the exercise of all powers granted to the President by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of a person determined by the President to be subject to subsection (a) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H38DFE2BF76764D7089EF560E782DE053"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that is subject to sanctions described in paragraph (1) shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C446A76821D4CE38EBE9E3A801B8870"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under subsection (b) on a case-by-case for a period of not more than 120 days, and may renew that waiver for additional periods of not more than 120 days with respect to a person if the President determines that such a waiver is in the national interests of the United States and on or before the date on which the waiver takes effect, submits to the appropriate congressional committees a notice of and justification for the waiver.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE4D3827B05A24536AB55004BD287ECEE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation authority</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1702">50 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref> and 1704) for purposes of carrying out this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0AE3208C55DA4486BA1B7D245FC5CC76"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text>The President shall issue such regulations, licenses, and orders as are necessary to carry out this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC9107D11751348089717741612680373"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HA465597F4CC049E0B0CFE86DF906C28C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H9412C0F9E4044952AC37B5A5B080936D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1194640CC8F4476835FDC8B9E7C3EF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC87830F9D9C4D61829EF6687FED9814"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered executive order</header><text>The term <term>covered Executive order</term> means any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HFE461469E32C410BB48E9FC1B114F31D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Executive Order No. 13660 (March 6, 2014; 79 Fed. Reg. 13493; relating to blocking property of certain persons contributing to the situation in Ukraine).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB6516F3A4C84357BFC422323A98CAF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Executive Order No. 13661 (March 16, 2014; 79 Fed. Reg. 15535; relating to blocking property of additional persons contributing to the situation in Ukraine).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69C498CCADD74795BB335880FE912B59"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Executive Order No. 13685 (December 19, 2014; 79 Fed. Reg. 77357; relating to blocking property of certain persons and prohibiting certain transactions with respect to the Crimea region of Ukraine).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B0F3E2B228246CEB35FC88B7A9CB68D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> has the meaning given such term in section 595.304 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B07F036C3164E679349D16583FAAADC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Structured</header><text>The term <quote>structured</quote>, with respect to a transaction, has the meaning given the term <quote>structure</quote> in paragraph (xx) of section 1010.100 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A867AD1F38F40E183348DE2B281D667"><enum>(5)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> has the meaning given such term in section 589.312 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4D69A01936E34CFABC91225825265FB6"><enum>11.</enum><header>Prohibiting certain transactions in areas controlled by the Russian Federation</header>
 <subsection id="HF1D714F00BD84DEB88BEBEDE2A1D16DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President is authorized to impose with respect to a foreign person the sanctions described in subsection (b) if the President determines that the foreign person, based on credible information—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5A4EA907990443A9892B76BAF5743AEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is responsible for, complicit in, or responsible for ordering, controlling, or otherwise directing, the commission of serious human rights abuses in any territory forcibly occupied or otherwise controlled by the Government of the Russian Federation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H04B63BF7C6A54E7BBD03DC31B2593F9F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to, a foreign person that is responsible for, complicit in, or responsible for ordering, controlling, or otherwise directing, the commission of serious human rights abuses in any territory forcibly occupied or otherwise controlled by the Government of the Russian Federation; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9556C8EDEB4540639CEA806C5A4C23B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is owned or controlled by a foreign person, or has acted or purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, a foreign person, that is responsible for, complicit in, or responsible for ordering, controlling, or otherwise directing, the commission of serious human rights abuses in any territory forcibly occupied or otherwise controlled by the Government of the Russian Federation.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC0A42999E5E044FA90C366FA749F0988"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header>
 <paragraph id="HB92F4633CE5C4AC58F955310D832FCFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the exercise of all powers granted to the President by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.), without regard to section 202 of such Act, to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of a person determined by the President to be subject to subsection (a) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD362A19ECADB4AA2BC0AEC09CFD61627"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that is subject to sanctions described in paragraph (1) shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2905FEBAE5BD4F57A81178747FB5FA5E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under subsection (b) on a case-by-case for a period of not more than 120 days, and may renew that waiver for additional periods of not more than 120 days with respect to a person if the President determines that such a waiver is in the national interests of the United States and on or before the date on which the waiver takes effect, submits to the appropriate congressional committees a notice of and justification for the waiver.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF905009EC3064A259B89949DEB6EA24C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation authority</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1702">50 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref> and 1704) for purposes of carrying out this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1F707273346D4C13AF9848E044ECE59B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text>The President shall issue such regulations, licenses, and orders as are necessary to carry out this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3AA6B5ED430A4ECDBE22A1582137BB7C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H141BD2DF85FB43DFA56B3C8EC5973AA8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2F68167A829341EEA4F922C40D2685BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56657C59723F491D9F8BE1B998C3C4EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8CBC10139224B138360CA240155F9B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> has the meaning given such term in section 595.304 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7AC19145FEA54E49A6415EFF8A1B3382"><enum>(3)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> has the meaning given such term in section 589.312 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </section><section id="HCE94FDD2123A4856A31E6471762B40F7"><enum>202.</enum><header>Report on certain foreign financial institutions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Support for the Sovereignty, Integrity, Democracy, and Economic Stability of Ukraine Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/95">Public Law 113–95</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8901">22 U.S.C. 8901</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 11 (as added by section 201 of this Act) the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HC76F0E0DCD574C0C8DF771485C9EB461" style="OLC">
					<section id="HF91A6E415181458FBE10C6D19032DCAC"><enum>12.</enum><header>Report on certain foreign financial institutions</header>
 <subsection id="HA68048E89FBD485581B4E9F49F7A616E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury shall jointly submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFF04C0BBFD4544C496FCD50139DAFFD7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">foreign financial institutions that are in direct control of assets owned or controlled by the Government of Ukraine in a manner determined by the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury to be in violation of the sovereignty, independence, or territorial integrity of Ukraine;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BA7CB943C3549A2854ADB9CD1F40127"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">foreign financial institutions that are directly or indirectly assisting or otherwise aiding the violation of sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity of Ukraine; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H581A885B74054A97AC7629AC287D8184"><enum>(3)</enum><text>foreign financial institutions determined by the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury to be complicit in illicit financial activity, including money laundering, financing of terrorism, transnational organized crime, or misappropriation of state assets, that are—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1E76A2DA1C29452F922FEA1B15E5E1DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>organized under the laws of the Russian Federation; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AAB39F1CC2E4B2AABDE47669CD467F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>owned or controlled by a foreign person whose property or interests in property have been blocked pursuant to any covered Executive order.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAAB1C7CD1BA94C73B51632D38B154588"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required to be submitted under this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3467348A866E474983E3D28E090E3916"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HA7A83564D0594D589259E7E55557F5AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE995B3980C1042F099A88EA7EEE68A6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Ways and Means, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1C8CB72DBAA41088C8AD9AC68D4F531"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H848C25A073E54AD3ABCA6FB751CFF2F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered executive order</header><text>The term <term>covered Executive order</term> has the meaning given the term in section 10(f) of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section><section id="H0F4A53ECA97C4A098993BB1C566F9CEA"><enum>203.</enum><header>Requirements relating to transfers of defense articles and defense services to the Russian Federation</header> <subsection id="HDB27FE65E61245F08763994DD1EF7772"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States to oppose the transfer of defense articles and defense services from any country that is a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) to, or on behalf of, the Russian Federation, during any period in which the Russian Federation forcibly occupies the territory of Ukraine or of a NATO member country.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF3FCFE7DD9274FB69BF053D89876E69C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adoption of NATO policy</header><text>The President shall use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States in NATO to seek the adoption of a policy by NATO that is consistent with the policy of the United States specified in subsection (a).</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="H9E9A6A5FD4AC4FE58E77063FBC2211E6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Monitoring and identification of transfers</header>
 <paragraph id="HAF0EB374F25C4B0F800B1D8EC0A1C885"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall direct the heads of the appropriate departments and agencies of the United States to identify those transfers of defense articles and defense services described in subsection (a) that are contrary to the policy of the United States specified in subsection (a).</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="H63F72ABDEC694794B52E46A81FA0D21E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header>
 <subparagraph id="H987F448A65FE49F09BB5D4DD74F8D277"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall submit a written report to the chairmen and ranking members of the appropriate committees of Congress within 5 days of the receipt of information indicating that a transfer described in paragraph (1) has occurred.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89EE4E4754E547D1866DFEC0D969DA20"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subparagraph (A) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF97BD3B984DC42198A20CB027FFBD67B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H85B67F2B59864C79BDA8E04710770091"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0D104B62445E456D94B4FB64F508A2F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E3E7B304964428A99A329F0D44E2FE3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB70F4DBDE46B44B1A35D4E8816A07A68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Defense articles and defense services</header><text>The terms <term>defense article</term> and <term>defense service</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 47 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2794">22 U.S.C. 2794</external-xref> note).</text>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H744F1AB07E734D2AA0E1782391B36A99"><enum>III</enum><header>Other matters</header>
			<section id="H2E5DF370E2B744DC9B9607D8A3534FB6"><enum>301.</enum><header>Strategy to respond to Russian Federation-supported information and propaganda efforts directed
			 toward Russian-speaking communities in countries bordering the Russian
			 Federation</header>
 <subsection id="HD00FCA9169F842D6A4B7A5E8D5708444"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall develop and implement a strategy to respond to Russian Federation-supported disinformation and propaganda efforts directed toward persons in countries bordering the Russian Federation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2AE8C35D937E4068B3CE2944A65FF6CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (a) should include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HBB9B9A0DA9584AA2AE0F8434ABC192DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Development of a response to propaganda and disinformation campaigns as an element of the ongoing crisis in Ukraine, specifically—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H323D150CD51E47A2A122CE13DE237E15"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assistance in building the capacity of the Ukrainian military to document conflict zones and disseminate information in real-time;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3E935676B1E406893CCA992C0C19706"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assistance in enhancing broadcast capacity with terrestrial television transmitters in Eastern Ukraine; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFECF43D151E4E80B3B728F9C7D8F138"><enum>(C)</enum><text>media training for officials of the Government of Ukraine.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2A1FCF118794712BC30806971FAA012"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Establishment of a partnership with partner governments and private-sector entities to provide Russian-language entertainment and news content to broadcasters in Russian-speaking communities bordering the Russian Federation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1C77A418DEF04641A984B7433D46D9D5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Assessment of the extent of Russian Federation influence in political parties, financial institutions, media organizations, and other entities seeking to exert political influence and sway public opinion in favor of Russian Federation policy across Europe.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09AFBD7D60D14915B11B2215A45EEBBB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the strategy required under subsection (a) and its implementation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H79CEA81FF5364F9788820A9EB76642E5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="HC78A5F8B3B4B4459934D0452439F6C38"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A91CBA34BE449B68DE5BA0740D5B52E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1D8153B993404AAEA966E8453FCA3F6A"><enum>302.</enum><header>Cost limitation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this Act and the amendments made by this Act. Such requirements shall be carried out using amounts otherwise authorized.</text>
 </section><section id="H04308B920D6D487DAAAE72488EB13120"><enum>303.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall cease to be effective beginning on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</section></title></legis-body></bill>


