<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2F03417E398D45F68FCB917DE6056873" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1413 IH: ENRICH Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1413</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170307">March 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000462">Mr. Tiberi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a grants program to develop and enhance integrated nutrition and physical activity curricula in medical schools.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4CC4F43896D74137BDCF491F7BB02677" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H437EE8A753774A1F9554010FADF47ACD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding Nutrition’s Role in Curricula and Healthcare Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>ENRICH Act</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H04D6CE2A2A86481EA3D40FDEA175A218"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HAB51E2DE07084CCEAD60034C16048DFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In 2012, United States health care spending was about $8,915 per resident and accounted for 17.2 percent of the Nation’s gross domestic product, which is among the highest of all industrialized countries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF97362397FAE499CAF202604341FEABB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expenditures in the United States on health care surpassed $2.3 trillion in 2008, more than three times the $714 billion spent in 1990, and over eight times the $253 billion spent in 1980. Cardiovascular disease cost American’s $555 billion in 2016 alone. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF227E2DF7B034E1BA8F2966F421E9184"><enum>(3)</enum><text>It is estimated that health care costs for chronic disease treatment account for over 75 percent of national health expenditures.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB77B651955A24A298AC83F91966C667B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In March 2003, a report from the World Health Organization concluded diet was a major factor in the cause of chronic diseases.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H26D2E17E8A3E47C99D70C57B85D1B166"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Seven out of 10 deaths among Americans each year are from chronic diseases. Heart disease, cancer, and stroke—each of which has been strongly linked to dietary and lifestyle choices—account for more than 50 percent of all deaths each year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H49166B3A8178413C9022DD18264F84C7"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2015, 102.7 million people in the United States had at least one form of cardiovascular disease. Approximately 2,300 Americans die every day from cardiovascular disease. In 2010, cardiovascular disease cost American taxpayers $189.4 billion. The American Heart Association estimates that, by 2035, costs related to cardiovascular disease will triple to around $1.1 trillion. Research has shown that following a healthful diet can not only reduce symptoms related to heart disease but also reverse the damage done to the arteries.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H380E201083524797A90BF9E6134CA865"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Two-thirds of the American population is currently overweight, half of whom are obese. One in three children is now overweight, and one-fifth of children are obese. In 2008, the United States spent $190 billion on obesity-related health care costs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE87F640DFE3D4AC59158D00C2E0C3CA6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>An estimated 29 million Americans have diabetes. Another 86 million adults have prediabetes. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention predict that one in three children born in 2000 will develop diabetes at some point in their lives. Diabetes cost the government $116 billion in 2007. Research has shown that nutrition therapy is a key component of diabetes management and can improve clinical outcomes. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H65B03702C41D4B5486AC5A804BD60C37"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Cancer kills approximately 570,000 Americans each year, accounting for one in every four deaths. More than 1.5 million new cancer cases are diagnosed annually. In 2010, the direct costs of cancer were $102.8 billion and that number is expected to rise to $172 billion by 2020. More than 33 percent of cancers are diet related and could be prevented with a healthful diet.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2B8953716FEE4520B62FCD22EE3B8369"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eating is a complex social phenomenon influenced by family, social networks, culture, socioeconomic and educational status. An interprofessional approach to nutrition education for clinicians may not necessarily overcome these forces but may help the health professions team, including physicians and non-physicians, identify effective strategies for nutrition counseling and management.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47C7841EB994420A849F62049FAFD881"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Physicians are an important source of information and motivation for patients’ health behavior. Multiple studies have shown that physician counseling on weight loss increases the likelihood that patients will attempt weight loss, increase physical activity, improve diet, and lose weight.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D00E1381A934523AFD0DCB618F4B684"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Leading medical bodies recommend that physicians address diet with overweight patients. Guidelines from leading medical bodies such as the National Institutes of Health, the American Heart Association, the American College of Cardiology, and the Obesity Society recommend that physicians counsel overweight and obese patients on the benefits of lifestyle changes through lifestyle changes such as diet and physical activity.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HB9ADD6850E414E44980C131855EBFEDF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants program to develop or enhance integrated nutrition curricula in medical schools</header> 
<subsection id="HAFC00054171C4EEB9D4D511F663F62A8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration and in conjunction with the National Institutes of Health National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, shall establish a competitive grants program under which the Secretary may award grants to medical schools in the United States for the purpose described in subsection (b)(1).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H31EAF77335E34A1286CCE7612F75390D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of grant funds</header> <paragraph id="HDF89B278A57244F5B394C753A7C0DE63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A medical school receiving a grant under this section shall use the grant to create new or expand existing integrated nutrition and physical activity curriculum described in paragraph (2) for the medical school. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5B96950707742DE8B6D2BD45A5F3AAE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Integrated nutrition curriculum</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), an integrated nutrition and physical activity curriculum—</text> <subparagraph id="HC85E702C1FE04CFB88E2E4C74851DEAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be designed based on the best possible evidence to improve communication and provider preparedness in the prevention, management, and, as possible, reversal of obesity, cardiovascular disease, diabetes, and cancer; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB384CF5E157A4DA2BCE0744D0C2048EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall, to the greatest extent practicable, address such additional topics, including nutrition across the life cycle of individuals who are members of at-risk populations, physical activity training and programs for such individuals, food insecurity among such individuals, and malnutrition among such individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6912ADDE21734D55A89BCB4BD13189E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDFE908081CAA47EFBD51A59ED6EAAB8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be a medical school in the United States that is accredited by the Liaison Committee on Medical Education and Residency Program Accreditation Council for Graduate Education or by the American Osteopathic Association Commission on Osteopathic College Accreditation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC62D560C34A4C0D89AC70B4A236F30D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit an application to the Secretary, in accordance with such time, form, and manner and containing such information as specified by the Secretary, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H07A7411C0DDC40A6B815220B7237B206"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of how the medical school intends to implement the integrated nutrition and physical activity curriculum described in subsection (b)(2); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCBE755094EDE4F48B6F33DB2BE49E553"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of benchmarks to measure the success of the implementation of such curriculum.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H07DD686A6623460EA5905F848D93BD57"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header> 
<paragraph id="H66A34C96151B4B31911D10C4BDFED0A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Duration of Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded to a medical school under this section shall be for a three-year period, beginning on the date of the establishment of the grants program under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3BD1DFDD6BE846648314F700C0527DC9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header> <subparagraph id="H80338E9D806440DB9D87AA2E3270B4D5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Grant amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded to a medical school under this section may not exceed $500,000.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCD62B489302D4F288B3EF449744C2644"><enum>(B)</enum><header>One grant per school</header><text>A medical school shall not be eligible for more than one grant under this section and may not renew such a grant. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H437C9A2D10A244708FC66EAE23407ADD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants, the Secretary shall give priority to medical schools—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4E43F5B825974DEC806288E2B175BDCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that submit applications under subsection (c)(1) that describe an integrated nutrition and physical activity curriculum that will be implemented through the use of such a grant—</text> <clause id="HFCA40CBB39DF4B35916F0335004A1F22"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that is coordinated with a residency program; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H780DBDFDF4CE488784000C44CEB60001"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides that students of such school should receive at least 25 hours of nutrition education; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB0A8417DAF0C4DF5AC594277CCFCBE74"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that, for purposes of carrying out such curriculum through the use of such a grant, partner with education programs for both physicians and non-physician health professionals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3E446F14FC664AAFB10F48CA563BA165" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H1BC90CDAD992496789CBFE1DE2B01854" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Periodic reports during grants program</header> 
<subparagraph id="H8A0E74B12EBD40619E7D44560FAABA39" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each school year ending during the duration of the grants program under this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the grants program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H858BB316BD5443A59FC3E8906199982A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report Elements</header><text>Each such report shall include—</text> 
<clause id="HD86B9DEB64054DE7861480AD93B87B28" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the findings and conclusions of the Secretary with respect to the integration of nutrition and physical activity curriculum into the curriculum of the medical schools receiving a grant under the grants program;</text></clause> <clause id="H29919385FEE44117B014D8C31F484CFC" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an assessment of the benefits of the grants program for—</text> 
<subclause id="HA602F86FC62344E988CD09EE2DC2B7DF" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>establishing best practices for providers to advise patients in the clinical setting;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0F5405AA605343839695246F26A32B27" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>providing greater nutrition and physical activity awareness to physicians and other health professionals and patients of such physicians and professionals; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7EDF7002BC8F45AEB20A70522873A8B7" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>improving healthfulness of patients’ diets and improving patient health outcomes; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H9636D43ADD5148938A9797C95DEEC195"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">suggestions on how to promote the integration of nutrition curriculum in medical schools around the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB12B39C0B97D4FF39FB95F0783C750BA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the last day of the grants program under this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report detailing the recommendations of the Secretary as to any benefits or barriers of integrating nutrition and physical activity curriculum at both the medical school and residency levels.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDE8747FE068848A697E9DBA5015EABEA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to carry out the requirements of this section. The Secretary shall carry out such requirements by using, from amounts otherwise authorized or appropriated, up to $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2020.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

