<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H92EB752DCDCD4CE89878F2259E5171F7" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3261 IH: North Korea Follow the Money Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3261</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170714">July 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of National Intelligence to produce a national intelligence estimate of the
			 revenue sources of the North Korean regime, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H333E9E4809F44BF3BBE71EEF30B4703C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5FD8B1620C9246FC9CEEF1A18E493792" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>North Korea Follow the Money Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBFF90ECD659844B6ABF52A3C01E5677B"><enum>2.</enum><header>National intelligence estimate of North Korean sources of revenue</header> <subsection id="HEA6C84208BCE4FDD8FB4229B47AEFC34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="H2B5F110BF2B24157A3EF177D02E9CFC2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Although, as a result of the work of the Bureau on Energy and Resources, the Department of State has made significant progress in identifying North Korea’s revenues from coal exports, the United States Government as a whole lacks sufficient comprehension of how North Korea generates and expends revenue.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1DB8309DD77B4DFCA88A9B8876C30596"><enum>(2)</enum><text>It is critical to track the revenue sources of the North Korean regime in order to target sanctions and thwart further advancement of North Korea’s nuclear weapons program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H02B60537F9D445AAAF3B2004809C18A8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Specific information regarding revenue sources and means that the North Korean regime has for repatriating capital will allow sanctions experts at the Department of the Treasury and the Department of State to focus the full might of the financial power of the United States on stopping North Korea’s nuclear ambitions.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75D1678DEF364EC1A93F2B1F16AF785B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Estimate required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence, in coordination with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury, shall produce a national intelligence estimate of the revenue sources of the North Korean regime. Such estimate shall include revenue from the following sources:</text>
 <paragraph id="HE89ECECFD21347FC8EC3315C8ECEEBC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Trade in coal, iron, and iron ore.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H780BD966D8FD45C38F137CC6078A86CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The provision of fishing rights to North Korean territorial waters.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF2D716019434C6084273BAE15F8DFFC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Trade in gold, titanium ore, vanadium ore, copper, silver, nickel, zinc, or rare earth minerals, and other stores of value.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A5922E9C41A4194BF3F78E4502F4B0C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Trade in textiles.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC971DF87A614791977CA75BC3EAC554"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Sales of conventinal defense articles and services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCCA4D5D5DC244C9A8E8B9080E78634A0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Sales of controlled goods, ballistic missiles, and other associated purposes.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9B0129C7977442DDBD0DFDCDB0C4ED08"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other types of manufacturing for export, as the Director of National Intelligence considers appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H51E285E90D4E4A4C9AF1918D92CB9DDF"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exportation of workers from North Korea in a manner intended to generate significant revenue, directly or indirectly, for use by the government of North Korea.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5655EAFB700A4B8881A2AD7BD0E9AE23"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The provision of non-humanitarian goods (such as food, medicine, and medical devices) and services by other countries.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4746504A389E48908F1878A7978242C9"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The provision of services, including banking and other support, including by entities located in the Russian Federation, China, and Iran.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H656E3E30A626466394D39EF081F51132"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Online commercial activities of the Government of North Korea, including online gambling.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H36C46EBE9B5F486D979AEDAC45623958"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Criminal activities, including cyber-enabled crime and counterfeit goods.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H083F12737EDF4519A6E961DA4A56DB40"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The estimate required under subsection (b) shall include an identification of each of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HF78FE05CCAF049868C1587E3238C3573"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The sources of North Korea’s funding.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2E665CC9E5564E2184DC50021C75EC12"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Financial and non-financial networks, including supply chain management, transportation, and facilitation, through which North Korea accesses the United States and international financial systems and repatriates and exports capital, goods, and services; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H83624EBFC6F8468984D4125885D5DF3D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the global financial institutions, money services business, and payment systems that assist North Korea with financial transactions.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H493CAFD10918449F97D0536F75324BAD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Submittal to Congress</header><text>Upon completion of the estimate required under subsection (b), the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Development, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate a copy of such estimate.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


