<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H925502B753544DE7BB3D4657CD2750F1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3429 IH: Repatriate Our Patriots Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3429</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170726">July 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Gonzalez of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O'Rourke</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young of Alaska</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the removal from the United States of certain veterans, to expedite their
			 naturalization, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H203A7A8BFB124D208023E6900EB4F020" style="OLC">
 <section id="H56B0E9CEE8EE411692AC8E0D7E300524" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Repatriate Our Patriots Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H184E1ACB3CFC427985C7617E876631D8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>special veteran</quote> means an individual who is an alien and is described in section 101(2) of title 38, United States Code, except the term—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9D67779FA246471D867D6960C2876421"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">only includes individuals who were discharged or released from the Armed Forces under honorable conditions;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H788C13AC7775433AB3BE05D072F6332B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not include individuals who have been convicted of voluntary manslaughter, murder, rape, sexual abuse of a minor, or any offense under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/113B">chapter 113B</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code (relating to terrorism); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF89228ECAAC8438483D4A7122E6CA2C4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>does not include individuals who have been determined to be a child abuser or a pedophile.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H67D2B9260D9E4A09971FBDB415899704"><enum>3.</enum><header>Protecting special veterans from removal</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including section 237 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1227">8 U.S.C. 1227</external-xref>), a special veteran shall not be removed from the United States.</text>
		</section><section id="H00CA177391E34E348136F1A2743B5B0D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Naturalization for special veterans</header>
 <subsection id="H5602ACF6AC7144F5A30F3F6E9A1E0FED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a special veteran shall be naturalized as a citizen of the United States upon the filing of the appropriate application, paying the appropriate fees, and, except as provided in subsection (b), taking and subscribing before an officer of the Department of Homeland Security within the United States to the oath of allegiance required by section 337 of the Immigration and Nationality (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1448">8 U.S.C. 1448</external-xref>). The Secretary of Homeland Security shall take steps to ensure that the period in which an application for naturalization under this section is pending does not exceed 90 days. The Secretary shall furnish each special veteran naturalized under this section with a certificate of citizenship.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE7BB09F6E677457888D335DF5A0A0545"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special veterans abroad</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a special veteran residing abroad, the application for naturalization may be filed from abroad, and the oath of allegiance described in subsection (a) may be subscribed to abroad at United States embassies, consulates, and, as practicable, United States military installations overseas pursuant to the procedures available under section 1701(d) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1443a">8 U.S.C. 1443a</external-xref>) for naturalization proceedings overseas for members of the Armed Forces and their spouses and children.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB8A3190B3D974B129A6AC4B14A362AA1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consistent with section 337(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1448">8 U.S.C. 1448(a)</external-xref>), the Secretary of Homeland Security may waive the taking of the oath of allegiance described in subsection (a) by a special veteran if, in the opinion of the Secretary, the special veteran is unable to understand, or to communicate an understanding of, its meaning because of a physical or developmental disability or mental impairment.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HBB4423C39D6D435D8C581D244370E835"><enum>5.</enum><header>Treatment of special veterans in removal proceedings or ordered removed</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the case of a special veteran in removal proceedings on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall cancel the removal of the special veteran. In the case of a special veteran who was ordered removed before the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall rescind any outstanding order of removal, and any finding that the special veteran is subject to removal or is inadmissible. In the case of a special veteran physically present in the United States whose status as an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence was rescinded before the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall allow the veteran to adjust status to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence without regard to any numerical limitation in the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </section><section id="H155BB9DBEA3F48FAB166008E61A23E9D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Return of special veterans removed from the United States</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a program and application procedure to permit special veterans removed from the United States before the date of the enactment of this Act to enter the United States as an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence without regard to any numerical limitation in the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </section><section id="HC8BD01AD19004D8FB41605498C4EB456"><enum>7.</enum><header>Access to military benefits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A special veteran who has been naturalized or has obtained the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence pursuant to this Act shall be eligible for all military and veterans benefits for which the special veteran would have been eligible if the special veteran had never been ordered removed, been removed, or voluntarily departed, from the United States.</text>
		</section><section id="H9189584CEBF54455A5E7AF9A9427A903"><enum>8.</enum><header>Identification of special veterans</header>
 <subsection id="H52B21478C00A482198F14C0CB99E1BBE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall identify immigration cases involving special veterans by—</text> <paragraph id="HA5DACC55C82C44448EBBE7EAEC7F8781"><enum>(1)</enum><text>inquiring of every alien processed prior to initiating removal proceedings whether the alien is a special veteran; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD32F8481D6254ECCAF2C56BFBE8CBEA2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>keeping records of special veterans who have been detained under the immigration laws, had removal proceedings against them initiated before the date of the enactment of this Act, or been removed before such date.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFCBDDB8114084B798647E87947CB94D8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Record annotation</header><text>When the Secretary has identified a case under subsection (a), the Secretary shall annotate all immigration and naturalization records of the Department of Homeland Security relating to the special veteran involved so as to reflect that identification and afford an opportunity to track the outcomes for the veteran. Such annotation shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC8E404544C2B4E14BF4CD76334DE1954"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the veteran’s branch of military service;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2A3AFAD70DF94BA088605ECF75DCD954"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether or not the veteran served during a period of military hostilities described in section 329 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1440">8 U.S.C. 1440</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F3697B1E09D43C6A2C62A407F9C09D6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the veteran’s immigration status at the time of enlistment.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

