<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H59C3BDE8C9FF48CF90653AB08B8B6EC1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2888 IH: Ste. Genevieve National Historical Park Establishment Act </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2888</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170612">June 12, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Ste. Genevieve National Historic Site in the State of Missouri, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H342A59CE6A454D7A8D446BF07652D296" style="OLC">
 <section id="H6AC76D41234146888EB9128CE95DD531" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ste. Genevieve National Historical Park Establishment Act </short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H6490907FABD940A0B91D69669C71DB73"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H5D6AB8D4B93845CA8E9FCD569D58794B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Historic district</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Historic District</term> means the Ste. Genevieve Historic District National Historic Landmark, as generally depicted on the Map.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H60F51D24CBED400F8332B8015BB7850F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Historical Park</header><text>The term <term>Historical Park</term> means the Ste. Genevieve National Historical Park established by section 3(a).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H07ABAF9E6D5F4CFE91E00CE5D162891D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>Map</term> means the map entitled <quote>Ste. Genevieve National Historical Park Proposed Boundary</quote>, numbered 571/132,626, and dated May 2016.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB99461D605D34B0A808B0142D63C6344"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H461DD8ACFAA243D2B41825D0ED1098CC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Special resource study</header><text>The term <term>special resource study</term> means the study entitled <quote>Ste. Genevieve Final Special Resources Study and Environmental Assessment, Missouri</quote> and dated May 2016.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5F555EB0802B4D19B9AE5A7B925ADE93"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Missouri.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H06AF60B2D1E94C9BA49C9DCE8CCC2809"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of the Ste. Genevieve National Historical Park</header> <subsection id="H794953C0A4A34B97A9D72C9401640618"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> <paragraph id="H02165A4DECD3440A9710D0D7337BE3B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), there is established the Ste. Genevieve National Historical Park in the State as a unit of the National Park System to preserve, protect, and interpret for the benefit of present and future generations the themes of French settlement, vernacular architecture, and community form and farming on the frontier associated with Ste. Genevieve.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H66B8E77AD1F84C769940EB9139C19CEA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conditions for establishment</header><text>The Historical Park shall not be established until the date on which the Secretary determines that—</text> <subparagraph id="HEDAE8844DEEE477DB6A9891D38688C0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sufficient land has been acquired for the Historical Park to constitute a manageable unit; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12081B4D5CB043D0B7AEA49603FC93DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary has entered into a written agreement providing that land owned by the State, the City of Ste. Genevieve, or other entity within the Historic District shall be managed consistent with the purposes of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H385DB60750B745569D07771A46DC809A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Boundaries</header><text>The boundaries of the Historical Park shall be the boundaries generally depicted on the Map.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HEAFCD4DFBDBD438E90C87B47BBB66325"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of map</header><text>The Map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HAC0D94F909984731AC821D3D92362B6A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Acquisition authority</header>
 <paragraph id="HF9FF743156A04DA391B04EF3FC396CF0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may acquire any land or interest in land located within the boundary of the Historical Park or any nationally significant property identified in the special resource study within the Historic District by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H12296BDC5938452CBFBB81EE0134FEE5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>donation;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87610D73BB0345139299E165A3AA6A51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>purchase with donated or appropriated funds; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CF327562C124B3482DD721093583854"><enum>(C)</enum><text>exchange.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF7266AF83C64919AEA2C1C4ABC61A01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Boundary revision</header><text>On the acquisition of any property within the Historic District under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall revise the boundary of the Historical Park to include the property.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75059D3DF2D040509A75C81019228436"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administration</header>
 <paragraph id="H65C77A39EC74456BAA7A90ACBD20BEAE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall administer the Historical Park in accordance with—</text> <subparagraph id="H6F8EE7F6BE794BE2B36594250C3BE4F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB18A4A385124F21979010924911AFAD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including—</text> <clause id="H93FCA34383784ED4807E53D9C347E532"><enum>(i)</enum><text>section 100101(a), chapter 1003, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753, and 102101 of title 54, United States Code; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H06A68BAD38AF4A7DBA4CC4A284FA6A88"><enum>(ii)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/3201">chapter 3201</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5B0A27E16FE4C778E0955A53B5FC692"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management plan</header> <subparagraph id="H4611708AFD804DDE8879803443FB665F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which funds are made available to prepare a general management plan for the Historical Park, the Secretary shall prepare the general management plan in accordance with section 100502 of title 54, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA4CDA495A2B4890BF85ABB41336F592"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text>On completion of the general management plan under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate the general management plan.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6659E9BB7F7B4BD9B21EEE058EC8DA0D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Related sites</header><text>The Secretary may provide interpretative tours and educational programs at related historic and cultural sites within the Historic District associated with the purposes for which the Historical Park is established.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC6608EAC0FB4282A8FE5C994B05EC10"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header>
 <paragraph id="H66A68E607D4747588D067DA2553E28AD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may provide technical assistance and enter into cooperative agreements with the owner of a nationally significant property within the Historical Park or the Historic District, to identify, mark, interpret, improve, and restore the property.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A5AE6D3706041D7B41594BAF5EF6304"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Right of access</header><text>A cooperative agreement entered into under paragraph (1) shall provide that the Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Park Service, shall have the right of access at all reasonable times to all public portions of the property covered by the agreement for the purposes of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF651684B58F643FCAD388ED1D7F55F32"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conducting visitors through the property; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27CD10DFEC5B4044AA98616A8AF892AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>interpreting the property for the public.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H21896F3FCD344B74B39BD1BA7A0F78A1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cost-sharing requirement</header>
 <subparagraph id="HB28DBFFE8AA6465FB69FAD1D1FEF7DB2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>The Federal share of the total cost of any activity carried out under a cooperative agreement entered into under this subsection shall be not more than 50 percent.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AB232DBF06B47E6BA9F55802F343BE1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Form of non-federal share</header><text>The non-Federal share of an activity carried out under a cooperative agreement entered into under this subsection may be in the form of donated property, goods, or services fairly valued.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFB955A8888B43489E60CE998C4CAA4F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Changes or alterations</header><text>No changes or alterations shall be made to any property or project covered by a cooperative agreement entered into under paragraph (1) unless the Secretary and the other party to the agreement agree to the changes or alterations.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52CBDC171D144ED69F6A36828D62BE8E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Conversion, use, or disposal</header><text>Any payment by the Secretary under this subsection shall be subject to an agreement that the conversion, use, or disposal of a property or project for purposes contrary to the purposes of this section, as determined by the Secretary, shall entitle the United States to reimbursement in any amount equal to the greater of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HACEC79A31A4F42FB8B022662842B0A35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amounts made available to the property or project by the United States; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B829608F1CF41A98C744230EA669624"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the portion of the increased value of the property or project attributable to the amounts made available under this subsection, as determined at the time of the conversion, use, or disposal.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDCC4F3A12D724FE6A46A312C0DE3E98E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limited role of the Secretary</header><text>Nothing in this Act authorizes the Secretary to assume overall financial responsibility for the operation, maintenance, or management of the Historic District.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


