<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HFD267E1772D342F0A8563F6D98774B7D" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4114 IH: Environmental Justice Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4114</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171024">October 24, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001200">Mr. McEachin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000390">Mr. Kihuen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require Federal agencies to address environmental justice, to require consideration of
			 cumulative impacts in certain permitting decisions, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H79A379A805C64F44B9354998076E3312" style="OLC">
 <section id="H1CEDF6F69F01481BB0A61C071F596CC1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Environmental Justice Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H06224506A13249028B8CAE859FC3D3FF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0C691EBEA8FB46569CDD88C44367CF27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to require Federal agencies to address and eliminate the disproportionate environmental and human health impacts on communities of color, indigenous communities, and low-income communities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H030B9F2C45DF405DBA30F1A28A8BCCE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to ensure that all Federal agencies develop and enforce rules, regulations, guidance, standards, policies, plans, and practices that promote environmental justice;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB11A09C9B6E34FFBB532DFB40FBA03D5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to increase cooperation and require coordination among Federal agencies in achieving environmental justice;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H60761C82EAF44E77AECE12B3E8ED266A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to provide to communities of color, indigenous communities, and low-income communities greater access to public information and opportunities for participation in decisionmaking affecting human health and the environment;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE71E2CDC47E449F8D1A8C78BB7D878F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to mitigate the inequitable distribution of the burdens and benefits of Federal programs having significant impacts on human health and the environment;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96651722B8B145CDB27626FA410C1902"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to require consideration of cumulative impacts in permitting decisions;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6BA3B9F4C3C7499FA812410783BA41B0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to clarify congressional intent to afford rights of action pursuant to certain statutes and common law claims; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD772C6708DF040A9A455686B0075862B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to allow a private right of action under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref> et seq.) to challenge discriminatory practices.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HD99E2617B6B9464A870ACBCA57B96D5F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H0253053392C148A498F1CB0F4773E817"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2FCD4CE0E8F848F5A00B720986AEC834"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Citizen science</header><text>The term <term>citizen science</term> means voluntary public participation in the scientific process and the incorporation of data and information generated outside of traditional institutional boundaries to address real-world problems in ways that may include formulating research questions, conducting scientific experiments, collecting and analyzing data, interpreting results, making new discoveries, developing technologies and applications, and solving complex problems, with an emphasis on the democratization of science and the engagement of diverse people and communities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBC714534F5CD4D619F725CE77AB5E979"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Community of color</header><text>The term <term>community of color</term> means any geographically distinct population with a substantial number of individuals who identify as black, African-American, Hispanic, Latino, Asian, Pacific Islander, or any other nonwhite race.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3632168AD9DE4DC7BB8A7AB09E38D194"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Environmental justice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>environmental justice</term> means the fair treatment and meaningful involvement of all individuals, regardless of race, color, national origin, educational level, or income, with respect to the development, implementation, and enforcement of environmental laws, regulations, and policies to ensure that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7E06DF3695CD447AA8770CD08876B762"><enum>(A)</enum><text>communities of color, indigenous communities, and low-income communities have access to public information and opportunities for meaningful public participation relating to human health and environmental planning, regulations, and enforcement;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF13DE5022AF74F4194D129A8BABAA401"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no community of color, indigenous community, or low-income community shall be exposed to a disproportionate burden of the negative human health and environmental impacts of pollution or other environmental hazards; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2F57A2567944DA7896638FAF9853613"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the 17 Principles of Environmental Justice written and adopted at the First National People of Color Environmental Leadership Summit held on October 24 through 27, 1991, in Washington, DC, are upheld.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF023B26BD4E494B823166307710BEB5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal agency</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H3826908D02E74510ADC7EA3AF94747DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each Federal agency represented on the Working Group; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08409F1FD5BC4348B131094191487766"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other Federal agency that the President may designate that carries out a Federal program or activity that substantially affects human health or the environment.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B44B13D58AA4857869EA91860F6A35F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Infrastructure</header><text>The term <term>infrastructure</term> means any system for safe drinking water, sewer collection, solid waste disposal, electricity generation, communication, or transportation access (including highways, airports, marine terminals, rail systems, and residential roads) that is used to effectively and safely support housing, an educational facility, a medical provider, a park or recreational facility, or local businesses.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5B2DFED1E1824860AC5DAA0693606BB1"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Publish</header><text>The term <term>publish</term> means to make publicly available in a form that is—</text> <subparagraph id="HE226DE0E504D4EFCA98E6306D5F393C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>generally accessible, including on the Internet and in public libraries; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC08C129CE304E20A8E914AC7B678CAA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>accessible for—</text> <clause id="H598BFCF6291B42FC8D9C80205AD8C1E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>individuals who are limited in English proficiency, in accordance with Executive Order 13166 (65 Fed. Reg. 50121 (August 16, 2000)); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H2A4345EE99834E47BCF7705D3D074D1E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>individuals with disabilities.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H051EB0FC405B4DB2866BE0454C55C720"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Working Group</header><text>The term <term>Working Group</term> means the interagency Federal Working Group on Environmental Justice convened under section 1–102 of Executive Order 12898 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> note; relating to Federal actions to address environmental justice in minority populations and low-income populations), as amended by Executive Order 12948 (60 Fed. Reg. 6381 (January 30, 1995)) and modified by section 4.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H5B785CBE3B054B768D4E3539CC6F70BC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Interagency Federal Working Group on Environmental Justice</header>
 <subsection id="H2AF816111ABE4D8DBAC55F845F1F2A21"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall convene, as appropriate to carry out this section, the Working Group.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H848BD094EB5340FDBD69D1F46E56F410"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="H658D74C421CF4187AED2A0BCBE62DFA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Working Group shall be comprised of the following (or a designee):</text> <subparagraph id="H1209A030E9104CF585EFE0335DAFA09B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D7D19F052CD43DC94CA49ECF0FB7B5D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary of Commerce.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D0737DE94914F2CAA9049D4AAD308C4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FBE369F3C204B4B8115AFA092A4CC97"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Secretary of Energy.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90D3E40105F44C4E99C4BE376F44F50C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FA0D1D98CC94D2ABD92E4456F8EEB77"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE193AD2A917344A89775E50B7129E0A4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H209E957251184DCDA12949ACD5C2919A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Interior.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC491B94B3D774A57996E40BDA98F9D76"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Secretary of Labor.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1C0FA4361EF40CDBA87F33DD40FA651"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The Secretary of Transportation.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA163AAB4860540DAB5CADB68D272D2D1"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The Attorney General.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AFB613F83214CF6990AAD0F6F153850"><enum>(L)</enum><text>The Administrator.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3711D838AFFE4329BBBE977083C4DBF4"><enum>(M)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Environmental Justice.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD355D4B5B52D4A3A995D49DE8BB1F629"><enum>(N)</enum><text>The Chairman of the Consumer Product Safety Commission.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H172ED13DF8204D008A04D0988D0D66CD"><enum>(O)</enum><text>The Chairperson of the Chemical Safety Board.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24CDB6A1213C4858A38876813573839D"><enum>(P)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H107AF4E5B1CD4233976CA4465EB78913"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2040DAECDE1C43F08264D365EEFF0BB5"><enum>(R)</enum><text>The Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DAFE0FB492E43A2B08719854406513A"><enum>(S)</enum><text>The Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE76FB525E6364C27A605B7E3D4403F68"><enum>(T)</enum><text>The Director of the National Economic Council.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B377509C00B402A86109413D0940E74"><enum>(U)</enum><text>The Chairman of the Council of Economic Advisers.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8106BF3C141546B0B032798523F0BA03"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Such other Federal officials as the President may designate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D495F84BBBC4B93A56370232944F175"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Working Group shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H12A29CD3588844FBA08CB7C3C3F1F7AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>report to the President through the Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality and the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E0F948FE3DD42F3A91B25D47EF86AB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide guidance to Federal agencies regarding criteria for identifying disproportionately high and adverse human health or environmental effects—</text>
 <clause id="H894ED4AAF0FF446D998E72E3EDBEAA06"><enum>(i)</enum><text>on communities of color, indigenous communities, and low-income communities; and</text> </clause><clause id="H2E73B57364B14E8CB570432EDD8F978D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on the basis of race, color, national origin, or income;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B999E35372D46CBBA5ACCF2B8B1E3BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coordinate with, provide guidance to, and serve as a clearinghouse for, each Federal agency with respect to the implementation and updating of an environmental justice strategy required under this Act, in order to ensure that the administration, interpretation, and enforcement of programs, activities, and policies are carried out in a consistent manner;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H958978552D824AF4962465E021AD77AA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assist in coordinating research by, and stimulating cooperation among, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and other Federal agencies conducting research or other activities in accordance with this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17BF04DBDFE949C4864345DBCF363BE7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>identify, based in part on public recommendations contained in Federal agency progress reports, important areas for Federal agencies to take into consideration and address, as appropriate, in environmental justice strategies and other efforts;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H772A1529B90746FE9524B9B399E3F5E6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>assist in coordinating data collection and maintaining and updating appropriate databases, as required by this Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64D08D2E5F3A4B32BA544306FBE33B1A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>examine existing data and studies relating to environmental justice;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4AF5DAAFE8B446789BF89C3F7E9ED03"><enum>(H)</enum><text>hold public meetings and otherwise solicit public participation under paragraph (3); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H497766ED1CCC46F4A940FBD2F0DA3E18"><enum>(I)</enum><text>develop interagency model projects relating to environmental justice that demonstrate cooperation among Federal agencies.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E409BA56F2B472C97240F86585874F7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public participation</header><text>The Working Group shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HF59CFC40BBDE40C18A01A65C5FFA1352"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hold public meetings or otherwise solicit public participation and citizen science for the purpose of fact-finding with respect to the implementation of this Act; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD273258D1F7245E8BC42EB0F972AD4C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prepare for public review and publish a summary of any comments and recommendations provided.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD25093FA054345A6B7D373046BC12E8B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Judicial review and rights of action</header><text>Any person may commence a civil action—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7EB43E2CDA064E08B986410ECB78B73C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to seek relief from, or to compel, an agency action under this section (including regulations promulgated pursuant to this section); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C1BD03B552240DA957CC4FD31B810BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>otherwise to ensure compliance with this section (including regulations promulgated pursuant to this section).</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFDFFBDEDA6B1416A83B9D373F71AC335"><enum>5.</enum><header>Federal agency actions to address environmental justice</header>
			<subsection id="H40B90B6011A84AD19B18512F50944104"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal agency responsibilities</header>
 <paragraph id="HEFA0CFDC41A948DDA6D5E36947B9AA7C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Environmental justice mission</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable and permitted by applicable law, each Federal agency shall make achieving environmental justice part of the mission of the Federal agency by identifying, addressing, and mitigating disproportionately high and adverse human health or environmental effects of the programs, policies, and activities of the Federal agency on communities of color, indigenous communities, and low-income communities in the United States (including the territories and possessions of the United States and the District of Columbia).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H11DBE3FC6F2F4758996A97017EBC418D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nondiscrimination</header><text>Each Federal agency shall conduct any program, policy, or activity that substantially affects human health or the environment in a manner that ensures that the program, policy, or activity does not have the effect of excluding any individual or group from participation in, denying any individual or group the benefits of, or subjecting any individual or group to discrimination under, the program, policy, or activity because of race, color, or national origin.</text>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="HA47F76189A584FF7B69E1CBEA6413632"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Strategies</header>
 <subparagraph id="H99539EFF47A143DA8347F92BB21D7D83"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Agencywide strategies</header><text>Each Federal agency shall implement and update, not less frequently than annually, an agencywide environmental justice strategy that identifies and addresses disproportionally high and adverse human health or environmental effects of the programs, policies, spending, and other activities of the Federal agency with respect to communities of color, indigenous communities, and low-income communities, including, as appropriate for the mission of the Federal agency, with respect to the following areas:</text>
 <clause id="HAA1A1E67D40E4A4EB160E61AE7D8BC08"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Implementation of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.).</text> </clause><clause id="HF6A8BD214203480797F2A3D1B5B8788F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Implementation of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref> et seq.) (including regulations promulgated pursuant to that title).</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8287A7912CB34C369AF5FE5FF1DD5B94"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Implementation of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB85EA2401F9A48AFBF53E53288E2772D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Impacts from the lack of infrastructure, or from deteriorated infrastructure.</text> </clause><clause id="H45197E1EB7354A8EA68937C61C4B95E6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Impacts from land use.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7059AF583FBE4DE58C8E3FD57B8826EC"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Impacts from climate change.</text> </clause><clause id="H3AFF94D2F25A4887B18F589354C7FD88"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Impacts from commercial transportation.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3503256874344575B0AB0AB1EC1E77C2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Revisions</header>
 <clause id="HAA9E7B0A99094E66A4C7516E7C708C01"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each strategy developed and updated pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall identify programs, policies, planning and public participation processes, rulemaking, agency spending, and enforcement activities relating to human health or the environment that may be revised, at a minimum—</text>
 <subclause id="HFB96DAC01F2248F9B16B2995C58118A1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to promote enforcement of all health, environmental, and civil rights laws and regulations in areas containing communities of color, indigenous communities, and low-income communities;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H89CB6F8A06B34511A192AE1EEC79CA5A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to ensure greater public participation;</text> </subclause><subclause id="HF6937D8CDD6747A1916AE1A34A9A1230"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to provide increased access to infrastructure;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H5C7A2BF827DC4266ACD6D9BA1842B709"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>to improve research and data collection relating to the health and environment of communities of color, indigenous communities, and low-income communities, including through the increased use of citizen science; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H197D92FC1D35435BA9B801725E434D58"><enum>(V)</enum><text>to identify differential patterns of use of natural resources among communities of color, indigenous communities, and low-income communities.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H945066BDA3FB4CA5824E24E2BD525D87"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Timetables</header><text>Each strategy implemented and updated pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall include a timetable for undertaking revisions identified pursuant to clause (i).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD03DEE9DFAB4FDB806DE9294DCA724B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Progress reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once every 5 years thereafter, each Federal agency shall submit to Congress and the Working Group, and shall publish, a progress report that includes, with respect to the period covered by the report—</text>
 <clause id="H70161EFAAA0C430BBD61A4F3C0F65465"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the current environmental justice strategy of the Federal agency;</text> </clause><clause id="H534C48DBDD364D9AAC7D9A370E0890B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an evaluation of the progress made by the Federal agency at national and regional levels regarding implementation of the environmental justice strategy, including—</text>
 <subclause id="HD212B776A3484145A2398AD126710E7B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>metrics used by the Federal agency to measure performance; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HF5D21020847245888663CB1002F6D2E6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the progress made by the Federal agency toward—</text>
 <item id="HD8E15FAD51904C8798FA31A100E5FB52"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the achievement of the metrics described in subclause (I); and</text> </item><item id="H6E0E82D214CF45FF8339F8406E46334A"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>mitigating identified instances of environmental injustice;</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="H246C06BCB1814C2CBF3E2BF703042F2B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of the participation by the Federal agency in interagency collaboration;</text> </clause><clause id="HE35EC6AC27F44B7195DC7B652360DB5A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>responses to recommendations submitted by members of the public to the Federal agency relating to the environmental justice strategy of the Federal agency and the implementation by the Federal agency of this Act; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H027B2B61D7AA45238AC01763EA86A646"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any updates or revisions to the environmental justice strategy of the Federal agency, including those resulting from public comments.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H54A1378A69B541F5B6AD330E544907AD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public participation</header><text>Each Federal agency shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H401FBC77F3744882984FC1FBCA2B857F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that meaningful opportunities exist for the public to submit comments and recommendations relating to the environmental justice strategy, progress reports, and ongoing efforts of the Federal agency to incorporate environmental justice principles into the programs, policies, and activities of the Federal agency;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C0A08EC503E41D5916CC55865818D43"><enum>(B)</enum><text>hold public meetings or otherwise solicit public participation and citizen science from communities of color, indigenous communities, and low-income communities for the purpose of fact-finding and policy development, receiving public comments, and conducting inquiries concerning environmental justice; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE83CCF29356543A993A59E0DCC9C24E4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>prepare for public review and publish a summary of the comments and recommendations provided.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H879145E5C18A426993190675B06EB21D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Access to information</header><text>Each Federal agency shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8020474CB1AC41FA8909F4095FE50D26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publish public documents, notices, and hearings relating to the programs, policies, and activities of the Federal agency that affect human health or the environment; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4209EA0DB7354E2AB7F61ED107E5FB20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>translate and publish any public documents, notices, and hearings relating to an action of the Federal agency as appropriate for the affected population, specifically in any case in which a limited English-speaking population may be disproportionately affected by that action.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A2DCD100978461C999A4D372AFB5759"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Codification of guidance</header>
 <subparagraph id="HF3E79E87C1AD4371A10E130E093E2A80"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Council on Environmental Quality</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, sections II and III of the guidance issued by the Council on Environmental Quality entitled <quote>Environmental Justice Guidance Under the National Environmental Policy Act</quote> and dated December 10, 1997, are enacted into law.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AB647E8BBF546699BA4D7B6F4EF9708"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Environmental Protection Agency</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the guidance issued by the Environmental Protection Agency entitled <quote>EPA Policy on Consultation and Coordination with Indian Tribes: Guidance for Discussing Tribal Treaty Rights</quote> and dated February 2016 is enacted into law.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC87738157AE4F58ACB22F3BA0FC5B3E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Human health and environmental research, data collection, and analysis</header>
 <paragraph id="H98B741F684DF4394A4C211C9152CAFF7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Research</header><text>Each Federal agency, to the maximum extent practicable and permitted by applicable law, shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H62A1B280CAC84F8C9B98B312B8DFFC90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in conducting environmental or human health research, include diverse segments of the population in epidemiological and clinical studies, including segments at high risk from environmental hazards, such as—</text>
 <clause id="HBCE512A129B74C8FB9FB10EEFB20940A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>communities of color, indigenous communities, and low-income communities; and</text> </clause><clause id="HD3D42073D6E54AD89E3DBE6D585D64E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>workers who may be exposed to substantial environmental hazards;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FA40788DA92464AA2B951DD2008C4E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in conducting environmental or human health analyses, identify multiple and cumulative exposures; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H956EA3B86CA7492F9087D6DE1B4800F1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>actively encourage and solicit citizen science, and provide to communities of color, indigenous communities, and low-income communities the opportunity to comment regarding the development and design of research strategies carried out pursuant to this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD46E39DDDA4C4927AA1EA55E95AE2D19"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disproportionate impact</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable and permitted by applicable law (including section 552a of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Privacy Act</quote>)), each Federal agency shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAA08B3E2F5B2453291A423A03C9F3538"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collect, maintain, and analyze information assessing and comparing environmental and human health risks borne by populations identified by race, national origin, or income; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1094A49CC924F1A8CE3C0A0D2C0D38B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use that information to determine whether the programs, policies, and activities of the Federal agency have disproportionally high and adverse human health or environmental effects on communities of color, indigenous communities, and low-income communities.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H42207C4665F947909761526A5FA8823C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information relating to non-Federal facilities</header><text>In connection with the implementation of Federal agency strategies under subsection (a)(3), each Federal agency, to the maximum extent practicable and permitted by applicable law, shall collect, maintain, and analyze information relating to the race, national origin, and income level, and other readily accessible and appropriate information, for areas surrounding any facility or site expected to have a substantial environmental, human health, or economic effect on the surrounding populations, if the facility or site becomes the subject of a substantial Federal environmental administrative or judicial action.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A883E9F9BE7416A89A4726C0A533561"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Impact from Federal facilities</header><text>Each Federal agency, to the maximum extent practicable and permitted by applicable law, shall collect, maintain, and analyze information relating to the race, national origin, and income level, and other readily accessible and appropriate information, for areas surrounding any facility of the Federal agency that is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H02322B6AA72C40AE8D69639D795CE059"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subject to the reporting requirements under the Emergency Planning and Community Right-to-Know Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11001">42 U.S.C. 11001</external-xref> et seq.), as required by Executive Order 12898 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> note; relating to Federal actions to address environmental justice in minority populations and low-income populations); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE78F5063716A4547838B0CDED07DBC7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>expected to have a substantial environmental, human health, or economic effect on surrounding populations.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H249864CEB4664091BB2A0F69BA53AAD3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consumption of fish and wildlife</header>
 <paragraph id="HDEC35274C1CD43BF98577A4D13FCEFE2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each Federal agency shall develop, publish (unless prohibited by law), and revise, as practicable and appropriate, guidance on actions of the Federal agency that will impact fish and wildlife consumed by populations that principally rely on fish or wildlife for subsistence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H18DB2C4EBB034D96905B416BE86F04FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The guidance described in paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HF757E1392E634C3D8902E3492BDC25B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reflect the latest scientific information available concerning methods for evaluating the human health risks associated with the consumption of pollutant-bearing fish or wildlife; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBE9D8FE0D63446FAC83CB708BC124D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publish the risks of such consumption patterns.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H44F7CBC7F9AB4A218F0CED234C02FAD8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Mapping and screening tool</header><text>The Administrator shall continue to make available to the public an environmental justice mapping and screening tool (such as EJScreen or an equivalent tool) that includes, at a minimum, the following features:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HDC89E4706E28455B9872F803BEAFF288"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Nationally consistent data.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H580961A4B9BD4EA78DA36AC8D5C4E9AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Environmental data.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3927A63A338349AC820DD0569DC11775"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Demographic data, including data relating to race, ethnicity, and income.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H22DB4E33B4E34323A2D3AC458730B369"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Capacity to produce maps and reports by geographical area.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA6F4D8F298640D4AFDA82B4E46AEB6A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Judicial review and rights of action</header><text>Any person may commence a civil action—</text> <paragraph id="H18BDF5B1720C4974A48778F5ED2A9F19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to seek relief from, or to compel, an agency action under this section (including regulations promulgated pursuant to this section); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5B8C1C3A1953430C8B85E4EA94FC43A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>otherwise to ensure compliance with this section (including regulations promulgated pursuant to this section).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H78CBB817D485464CB521F45BA8C74C2E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Information sharing</header><text>In carrying out this section, each Federal agency, to the maximum extent practicable and permitted by applicable law, shall share information and eliminate unnecessary duplication of efforts through the use of existing data systems and cooperative agreements among Federal agencies and with State, local, and Tribal governments.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H93FBC6E88A7F4F1790D56ECEC4982161"><enum>6.</enum><header>National Environmental Justice Advisory Council</header>
 <subsection id="HF41659436192416291AB75F4B31F61DE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The establishment by the Administrator on September 30, 1993, by charter pursuant to the <act-name parsable-cite="FACA">Federal Advisory Committee Act</act-name> (5 U.S.C. App.) of the National Environmental Justice Advisory Council (referred to in this section as the <term>Advisory Council</term>) is enacted into law.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3A4D2B36D58D4A80873CEADAA233ADAC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Advisory Council may carry out such duties as were carried out by the Advisory Council on the day before the date of enactment of this Act, subject to modification by the Administrator, by regulation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H02A0EF42CE004156B692AAC8CC6DB22D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The membership of the Advisory Council shall—</text> <paragraph id="H0055B7D2E2724CC2BE6467DFC21F762C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be determined and appointed in accordance with, as applicable—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAE30B10F5096430A91604FF1AEB54F4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the charter described in subsection (a) (or any subsequent amendment or revision of that charter); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H950B3B234C264A34865485AC3B51F1BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other appropriate bylaws or documents of the Advisory Council, as determined by the Administrator; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FDBBECC60CC46EBB62CD7FCDB77AADE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>continue in effect as in existence on the day before the date of enactment of this Act until modified in accordance with paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3BEED605DDFC4797A259783D08464FED"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Designated Federal officer</header><text>The Director of the Office of Environmental Justice of the Environmental Protection Agency is designated as the Federal officer required under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Federal Advisory Committee Act /10">section 10(e)</external-xref> of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) for the Advisory Council.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H9D0321332ABE4797AF6B68641C3360C3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Meetings</header>
 <paragraph id="H5BA91B9A51C44DF8AA2CE045CD34EE98"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Advisory Council shall meet not less frequently than 3 times each calendar year.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE3A01A915E9E49C4A5CBAAF97A932A79"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Open to public</header><text>Each meeting of the Advisory Council shall be held open to the public.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H957B793F5C9B480B9314103602176672"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Designated Federal officer</header><text>The designated Federal officer described in subsection (d) (or a designee) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HEF960BAA39934B0B8E83AD6DADA87653"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be present at each meeting of the Advisory Council;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13F133C4A06C4400863BBE5C3050B2F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that each meeting is conducted in accordance with an agenda approved in advance by the designated Federal officer;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAD0592878CE4745A4B78BCCA26D067B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide an opportunity for interested persons—</text> <clause id="HB29FB9D727304138A3829C5CC1B0E7AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to file comments before or after each meeting of the Advisory Council; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7AC34D8DD0B741DF8D6091CC2B4EE650"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to make statements at such a meeting, to the extent that time permits;</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H867A8A9B68B144E68C770C204BDADE3B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensure that a representative of the Working Group and a high-level representative from each regional office of the Environmental Protection Agency are invited to, and encouraged to attend, each meeting of the Advisory Council; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFE71E4ED9D744A0AE89D35F827FC00C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to States seeking to establish State-level environmental justice advisory councils or implement other environmental justice policies or programs.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0FF63E87ECBC4C40A9A47396BD1A618A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Responses from Administrator</header>
 <paragraph id="HB08763B9D13041BD9047FCBE3014CA53"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Public comment inquiries</header><text>The Administrator shall provide a written response to each inquiry submitted to the Administrator by a member of the public before or after each meeting of the Advisory Council by not later than 120 days after the date of submission.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H184CD6951736486FA48BAB019AD1C243"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recommendations from Advisory Council</header><text>The Administrator shall provide a written response to each recommendation submitted to the Administrator by the Advisory Council by not later than 120 days after the date of submission.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAD99009D5F244155B9CACCE91555809C"><enum>(g)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Travel expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member of the Advisory Council may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at such rate as the Administrator determines to be appropriate while away from the home or regular place of business of the member in the performance of the duties of the Advisory Council.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4534FF0F2672417DAB14D22CD6D10C72"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Advisory Council shall remain in existence unless otherwise provided by law.</text> </subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HCA572261D19641F4AB275663EAE8F15F"><enum>7.</enum><header>Environmental justice grant programs</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H3044DF88C1A74A579BC7DEEB47E53096"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall continue to carry out the Environmental Justice Small Grants Program and the Environmental Justice Collaborative Problem-Solving Cooperative Agreement Program, as those programs are in existence on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H5E09B9C60ECA4FD4BD3B26694BD820CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>CARE grants</header><text>The Administrator shall continue to carry out the Community Action for a Renewed Environment grant programs I and II, as in existence on January 1, 2012.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H77D9CC2D367547189EDECB95C25C16C9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out the programs described in subsections (a) and (b) $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2027.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HCAEBBCEBA21D44C787A2750F0C4CADCA"><enum>8.</enum><header>Consideration of cumulative impacts and persistent violations in certain permitting decisions</header>
 <subsection id="H44A23FDB07904B4EBBE71007AD528489"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal Water Pollution Control Act</header><text>Section 402 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1342">33 U.S.C. 1342</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H53EFAF73095C48F1B6BBFB7582F7D0EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the section designation and heading and all that follows through <quote>Except as</quote> in subsection (a)(1) and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H54BBBE6706134811B9B8728A8D532D40" style="OLC">
						<section id="H6D02CD4FB28D4D11996400B19B00B178"><enum>402.</enum><header>National pollutant discharge elimination system</header>
							<subsection id="H13A9BE5C2F1D465686DB89FAC72945EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Permits issued by Administrator</header>
 <paragraph id="HEC8159F5C5A742C9A7EDF44DA074193F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE89A04F9ED37439BA04B91AE8DB2F9F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA2FFE7261AAF436CB2761FB76C5CC16A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="HBF1D85F0865D4BB2A62A3B097F397305"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>upon condition that such discharge will meet either (A) all</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2B851CD6C80B4F92B28305E4CA53C13D" style="OLC">
 <text>subject to the conditions that—</text><subparagraph id="HFAEBDE392A6B4179B138F661A797B05C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the discharge will achieve compliance with, as applicable—</text> <clause id="H25A196C608684B0FA917ACAEC485BB5A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause id="HE33416EB4D554B5CABAD1105C02A2572"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>403 of this Act, or (B) prior</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4D4F5F5F529445F2859FF0E16AA629C4" style="OLC"> <text>403; or</text><clause id="HD13418A46F224BD1BBE9DC30FEE9D8F1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prior</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </clause><clause id="HCE7B5E5CAAF74C88ADCAEA127F59F579"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>this Act.</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H543A9DA877344CDA8220EF2811D29D7D" style="OLC">
 <text>this Act; and</text><subparagraph id="H8DA268A21BC148B6B6AB0605F528746F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to the issuance or renewal of the permit—</text> <clause id="HF4617659AC8A41B7AB8D5D5DC8C5CBF3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>based on an analysis by the Administrator of existing water quality and the potential cumulative impacts (as defined in section 501 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7661">42 U.S.C. 7661</external-xref>)) of the discharge, considered in conjunction with the designated and actual uses of the impacted navigable water, there exists a reasonable certainty of no harm to the health of the general population, or to any potentially exposed or susceptible subpopulation; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H280D4E9AE9F949E382FCC466FB727680"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the Administrator determines that, due to those potential cumulative impacts, there does not exist a reasonable certainty of no harm to the health of the general population, or to any potentially exposed or susceptible subpopulation, the permit or renewal includes such terms and conditions as the Administrator determines to be necessary to ensure a reasonable certainty of no harm.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1DCB2026B0E465E967C813EA7DC1A3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>assure compliance with the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection, including conditions on data and information collection, reporting, and such other requirements as he deems appropriate.</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H901A5723BD9745D7AD969DF2A2C936B0" style="OLC">
 <text>ensure compliance with the requirements of paragraph (1), including—</text><subparagraph id="HA9B50A29F61641DFBBD382FAF7125668"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conditions relating to—</text> <clause id="H43C93EE1988C42F3BC6701BC4EF3F7E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>data and information collection;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H5FC4FFB0E2FE446D9B64864D0CED2705"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reporting; and</text> </clause><clause id="HD4BA3A08066447FAB1D7E3F0A50AF649"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such other requirements as the Administrator determines to be appropriate; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAF8DE3B9D454F33B344F9181833D073"><enum>(B)</enum><text>additional controls or pollution prevention requirements.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H832F37CAD5EF40D381ED9CC2765C5117"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF2650272DC8A4ED280E60B9819D4B2D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in each of paragraphs (1)(D), (2)(B), and (3) through (7), by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting a period;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FCE11130522452F842942FD6B679FC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>; and</quote> at the end and inserting a period; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC90E2F7AE5D4610B00F95608A4A5C58"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFFDC86B4C62B494C8EF2444B09C5553A" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H4FE0CBB3734F488D86B14447A2494942"><enum>(10)</enum><text>To ensure that no permit will be issued or renewed if, with respect to an application for the permit, the State determines, based on an analysis by the State of existing water quality and the potential cumulative impacts (as defined in section 501 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7661">42 U.S.C. 7661</external-xref>)) of the discharge, considered in conjunction with the designated and actual uses of the impacted navigable water, that the terms and conditions of the permit or renewal would not be sufficient to ensure a reasonable certainty of no harm to the health of the general population, or to any potentially exposed or susceptible subpopulation.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4764F6359B2443D5829A57894E08DCCF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clean Air Act</header>
 <paragraph id="H07CBFF1C788F4BBA93E5EE9241457623"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 501 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7661">42 U.S.C. 7661</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H3AC4DADEB7B442679AC5E09625CD3756"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>As used in this title—</quote> and inserting <quote>In this title:</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H989965035DD747DB894E49485B5BBC2B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) as paragraphs (3), (5), and (4), respectively, and moving the paragraphs so as to appear in numerical order; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H598E6DE07C3B4ABAA2A17B303CB0E296"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E2F675B22004272BACBE7960A454C09" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H1E59F244A2B54E08A9DF1B2D1387F617"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cumulative impacts</header><text>The term <term>cumulative impacts</term> means any exposure, public health or environmental risk, or other effect occurring in a specific geographical area, including from an emission or release—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2C664C36AF854844A225236596DF79C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>including—</text> <clause id="H9F49D60499D3449A80AD35408F6BDCB1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>environmental pollution released—</text>
										<subclause id="H461BB97A604440BA949E1260AFB92AC0"><enum>(I)</enum>
 <item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC8EF89CFCCB945D8990EC398D6E61BB8"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>routinely;</text> </item><item id="H7E05E4806CE5492B99A1A86FC435E7F1" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>accidentally; or</text>
 </item><item id="H0FB8135B74CF496F9D0E6072E934DE02" indent="up1"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>otherwise; and</text> </item></subclause><subclause id="HBDBAF6A4FF7845BA99FC6417B38A59F8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>from any source, whether single or multiple; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H432F98F43BDF44E183A56AB0A600F014"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as assessed based on the combined past, present, and reasonably foreseeable emissions and discharges affecting the geographical area; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62F6D703F5384B839A2175A8D291CF47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluated taking into account sensitive populations and socioeconomic factors, where applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H47CD6499E1FB43D48E48925F9AF8CA71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permit programs</header><text>Section 502(b) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7661a">42 U.S.C. 7661a(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H263F778DC16C423AB147FA9F53163E95"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text> <clause id="HC17FFA1CE0E84E628F7D39AB1D93BC23"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraphs (A) and (C), by striking <quote>assure</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>ensure</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H73B7D230870241EFB4A4E3EDE0C95ECC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (F) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD20F718B93804ADDB79A4FA1065D60C6" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H13307F670D0E4789AFC69F0CA86D44DD" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>ensure that no permit will be issued or renewed, as applicable, if—</text>
 <clause id="H6075D7A3BBAF4B789ECEB661B3E6A458"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to an application for a permit or renewal of a permit for a major source, the permitting authority determines under paragraph (9)(A)(i)(II)(bb) that the terms and conditions of the permit or renewal would not be sufficient to ensure a reasonable certainty of no harm to the health of the general population, or to any potentially exposed or susceptible subpopulation, of the applicable census tracts or Tribal census tracts (as those terms are defined by the Director of the Bureau of the Census); or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H264968746B1F4DE79B884DD0588B3457"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Administrator objects to the issuance of the permit in a timely manner under this title.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8F939702595420496B941C86D6EFD0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (9)—</text>
 <clause id="H3DE114B09DCF4B7C99DF37A0B79D11C8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the fourth sentence, by striking <quote>Such permit revision</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99CCEAA3A3DC42D4B581A0ED93A8ED6B" style="OLC"> <clause id="H28F287F885ED4889877C36A1005B121B"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Treatment as renewal</header><text>A permit revision under this paragraph</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause id="H30F6790223B649349619982CA97CEA9C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the third sentence, by striking <quote>No such revision shall</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE89EA3867A1C4B82B5A10DA79CA5A63C" style="OLC"> <clause id="H9AAFA9EAB6DC4A189A991A77FAB969D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>A revision under this paragraph shall not</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause id="H0BF317E0BFA6446F94120A6CA3E4957F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>Such revisions</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC84601236995409EA39692E605679651" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H1EF1D51778854547A89FCF723B95CD1B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Revision requirements</header> <clause id="H1F666B3F309E4DCA9A10C41802304B4E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>A revision described in subparagraph (A)(ii)</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause><clause id="H31C0795F3E8F45D4BEF45695FF016984"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by striking the paragraph designation and all that follows through <quote>shall require</quote> in the first sentence and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H227D2CB85A754E309CD5320C25F96FAA" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H80441D75608041F394FCDB292908D4A4"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Major sources</header> <subparagraph id="H9001D447A0D245F2BA2C893C51752403"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to any permit or renewal of a permit, as applicable, for a major source, a requirement that the permitting authority shall—</text>
 <clause id="H9E895EBC99554FBC81ED15A132858151"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in determining whether to issue or renew the permit—</text> <subclause id="H8C9F0878035E4FD9BCBB34448A82E387"><enum>(I)</enum><text>evaluate the potential cumulative impacts of the proposed major source, as described in the applicable cumulative impacts analysis submitted under section 503(b)(3);</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H21D8DF3FA35E4C939A7EC90EB0AC91D8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if, due to those potential cumulative impacts, the permitting authority cannot determine that there exists a reasonable certainty of no harm to the health of the general population, or to any potentially exposed or susceptible subpopulation, of any census tracts or Tribal census tracts (as those terms are defined by the Director of the Bureau of the Census) located in, or immediately adjacent to, the area in which the major source is, or is proposed to be, located—</text>
 <item id="H756EE04F88B54CEBAA1DE471AA9D2AF6"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>include in the permit or renewal such terms and conditions (including additional controls or pollution prevention requirements) as the permitting authority determines to be necessary to ensure a reasonable certainty of no harm; or</text>
 </item><item id="H4D0DB4E86134472CB61DFA60221EECB5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>if the permitting authority determines that terms and conditions described in item (aa) would not be sufficient to ensure a reasonable certainty of no harm, deny the issuance or renewal of the permit;</text>
 </item></subclause><subclause id="HDA1EF21AA2EE43BE8101D00BD38CB17F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>determine whether the applicant is a persistent violator, based on such criteria relating to the history of compliance by an applicant with this Act as the Administrator shall establish by not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Environmental Justice Act of 2017</short-title>;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H79B3F1736B4C4BE88644805D8A96AE37"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>if the permitting authority determines under subclause (III) that the applicant is a persistent violator and the permitting authority does not deny the issuance or renewal of the permit pursuant to subclause (V)(bb)—</text>
 <item id="HCE18BAC1FBA344EC8301A1E2F34DC7B2"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>require the applicant to submit a redemption plan that describes—</text> <subitem id="H1AB615CF3F734431B711B6D2A8914F28"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>if the applicant is not compliance with this Act, measures the applicant will carry out to achieve that compliance, together with an approximate deadline for that achievement;</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="H666AD3EED87E43D3BAA14289B11DBE56"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>measures the applicant will carry out, or has carried out to ensure the applicant will remain in compliance with this Act, and to mitigate the environmental and health effects of noncompliance; and</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="H8D77A1EF00214D3DA347E774A4ED7E86"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>the measures the applicant has carried out in preparing the redemption plan to consult or negotiate with the communities affected by each persistent violation addressed in the plan; and</text>
 </subitem></item><item id="HED504A14518448FD95054CC8E501E9F2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>once such a redemption plan is submitted, determine whether the plan is adequate to ensuring that the applicant—</text>
 <subitem id="HD370521488B7446B8E85670FFE88DD21"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>will achieve compliance with this Act expeditiously;</text> </subitem><subitem id="HD26E447F30534B93A617295D42CB58F1"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>will remain in compliance with this Act;</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="HEDC95D4EDDC64193AA8AB52A5EEBC713"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>will mitigate the environmental and health effects of noncompliance; and</text> </subitem><subitem id="HD3EF2B1B5CA7424794E649AA05BB7689"><enum>(DD)</enum><text>has solicited and responded to community input regarding the redemption plan; and</text>
 </subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="H66122785FA964F4A88338442A2C798EC"><enum>(V)</enum><text>deny the issuance or renewal of the permit if the permitting authority determines that—</text> <item id="HC58AB592C4254068A5035E54D886E189"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the redemption plan submitted under subclause (IV)(aa) is inadequate; or</text>
												</item><item id="H1E14CC0DC8FD4C578FE5CA05A6D4B6E8"><enum>(bb)</enum>
 <subitem commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEBCF451B61F64DC2B982E05AAB192696"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the applicant has submitted a redemption plan on a prior occasion, but continues to be a persistent violator; and</text>
 </subitem><subitem id="HD896C72993DF48F287B9B4B29B0D6AB2" indent="up1"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>no indication exists of extremely exigent circumstances excusing the persistent violations; and</text> </subitem></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H86A0A7426778489E9CF69ED214E62A61"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of such a permit with a term of 3 years or longer, require in accordance with subparagraph (B).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H00E13A69BF404293A1364D1062694334"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Permit applications</header><text>Section 503(b) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7661b">42 U.S.C. 7661b(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0A48AB892634303AA52818E0D85EA4F" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H84742773B27F42F9BCE3C90166723561"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Major source analyses</header><text>The regulations required by section 502(b) shall include a requirement that an applicant for a permit or renewal of a permit for a major source shall submit, together with the compliance plan required under this subsection, a cumulative impacts analysis for each census tract or Tribal census tract (as those terms are defined by the Director of the Bureau of the Census) located in, or immediately adjacent to, the area in which the major source is, or is proposed to be, located that analyzes—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H83D69E415FC649D9BFAB0CC000D01883"><enum>(A)</enum><text>community demographics and locations of community exposure points, such as schools, day care centers, nursing homes, hospitals, health clinics, places of religious worship, parks, playgrounds, and community centers;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8384DA716B0746DB952A77AB74D61CCE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>air quality and the potential effect on that air quality of emissions of air pollutants (including pollutants listed under section 108 or 112) from the proposed major source, including in combination with existing sources of pollutants;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD8B6990582B4647A8A1DDFC15BB99CE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the potential effects on soil quality and water quality of emissions of lead and other air pollutants that could contaminate soil or water from the proposed major source, including in combination with existing sources of pollutants; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAD97621F36649B382E8C507266E31CA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>public health and any potential effects on public health of the proposed major source.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H78F9FA1FA9FF4318BAF2E55B6DB79050"><enum>9.</enum><header>Implied rights of action and common law claims</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 505 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1365">33 U.S.C. 1365</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC9873A53677E455D813F65D808300EBD" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H3F7D4D5D2DE74AB89393832C4614961B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Effect on implied rights of action and common law claims</header>
 <paragraph id="H63FDD2CEC2894F83BD9BB8C153E65184"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition of covered Act</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="HEE1AA0A73814464F99F8063075C6C323"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>covered Act</term> means—</text>
 <clause id="HC042B9BFAA4341058E3A9CC9EFB86FCE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this Act;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H18EC39BDF18946ACB32EBDFC5929E1AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <act-name parsable-cite="FIFRA">Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/136">7 U.S.C. 136</external-xref> et seq.);</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD69AB828F754C12A9DA47208D716C73"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1201">30 U.S.C. 1201</external-xref> et seq.);</text> </clause><clause id="H67C2F13D4BC440CC968BF0FAFF567420"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1401">33 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref> et seq.);</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15C3107C3F71411390CFB79AAF9BF4B4"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300f">42 U.S.C. 300f</external-xref> et seq.);</text> </clause><clause id="HBF5FCE34C10B43F0B182D7A0AB788F4B"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the <act-name parsable-cite="SWDA">Solid Waste Disposal Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6901">42 U.S.C. 6901</external-xref> et seq.);</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7C4DE1D2DA24529937035FD40D84A1A"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401</external-xref> et seq.);</text> </clause><clause id="HC61EA1A04E124190B5544D63D31DAF68"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the <act-name parsable-cite="CERCL">Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</external-xref> et seq.); and</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9DB9CB2A4DB4D21AAF3DBE1018595E1"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>any other Act administered by the Administrator.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB63EA570D30473496F331259B2B2ECF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>covered Act</term> includes any provision of an Act described in subparagraph (A) the date of enactment of which is after the date of enactment of this subsection, unless that provision is specifically excluded from this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H00C4CB875E1A4AE382118A5FF67756DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in a covered Act precludes the right to bring an action—</text> <subparagraph id="H78CB610DCE274652A6D1B38A0F6DE516"><enum>(A)</enum><text>under section 1979 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1983">42 U.S.C. 1983</external-xref>); or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H335BA0035A3C47399E383D9436DB4A02"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is implied under—</text> <clause id="H6DA0D41FB4E44E9F81B44D789D08307D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a covered Act; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0A2EFE806A64912AA6EC1EB1A1105F2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>common law.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H34D449AB7DDE47A18F1A75EAED0771E2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Nothing in this section precludes the right to bring an action under any provision of law that is not a covered Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section><section id="H1E2ACDA47C1142B7A76F2C59F4DA28CE"><enum>10.</enum><header>Private rights of action for discriminatory practices</header>
 <subsection id="HE91DB013DBD64087A73DFBA49A7E54D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Right of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 602 of the <act-name parsable-cite="CRA64">Civil Rights Act of 1964</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d-1">42 U.S.C. 2000d–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H043D07D4434E4920A92090039ED5B869"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(a)</quote> before <quote>Each Federal department and agency which is empowered</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF0A883EB2C74A98A6617EC24ACACE09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HB69698BE70C743C6A940D90536DA76FB" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H895A99F5534345EDB8D97A7566FEF57B"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Any person aggrieved by the failure of a covered entity to comply with this title, including any regulation promulgated pursuant to this title, may bring a civil action in any Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction to enforce such person’s rights under this title.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3E9401D3DF22463FA951B8DB72190C2E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="H22CC0FD90C584546A22873972A4BA586"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This section, including the amendments made by this section, takes effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H396D9F738BC543C9AD996D069B32110D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>This section, including the amendments made by this section, applies to all actions or proceedings pending on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


