<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H02454A34D7704321A64DAA4E058E893E" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2499 IH: Voting Access Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2499</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170517">May 17, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000598">Mrs. Davis of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require States to meet standards for the location and
			 operation of polling places used in elections for Federal office,
			 including a standard requiring States to ensure that no individual waits
			 for longer than one hour to cast a vote at a polling place, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H6EC9731B8BAE4C7E84E0CF2C6C1FD672" style="OLC">
 <section id="H401EC416C58D4BD78D8FFD22B190B0B2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Voting Access Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0730EE6DB61E4C909932EE7A717E57A9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring States to meet standards for location and operation of polling places used in elections for Federal office</header> <subsection id="H8DEBF0F7B32245AB9989E21970335575"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of Standards</header> <paragraph id="HAF1C51F2BC9049929D93E608E6597283"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title III of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21081">52 U.S.C. 21081</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 303 the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19BAD44364B34BD081829FC72EF77375" style="OLC">
						<section id="HA82C3A6B68A242D9B94AF8807D0962C6"><enum>303A.</enum><header>Compliance with standards for location and operation of polling places</header>
 <subsection id="H01C1902AE8EB402496C4CAB98160D003"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State shall comply with the standards established by the Commission under this section for the location and operation of polling places used in elections for Federal office.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HA74FEB5909AF4389B0C5F4CEE17B07C5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of standards</header>
 <paragraph id="H446F2A1DAE774E26B44B8ED91A8009BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Standards described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In consultation with the chief State election officials of the States, the Commission shall establish national standards for the location and operation of polling places used in elections for Federal office (other than sites used as polling places on dates other than the date of the election), including the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="HBD507C991CB74F3EBEF5097CB9F3FDD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A requirement that no individual shall be required to wait for longer than one hour in order to cast a vote at a polling place.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6EF7ACCDCD54C6FB68FAB54C2393E75"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Standards for determining the number of polling places within a jurisdiction on the basis of the voting age population of the jurisdiction, taking into consideration factors which include the linguistic preferences of voters in the jurisdiction, the availability of same-day voter registration in the jurisdiction, and other relevant factors.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98EF2FC87EFB4D689DCFF0DB7F467E57"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Standards for the nondiscriminatory placement and location of polling places within a jurisdiction, including standards to ensure that polling places are accessible to voters with disabilities and voters using public transportation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04AF8485AD434548A02FF8369DADFC12"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Standards for ensuring that each polling place has sufficient resources, including voting systems, ballots, and election officials, to meet the requirement described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D49CD86B1684146B07C0C572F1407E1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Standards for ensuring that voters are given timely, accurate, and current information in clear and concise language regarding ballot information and the location of polling places.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7246B50273D44317BFC3128B458A9B9C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Best practices for preventing violations of laws prohibiting the intimidation or harassment of voters at polling places.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C0C7989685F45CEAD13A17571D6B97C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Process for establishment of standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The establishment of the standards under this section shall be carried out by the Commission in a manner that provides for each of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H340A54AB96F54EB0BC88D51010A0CC2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Publication of notice of the proposed standards in the Federal Register.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H373A4DE7F573463ABD8C2749B94DB4C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An opportunity for public comment on the proposed standards.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BA23FA4DCD8466FA80D6B32B614EE97"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Publication of the final standards in the Federal Register.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4BC532EBA8A34AB88343622E171413B3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadline; Effective date</header><text>The Commission shall establish the standards under this section not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, and each State shall comply with the standards with respect to all elections for Federal office held on or after the expiration of the 180-day period which begins on the date the Commission establishes the standards.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF49AA3A2A37F425B802A4DBEC26B2A70"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 303 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H845237BD96524F259BD51314AAB5E672" style="OLC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 303A. Compliance with standards for location and operation of polling places.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6350DB61B44247BB99FB6C3546DD4573"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>Section 401 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21111">52 U.S.C. 21111</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>and 303</quote> and inserting <quote>303, and 303A</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H53711E1A98E043D8AA78D0065A8BE6C8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Section 257(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21007">52 U.S.C. 21007(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE9ECBB595184DA08AF2ED9DF8AD09F1" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H9C0CF04FE4394065A60621E054B3CA8B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the first fiscal year during which States are subject to the requirements of section 303A (relating to standards established by the Commission for the location and operation of polling places), such sums as are necessary for requirements of payments to enable the States to meet the requirements of such section.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H7BD615F6100B48BE87A115F305DF3C50"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study and report on misidentification of individual political party registration</header>
 <subsection id="H9A698B6132EB40D3BB2000F338079F92"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Election Assistance Commission shall conduct a study of instances of the misidentification by election officials of the political party registration of individuals attempting to vote in primary elections for Federal office, including an analysis of the frequency of such misidentification among various jurisdictions.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDA14710ECFF942BB97719454AB281555"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to Congress a report on the study conducted under subsection (a), and shall include in the report such recommendations as the Commission considers appropriate to prevent and respond to the misidentification of an individual’s political party registration, including recommendations to permit individuals to correct their political party registration at the polling place on the date of voting.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


