<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H243E485E74BF404A8DA0E6845E5CF98C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3614 IH: Guaranteed COLA Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3614</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170728">July 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000611">Mr. Poliquin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of General Services to establish a program to sell Federal buildings
			 that are not utilized to provide revenue for increases in Social Security
			 benefits and military retirement pay, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HEE80772F99BE4ABEA10963A2EAD792E4" style="OLC">
 <section id="HDCE8CA5B1893483FAB8FBF931577098E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Guaranteed COLA Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HBACC6AF8BC934B869D7AA777D28F93C9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Certain building sales</header> <subsection id="H4AA8AE9799FE4370AAF4AA6DBCF6C1D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of General Services shall establish a program under which the Administrator shall sell all Federal buildings that are not utilized by the Federal Government.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H4FD68D59FB7F419EA20E2DD0EFF9C5A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification of buildings</header>
 <paragraph id="H381D6C9B4F5348AB9FEE0F60AC5454A6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial identification</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall make an initial identification of all buildings owned and not utilized by the Federal Government.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H62DB001A1746493F92E577DF2CA64B6E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regular identification</header><text>After the date on which the Administrator makes the initial identification under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall identify on a continuing basis any building owned and not utilized by the Federal Government that was not included in such initial identification.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H60E25BC2B2B548B682363424FAAB4301"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sale required</header><text>Not later than 5 years after a building is identified under subsection (b), the Administrator, notwithstanding any other provision of law and to the extent practicable, shall complete a sale of—</text>
 <paragraph id="H892D6F91187A4674B7D72E3BD83435A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such building; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7B0F6FFAF274602BB3B74B412EA7F28"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the land relevant to such building.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6AD2A3281EA8403BAFBE66A5166EB76A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Administrator shall not sell a building identified under subsection (b) if the building, or the land relevant to such building, has been set aside for preservation or historic purposes.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H1C33F861F1584CC0A0BDC583634224E2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Revenues from sale</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the revenue from a sale under subsection (c), after payment of any costs related to the sale, shall be made available only for the following:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HCC652891F4EF4FC98287DE9B47247613"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To increase benefits under title II of the Social Security Act, effective with the month of December 2017, by applying section 215(i) of such Act as if the applicable increase percentage with respect to the base quarter in 2017 (as determined under such section without regard to this paragraph) is increased by an additional 1.5 percentage points.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H45166EB1BFBB476E96358BB4CC5922EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective December 1, 2017, to make the cost-of-living adjustment to the retired pay of members and former members of the Armed Forces pursuant to section 1401a of title 10, United States Code, as if the applicable percentage of the increase calculated under subsection (b)(2) of such section (without regard to this paragraph) is increased by an additional 1.5 percentage points.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


