<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H13F7710060A64664B1F718EB1BD9A28A" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3805 IH: To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to carry out a land exchange involving lands within the boundaries of the Cape Cod National Seashore, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3805</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170918">September 18, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to carry out a land exchange involving lands within the
			 boundaries of the Cape Cod National Seashore, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H1399EC23755242A3AE749D37EC72C7DF" style="OLC">
		<section id="HFE2AED46DFCC4148B7C4FC01C3DEB35B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Land exchange involving Cape Cod National Seashore</header>
 <subsection id="H372F98D8E21541259329E50070D45CCB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of exchange</header><text>If title acceptable to the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the National Park Service (referred to hereafter in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), for non-Federal land defined in subsection (b)(1) is conveyed to the United States, the Secretary shall convey to the owner of the non-Federal land, subject to valid existing rights, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the Federal land defined in subsection (b)(2).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HC13255A22719406F9B6E9F1F4D37BCBA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Land descriptions</header>
 <paragraph id="H9EA60A0B58BA4FFBB0EC8EC4BC8904C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal land</header><text>The term <quote>Federal land</quote> means the approximately 1.09 acres of land depicted as Tract 22-4556 on the map titled <quote>United States Department of the Interior, National Park Service, Northeast Region, Cape Cod National Seashore</quote> and dated October 20, 1963, Sheet 202-22A.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0809EF346E7644FA8DBC1CB25D5F0891"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-Federal land</header><text>The term <quote>non-Federal land</quote> means the approximately 1.02 acres of land depicted as Tract 26-4653 on the map titled <quote>United States, Department of the Interior, National Park Service, Northeast Region, Cape Cod National Seashore</quote> and dated October 27, 1964, Sheet 202-26.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5545947350564006B0560A23D63CDFD9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Acceptable title</header><text>Title to the non-Federal land conveyed to the United States under subsection (a) shall be such title as is acceptable to the Secretary, in conformance with title approval standards applicable to Federal land acquisitions.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9330A41AD6484D94AF224DCD57384D71"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicable laws; terms and conditions</header><text>The exchange under this section shall be subject to—</text> <paragraph id="H40959BB470A44FC8885473124BE3327E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the laws (including regulations) and policies applicable to exchanges of land administered by the National Park Service, including the laws and policies concerning equalization of values, and environmental compliance; with the exception of appraisal requirements, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H87A3919EF0CB4F2384A1782DCF33D051"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63BA403DB1D146F38C53ACDE1FDF7931"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appraisals</header><text>For the purpose of valuation of the land proposed for exchange under this section, the Secretary may use the appraisals conducted by Michael Sutton, Certified General Real Estate Appraiser, and dated July 14 and July 22, 2009.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA04ECB0CE57B4A33ADE7EE626CE451C2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The land acquired by the Secretary pursuant to the exchange authorized by this section shall be administered as part of the Cape Cod National Seashore.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HAF6EFB6390B644E5AD3BC858D1047CF0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Maps</header><text>The maps referred to in subsection (a) shall be on file and available for inspection in the appropriate offices of the Department of the Interior.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA46D2C9B296841A9AB04A2441C022626"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definition of improved property</header><text>Section 4(d) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/87/126">Public Law 87–126</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/459b-3">16 U.S.C. 459b–3(d)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>The term <quote>improved property</quote> includes such dwelling structures (including the land thereon) as shall be conveyed by the Secretary pursuant to section 2 in exchange for conveyance to or acquisition by the Secretary of an improved property as described in this section.</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


