<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H9F4EF98C556341BBB8257EEA3B905C1C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1995 IH: V-BID for Better Care Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1995</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170406">April 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001273">Mrs. Black</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. McMorris Rodgers</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for national testing of a model of
			 Medicare
			 Advantage value-based insurance design to meet the needs of chronically
			 ill Medicare Advantage enrollees.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4E63AE7B768D4AA8B2C7CECCFAD3657A" style="OLC">
 <section id="HDB550974F61241049790D283F1818601" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Value-Based Insurance Design for Better Care Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote>V-BID for Better Care Act of 2017</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H9060C06B8621437F89377C8F5AA5514E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Adapting benefits to meet the needs of chronically ill Medicare Advantage enrollees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1859 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-28">42 U.S.C. 1395w–28</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
			<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC49A5E67B8764F489E5BEECCA9A62485" style="OLC">
				<subsection id="H2E3F526BA49F456CAD592B05210A71C8"><enum>(h)</enum><header>National testing of model for Medicare Advantage value-Based insurance design</header>
 <paragraph id="H3DA33D9C771645BA8808A92AC6942C63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In implementing the model described in paragraph (2) proposed to be tested under section 1115A(b), the Secretary shall revise the testing of the model under such section to cover, effective not later than January 1, 2019, all States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H31E34BCF8BCE46BA8EC5D30552649C78"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Model described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The model described in this paragraph is the testing of a model of Medicare Advantage value-based insurance design that would allow Medicare Advantage plans the option to propose and design benefit structures that vary benefits, cost-sharing, and supplemental benefits offered to enrollees with specific chronic diseases proposed to be carried out in Oregon, Arizona, Texas, Iowa, Michigan, Indiana, Tennessee, Alabama, Pennsylvania, and Massachusetts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC51917146BAF4663B95170A05BE5C5D4"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Termination and modification provision not applicable until January 1, 2022</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of section 1115A(b)(3)(B) shall apply to the model described in paragraph (2), including such model as expanded under paragraph (1), beginning January 1, 2022, but shall not apply to such model, as so expanded, prior to such date.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H30DBADCA3F954A4DB315FEF191D01995"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Secretary shall allocate funds made available under section 1115A(f)(1) to design, implement, and evaluate the model described in paragraph (2), as expanded under paragraph (1).</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


