<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H23BD3A0AD0EA42F69319D50C8169F92C" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4139 IH: End Outsourcing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4139</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171026">October 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide incentives for businesses to keep jobs in America.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HE426FC0154614C7094676B8023313121" style="OLC">
 <section id="H50CCA2119B3E45E5A05FCE8C2C35CD82" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End Outsourcing Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H08CB625F0F064FCAA86002A337BD1AC8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Outsourcing statement in worker adjustment and retraining notice</header> <subsection id="H0723CACDCB624F7591E3B1BC27B30780"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Outsourcing statement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3 of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2102">29 U.S.C. 2102</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30FFC9BA78834330A82034200D57F4BB" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="H01E43045CBA7436996632D2A5F485601"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Outsourcing statement</header>
 <paragraph id="HB4919C7EF5774128B5C68C18BDBB212F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the employer shall include an outsourcing statement in the notice described in that subsection. The outsourcing statement shall specify whether part or all of the positions held by affected employees covered by subsection (a) will be moved to a country outside the United States, regardless of whether the positions are moved within the business enterprise involved or to another business enterprise. The employer shall make the determination of whether the positions are being so moved in accordance with regulations issued by the Secretary. The employer shall serve the notice as required under subsection (a) and submit the notice to the Secretary of Labor.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1AD85D4B8ADB4019B63E92012CD703BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>List</header><text>Not less often than annually, the Secretary shall publish and make available on the website of the Department of Labor, a list including each employer who—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H200DB1201F5A4C0CB464B4BE47D8D1EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has included an outsourcing statement in a notice under paragraph (1); or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE366FCE251D440C88C9BA893CF82CBB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has incurred liability under section 5, in part or in whole, because the employer ordered a plant closing or mass layoff without having served a notice that is required, under this section, to include an outsourcing statement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEC6101F856D1468A9226824AB9A93877"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation report</header><text>The Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act is amended by inserting after section 10 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2109">29 U.S.C. 2109</external-xref>) the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE11341A6F714127915BFD8E459C6717" style="OLC">
					<section id="HE9602516E8BC41C99C3045E6A0241493"><enum>10A.</enum><header>Implementation study</header>
 <subsection id="H815EBA2A1B6F4052BFC1ABD76F35D922"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study of the implementation of section 3(e) of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2102">29 U.S.C. 2102(e)</external-xref>) by the Department of Labor.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H665BAD6C280649C6B164745A012C67C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report containing the results of the study.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H74F3BDB503644BEFB16A610641C6C5EF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Denial of deduction for outsourcing expenses</header>
 <subsection id="H5CE41BD32ABA4996839A2843AFCF88D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part IX of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10A99C96B44E41F3B8BE5FFA49FC9EF3" style="OLC">
					<section id="HE58C90F2C59F4DFD97C792D70900F879"><enum>280I.</enum><header>Outsourcing expenses</header>
 <subsection id="HE458C08618CB4434923C57963E07F24A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No deduction otherwise allowable under this chapter shall be allowed for any specified outsourcing expense.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDFD46E73759F4E8CB27AA37A8FEBFF4E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Specified outsourcing expense</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H8EF7946382E44865820AC851B19CFFB1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>specified outsourcing expense</quote> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF503688B2CBB406886B80D4667FF9672"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any eligible expense paid or incurred by the taxpayer in connection with the elimination of any business unit of the taxpayer (or of any member of any expanded affiliated group in which the taxpayer is also a member) located within the United States, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46511A707D624FD8BA522270CE182E86"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any eligible expense paid or incurred by the taxpayer in connection with the establishment of any business unit of the taxpayer (or of any member of any expanded affiliated group in which the taxpayer is also a member) located outside the United States,</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">if such establishment constitutes the relocation of the business unit so eliminated. For purposes
			 of the preceding sentence, a relocation shall not be treated as failing to
			 occur merely because such elimination occurs in a different taxable year
 than such establishment.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2E30618AAB14EA4B04F5F26C4DC9B1E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible expenses</header><text>The term <quote>eligible expenses</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H606223E034634E7C916DB091CB902D75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any amount for which a deduction is allowed to the taxpayer under section 162, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0E683063F5B4375BFC2FABD594EEFFD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permit and license fees, lease brokerage fees, equipment installation costs, and, to the extent provided by the Secretary, other similar expenses.</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Such term does not include any compensation which is paid or incurred in connection with severance
			 from employment and, to the extent provided by the Secretary, any similar
 amount.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD16FE3B2AC244539A004796CA4B393CC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Business unit</header><text>The term <quote>business unit</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H11987AB93E0E40B19AF139E0CB46D0F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any trade or business, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E4B9471ACC949F498E171E1A93BAC32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any line of business, or functional unit, which is part of any trade or business.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF469A59104504EAE90CAC71834E1D9FC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Expanded affiliated group</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>expanded affiliated group</quote> means an affiliated group as defined in section 1504(a), determined without regard to section 1504(b)(3) and by substituting <quote>more than 50 percent</quote> for <quote>at least 80 percent</quote> each place it appears in section 1504(a). A partnership or any other entity (other than a corporation) shall be treated as a member of an expanded affiliated group if such entity is controlled (within the meaning of section 954(d)(3)) by members of such group (including any entity treated as a member of such group by reason of this paragraph).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H715C939694184480B953427D600DA089"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Operating expenses not taken into account</header><text>Any amount paid or incurred in connection with the ongoing operation of a business unit shall not be treated as an amount paid or incurred in connection with the establishment or elimination of such business unit.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA07A9E8AE8E74BDFA1BF367C84A23F9B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <paragraph id="H1EBE3203F07E469FA69482D1D02C3C94"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application to deductions for depreciation and amortization</header><text>In the case of any portion of a specified outsourcing expense which is not deductible in the taxable year in which paid or incurred, such portion shall neither be chargeable to capital account nor amortizable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB8E828BA4064404AA5D5738CBD082985"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Possessions treated as part of the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>United States</quote> shall be treated as including each possession of the United States (including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD167FF5B8305476DA9DFA109D85AC337"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations which provide (or create a rebuttable presumption) that certain establishments of business units outside the United States will be treated as relocations (based on timing or such other factors as the Secretary may provide) of business units eliminated within the United States.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HBD0C178E9B074AFBBA5CB829A5F5CCBF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on subpart F income of controlled foreign corporations determined without regard to
 specified outsourcing expenses</header><text>Subsection (c) of section 952 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C6EA186A14B4DCABB9F7968FF04596F" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H7CBD401519F5416290690747C806CCFE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Earnings and profits determined without regard to specified outsourcing expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, earnings and profits of any controlled foreign corporation shall be determined without regard to any specified outsourcing expense (as defined in section 280I(b)).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6D03E9E3A3634D32B5B1412CE7E61D1D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for part IX of subchapter B of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBA4C2E99DD44BB094FE0E65BA316865" style="OLC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 280I. Outsourcing expenses.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H56F9A865E4964003B79C96D36897A5E7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to amounts paid or incurred after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H0DF07AF249C4400B8BFE1FE105471B1A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Denial of certain deductions and accounting methods for outsourcing employers</header>
 <subsection id="H4187F3B5653A4F6EAAC936AA15DDC75A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part IX of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H82D8C69396954F85BA9022B81496AF2A" style="OLC">
					<section id="H3553F560267C4CFB8D6098EFC135D99E"><enum>280J.</enum><header>Limitations for outsourcing employers</header>
 <subsection id="H24BA5E28633A4147B7D1D459A911AA6B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the disallowance period, an applicable taxpayer—</text> <paragraph id="HE13BD52E61F84DCAA56A83B38E27F9D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be allowed any deduction under section 199 for any income of the taxpayer,</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H744EFD96C66646318F1FA545C2E6035A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may not use the method provided in section 472(b) in inventorying goods,</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDCDA90B8F65455C8B2FA66BED19939F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may not use the lower of cost or market method of determining inventories for purposes of determining income, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF269DEBF77C4A598CF8BABE4D924B74"><enum>(4)</enum><text>shall not be allowed any deduction under section 163 for interest paid or accrued on indebtedness.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC1D53878FA7F4E1DA6738E23B0E12A3C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicable taxpayer</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the term <term>applicable taxpayer</term> means a taxpayer which—</text>
 <paragraph id="H84D8EF8E7F1E4D0181506E4CEF9765CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>during the taxable year, has served written notice under subsection (a) of section 3 of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act which includes an outsourcing statement described in subsection (e) of such section, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H314357C75EAE44238215D5CF356A80BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the cumulative employment loss (excluding any part-time employees) for positions at facilities owned by such taxpayer which will be moved to a country outside of the United States, as determined pursuant to any outsourcing statements served by such taxpayer during such taxable year, exceeds 50 employees.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA668F8C029E745A9A8AE87F071536E67"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disallowance period</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the disallowance period is the period of 3 taxable years after the taxable year in which the statements described in subsection (b)(2) are required to be served.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3B6BB4950C9A45B1B45486557BBE050C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Expanded affiliated group treated as single taxpayer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the members of an expanded affiliated group (as defined in section 280I(b)(4)) shall be treated as a single taxpayer.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9C7815E958AC448A8D5EBC8AFFD16436"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H59B4196AD7D94967875157D4EB52C31E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for part IX of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26A2382689154F57995F1C39F02EB613" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 280J. Limitations for outsourcing employers.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H76435162B9874A3B91E8DAE210F7EB71"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H1692F389841B4EB1ABA32C9EDD419CC8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Recapture of credits for outsourcing employers</header>
 <subsection id="HCF26E09D3B7846419AC9B375D442AB6E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subpart:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H023D3E97CA4D4002B4EEAD05E0634BC5" style="OLC">
					<subpart id="H8539CC373416403E89F9F37E66823FFE" style="OLC"><enum>K</enum><header>Recapture of credits for outsourcing employers</header>
						<toc>
							<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 54BB. Recapture of credits for outsourcing employers.</toc-entry></toc>
						<section id="H8FE981181463419EBA910FA52D79DA6F"><enum>54BB.</enum><header>Recapture of credits for outsourcing employers</header>
 <subsection id="HAF9EFC09E56C4B4DA0E89B7D3512E2D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary, in the case of a taxpayer which owns a facility for which there is an outsourcing event during the taxable year, the tax under this chapter for such taxable year shall be increased by the amount equal to the sum of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFE3B90FEBEAA4BDAB139AC6576555C0B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any credits allowed under this chapter relating to expenses for design, construction, operation, or maintenance of such facility during the 5 taxable years preceding such taxable year, and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9E83A851A59149A3891879F945BAFB8E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any grants provided by the Secretary in lieu of credits described in paragraph (1) during the 5 taxable years preceding such taxable year.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9437DE3AD0F744B88A378C78EDEDACEF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Outsourcing event</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the term <term>outsourcing event</term> means a plant closing or mass layoff (as described in section 2(a) of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act) in which the employment loss (excluding any part-time employees) for positions which will be moved to a country outside of the United States, as determined pursuant to the outsourcing statement (as described in paragraph (1) of such section 3(e) of such Act) served by the taxpayer during the taxable year, exceeds 50 employees.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9DA685CBCAF74AD7BFA0D94A29CFFF65"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expanded affiliated group treated as single taxpayer</header><text>For purposes of this section, the members of an expanded affiliated group (as defined in section 280I(b)(4)) shall be treated as a single taxpayer.</text></subsection></section></subpart><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4FE6D686042844849E6D6D4E3CB2EE68"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of subparts for part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEBF58E709F244AFEAC5A3EDFF64C77AF" style="OLC">
					<toc>
						<toc-entry bold="off" level="subpart">Subpart K. Recapture of credits for outsourcing employers</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE445A4EA603A4483A0C4E0922175820A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HCAE5198A69744F2A915504CF2CA515A7"><enum>6.</enum><header>Credit for insourcing expenses</header>
 <subsection id="H2742D0B8A7B041AD9886AC86EBFEBCDA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90C4EE69B5214908999A5F6B0AD56EC6" style="OLC">
					<section id="HC56F07A098374E2C8029356F7E62A00F"><enum>45S.</enum><header>Credit for insourcing expenses</header>
 <subsection id="H6641643BF6B44D1E8BF7FD9C10F2F825"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of section 38, the insourcing expenses credit for any taxable year is an amount equal to 20 percent of the eligible insourcing expenses of the taxpayer which are taken into account in such taxable year under subsection (d).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H016BE1B6A1794FA08612285B13823976"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible insourcing expenses</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="HAF04C66CD4B34D5D9B8551889D4A0B88"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>eligible insourcing expenses</quote> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA20515E3310646B79F856EBBEE25507B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>eligible expenses paid or incurred by the taxpayer in connection with the elimination of any business unit of the taxpayer (or of any member of any expanded affiliated group in which the taxpayer is also a member) located outside the United States, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D81E2379D484422A9DA734B6C5F02F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>eligible expenses paid or incurred by the taxpayer in connection with the establishment of any business unit of the taxpayer (or of any member of any expanded affiliated group in which the taxpayer is also a member) located within—</text>
 <clause id="HEC096AA6AE9045289BABD81BBD0C63BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a HUBZone (as defined in section 3(p)(2) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632(p)(2)</external-xref>)), or</text> </clause><clause id="H110EC57961EE4576A36F6518673AAF8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a low-income community (as described in section 45D(e)),</text>
									</clause></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">if such establishment constitutes the relocation of the business unit so eliminated. For purposes
			 of the preceding sentence, a relocation shall not be treated as failing to
			 occur merely because such elimination occurs in a different taxable year
 than such establishment.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25D717CF2BFB49DF810FBBE329F0248A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible expenses</header><text>The term <quote>eligible expenses</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HC4C3C65E7DE045F1B858FD218F07BC9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any amount for which a deduction is allowed to the taxpayer under section 162, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE0FAA8365BF41C799B1B3657A2AACC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permit and license fees, lease brokerage fees, equipment installation costs, and, to the extent provided by the Secretary, other similar expenses.</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Such term does not include any compensation which is paid or incurred in connection with severance
			 from employment and, to the extent provided by the Secretary, any similar
 amount.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7221EB301D747E1A0AAFD7B5FF8C6ED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Business unit</header><text>The term <quote>business unit</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H73D8F5C299F14C088CCE51D9F8F55CA0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any trade or business, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90CA6BCD5F4645E5817327C0DD2880F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any line of business, or functional unit, which is part of any trade or business.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H20016B5593E846279B8D2810F81D6F36"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Expanded affiliated group</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>expanded affiliated group</quote> means an affiliated group as defined in section 1504(a), determined without regard to section 1504(b)(3) and by substituting <quote>more than 50 percent</quote> for <quote>at least 80 percent</quote> each place it appears in section 1504(a). A partnership or any other entity (other than a corporation) shall be treated as a member of an expanded affiliated group if such entity is controlled (within the meaning of section 954(d)(3)) by members of such group (including any entity treated as a member of such group by reason of this paragraph).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB7E60B717538441589B1D0707714CFDE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Expenses must be pursuant to insourcing plan</header><text>Amounts shall be taken into account under paragraph (1) only to the extent that such amounts are paid or incurred pursuant to a written plan to carry out the relocation described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8CACEC40DBAF4E619FDFE2A4E7B683A3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Operating expenses not taken into account</header><text>Any amount paid or incurred in connection with the on-going operation of a business unit shall not be treated as an amount paid or incurred in connection with the establishment or elimination of such business unit.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE84DACC64294C38B0B15C7119EC4168"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Increased domestic employment requirement</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under this section unless the number of full-time equivalent employees of the taxpayer for the taxable year for which the credit is claimed exceeds the number of full-time equivalent employees of the taxpayer for the last taxable year ending before the first taxable year in which such eligible insourcing expenses were paid or incurred. For purposes of this subsection, full-time equivalent employees has the meaning given such term under section 45R(d) (and the applicable rules of section 45R(e)). All employers treated as a single employer under subsection (b), (c), (m), or (o) of section 414 shall be treated as a single employer for purposes of this subsection.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H45393F112ECC4BE0A80EF43C3C2E571A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Credit allowed upon completion of insourcing plan</header>
 <paragraph id="H756B89ED1AB84F5F9589F1A76263330D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), eligible insourcing expenses shall be taken into account under subsection (a) in the taxable year during which the plan described in subsection (b)(5) has been completed and all eligible insourcing expenses pursuant to such plan have been paid or incurred.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="H10B14664FECE41FE80A3025B572083CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Election to apply employment test and claim credit in first full taxable year after completion of
 plan</header><text>If the taxpayer elects the application of this paragraph, eligible insourcing expenses shall be taken into account under subsection (a) in the first taxable year after the taxable year described in paragraph (1).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF62309D9561E4E889A1E997B1689D740"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Possessions treated as part of the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>United States</quote> shall be treated as including each possession of the United States (including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1B2BFCCC1DC34E7FBACB2C30CDE6656C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC3286CE1BDE2461CB761D2228DBDE373"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit To be part of general business credit</header><text>Subsection (b) of section 38 of such Code is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (35), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (36) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H12528127936F430EB1DA5CE7EBB2CB4B" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H9FC4FBF999714F1D96DBB3A5B06DF65C"><enum>(37)</enum><text>the insourcing expenses credit determined under section 45S(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3F25B63495E94909B32DE2ACE7F866B9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B48F5816C1E4FB5803E5E49E74993E5" style="OLC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H90C4EE69B5214908999A5F6B0AD56EC6" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="HC56F07A098374E2C8029356F7E62A00F" level="section">Sec. 45S. Credit for insourcing expenses.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC31EB3A4DA8E4FCE80CBE766239285CF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to amounts paid or incurred after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H45DF3617126D4EC98622E0D9087E9F81"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application to United States possessions</header>
				<paragraph id="HB212AB6A6BF143438492EABB6701DE2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payments to possessions</header>
 <subparagraph id="H7B1CEC43FDC942F8977FD55F8BE909A3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Mirror code possessions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall make periodic payments to each possession of the United States with a mirror code tax system in an amount equal to the loss to that possession by reason of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45S">section 45S</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986. Such amount shall be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury based on information provided by the government of the respective possession.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28FFC6A459DB4990A2C8EBB408DE9929"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other possessions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall make annual payments to each possession of the United States which does not have a mirror code tax system in an amount estimated by the Secretary of the Treasury as being equal to the aggregate benefits that would have been provided to residents of such possession by reason of section 45S of such Code if a mirror code tax system had been in effect in such possession. The preceding sentence shall not apply with respect to any possession of the United States unless such possession has a plan, which has been approved by the Secretary of the Treasury, under which such possession will promptly distribute such payment to the residents of such possession.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE258D5CFD7B84E738B8586962E327479"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination with credit allowed against united states income taxes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No credit shall be allowed against United States income taxes under section 45S of such Code to any person—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H7215660839374E5CB903172524BE83F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to whom a credit is allowed against taxes imposed by the possession by reason of such section, or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9256B34D4884B9BA93AC95C636EBFEF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is eligible for a payment under a plan described in paragraph (1)(B).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7E13984FA344189A3EC2A5636119AB0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header>
 <subparagraph id="HAAC7A1869BBF4250A5F1DFC7EC86BCF8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Possessions of the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>possession of the United States</quote> includes the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD07503CD60F649DF9C69B7252DE80E3B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mirror code tax system</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>mirror code tax system</quote> means, with respect to any possession of the United States, the income tax system of such possession if the income tax liability of the residents of such possession under such system is determined by reference to the income tax laws of the United States as if such possession were the United States.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1E72AFFD202419D81E8E1FB15C1ACDA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Treatment of payments</header><text>For purposes of section 1324(b)(2) of title 31, United States Code, the payments under this section shall be treated in the same manner as a refund due from sections referred to in such section 1324(b)(2).</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1C57692F1CDC4673A913A19301747A26"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authority for Federal contracting officers to take the outsourcing of jobs from the United States
			 into account in awarding contracts</header>
			<subsection id="HC8FD5DE206A6467B969033A327BA03E8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Department of Defense and related agency contracts</header>
				<paragraph id="HECD8FD15B2F445469B04DAFF2B2FC35D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consideration of outsourcing</header>
 <subparagraph id="H5236423A3F434F74B0739CAE6234CCD9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/137">Chapter 137</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2327">section 2327</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF72AA997CBB347F3B3E3F456E733262F" style="USC">
							<section id="HD918711AC8484742862E16AD2E646B76"><enum>2327a.</enum><header>Contracts: consideration of outsourcing of jobs</header>
								<subsection id="H23C85586EF054A8D9D13A34FAFD2ED1F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disclosure of outsourcing of jobs</header>
 <paragraph id="H782DF8D28C574F7D9858070D72E28FAC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of an agency shall require a contractor that submits a bid or proposal in response to a solicitation issued by the agency to disclose in that bid or proposal if the contractor, or a subsidiary of the contractor, owns a facility for which there is an outsourcing event during the three-year period ending on the date of the submittal of the bid or proposal.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8D16327E00E41B4856A3DAA2CD15BAF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Outsourcing event</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <term>outsourcing event</term> means a plant closing or mass layoff (as described in section 2(a) of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act) in which the employment loss (excluding any part-time employees) for positions which will be moved to a country outside of the United States, as determined pursuant to the outsourcing statement (as described in paragraph (1) of such section 3(e) of such Act) served by the taxpayer during the taxable year, exceeds 50 employees.</text>
									</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD39CD00266BF468C81FC7407547C0098"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consideration authorized</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H68C0A871EDEF48E78F9F6546E1F34314"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Agency contracting officers considering bids or proposals in response to a solicitation issued by the agency may take into account any disclosure made pursuant to subsection (a) in such bids and proposals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6103C90C87544EF7A3B278C2FFF77DE6" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The head of an agency may establish a negative preference of up to 10 percent of the cost of a contract for purposes of evaluating a bid or proposal of a contractor that makes a disclosure pursuant to subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA6880E34FD99422E9D61499242C033F5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that agency contracting officers should, using section 2304(b)(3) of this title, exclude contractors making a disclosure pursuant to subsection (a) in response to solicitations issued by the agency from the bidding process in connection with such solicitations on the grounds that the actions described in the disclosures are against the public interests of the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD038BA8256A14E7A8295797B031E99B1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The head of each agency shall submit to Congress each year a report on the following:</text> <paragraph id="HC5662E6E93FB447A93CD4F212846EA8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of solicitations made by the agency during the preceding year for which disclosures were made pursuant to subsection (a) in responsive bids or proposals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA8CA965562594A48A5DBC8B1C983A41A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of contracts awarded by the agency during the preceding year in which such disclosures were taken into account in the contract award.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6BFB576A2564F80B10012DA6FC57C93"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 137 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 2327 the following new item:</text>
						<quoted-block id="H0F3FB04341F24D87A457BA4E400134A3" style="USC">
							<toc>
								<toc-entry idref="HD918711AC8484742862E16AD2E646B76" level="section">2327a. Contracts: consideration of outsourcing of jobs.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H910EF5F62B9A45D9A61779C45B413957"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion of firms from sources</header><text>Section 2304(b) of such title is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HB240F537E7BB465CB9C4331EEC67344F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) and (4) as paragraphs (4) and (5), respectively;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFE1EE2325CE4F5CB3C502019F9EF0BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5A502EF2413D4EA89F57D2C4E6E52C93" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HC34A21D7EECC487AA4792D92E00FBC33" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The head of an agency may provide for the procurement of property and services covered by this chapter using competitive procedures but excluding a source making a disclosure pursuant to section 2327a(a) of this title in the bid or proposal in response to the solicitation issued by the agency if the head of the agency determines that the actions described by disclosure are against the public interests of the United States and the source is to be excluded on those grounds. Any such determination shall take into account the sense of Congress set forth in section 2327a(c) of this title.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CB2A4DDF8E14170A6DD463FBCEFC9AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>paragraphs (1) and (2)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (1), (2), and (3)</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F0D1C497B4F4208808B70DFA9E3F1BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other Federal contracts</header> <paragraph id="HEBC99B170CD049EEA4C2685B1437E26A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consideration of outsourcing</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/35">Chapter 35</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/41/3303">section 3303</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F5F02996AF44D26A1AD5C5D483E9057" style="USC">
						<section id="HC461A15BA0A34F779A407039D6A835FD"><enum>3303a.</enum><header>Bidders outsourcing jobs: disclosure of outsourcing; consideration of outsourcing in award;
			 exclusion from sources</header>
							<subsection id="H182A4EE70D704DF1ACB198CA18A731AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disclosure of outsourcing of jobs</header>
 <paragraph id="H5C698A7A6BA4480480D7A2A27152BBDB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of an executive agency shall require a contractor that submits a bid or proposal in response to a solicitation issued by the executive agency to disclose in that bid or proposal if the contractor, or a subsidiary of the contractor, owns a facility for which there is an outsourcing event during the three-year period ending on the date of the submittal of the bid or proposal.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2802A9745E9D4E4290F7416C8E9430D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Outsourcing event</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <term>outsourcing event</term> means a plant closing or mass layoff (as described in section 2(a) of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act) in which the employment loss (excluding any part-time employees) for positions which will be moved to a country outside of the United States, as determined pursuant to the outsourcing statement (as described in paragraph (1) of such section 3(e) of such Act) served by the taxpayer during the taxable year, exceeds 50 employees.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5635080950B847BFA7FB70771D782563"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consideration authorized</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB8EA660580F54E5493892B69938EC2B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Contracting officers of an executive agency considering bids or proposals in response to a solicitation issued by the executive agency may take into account any disclosure made pursuant to subsection (a) in such bids and proposals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA80C45CF5310486EB9A886224642E9AF" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The head of an executive agency may establish a negative preference of up to 10 percent of the cost of a contract for purposes of evaluating a bid or proposal of a contractor that makes a disclosure pursuant to subsection (a).</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E5956C053314307B9E3C51BE53FFD32"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exclusion from sources</header>
 <paragraph id="HF4B59E87D99E4FB7A0B524391D75B2C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of an executive agency may provide for the procurement of property and services using competitive procedures but excluding a source making a disclosure under subsection (a) in the bid or proposal in response to the solicitation issued by the executive agency if the head of the executive agency determines that the actions described by disclosure are against the public interests of the United States and the source is to be excluded on those grounds. Any such determination shall take into account the sense of Congress set forth in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE083462480CC4AC3A3D680DACBE6D0A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that contracting officers of executive agencies may use paragraph (1) to exclude contractors making a disclosure pursuant to subsection (a) in response to a solicitation issued by the executive agency from the bidding process in connection with the solicitation on the grounds that the actions described by the disclosure are against the public interests of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBFD7A1000DA14FAFB3FC8F25626BAD66"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The head of each executive agency shall submit to Congress each year a report on the following:</text> <paragraph id="H6930B3329A1A4489B4BFD13BD297960D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of solicitations made by the executive agency during the preceding year for which disclosures were made pursuant to subsection (a) in responsive bids or proposals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBDDD8297FB284AFD8DF65DC0AD98326A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of contracts awarded to contractors that disclosed having outsourced more than 50 jobs during the preceding three years.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A39EE1028D44017BD11CE20E7E87B12"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 35 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 3303 the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block id="HD3D80864D77649AC9043FE1641D21668" style="USC">
						<toc>
							<toc-entry idref="HC461A15BA0A34F779A407039D6A835FD" level="section">3303a. Bidders outsourcing jobs: disclosure of outsourcing; consideration of outsourcing in award;
			 exclusion from sources.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4ECD48841EC419AB1BBA5EBB93FB1F5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 3301(a) of such title is amended by inserting <quote>3303a(c),</quote> after <quote>3303,</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB8D32A4543C4085B296B44F0450A4EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header> <paragraph id="HC118463D6FA74CB7AD21BE6FBB19CE75"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council, in consultation with the heads of relevant agencies, shall amend the Federal Acquisition Regulation and the Defense Federal Acquisition Regulation Supplement to carry out the requirements of section 3303a of title 41, United States Code, and section 2327a of title 10, United States Code, as added by this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7501569964B04E67AF77693EBD87462A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition of outsourcing</header><text>For purposes of defining outsourcing pursuant to paragraph (1), the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council may utilize regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Labor.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C6EE8A00CE04632BD90F0A42C84E571"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>This section, and the amendments made by this section, shall be applied in a manner consistent with United States obligations under international agreements.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


