<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H8FCC75A227854B309DF4F22CBC2EE6A0" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3241 IH: To require the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to consider greenhouse gas emissions related to natural gas pipelines, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3241</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170714">July 14, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to consider greenhouse gas emissions related to
			 natural gas pipelines, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H34217B8D7E7042FEAD9F5227196FAEBF" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA07F4B8226C44D18AD54D48AE61132DF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Review of greenhouse gas emissions from pipeline projects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In complying with the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> et seq.) with respect to the issuance of a certificate of public convenience and necessity under section 7 of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717f">15 U.S.C. 717f</external-xref>) for a natural gas pipeline, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission shall consider greenhouse gas emissions associated with the construction and operation of the pipeline, and the production, transportation, and combustion of the natural gas to be transported through the pipeline.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


