<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H064FFBFB6C0949BBB0849E94CB9034F0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2918 IH: Patients First Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2918</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170615">June 15, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks of Indiana</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To intensify stem cell research showing evidence of substantial clinical benefit to patients, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1401DFC88CDC4B549AB6C2426CFA3734" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA7B194978ADC4F9F98B98BD08C6A4075" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Patients First Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H380DFF3BEFD84993A3C38C7118880A2B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the purpose of this Act to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC7166928049E4A85B63B2FCC944BB117"><enum>(1)</enum><text>intensify research that may result in improved understanding of or treatments for diseases and other adverse health conditions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1417546923054B47A479597279F4B0C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promote research and human clinical trials using stem cells that are ethically obtained and show evidence of providing clinical benefit for human patients; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDA55E3D1E0704FDD9F53576F53DFB0C6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promote the derivation of pluripotent stem cell lines without the creation of human embryos for research purposes and without the destruction or discarding of, or risk of injury to, a human embryo.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H25BE026FF8CB4923BFEFDFD0F26FF4E9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Human stem cell research and therapy</header> <subsection id="HC468338902544AFC830EB17AC8AEF632"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part B of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/284">42 U.S.C. 284</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by inserting after section 409J the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H29157F7EA16D402BA4E82AEB48FC356E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H55B72B08A9684485A3C9D14E5C76A82B"><enum>409K.</enum><header>Human stem cell research and therapy</header> 
<subsection id="HF856C31E34404D8288F23DEC8A24181A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct and support basic and applied research to develop techniques for the isolation, derivation, production, testing, and human clinical use of stem cells that may result in improved understanding of or treatments for diseases and other adverse health conditions, including pluripotent stem cells that have the flexibility of embryonic stem cells (whether or not such pluripotent stem cells have an embryonic source), prioritizing research with the greatest potential for near-term clinical benefit in human patients, provided that such isolation, derivation, production, testing, or use will not involve—</text> <paragraph id="H2100F6DC641F46CCAF80AC056FA4BF4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the creation of a human embryo for research purposes;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8FDB28D969EE48729138D31DC213A561"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the destruction of or discarding of, or risk of injury to, a living human embryo; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H927BF8CFCF844673A87134E12EA07BBD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the use of any stem cell, the derivation or provision of which would be inconsistent with the standards established in paragraph (1) or (2).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1EE2D7096687490EA0A036DE26F3E45C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary, after consultation with the Director of NIH, shall issue final guidelines implementing subsection (a) to ensure that any research (including any clinical trial) supported under subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="HAFCA3D18A72440C1967F30CF0BCD8E10"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is clearly consistent with the standards established in subsection (a) if conducted using human cells, as demonstrated by animal trials or other substantial evidence; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7BC93D59A4A4A2B9FF0440C7FFF4212"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is prioritized in terms of potential for near-term clinical benefit in human patients, as indicated by substantial evidence from basic research or by substantial clinical evidence which may include but is not limited to—</text> <subparagraph id="HA4DFF6FF5E9940938E22D272FED7A2DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evidence of improvement in one or more human patients suffering from illness or injury, as documented in reports by professional medical or scientific associations or in peer-reviewed medical or scientific literature; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8E9B8610576441E5A0195701D487D37B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>approval for use in human trials by the Food and Drug Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H12FD95A5C64D45589C910BC0464285B0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFABF581CAFDE4708A2B7B7E499CA7F03"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Human embryo</header><text>The term <term>human embryo</term> includes any organism, not protected as a human subject under part 46 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, as of the date of the enactment of this section, that is derived by fertilization, parthenogenesis, cloning, or any other means from one or more human gametes or human diploid cells.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H11576D443BD04326B046AC38AC6E8614"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Risk of injury</header><text>The term <term>risk of injury</term> means subjecting a human embryo to risk of injury or death greater than that allowed for research on fetuses in utero under section 46.204(b) of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), or section 498(b) of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE2AA03E0AD9B4FCABB50FF1806AC3A5E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority setting; reports</header><text>Section 492 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/289a">42 U.S.C. 289a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H09DFCC45E38E40CEB099C6C367632BB6" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HD16E082979BF4D84AE096A29320473F5"><enum>(d)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H81676DEE9E6B44DA8AF9F3A7D03B1D2F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>With respect to human stem cell research, the Secretary, acting through the Director of NIH, shall give priority to conducting or supporting research in accordance with section 409K.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD976942DC03847F1972CBF60F5D74220" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>At the end of fiscal year 2018 and each subsequent fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a report outlining the number of research proposals under section 409K that were peer reviewed, a summary and detailed list of all such research proposals that were not funded, and an explanation of why the proposals did not merit funding. The reports under this paragraph shall be in addition to the reporting on stem cell research included in the biennial report required by section 403.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HDEE3EBA197A94CFABC450886503A8AD1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Biennial reports</header><text>Section 403(a)(5) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/283">42 U.S.C. 283(a)(5)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H14DF22BCFC5F48E58F7E210F687DD232"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (L) as subparagraph (M); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H393846D509C340B984F0EFA5DD87B3C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (K) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA83D25A830E4FEFB18C3CA9521E30EE" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H124D02A97B754B0884EEFCD66F1BB845"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Stem cells.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

