<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HAB7ED1B2221F4C78B219B6DC8A400686" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4558 IH: Grand Staircase Escalante Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-12-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4558</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171206">December 6, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001250">Mr. Bishop of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000584">Mrs. Love</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001114">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide greater conservation, recreation, economic development and local management of Federal
			 lands in Garfield and Kane Counties, Utah.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H57C26866FF17414BAEFF961535232D0A" style="OLC">
 <section id="H07C97F7BF2964097A32EB996590866CB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Grand Staircase Escalante Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H05599D686F894F6681CF1DADDFE99E65"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of Contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
			<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
				<toc-entry idref="H07C97F7BF2964097A32EB996590866CB" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H05599D686F894F6681CF1DADDFE99E65" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HF2844599ADC74CD7951B2026D6BBC583" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H718A8E7B13C14A2091A1C3915575BB9A" level="section">Sec. 4. Establishment of Escalante Canyons National Park and Preserve.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H65279DB1D69541AC8614294E25A1581B" level="section">Sec. 5. Withdrawals.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H6AC7EE06BD4E44348C013F2F17DE8237" level="section">Sec. 6. Map and legal description.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HC984497293B14A88B0F99AA210A59C49" level="section">Sec. 7. Grand Staircase National Monument.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H5B1DB1BC844649D8B8EFC17443A48643" level="section">Sec. 8. Kaiparowits National Monument.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H639F3C8631644D73821A2455225BE418" level="section">Sec. 9. Escalante Canyons National Monument.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HF9A5BBC72F8F47EAAF3C64CF8C773D9A" level="section">Sec. 10. Escalante Canyons National Park and Preserve, Grand Staircase National Monument,
			 Kaiparowits National Monument, and Escalante Canyons National Monument
			 Management Council.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H365295BDA75544F99CB9EC51735B5AB1" level="section">Sec. 11. Federal land manager adherence.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H0C588329A2264A81B7B8EE9E1C6B622B" level="section">Sec. 12. Clarification.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H5A44901AA6A4447AA1B234825FEE515D" level="section">Sec. 13. Restoration of land status.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="H4F221C79599B4161BD3D453C0E333716" level="section">Sec. 14. Hole in the Rock Road.</toc-entry>
				<toc-entry idref="HFD0F613A078D47BCB4AED609813CF525" level="section">Sec. 15. Effect on proclamations.</toc-entry>
			</toc>
 </section><section id="HF2844599ADC74CD7951B2026D6BBC583"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HE67C6E63BD6C4723AD46CD01BB3FF639"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Management Council</header><text>The term <term>Management Council</term> means the council established under section 10.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H47F6A353CB264DE6BE1D106C05BE2E7D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H718A8E7B13C14A2091A1C3915575BB9A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of Escalante Canyons National Park and Preserve</header> <subsection id="HD95B003F239E4819A2F1A4F1FA9BC563"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby established within the Escalante Canyons National Monument the <quote>Escalante Canyons National Park and Preserve</quote> in the State of Utah.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3BFBD0454C3B4742BC74C640A61A7F8B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Boundaries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The boundaries of Escalante Canyons National Park and Preserve are as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>____</quote>, numbered ___, and dated ____. The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8302AEDE12FB472083EF9E157A971CC8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of the Escalante Canyons National Park and Preserve shall be to protect, conserve, and enhance in the Escalante Canyons National Park and Preserve—</text>
 <paragraph id="H6D5F13EB24DF4B538CBF2DE291E4109A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the unique and nationally important historic, natural, scenic, and natural resources;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H73839087AE664D0A9E73B302369F6F08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recreation, including hunting; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC7F59F5E87D2405F8102E07CAC904780"><enum>(3)</enum><text>grazing.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H65279DB1D69541AC8614294E25A1581B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Withdrawals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights, any Federal land within the Escalante Canyons National Park and Preserve, including any land or interest in land that is acquired by the United States after the date of enactment of this Act, is withdrawn from—</text>
 <paragraph id="HECD6DE2DD01C484B864BD648CB7D626D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H1A800CF0720E4F64BA711F9523C0C87F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H021C9F47B98740A6889D88DA40FA4DD1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H6AC7EE06BD4E44348C013F2F17DE8237"><enum>6.</enum><header>Map and legal description</header> <subsection id="HD839074EA37A425EBD1DF0DEEE12901F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a map and legal description of the Escalante Canyons National Park and Preserve.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9F8E898B621542B8B56442C521B16EF2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Force and effect</header><text>The map and legal description submitted under this section shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary may make minor modifications of any clerical or typographical errors in the map or legal description provided these changes are first reported to the State of Utah, Garfield and Kane Counties in Utah, and the Management Council.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="HC984497293B14A88B0F99AA210A59C49"><enum>7.</enum><header>Grand Staircase National Monument</header>
 <subsection id="HE7BE8B8832AC4C8C90A4C33EBFD2F211"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land comprising approximately 211,983 acres, identified as <quote>Grand Staircase Unit</quote> and generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Grand Staircase-Escalante National Monument Modification</quote> is hereby established as the <quote>Grand Staircase National Monument</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4C1AB57E8FB642EBB79516F7AA9D67C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Grand Staircase National Monument shall be to protect, conserve, and enhance the monument’s—</text>
 <paragraph id="H0EC04CA4F22C4A898D715FAB4C1C26AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>unique and nationally important historic, scenic, and natural resources;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D0581C39B8E49D194729995C2C13D0E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recreation, including hunting; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2EBAFE06649B4B978CC0C5ADDB1A2307"><enum>(3)</enum><text>grazing.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD794D0826A8444B89F543FE30B8A2437"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Map</header> <paragraph id="H0515EAE0BD4A49CEA43C501D10797C19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a map and legal description of the Grand Staircase National Monument established in this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H39EE9891822948649B93503DD8C94AAD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The map and legal description submitted under this section shall have the same force and effect as if included in this title, except that the Secretary may make minor modification of any clerical or typographical errors in the map or legal description provided these changes are first reported to the State of Utah, Kane County, Utah, and the Management Council.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF4A0CC6BE4A9418BA7518154BDD0C845"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A copy of the map and legal description shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate field offices of the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5B1DB1BC844649D8B8EFC17443A48643"><enum>8.</enum><header>Kaiparowits National Monument</header>
 <subsection id="H849B8AA910444FE2A760ABBAD9EA7F26"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Federal land comprising approximately 551,117 acres, identified as <quote>Kaiparowits Unit</quote> and generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Grand Staircase-Escalante National Monument Modification</quote> is hereby established as the <quote>Kaiparowits National Monument</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF0856C4D28AD439F80250F2B4A05DAB7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Kaiparowits National Monument shall be to protect, conserve, and enhance the monument’s—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB08CE2A9B0234B44A5919509BE5481CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>unique and nationally important historic, scenic, and natural resources;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HBFEB7B461EF846639E66083C257CB5AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recreation, including hunting; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2756C12A410646D9B2A177B0BC27EE49"><enum>(3)</enum><text>grazing.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0EC7F0FCDCD8485EB56F70E3F5845879"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Map</header> <paragraph id="H3595AD9BCDB14E7D800791B152F53C41"><enum>(1)</enum><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a map and legal description of the Kaiparowits National Monument established in this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB500754BB4E644BEACD45A0158946124"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The map and legal description submitted under this section shall have the same force and effect as if included in this title, except that the Secretary may make minor modification of any clerical or typographical errors in the map or legal description provided these changes are first reported to the State of Utah, Kane and Garfield Counties, Utah, and the Management Council.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF45AEA84147D49DEA63399652CC0F685"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A copy of the map and legal description shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate field offices of the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H639F3C8631644D73821A2455225BE418"><enum>9.</enum><header>Escalante Canyons National Monument</header>
 <subsection id="H5DE694758AB843B1AAA13CA5BE8A09E1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Subject to the valid existing rights, the Federal land comprising approximately 243,241 acres, identified as <quote>Escalante Canyons Unit</quote> and generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Grand Staircase-Escalante National Monument Modification</quote> is hereby established as the <quote>Escalante Canyons National Monument</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0568F300E2144257874B8247234EFE05"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Escalante Canyons National Monument shall be to protect, conserve, and enhance the monument’s—</text>
 <paragraph id="HD50DC5F8D045407C9191978F96BF77E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>unique and nationally important historic, scenic, and natural resources;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H77E9616F842C4590BB14000573AA42B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recreation, including hunting; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H618B24FAF93A481892FD223C846AD5AC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>grazing.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE6A3F8292F1643A6935FDDBA32D056A9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Map</header> <paragraph id="HF2F98E3D49C545DF81786B648E37BB16"><enum>(1)</enum><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a map and legal description of the Escalante Canyons National Monument established in this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE516947F8BB243F6BCAE7A3E225A90A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The map and legal description submitted under this section shall have the same force and effect as if included in this title, except that the Secretary may make minor modification of any clerical or typographical errors in the map or legal description provided these changes are first reported to the State of Utah, Garfield County, Utah, and the Management Council.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H77BE25ED7B224021A7751B8E14BC108B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A copy of the map and legal description shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate field offices of the Bureau of Land Management.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF9A5BBC72F8F47EAAF3C64CF8C773D9A"><enum>10.</enum><header>Escalante Canyons National Park and Preserve, Grand Staircase National Monument, Kaiparowits
			 National Monument, and Escalante Canyons National Monument Management
			 Council</header>
 <subsection id="H8F8A00AF4E2946B0B70B9E65CDBE6772"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Management Council is hereby established.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HD9F755E663DE442C9D9CB1AE3267F35B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Management Council shall develop and implement the comprehensive management plans for the Escalante Canyons National Park and Preserve, the Grand Staircase National Monument, the Kaiparowits National Monument, and the Escalante Canyons National Monument consistently with the purposes of those areas as provided in this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H681C1FF656124DD88B3B31B6EE334A6E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Management Council shall be composed of 7 members appointed not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act as follows:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1447FFC4FD1D4E9D8CD05ED6B05934CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One individual from the Department of Interior, appointed by the President.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H72DAC2B6E0A343B8903D396D6D495FC2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Five individuals, appointed by the President in consultation with the Congressional delegation from the State of Utah and the Governor of Utah, who shall represent the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4F532E122BBD410AAC2AFA91A2818D44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Two from the Garfield County, Utah, Board of Commissioners.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF69693127CF4A88A527431AC80532AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Two from the Kane County, Utah, Board of Commissioners.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB997229863EF4B25BD012A9C159AB8A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>One Utah State Legislator representing Kane County, Garfield County, or both.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70251669DC934530A14F292DF42AFAD1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One at-large representative appointed by the President.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HECC64E768F784E828B51D741FB705270"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>The members appointed under subsections (c)(2) and (3) shall not be employees of the Federal Government.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBE207E76714A4406991816D5AC5E4E55"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>The President shall appoint the members under subsections (c)(2) and (3) for a term of 5 years, except that the President shall designate staggered terms for the members initially appointed to the Management Council. The President may reappoint a member to not more than three consecutive terms.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD0E9634E86D64C9FB8192D8B76DC81B6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Vacancies of members appointed under subsections (c)(2) and (3) shall be filled in the same manner as such positions were originally filled as soon as practicable after the vacancy has occurred.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9AE55C6CD8ED473B92EBF7B37BAE3230"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members appointed under subsections (c)(2) and (3) shall serve without pay, except for reasonable travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at the rate authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of duties for the Council.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2EE0036149694FD08796283966FC0AD7"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Chair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members shall select the chair of the Management Council from the members appointed under subsection (c)(2) and (3) for a term beginning on the date of selection, and ending in 5 years or until the member’s term of office expires, whichever occurs first.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H85C9627B9BD84D899EE75CA87FEAB548"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Staff assistance</header><text>The Management Council may request administrative assistance from Federal employees under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H01005E878C8C4E99B47B64337FD564D4"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Meetings</header>
 <paragraph id="H4F4924BFF9294DB58AFC8BA71437BF31"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>The Management Council shall meet at the call of the Chair or a majority of the members. Meetings shall be held no less than once per year. A majority must be present to constitute a quorum to conduct official business.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA576534920F84F6591BE4B1C61D184DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Announcement; open meetings</header><text>All meetings of the Management Council shall be announced at least one week in advance in publications of general circulation and shall be open to the public.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7233C69A06B9478B8C8D16A990DCD4F6"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Administration</header>
 <paragraph id="H0C019B3B0BB846A9A4A7FDE923C878E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Management Council shall allow hunting, fishing and trapping on lands and water under the jurisdiction of the Secretary within the Escalante Canyons National Park and Preserve in accordance with the applicable laws of the State of Utah.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C0663284CB446899F12A78882D59FD6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Management Council shall ensure that the privilege of grazing domestic livestock on lands with the Escalante Canyons National Park and Preserve shall continue to be exercised and enhanced in perpetuity. Grazing within the Escalante Canyons National Park and Preserve shall be administered by the National Park Service.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H365295BDA75544F99CB9EC51735B5AB1"><enum>11.</enum><header>Federal land manager adherence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Federal land managers shall adhere to the management plans created by the Management Council.</text> </section><section id="H0C588329A2264A81B7B8EE9E1C6B622B"><enum>12.</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act affects the jurisdiction of the State of Utah with respect to the management of fish, wildlife and predators in the State.</text>
 </section><section id="H5A44901AA6A4447AA1B234825FEE515D"><enum>13.</enum><header>Restoration of land status</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights, the provisions of existing withdrawals, and the requirements of applicable law, the public lands excluded from the monument reservation under Presidential Proclamation ___, dated December 4, 2017, and issued under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/3203">chapter 3203</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code, shall be open to:</text>
 <paragraph id="H32F9B96BE82747A4AB66F3AEB6265DF3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entry, location, selection, sale or other disposition under the public land laws;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC160A532F68E4CECAD3BA8CD8487307D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>disposition under all laws relating to mineral and geothermal leasing; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H75A8AA53AACC48B087897D7FE486B49A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H4F221C79599B4161BD3D453C0E333716"><enum>14.</enum><header>Hole in the Rock Road</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall convey to the State of Utah all right, title and interest of the United States in and to the Hole in the Rock Road (BLM Road 200).</text>
 </section><section id="HFD0F613A078D47BCB4AED609813CF525"><enum>15.</enum><header>Effect on proclamations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any provision of Presidential Proclamation 6920, dated September 18, 1996, and Presidential Proclamation ____, dated December 4, 2017, and issued under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/3203">chapter 3203</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code, that is inconsistent with this Act is hereby declared null and void.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


