<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HEAD1530CCEB14F95B89F8741D5FBB9D9" key="H" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3646 IH: Water Quality Conservation Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-08-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3646</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20170804">August 4, 2017</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000066">Mr. Young of Iowa</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out a precision conservation pilot program, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H62326385427F48ED8685DB75A24A8FA8" style="OLC"> 
<section commented="no" id="H2CFD9703C01E44608D478F8E8C3CD84B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Water Quality Conservation Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H8927E6702D0A4B189E374E934FEBB8C8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA35526715EC54BA7837F39E2A49040D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To identify and promote the use of innovative and effective conservation practices.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8885AD38C9F74224A917F18EB0331E1F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To apply targeted soil and water conservation practices at the watershed, sub-watershed, and field scales.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H18E54C9398EE400D9DC01DA887A6C3D8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To increase the use of conservation practices by producers.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0050F22D872420992E776985B18EFE7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To collect data on how the implementation of precision conservation practices affects soil health, reduces erosion and nutrient runoff of soil, and enhances water quality.</text> </paragraph></section> 
<section id="H59566C3F211740EDBB8DE73BD7F25831"><enum>3.</enum><header>Precision conservation pilot program</header> 
<subsection id="HCFCEE27A48AB4CB580EC7529651707BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1240B of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3839aa-2">16 U.S.C. 3839aa–2</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B277145E8C849C082EDA352A8187A9F" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HA85D1D4FEE744942A1F87CA14BE9E84C"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Precision conservation pilot program</header> <paragraph id="H5B876B5270864D63BBAB482C9F784EC0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pilot program authorized</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to carry out a precision conservation pilot program to provide grants to not more than 10 States to assist producers with projects that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF1E214FE25FD4EB5A29E2397D31069B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increase nutrient retention in soil;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0D04065D7DC742A4A599375C477D6C94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduce soil erosion;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0CD713A19F634BEA85337FE6EE43E87D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reduce nutrient loss from soil;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H45BF82B3F71D4C4DA384AF821B45A3FF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>improve soil health; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1D82E754FA1044B48816C921DA9E4D3D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>improve water quality.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00D93AC75C824CBAAB9411654B55AD26"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), a State shall submit an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a description of how the State will—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC8668DD18A7D41A9904841AFF0E43914"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collaborate with a partnership of entities, which may include State agencies, local governments, institutions of higher education, soil and water conservation districts, producers, Indian tribes, agricultural associations, nonprofit entities, and other relevant entities to carry out precision conservation pilot programs; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H04B7765546174D40BDA14C7595694A32"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">give priority to assisting producers with projects within critical areas, including—</text> 
<clause id="HF46025BCB69E4371929C9CE2539B9BC4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>critical conservation areas designated under section 1271F; and</text> </clause> <clause id="HE84E3AD0BEC14174B3CC72B2DFA75C94"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>critical watersheds, as defined by such State.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAFC5574993A447EBBB4D8E787F480E03"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Matching funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State awarded a grant under this subsection shall provide non-Federal funds, including cash and in-kind contributions, in an amount that is at least equal to the amount of such grant.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C202045B9724BD3935D53947545C720"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A State awarded a grant under this section may use grant funds only—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H010FB081176646BBB970123C5BC9FF5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to educate and recruit agricultural producers to participate in the pilot program;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H85C74179E1E1417E981BD09953BA114C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide technical and financial assistance to producers that elect to participate in a precision conservation pilot program for which the State received a grant under this section to create and implement precision conservation plans;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H354F1CC1C28F4FCEA17E545D4665009B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to monitor and analyze the effectiveness of such precision conservation plans; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H28D430BD4F4F4957A53F735E22BB256C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to encourage the use of precision agriculture technology to achieve conservation benefits.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H52002811EC63449AB6F207FAD5576F33"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header> 
<subparagraph id="HB7CA0114E17C4D94B64BC70B5CB5CB5E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of information furnished by a producer or State in order to facilitate the creation and implementation of a precision conservation plan pursuant to paragraph (4)(B) or comply with the reporting requirements under paragraph (6)(B), the Secretary, any other officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture or agency thereof, or any other person may not—</text> <clause id="HAB6BFE9B8E684F96AC197E2B39AA57C6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>use such information for a purpose other than the development or reporting of aggregate data under paragraphs (6) and (7) in a manner such that the identity of the producer who supplied such information is not discernible and is not material to the intended uses of such information; or</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H8DD1C5C2ACAA494DB8284E40FED21485"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>disclose the information to any person or any Federal, State, local, or tribal agency outside the Department of Agriculture, unless the information has been converted into a statistical or aggregate form that does not allow the identification of the producer that supplied particular information.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H26D997FFCA2D4E5F861E5593C17F5D08"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to limit a producer from sharing the information furnished by such producer pursuant to subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H364579A1FA694F1E81F52712CBE8B2B2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State reporting</header> 
<subparagraph id="HABBA2C25DC7E4C819D41224B7A9631C9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reports to producers</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which a State assists a producer with the creation of a precision conservation plan pursuant to paragraph (4)(B), and each year for the succeeding 4 years thereafter, the State shall submit to such producer a report that includes an analysis of the effectiveness of the precision conservation plan for such producer.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE84F5EBE037C4B19B9EF4B4FCE055CA1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reports to Secretary</header> <clause id="HAE9FF1AEF0BA411A80488DCC8B3D7FA7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Annual</header><text>Not later than one year after the date on which a State receives grant funds under this section, and each year for the succeeding 3 years thereafter, the State shall submit to the Secretary a report that includes the data used to create, implement, and analyze precision conservation plans pursuant to this subsection.</text> </clause> 
<clause id="HF69BE83D654A4DA2A2BB2E3724CBDCD4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>5-year report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date on which a State receives grant funds under this section, the State shall submit to the Secretary a report that includes an analysis of the effectiveness the use of grant funds under this subsection has had in fostering—</text> <subclause id="HADDC432D27FE47A79D294FC22330A01B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>improved soil health;</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="H2D0F29D647264DEA8C0CFED0A995C180"><enum>(II)</enum><text>reduced soil erosion and soil runoff;</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H1BCC49E08FB344F88433D389DD95AC16"><enum>(III)</enum><text>improved water quality;</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="H1D5508B3C1974E0F95C664856085B327"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>improved understanding of the relationship between precision agriculture technology and conservation improvement; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H1F617C8BF84E4AEDBF2266AD6DA3A4B2"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the effectiveness of different methods used.</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H267219981C0445A7B3C54E50CC6DBE92"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Soil nutrient retention database</header> 
<subparagraph id="H4B57BA80C742406B9BCFF8C7EA45E366"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall use the data reported under paragraph (6) to establish and maintain a publically available soil nutrient retention database that provides—</text> <clause id="HCEACA3D890294C8D842302E8E9D9D2D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a compilation and analysis of effective conservation practices for nutrient management in varying soil compositions, cropping systems, slopes, and landscapes; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H7E6D9830BEAA4C7995774682209B58BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommended new and effective conservation practices for nutrient management.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H86BE4B5CFF6C44A0A6B4C60DC37D4D63"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Funding for database</header><text>The Secretary may reserve up to $75,000 of the funds made available under subsection (f)(3) to carry out this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H767CED7BE3DB473887C9CBDD6B5D04B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allocation of funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1240B(f) of the Food Security Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3839aa-2">16 U.S.C. 3839aa–2(f)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE30A327C8794C9890B6D3556D349296" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HEFCFBBD4452049B7ACE44B89381E6496"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Precision conservation pilot program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, at least 5 percent of the funds made available for payments under the program shall be targeted for the precision conservation pilot program under subsection (j).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


