<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H1E544035471947E391E3935428812275" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1757 IH: Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1757</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170328">March 28, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To address the psychological, developmental, social, and emotional needs of children, youth, and
			 families who have experienced trauma, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H347FE4504E794B2A885065D9DE28E872" style="OLC">
 <section id="H5090670C894343DCB1E6664517272280" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H29925400B8F643B68CC5548C7E0C2DD0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB8B36028D5CE4BC4A739575DD5C3FA46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The 2007 Great Smoky Mountains Study, a representative longitudinal study of children, found that by age 16, more than 67 percent of the children had been exposed to 1 or more traumatic events, such as child maltreatment, domestic violence, or sexual assault.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H80061C586ABF4C7D8AAE4F6869D8C5E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>According to a 2009 Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention study of children ages 0 through 17, more than 60 percent of the children surveyed were exposed to violence within the past year, either directly or indirectly.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DA43767A37D4427871F5C4580914A32"><enum>(3)</enum><text>According to the Administration for Children and Families, the rate of substantiated reports of child maltreatment in fiscal year 2015 was 9.2 per 1,000 children ages 0 through 17, with children under age 1 having the highest rate of 24.2 per 1,000 children.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H436BBC7BAD6C49429E1660428EF0035D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>According to the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention, a longitudinal study of youth detained at a juvenile detention center in Chicago showed that 92.5 percent of youth had experienced at least 1 trauma, and 84 percent had experienced more than 1 trauma.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1350F4D42D3D46109820FB87E0CCECF3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The National Intimate Partner and Sexual Violence Survey conducted by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention revealed that nearly 1 in 5 women reported having been the victim of a rape at some time during their lives. Seventy-eight percent experienced their first rape before the age of 25.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA5AE870850CC4E198F08D0E5788E5FFF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A 2017 study found that abuse and maltreatment suffered as a child was associated with post-traumatic stress disorder and opioid-related misuse as an adult, and recommended that trauma history and post-traumatic stress disorder symptom severity be addressed as part of opioid addiction treatment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADCFB6403C5A4B5C958E1F035F2C0BD4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Findings from the Adverse Childhood Experiences Study conducted by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention have shown that adverse childhood experiences predispose children towards negative trajectories from infancy through adolescence. Followup representative studies have shown the long-range impact of early trauma exposure on adult health conditions, including heart disease, asthma, and mental health.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF3C83FB8CBBA4F9E8518D93F37D27302"><enum>(8)</enum><text>According to a subsequent study conducted by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, adults who had been exposed to multiple adverse childhood experiences were significantly more likely to be unemployed, to be living in poverty, and not to have graduated high school than adults who had zero adverse childhood experiences.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE0504277F4443A28B2B9A150379FA69"><enum>(9)</enum><text>According to a 2008 finding by the National Child Traumatic Stress Network, educators who work directly with traumatized children and adolescents are particularly vulnerable to secondary traumatic stress, experiencing burnout, fatigue, irritability, and other symptoms, and can be supported through early recognition of that stress, self-care, and trauma-informed support systems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFFF7298A929842CBA8F61EF500F0F89D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Findings from a 2012 study conducted by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention included an estimate that the total lifetime burden of child maltreatment cases that occur each year in the United States, including medical, welfare, and criminal justice costs, is $124,000,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H647D9463F0BD4250BC226C219EC2B09A"><enum>(11)</enum><text>According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention’s National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey, only half of children ages 8 through 15 with a mental disorder had received treatment for their disorder within the past year. Children with anxiety disorders such as post-traumatic stress disorder were the least likely to be treated, with only 32.2 percent having received treatment for a mental disorder in the past year.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C20FA44B11449FBBB8957906195B6BD"><enum>(12)</enum><text>According to a 2014 report of the Institute of Medicine and National Research Council of the National Academies entitled <quote>New Directions in Child Abuse and Neglect Research</quote>, research has shown that child abuse and neglect experiences resulted in higher risk for behavioral health problems (such as depression and substance use) throughout life, but that with informed prevention approaches, child abuse and neglect can be both preventable and manageable.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H54FC0F6D8096476C8724774996FF0969"><enum>(13)</enum><text>According to a 2017 finding by the National Child Traumatic Stress Network, of the children served by the Network with problems in the clinical range when entering care, 83 percent showed significant improvements in post-traumatic stress disorder, behavioral problems, or traumatic stress symptoms after receiving evidence-based treatments.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCCE1CD730EB64003B0D9B1EF376212A6"><enum>(14)</enum><text>According to a 2008 Washington State report on prevention programs that assessed both cost and effectiveness, evidence-based, two-generational child trauma treatments such as Parent-Child Interaction Therapy return $3.64 per dollar of cost.</text>
			</paragraph></section><title id="H064845D5B1E5495CB82F2FA681F482FC" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Development of best practices</header>
			<section id="H0F24FFD8FBFC4AD4955BCF83A96643D3"><enum>101.</enum><header>Task force to develop best practices for trauma-informed identification, referral, and support</header>
				<subsection id="HAD67ECC45D0E40BCB1B90BDFC632465C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of task force To identify, evaluate, recommend, maintain, and update best practices</header>
 <paragraph id="H3FFAE906697B43C78C1CB297A0AD9F2E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established a task force, to be known as the Interagency Task Force on Trauma-Informed Care.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC39D859A9C374C5DB3F6C921FF3D94C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Main duties</header><text>The task force shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H9D4A8C96E8374CBB8439DEBF0FED50D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify, evaluate, recommend, maintain, and update, as described in subsection (c) and in accordance with subsection (d), a set of best practices with respect to children and youth, and their families as appropriate, who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3140F54DD47E4B05A2BA3136AF66B1C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carry out other duties as described in subsection (c).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6EA5AEC33D9642219B092A162A702064"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Task force composition</header> <paragraph id="H9634842CE9314D809A7FA1756E226C1A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The task force shall be composed of Federal employees, consisting of the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use (referred to in this section as the <quote>Assistant Secretary</quote>, except where another Assistant Secretary is specifically named) and 1 representative of each of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H484FA507AD9D464BAF10A991A689ABF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the National Center for Injury Prevention and Control of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB4C70042460416689B173323E0DCF18"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Center for Mental Health Services of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD967D9C3C2F044B384E9C1F348642F31"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Center for Substance Abuse Prevention of that Administration;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FC60C019477446098B9D99DD54F45F5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Center for Substance Abuse Treatment of that Administration;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2833E5D36364FEB92C3169605DD81CF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Center for Behavioral Health Statistics and Quality of that Administration;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4BDB763CB91404F9E44B8E0FAE7B0A3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Maternal and Child Health Bureau of the Health Resources and Services Administration;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69F502EFF1594C3B984596848F17487D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Center for Medicaid and CHIP Services;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67ADD661D74242C1A205A035963CEFEE"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the National Institute of Mental Health;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1F06096DDBE4F1DAF173588D51CA507"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE114A91A68D7469CB20E429230C96A81"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the National Institute on Drug Abuse;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C0867B530F249B8B377F198FEB53645"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BC091EDC05945769D34CD6844E77CF8"><enum>(L)</enum><text>the Administration on Children, Youth and Families of the Administration for Children and Families;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8C84175C2D3469EB78EE8A438F98273"><enum>(M)</enum><text>the Administration for Native Americans of the Administration for Children and Families;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H187EDA453E344838B65396E6DDE4286A"><enum>(N)</enum><text>the Office of Child Care of the Administration for Children and Families;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96438BE624F94D46BE00A42096A949E1"><enum>(O)</enum><text>the Office of Head Start of the Administration for Children and Families;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3608740D34964FF986B972BBFD94DD35"><enum>(P)</enum><text>the Office of Refugee Resettlement of the Administration for Children and Families;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2285056A71546A6B092A25FB5B284ED"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>the Indian Health Service of the Department of Health and Human Services;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51B4559DC5BE4CDCAC9D1BB5D60D1BC1"><enum>(R)</enum><text>the Office of Minority Health of the Department of Health and Human Services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5378DB52C8546789864023A1AC2F247"><enum>(S)</enum><text>the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCECBABD6DF0436482E1FD23C5E51E39"><enum>(T)</enum><text>the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention of the Department of Justice;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A5EBA0FC4BD41DC9B15BEB7F4F4D844"><enum>(U)</enum><text>the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services of the Department of Justice;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72BC0A8FC96946DE84B071862514E309"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the Office on Violence Against Women of the Department of Justice;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98AD33014ACA47E4BD1E5C4A60B7830D"><enum>(W)</enum><text>the National Center for Education Evaluation and Regional Assistance of the Department of Education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59436AA14E0D4816BE553482F449AFF3"><enum>(X)</enum><text>the Office of Safe and Healthy Students of the Department of Education;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11A1F00B9E52499A999A9981A265BC3D"><enum>(Y)</enum><text>the Office of Special Education and Rehabilitative Services of the Department of Education;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE783BEF5DA249BDB71C8F8D2B04988B"><enum>(Z)</enum><text>the Office of Indian Education of the Department of Education;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H293EE43CB6CA46F5897289A7D93C6410"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the Bureau of Indian Affairs of the Department of the Interior;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08FBBA9C2E544CD7AC04E1BFB42542C2"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the Bureau of Indian Education of the Department of the Interior;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB93A24846C14435A074CA000E4F6D7F"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>the Veterans Health Administration of the Department of Veterans Affairs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2217EF7B5C91455D91D3C4F3DA9C8255"><enum>(DD)</enum><text>the Office of Special Needs Assistance Programs of the Department of Housing and Urban Development; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41CB130D88CA4D27B702F6675CCBA38D"><enum>(EE)</enum><text>such other Federal agencies as—</text> <clause id="H9050B69155CE4F899AFF22B71B9C1574"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary recommends to the President; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC2C1DF43B8BD4C8786B2F1F13FD4F67C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the President determines to be appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DAD8472F549400F90A6F7C6E2FCFD87"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointment</header> <subparagraph id="H244492ECC8444AC1B0069DE3D234F34D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each member of the task force, other than the Assistant Secretary, shall be appointed by the Secretary or other head of the entire Federal agency that contains the office or other unit of government that the member represents.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96D165EAC8A44D6596B9229DC2CCC919"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Date of appointments</header><text>The heads of Federal agencies with appointing authority under this paragraph shall appoint the corresponding members of the task force not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEADC4C86C5CF46D680CA40CA96469880"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The task force shall be chaired by the Assistant Secretary.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDBCAE6DEA0C34A939B2F43A27F90BF81"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Task force duties</header><text>The task force shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HBE4F79F8A7EC402F83D0B1BD05E2A3B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and not less often than annually thereafter—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H08097FFCDAAB4E8F8513E75AB6BBF550"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify and evaluate a set of evidence-based, evidence-informed, and promising best practices, which may include practices already supported by offices of the Department of Health and Human Services, including the National Mental Health and Substance Use Policy Laboratory, the Department of Justice, the Department of Education, or another Federal agency, with respect to—</text>
 <clause id="HF4944425C542426ABA02340AF48D1145"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the early identification of children and youth, and their families as appropriate, who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HEBDFDD063C444779A441B52F969E7618"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the expeditious referral of such children and youth, and their families as appropriate, that require specialized services to the appropriate trauma-informed support (including treatment) services, in accordance with applicable privacy laws; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE515C6567DF546BEAD5424A2853C10CB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the implementation of trauma-informed approaches and interventions in child and youth-serving schools, organizations, homes, and other settings to foster safe, stable, and nurturing environments and relationships that prevent and mitigate the effects of trauma;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDA5F99CAC29B4655B0570CF4FDEEC9AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommend such set of best practices, including disseminating the set, to the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Justice, the Department of Education, other Federal agencies as appropriate, State, tribal, and local government agencies, including State, local, and tribal educational agencies, and other entities (including recipients of relevant Federal grants, professional associations, health professional organizations, national and State accreditation bodies, and schools) that the Assistant Secretary determines to be appropriate, and to the general public; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16983B58C4EF4B0BAB31919A9B7076E4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>maintain and update, as appropriate, the set of best practices recommended under subparagraph (B);</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H093A693687F246599274ED654AAD10A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H68745D710BE74F55865939004A267F1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prepare an integrated task force strategy report concerning how the task force and member agencies will collaborate, prioritize options for, and implement a coordinated approach to preventing trauma, and identifying and ensuring the appropriate interventions and supports for children, youth, and their families as appropriate, who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4B71437DC0742F48E76954ADF104DE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit the report to the appropriate committees of Congress; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B5D4436489446EAB8A2EA75A733AB75"><enum>(C)</enum><text>make the report publicly available; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7AFDCF75B7047E2B6FCB09DBC8C1A19"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and as often as practicable but not less often than annually thereafter, coordinate, to the extent feasible, among the offices and other units of government represented on the task force, research, data collection, and evaluation regarding models described in subsection (d)(1)(C), identify gaps in or populations or settings not served by models described in that subsection, solicit feedback on the models, from the stakeholders described in subsection (d)(1)(B), coordinate, among the offices and other units of government represented on the task force, the awarding of grants related to preventing and mitigating trauma, and establish procedures to enable the offices and units of government to share technical expertise related to preventing and mitigating trauma.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8A3516175BB9495D8229C7FB279196BE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Best practices</header>
 <paragraph id="H927CD108B0FE4EF8965376BC55B123CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In identifying, evaluating, recommending, maintaining, and updating the set of best practices under subsection (c), the task force shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6A4E66E08F0948D8980CFDBEA0C62271"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider findings from evidence-based, evidence-informed, and promising practice-based models, including from institutions of higher education, community practice (including tribal experience), recognized professional associations, and programs of the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Justice, the Department of Education, and other Federal agencies (including the National Mental Health and Substance Use Policy Laboratory and offices in such agencies that maintain registries and clearinghouses of relevant models), that reflect the science of healthy child, youth, and family development, and have been developed, implemented, and evaluated to demonstrate effectiveness or positive measurable outcomes;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H615D60173E994FB6B31B7951606AC9CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engage with, and solicit and receive feedback from—</text> <clause id="HC530F71EF12447278D12E6F9EAD33752"><enum>(i)</enum><text>faculty at institutions of higher education, community practitioners associated with the community practice described in subparagraph (A), and recognized professional associations that represent the experience and perspectives of individuals who provide services in covered settings, to obtain observations and practical recommendations on the best practices; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H0114BEB767B249839F44BDEF66141FC6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the public, by—</text> <subclause id="H5B506F290B5642F19F94CC9BD45A6184"><enum>(I)</enum><text>holding at least one public meeting to solicit recommendations and information relating to the best practices; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF506961F103C4052A20CBE4C256D84E7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>providing notice of the meeting in the Federal Register;</text> </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA25887FF181447AD80DB35D0321AC6D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommend models for settings in which individuals may come into contact with children and youth, and their families as appropriate, who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma, including schools, hospitals, settings where health care providers, including primary care and pediatric providers, provide services, preschool and early childhood education and care settings, home visiting settings, after-school program facilities, child welfare agency facilities, public health agency facilities, mental health treatment facilities, substance abuse treatment facilities, faith-based institutions, domestic violence centers, homeless services system facilities, refugee services system facilities, juvenile justice system facilities, and law enforcement agency facilities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98ACEBEDF3B34A8CB05B959D48F2D054"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommend best practices that are evidence-based, are evidence-informed, or are promising and practice-based, and that include guidelines for—</text>
							<clause id="HBCCDC4A3BA09487289A7235C20B0C6EF"><enum>(i)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0C3B2286617B4D81ADB986ED89EB912E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>training of front-line service providers, including teachers, providers from child- or youth-serving organizations, health care providers, individuals who are mandatory reporters of child abuse or neglect, and first responders, in understanding and identifying early signs and risk factors of trauma in children and youth, and their families as appropriate, including through screening processes; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC425D29452CF461C87C786E792F2FEA0" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>implementing appropriate responses;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="HD8F12813121F4C2EAB2ACBAB49ADE484"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>procedures or systems that—</text>
 <subclause id="H95451046F5FD4936B0D66E6DAA4790B7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are designed to quickly refer children and youth, and their families as appropriate, who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma to, and ensure the children, youth, and appropriate family members receive, the appropriate trauma-informed screening and support, including treatment; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HBF6EAE9DC0B14EDC92365CD0B9FD528F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>use partnerships that—</text> <item id="HFCAD658980DB4753AE7D5EB1D775FD97"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>include local social services organizations or clinical mental health or health care service providers with expertise in furnishing support services (including trauma-informed treatment) to prevent or mitigate the effects of trauma;</text>
 </item><item id="H2C4E082C0E734BF49CCEE6F98400BCAD"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>may be partnerships that co-locate or integrate services, such as by providing services at school-based health centers; and</text>
 </item><item id="H1CC1E42A19144477B4CF9630AA378D8F"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>are designed to make such quick referrals, and ensure the receipt of screening, support, and treatment, described in subclause (I);</text>
 </item></subclause></clause><clause id="HD30B11FF93EE44BE9273DB5103FA6FD3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>educating children and youth to—</text> <subclause id="H3DA5D52B9B1D4D8FA8F30167DC73AFAB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>understand trauma;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H4370CFB7326C41359388A7A9DD40274C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>identify the signs, effects, or symptoms of trauma; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HAA97EFD266E349DABD8EC6F86FA42146"><enum>(III)</enum><text>build the resilience and coping skills to mitigate the effects of experiencing trauma;</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H805384D3761D4DA6BBA0C9F36446DF20"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>multi-generational interventions to—</text> <subclause id="H06148FC8675C4B58A52A1ED22BB706E5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>support, including through skills building, parents (with an appropriate emphasis on fathers), foster parents, adult caregivers, and front-line service providers described in clause (i)(I) in fostering safe, stable, and nurturing environments and relationships that prevent and mitigate the effects of trauma for children and youth who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HE6B43519EF2C48C8B59D8DF95635579B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>assist parents, foster parents, and adult caregivers in learning to access resources related to such prevention and mitigation; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HB671F4D8EE204953A461A746026C0846"><enum>(III)</enum><text>provide tools to prevent and address caregiver or secondary trauma, as appropriate;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H185281E8F0514747862E5D6A70664944"><enum>(v)</enum><text>community interventions for underserved areas that have faced trauma through acute or long-term exposure to substantial discrimination, historical or cultural oppression, intergenerational poverty, civil unrest, a high rate of violence, or a high rate of drug overdose mortality;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7FD228D53C364583B3C34433FB1EF3CB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>assisting parents and guardians in understanding eligibility for and obtaining certain health benefits coverage, including coverage under a State Medicaid plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</external-xref> et seq.) of screening and treatment for children and youth, and their families as appropriate, who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H732AAAAA36EA4CDBB8FEED080D18C480"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>utilizing trained nonclinical providers (such as peers through peer support models, mentors, clergy, and other community figures), to—</text>
 <subclause id="HD6696D92C61346A4966A38862CC8EACE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>expeditiously link children and youth, and their families as appropriate, who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma, to the appropriate trauma-informed screening and support (including clinical treatment) services; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H9446270ABF944527800A97A4EA8F936D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provide ongoing care or case management services;</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H5E0F198FBF304E8E84A15C2BA5CFC26E"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>collecting and utilizing data from screenings, referrals, or the provision of services and supports, conducted in the covered settings, to evaluate and improve processes for trauma-informed support and outcomes;</text>
							</clause><clause id="HCF82FCCC4F9F4C44B8060BD3CB2A0303"><enum>(ix)</enum>
 <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H03C67A97178E43C4B1DAF5C823383C09"><enum>(I)</enum><text>improving disciplinary practices in early childhood education and care settings and schools, including use of positive disciplinary strategies that are effective at reducing the incidence of punitive school disciplinary actions, including school suspensions and expulsions; and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H41099A826B44454CB4247CA521DE8B01" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>providing the training described in clause (i) to child care providers and to school personnel, including school resource officers, teacher assistants, administrators, and heads of charter schools; and</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HAE322F8F150B40148A04E8684CD2B28D"><enum>(x)</enum><text>incorporating trauma-informed considerations into educational, preservice, and continuing education opportunities, for the use of health professional and education organizations, national and State accreditation bodies for health care and education providers, health and education professional schools or accredited graduate schools, and other relevant training and educational entities;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBFD5D595D0549E2B8672514C0BFA35F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>recommend best practices that—</text> <clause id="H19F59AA8128848E0BB68AD2C83CCDB22"><enum>(i)</enum><text>include practices that are culturally sensitive, linguistically appropriate, age- and gender-relevant, and appropriate for lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and queer populations;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3FAD2ECE23C949E3B349E4E8DE64AFE2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>can be applied across underserved geographic areas; and</text> </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA7318DF3088C45DBBE4781FA41034342"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>engage entire organizations in training and skill building related to the best practices; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B9422F193A04FB6B81DBC268440B214"><enum>(F)</enum><text>recommend best practices that are designed not to lead to unwarranted custody loss or criminal penalties for parents or guardians in connection with children and youth who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A446FDCC2534EE8AE64EF8454FA67E1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $3,000,000 for fiscal year 2018 and $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2022.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC869003149354FAE8C082C900EBC1BCA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE21920C716AE46BCA12051A9FCF533A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered recipient</header><text>The term <term>covered recipient</term> means a department or other entity described in subsection (c)(1)(B).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E458BDADAD04DCBB46BFF9DB650E14E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered setting</header><text>The term <term>covered setting</term> means a setting described in subsection (d)(1)(C).</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H750A84B1498B432498648651D746410E"><enum>102.</enum><header>Donald J. Cohen National Child Traumatic Stress Initiative</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 582(f) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290hh-1">42 U.S.C. 290hh–1(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCE47956AF94A4C7B8326980A47D09A8B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>$46,887,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$66,887,000</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HF8042F691D24422FBA6350BE13FA8777"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: <quote>Of the amounts appropriated under this subsection for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022, $7,500,000 shall be allocated to the operation of the coordinating center of the National Child Traumatic Stress Initiative for purposes of gathering and reporting data, evaluating models, and providing technical assistance.</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></section></title><title commented="no" id="H80AB8F8A64D9489BA6F854FC35CDD50C" level-type="subsequent"><enum>II</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Dissemination and implementation of best practices</header>
			<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA72F88B391B45DDA2DE9A2212D9AA1D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>201.</enum><header>Use of grant funds for training in best practices relating to child and youth trauma and community
			 support</header>
				<subsection id="H1A9C368A13C749F5932C96D1166D4274"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Head Start Act</header>
 <paragraph id="H9BC29F07EDA24637913C089FE326B4D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 640(a) of the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9835">42 U.S.C. 9835(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H7A3204A7D33242FDB798E0D0270CF6B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (7) as paragraph (8); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67A024E7639741ED9506328E1F2214B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H290DE3BF9DB747378FEA70800F7876C0" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H6A6FC95C4DF84BE2A39AB4FD121FB910"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any of the funds allocated under this subsection for Head Start programs (including Early Head Start programs), for training and technical assistance activities, or for collaboration grants may be used to provide training for administrators and other staff of Head Start agencies in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
						</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H27558D1EAC4D425AAF94E2C3C31C5709"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <subparagraph id="H66068356001A4C609F68F2DABB81E98A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 640(a)(2)(C)(i) of the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9835">42 U.S.C. 9835(a)(2)(C)(i)</external-xref>), in the matter preceding subclause (I), by inserting after <quote>training and technical assistance activities</quote> the following: <quote>(such as training in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017)</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCBC3E81B149433BB03B9FAD2564728B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Sections 641A(h)(1)(B) and 645(d)(3) of the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9836a">42 U.S.C. 9836a(h)(1)(B)</external-xref>, 9840(d)(3)) are amended by striking <quote>640(a)(7)</quote> and inserting <quote>640(a)(8)</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA443CDECE66B46D4A4DE7F0F1B9DB07B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 642B(a)(2)(B)(i) of the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9837b">42 U.S.C. 9837b(a)(2)(B)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the semicolon the following: <quote>(such as by providing training for administrators and other staff of those agencies in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017)</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA9A2D9D38444407BA902E8AF9577851"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Section 648 of the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9843">42 U.S.C. 9843</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="H906F91B106A64F21B6A9C7586DB9FA7F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(3)(B)(i), by inserting after <quote>systems</quote> the following: <quote>(such as systems that include training in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017)</quote>;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H8918D3A83CCE4EFF9A20D1C6ADEE74EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)(C), by inserting before the semicolon the following: <quote>(such as training in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017)</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7A0AB7B12BF24E1284CBEC7641030139"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1)(G), by inserting after <quote>staff training</quote> the following <quote>(such as training in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017)</quote>.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H69B0567CCBA74170802206BA8301BF8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Child Care and Development Block Grant</header><text>Section 658G(b)(1) of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858e">42 U.S.C. 9858e(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8CAE9F27F0DF4321B00497E6857557BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAC3DBB80AD2A415AB8133392D1BFE29B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BC840F08C0C463EB4A02500E0BC8BE6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB0EDEEC2DD04BA8806DA90DA1FB694A" style="OLC"> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H232E6F5F2E3044BC85DA129626DD1184"><enum>(I)</enum><text>providing training in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017 for administrators of child care programs, and child care providers, that receive assistance under this subchapter.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H980168AEDB434CD4BEFDDCD6DFE4B747"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Social Services Block Grant</header><text>Section 2002(a)(2)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397a">42 U.S.C. 1397a(a)(2)(B)</external-xref> is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HABD1AF4398FC4B74838DC2DF87725708"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3BA1F677F72640C690E4D44CBCED4656"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2A133AB296C844199F9CDAEFAB75D661"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text>
						<quoted-block act-name="" id="H1CE89FDB7ADC40EB920DFB91C1A7EC96" style="traditional">
 <clause id="H5EFFB407751448C1A9059811E16002A4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">training for providers in the best practices developed under section 101 of the <short-title>Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017</short-title>.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2083560D7711495ABB5B64DB4069FFB6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Maternal and Child Health Services Block Grant</header><text>Section 504 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/704">42 U.S.C. 704</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
					<quoted-block act-name="" id="H0BCFF5058F4C4BAB9B59A0F3FE61F3C9" style="traditional">
 <subsection id="H230F03E3F0A24D80AAAF4985664E8758"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State may use a portion of the amounts described in subsection (a) for the purpose of providing training for licensed health care providers and public health agencies in the best practices developed under section 101 of the <short-title>Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017</short-title>.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H133C7B31EFFF4E54BDC3F1491E690A94"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Maternal, Infant, and Early Childhood Home Visiting (MIECHV)</header><text>Section 511(i)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/711">42 U.S.C. 711(i)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H5C2CBE61FFA34CE4A4A79EED461340BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (D) through (G) as subparagraphs (E) through (H), respectively; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCEEA7F57E98C4E3A97DCD8E66309BE02"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block act-name="" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06436E1AA4364DE0BD62AD86682284E3" style="traditional"> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H50D25BBB053B4F6FA3FB5E19819C1007"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 504(e) (relating to the use of funds for training in the best practices developed under section 101 of the <short-title>Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017</short-title>).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H84ECCE5266BF4238BFA458C10B808E8F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Child Welfare Services</header><text>Section 422(b)(4)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/622">42 U.S.C. 622(b)(4)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the semicolon <quote>(which may include training in the best practices developed under section 101 of the <short-title>Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017</short-title>)</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE965797B09E64947AD36AC705E7B5CB8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Federal payments for foster care and adoption assistance</header><text>Section 474(a)(3)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/674">42 U.S.C. 674(a)(3)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, and including training in the best practices developed under section 101 of the <short-title>Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017</short-title></quote> after <quote>enrolled in such institutions</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H7C2BAA2C1B414E239F055E3ABC7BFF53"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Healthy start initiative</header><text>Section 330H(e) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254c-8">42 U.S.C. 254c–8(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A213F0CA2924847A46B83889EB1E4EC" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E7E8C2E309A464C8A55BA209317E7C6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Training providers in best practices relating to trauma</header><text>Any of the funds appropriated under paragraph (1) may be used to provide training for providers in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9160ADDB87E94AE5AB4FEB59BE16E888"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Block grants for community mental health services</header><text>Section 1920 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-9">42 U.S.C. 300x–9</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65D283366A0D482AAA2DAE0766E3F254" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HED53E26A604E4A19863468BCF138D69E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Training providers in best practices relating to trauma</header><text>Except as specified in subsection (c), any of the funds appropriated under subsection (a) may be used to provide training for providers in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1A36D321D2274252AE7188AB8A20A740"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Block grants for prevention and treatment of substance abuse</header><text>Section 1935 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-35">42 U.S.C. 300x–35</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4131FB88D6644D9D842AA345E3A62EAA" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HFEC760AACC0E4011AA815D81650F478D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Allocations for training providers in best practices relating to trauma</header><text>Any of the funds appropriated under subsection (a) may be used to provide training for providers in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection><subsection id="HA8B126FA504B4C8FBD5749AE11B78E86"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Use of grant funds for training providers in best practices relating to trauma</header>
 <paragraph id="HEA1D3BA428DE471E8BAABE32AA442BF4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>School-based health centers</header><text>Section 399Z–1(l) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280h-5">42 U.S.C. 280h–5(l)</external-xref>) is amended by adding <quote>Any of the funds appropriated under this subsection may be used to provide training for providers in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</quote> after the first sentence.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8C1F23CE2FF54E67BAB35D89B2D71406"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community health centers</header><text>Section 330(r) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254b">42 U.S.C. 254b(r)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD44A2E0E174B4534A48B9AC41808EC8D" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3226209787344885BDA58AAC3EB82886"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Training providers in best practices relating to trauma</header><text>Any of the funds appropriated under this subsection may be used to provide training for providers in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H59247C51F4BF4EC394774418E3C190BE"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Supporting effective instruction; local use of funds</header><text>Section 2103(b)(3) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6613">20 U.S.C. 6613(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2069657552C0438693467B8C500C302E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (O), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1AFA9AAB28B474F8E31176CD939D346"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (P) as subparagraph (Q); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFEE72C5415BA43788C4305AEFEEC5F39"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (O) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C67E99700B240468010A91AD47D7DE3" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HC6FD2F15B9D14CA9A673655833ADE193"><enum>(P)</enum><text>providing training for school personnel, including teachers, principals, other school leaders, specialized instructional support personnel, and paraprofessionals, in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7BEA67C1EF3D42CB8811F8DB7EDC55EF"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Student support and academic enrichment</header>
 <paragraph id="H05176FACF81F4587BEB223ADA15BB209"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State use of funds</header><text>Section 4104(b) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7114">20 U.S.C. 7114(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H873B1BE914DC4ED29A1F1A5538E74D25"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD48C54DEE57343E5ABD1C5F282CBECDE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3) by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC15D58D6CD26413E90C287F676D766AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2BBED6FB8E214C2DA6FEDB6E32D7158C" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H7A73B596218D40E882EA31468AB21351"><enum>(4)</enum><text>providing training for teachers, administrators, school counselors, mental health professionals, and other appropriate personnel in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC86647372D034D94BE6A9E8078ABC212"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Local use of funds</header><text>Paragraph (5) of section 4108 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7118">20 U.S.C. 7118</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HE116F86651C74455AF5607D16F5D6DD5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B29F7ADEF344C1BAD8909EF34841C4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17A48741475842E7B9AD7D273ABE59DB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEF24949A4654B719614EBE749A55C8D" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HC9FFDA864DEE4DBF82AD23E20B8428F8"><enum>(J)</enum><text>providing training for teachers, administrators, school counselors, mental health professionals, and other appropriate personnel in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
						</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF4EE143E91D84183B7503D7A85F89DBF"><enum>(n)</enum><header>21st century community learning centers</header>
 <paragraph id="H6CD92C8A36C64128834EE6037947E9F3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State use of funds</header><text>Section 4202(c)(3) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7172">20 U.S.C. 7172(c)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA80F48A4623543D4A022816B564D264D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (H), (I), and (G), as subparagraphs (G), (H), and (I), respectively; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8469F9D9994840F3B2351BCBF6F5E484"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H142FB78A86B347C4A6AA019DD797E48C" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HC04E8A40DA7B4560AA51DA7C68E269F1"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Providing training for teachers, administrators, school counselors, mental health professionals, and other appropriate personnel (including appropriate personnel involved with programs and activities that advance student academic achievement and support student success during nonschool hours) in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H06A8CE9AEC7E43169F0E2473A81A995B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Local use of funds</header><text>Section 4205(a) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7175">20 U.S.C. 7175(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB1CEE4B2ACB9484A94B1A73917D53B13"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (13), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B4331024C2742129540C7735BA17720"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (14), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72AA61DD551941928E0824B014F2DBA2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7DDCD54554AE4B4B91CA58EB7F24A445" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HD8618935F125487C9B34591F3557F63C"><enum>(15)</enum><text>training for teachers, administrators, school counselors, mental health professionals, and other appropriate personnel in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7774811415774DE0AABE8F19DB353568"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Full-Service community schools</header><text>Section 4625(e) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7275">20 U.S.C. 7275(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H2BF9E9A17F4C493B9F3D7EC3B1FBDE32"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F61B8159E4048A59F532BD34C918782"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (4); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5501814ACAE74E77822338E7BEA37053"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF46FBB146E3E46BD95237B519DB43CBC" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HFAE2427F09794EF4A4DBD82E5B794AAF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide training for teachers, administrators, school counselors, mental health professionals, and other appropriate personnel (including appropriate personnel involved with the full-service community school) in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H84F161B7C56D4EAFAD697A5118F57715"><enum>(p)</enum><header>National Activities for Schools</header><text>Section 4631(a)(1)(B) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7281">20 U.S.C. 7281(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or conducting a national evaluation.</quote> and inserting <quote>, conducting a national evaluation, or providing training for teachers, administrators, school counselors, mental health professionals, and other appropriate personnel in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBB5D3E40F9EE493598DFA00C315CA983"><enum>(q)</enum><header>IDEA</header><text>Section 638 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1438">20 U.S.C. 1438</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE9E1F6D4BFE146E693BEE56093418E3B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD8D72C5E4DDC4115AD5E3E964CDA6CDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2DD09D44A8B54B10A341AB8B08412C07"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5FBB2E11F6A243148AC80016B3DBB3F9" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H987B2BA1965C4DE3880A42C3D4DBEA3D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to provide training for appropriate personnel who provide direct early intervention services for infants and toddlers with disabilities in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0358D0C73BBE4DA9BD0EE7336DB3BD7D"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children</header><text>Section 17(f) of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1786">42 U.S.C. 1786(f)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD25A865D30B496FBF79B3D3991E20B7" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA11CCED9AF1422DA62F83D119052548"><enum>(27)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>A State agency may use a portion of the amounts made available to the State agency under this section for the purpose of providing training for local agencies in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection><subsection id="H4142AB85DF854F51A4471D66CDF77451"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Community services block grant act</header>
 <paragraph id="HF437F4E850C147859E0B09EE956F33C9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State activities</header><text>Section 675C(b)(1)(A) of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9907">42 U.S.C. 9907(b)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>providing training</quote> the following: <quote>(which may include providing training, to the entities that are providers of services to children and youth, in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB666A46494DE41A6B49E06CC7BFA253D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National activities</header><text>Section 678A(a)(1)(A) of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9913">42 U.S.C. 9913(a)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>training</quote> the following: <quote>(which may include providing training, to the entities that are providers of services to children and youth, in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H28C0A370227042758F1C331D14380256"><enum>(t)</enum><header>Runaway and homeless youth act</header><text>Section 342 of the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5714-22">42 U.S.C. 5714–22</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>technical assistance and training</quote> the following: <quote>(which may include providing training, to providers of services under this title, in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017)</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H35C01F2A9CFF4562A78DBFEEA041DD0A"><enum>(u)</enum><header>Programs of the office of refugee resettlement</header><text>Section 462(b)(1) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/279">6 U.S.C. 279(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H63EDE15462164BACBA9B234A1CA678F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (K), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H790B73435E4B4E7DA4E5B63CCE5F85DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (L), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA9F4D9978581443B88B19B1073D4C76B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1DF0A7AC447948999B41AD5E466CD9B4" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HF794FD22F6224320866DBA6B5A95E470"><enum>(M)</enum><text>at the election of the Director, providing training, to providers responsible for the care of the unaccompanied alien children, in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A46643DF7BD41AEA6D0BFA6ADC2A22A"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Child abuse prevention and treatment</header>
 <paragraph id="H53F8EDED6E75445EA357DFC08AB05625"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National clearinghouse</header><text>Section 103(b) of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5104">42 U.S.C. 5104</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H60826C2C5F074E049C431907B89C233B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26E407DF7D0741478862F752F9CBA1EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE271ED95A29145D1AE33CF20FFE2B977"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H37A4A7AB6DD2423CA0760F083E702257" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HE72DCB78A0834A61A2C565D635FF4808"><enum>(10)</enum><text>disseminate information regarding the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017 for individuals and officials described in paragraph (8).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB76193760FB648089D595680287B1EF1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Research and assistance activities</header><text>Section 104(b)(1) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5105">42 U.S.C. 5105(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>Such assistance may include technical assistance regarding the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3530ED6464994C0AB71EF4AA0FE3AA65"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Training</header><text>Section 105(a)(1) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5106">42 U.S.C. 5106(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H38BB19F541914F3287F350259887550B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (L), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF1D289BE8DE45D1855292ADB368F433"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (M), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7993A693E26044E1A60479A23CAB290A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF9CAB2250D24C1585AD011A5F1BCBA6" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="H1DA436235B3C4153819CCE4BDE53B717"><enum>(D)</enum><text>for providing training in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017 to individuals and entities described in this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CA31ED9056E49299A9F252D21F650EB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State child abuse or neglect prevention and treatment programs</header><text>Section 106(a) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5106a">42 U.S.C. 5106a(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H8ED0812DA64948B195C48DE59DEBADC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (13), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6425260134C432892708FB28832F376"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (14), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48558650221143118A40F710F93D7FE3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H398C18573E4B474F83A08AEC4602B6B5" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H6E63B553CCB24E5695577238302A60FB"><enum>(15)</enum><text>providing training in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017 for employees of agencies or systems described in paragraph (12), (13), or (14).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H045CCF8FB0164B62A41C849B10A127C1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Community-based grants for the prevention of child abuse and neglect</header><text>Section 205(b) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5116e">42 U.S.C. 5116e(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HED8C0EC5DC74465CB30EF012AE5F0A2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81F389FBA3314D37A3514BABAD2CAB5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H550BD5027AF74CD98FFA9C4B9773C7FD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48F92BFA8F8746AD9C68BC17404C8F79" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HD5CE3692BA71473C91A08063821508DA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>provide training in the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017 for providers of programs, activities, or services described in this subsection.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6BBCEF58AADB48CA8B8626131EA8B4B9"><enum>(w)</enum><header>Grants for juvenile and family court personnel</header><text>Section 222(1) of the Victims of Child Abuse Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/13022">42 U.S.C. 13022(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(which may include providing training, to the entities that are providers of services to children and youth, in the best practices developed under section 101 of the <short-title>Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017</short-title>)</quote> after <quote>technical assistance and training</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11FA5CBF02BE4CA3BF5BD42D89CB7205"><enum>(x)</enum><header>Grants To support families in the justice system</header><text>Section 1301(c) of the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10420">42 U.S.C. 10420(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58CE198ABCCB4AA084E30731F7A7D5BB" style="OLC">
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F83058288CA49879801C8B3A544F0F2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Best practices for trauma-informed care for children and families</header><text>In making grants under subsection (b), the Attorney General shall take into account the extent to which the applicant is using the best practices developed under section 101 of the <short-title>Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017</short-title>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</subsection></section><section id="HCCC1E2EE22F5492E95CD9589E9B0B7ED"><enum>202.</enum><header>Establishment of law enforcement child and youth trauma coordinating center</header>
				<subsection id="HF5926B3797B14B098904403EAFC56120"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of Center</header>
 <paragraph id="H3369DE929ADA40F5ABB63C1E687AD05B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall establish a National Law Enforcement Child and Youth Trauma Coordinating Center (referred to in this section as the <quote>Center</quote>) to provide assistance to State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies in interacting with children and youth who have been exposed to violence or other trauma, and their families as appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H60F646705BF344588E2D13EEE3AC0CD3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Age range</header><text>The Center shall determine the age range of children and youth to be covered by the activities of the Center.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA6D93E5A4794C9D89F9A40775D7D3E4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Center shall provide assistance to State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies by—</text> <paragraph id="H05C1CF69E2D1451C8CC1B0113C919388"><enum>(1)</enum><text>disseminating information on the best practices for law enforcement officers developed under section 101, which may include best practices based on evidence-based and evidence-informed models from programs of the Department of Justice and the Office of Justice Services of the Bureau of Indian Affairs, such as—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2D849A8F59404813B00E31C09B9C91AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>models developed in partnership with national law enforcement organizations, Indian tribes, or clinical researchers; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5348A2CE4CC54A90B92F1377740E4CBC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>models that include—</text> <clause id="HD6413C9553224F898DCC4FAFB171CBA5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>trauma-informed approaches to conflict resolution, de-escalation, and crisis intervention training;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFEA90FBCF2D04BBF8C9372B32576C0FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>early interventions that link child and youth witnesses and victims, and their families as appropriate, to appropriate trauma-informed services; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HBDA8D252F1A94271B9E5C0FBA91F84BD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>supporting officers who experience secondary trauma;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CB8C869DCBE426C997CF3A6B6C0BDB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing professional training and technical assistance; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F0E5CB1CD1645C798B12638BA28EAB1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>awarding grants under subsection (c).</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE94F64E579DE48A2A78B7822AE8854FE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant program</header> <paragraph id="H240275D654774E37BA3A6E0A4B297453"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General, acting through the Center, may award grants to State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies or to multi-disciplinary consortia to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H60F8351560E94322AA7AE052165CE2D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enhance the awareness of best practices developed under section 101 for trauma-informed responses to children and youth who have been exposed to violence or other trauma, and their families as appropriate; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H506C2F3D9887437EA9317F02E7795735"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide professional training and technical assistance in implementing the best practices described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AF8FABAD9E142EFBCEAB84C115047C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Any State, local, or tribal law enforcement agency seeking a grant under this subsection shall submit an application to the Attorney General at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may require.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCD132376C7E948BE9BB491C280FB0906"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A grant awarded under this subsection may be used to—</text> <subparagraph id="H464E2051B8CD471D9F26DEA0864AA707"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide training to law enforcement officers on the best practices developed under section 101, including how to identify early signs of trauma and violence exposure when interacting with children and youth; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H587F235ADAA14EEC9909F01F7807E1E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish, operate, and evaluate a referral and partnership program with trauma-informed clinical mental health, substance use, health care, or social service professionals in the community in which the law enforcement agency serves.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9949F11869074EDFB2A9097A55100695"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Attorney General—</text> <paragraph id="H4A8049D1EA8644BD94EEBA5712A09CB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022 to award grants under subsection (c); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD6A7A0000BD47A086EFED3B69EB82E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2022 for other activities of the Center.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H77C29C51F4CE4E66B4CAF6C9B2F89958"><enum>203.</enum><header>Establishment of Native American technical assistance resource center</header> <subsection id="HE38AD59D0C6248AEB261C49577604E30"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
 <paragraph id="HC65E2AFF703D49C2B75BC347784CEA62"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Indian tribe; tribal organization</header><text>The terms <term>Indian tribe</term> and <term>tribal organization</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4FADB9B02DD74C478FADFF90352A4C93"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4858F078CA474B499D5F2D8557A7B352"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting—</text> <subparagraph id="H5BD74EBE9BF64ACBBC478D48A3C0FCC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27178E3CAD254AD7A13C8999DF8EE977"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after consultation with—</text> <clause id="HA1EBF66CFC124C1DBBC0F85D63172DBF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Director of the Bureau of Indian Education of the Department of the Interior; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H7923BBCBEA20476596FB3AA26E062AB2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Director of the Indian Health Service.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H215BAFC73B3248D582FA9B0B390D2687"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of Center</header><text>The Secretary shall establish and operate a Native American Technical Assistance Resource Center (referred to in this section as the <quote>Center</quote>) to provide assistance to Indian tribes.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HCAE324557DEE444A80E2BF18B99A498A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Center shall provide assistance to the Indian tribes by—</text> <paragraph id="HDC4C62A3CBA341A98F11EF194573D51A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>providing trauma-informed technical assistance to tribal organizations in implementing the best practices developed under section 101; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD75ABEFE422A4F3C94DEAAE6176FBD71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>disseminating the best practices to the tribal organizations, to schools that serve students from the Indian tribes, to health care entities that serve the Indian tribes, to child welfare systems that serve children and youth from the Indian tribes, to law enforcement agencies that serve the Indian tribes, to criminal justice and court systems that serve the Indian tribes, and other relevant entities.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF37DD6FB1089457B9EB7158A4AC907E2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grant program</header>
 <paragraph id="HBEC615A848B74017BA0F9C5D71FA8EB0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may award grants to nonprofit organizations or institutions of higher education, to operate the Center.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H71D682DCBBF7430AA455F375AC6EDD65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An organization or institution seeking a grant under this subsection shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H06D6B405938B44758750F14E3F541D60"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary, to carry out this section, $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2021.</text>
				</subsection></section><section id="HE6B84E9DBFBE47A7B2DA9F43D4B168F5"><enum>204.</enum><header>Grants to improve trauma support services and mental health care for children and youth in
 educational settings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part A of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7101">20 U.S.C. 7101</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H43C37AFDFF72432AB7D28749712F5704" style="OLC">
					<subpart id="HD9D6557BBAD141DF87B9DCAC27B18F96" style="OLC"><enum>3</enum><header>Grants To improve trauma support services and mental health care for children and youth in
			 educational settings</header>
						<section id="H460ED4C551B14A409EA9D5003664C0DD"><enum>4131.</enum><header>Grants to improve trauma support services and mental health care for children and youth in
			 educational settings</header>
 <subsection id="H6FE847145A2246A6A1AA03A36A19613E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements authorized</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to award grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, State educational agencies, local educational agencies, Indian tribes or their tribal educational agencies, a school operated by the Bureau of Indian Education, or a Regional Corporation (as defined in section 3 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1602">43 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>)) for the purpose of increasing student access to quality trauma support services and mental health care by developing innovative programs to link local school systems with local trauma-informed support and mental health systems, including those under the Indian Health Service.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H579530C304EB4E9CA77E1D91B57770C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>With respect to a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement awarded or entered into under this section, the period during which payments under such grant, contract or agreement are made to the recipient may not exceed 5 years.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1067DCE48A47441BA66F8A65D83281C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An entity that receives a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section shall use amounts made available through such grant, contract, or cooperative agreement for any of the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H5B651967F39647F68B66CD7A968E754B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To enhance, improve, or develop collaborative efforts between school-based service systems and trauma-informed support and mental health service systems to provide, enhance, or improve prevention, screening, referral, and treatment services to students.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEEB7126AF7794EF5A6DAC1329C870BC8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To enhance the availability of trauma support services and school-based counseling programs, and provide appropriate referrals and interventions for students potentially in need of mental health services.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDEED54BF13947288E150A7DF98225A0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To provide universal trauma screenings to identify students in need of specialized support.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9EE448C302A4592805A063C154379FC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To implement multi-tiered positive behavioral interventions and supports, or other trauma-informed models of support.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB435A36EF27142B1B94F8C9063B9BA47"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To provide training to teachers, teacher assistants, specialized instructional support personnel, and mental health professionals to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEA9C51C7557043359C2AFAB94F1256AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop safe, stable, and nurturing learning environments that prevent and mitigate the effects of trauma, including through social and emotional learning; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD8FBA2A36F043A5A4A2A4883BF6EFFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improve school capacity to identify, refer, and provide services, as appropriate, to students in need of trauma support or behavioral health services.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA01CAEB149CA4083B9CA88119648FC8E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To provide technical assistance and consultation to school systems and mental health agencies as well as to families participating in the program carried out under this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAF01FE76BE084747B845852A702CA6BA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>To provide linguistically appropriate and culturally competent services.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HA7BB21EA3FFF4D91B8646C799AE65CAC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>To evaluate the effectiveness of the program carried out under this section in increasing student access to quality trauma support services and mental health care, and make recommendations to the Secretary about the sustainability of the program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5597B96BBAE34A1AAACCD1F3CEE3B08F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>To engage and utilize expertise provided by institutions of higher education, such as a Tribal College or University, as defined in section 316(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDE9877F596894F93B2B7D00BA7675E24"><enum>(10)</enum><text>To provide trainings and implement procedures pursuant to the relevant best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2FB2B772069748C49924DEFCAD52C590"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section, an entity described in subsection (a) shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require, such as the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HD3704E2945514612B869E837CBB33ED4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the program to be funded under the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0F9ED236702A4747B14C9161E35E317D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of how such program will increase access to quality trauma support services and mental health care for students.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D090D4145164626BC6050CF523D53DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of how the applicant will establish trauma support services or a school-based counseling program, or both, that provide immediate prevention and mental health services to the school community as necessary.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE340222FFCDA4FFC9E71CA9A215C5AE6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assurance that—</text> <subparagraph id="HE5FDC365266A4A1193ACD3AC5DC5F019"><enum>(A)</enum><text>persons providing services under the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement are adequately trained to provide such services;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB167E50BA1A4E0E8A7B7168EC934842"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the services will be provided in accordance with subsection (c);</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB2BC2BACEC64E11AB27B71A7C789FBA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>teachers, administrators, specialized instructional support personnel, parents or guardians, representatives of local Indian tribes, and other school personnel are aware of the program; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H811675DF7D2E45A4921FF2B70D0CB6D2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>parents or guardians of students participating in services under this section will be engaged and involved in the design and implementation of the services.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0F330E02F174C7D8788CA591693544F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An assurance that the applicant will support and integrate existing school-based services with the program in order to provide appropriate mental health services for students.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE9AEBA17C13D47489C60F9D6E56829E8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An assurance that the applicant will establish a program that will support students and the school in improving the school climate in order to support an environment conducive to learning.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2F12BC7047F402BBD99562BA6817AC9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Interagency agreements</header>
 <paragraph id="HD48D7C625E0746DEB818730A8AA9BE76"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation of lead agency</header><text>A recipient of a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section shall designate a lead agency to direct the establishment of an interagency agreement among local educational agencies, juvenile justice authorities, mental health agencies, and other relevant entities in the State, in collaboration with local entities, such as Indian tribes.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE4622F2BDCBC426DB659750162C4B184"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The interagency agreement shall ensure the provision of the services described in subsection (c), specifying with respect to each agency, authority, or entity—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCC8C7DBDF52E48F68BAC02637E4AFAE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the financial responsibility for the services;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49F37FA895184BC7B5D51005A0DA2E20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the conditions and terms of responsibility for the services, including quality, accountability, and coordination of the services; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6D079C24F6743A0823C67D56A80BDDA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the conditions and terms of reimbursement among the agencies, authorities, or entities that are parties to the interagency agreement, including procedures for dispute resolution.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF46C125798AF4D65ADB2ED62DEFFC7A9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall evaluate each program carried out under this section and shall disseminate the findings with respect to each such evaluation to appropriate public, tribal, and private entities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC4222D9B19FB4ADCB8D156039ED2FC8B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Distribution of awards</header><text>The Secretary may ensure that grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements awarded or entered into under this section are equitably distributed among the geographical regions of the United States and among tribal, urban, suburban, and rural populations.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H262189B5CD3E47F0B001A3B5AF69E28F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed—</text> <paragraph id="H8821164E080C45CBA46C58329C887FAE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to prohibit an entity involved with a program carried out under this section from reporting a crime that is committed by a student to appropriate authorities; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB7437CD98B84B8EAA60F9EEB3D3CF52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to prevent State and tribal law enforcement and judicial authorities from exercising their responsibilities with regard to the application of Federal, tribal, and State law to crimes committed by a student.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H33C0209A1A654F7E85183C3DE130E2CA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Any services provided through programs carried out under this section shall supplement, and not supplant, existing mental health services, including any services required to be provided under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H7B6B73ACAEE24BE4AC7CF1F2BEBCA752"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Consultation with indian tribes</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall, in a timely manner, meaningfully consult, engage, and cooperate with Indian tribes and their representatives to ensure notice of eligibility.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5589D0B3975D4EEC8C1CEF0712D5E20B"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $6,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2018 through 2023.</text></subsection></section></subpart><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section></title><title commented="no" id="HFF28EC5A65DF4B9AABE0F80FA411C771" level-type="subsequent" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Understanding the Scope of Trauma Exposure</header>
			<section id="HCD00FA2A83CB4F6580F65B4383BFEC82"><enum>301.</enum><header>CDC surveillance and data collection for child, youth, and adult trauma</header>
 <subsection id="H05621D0B1DCB427B94FE7E7EBD68A5A8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text>The Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (referred to in this section as the <quote>Director</quote>) shall authorize and encourage States to collect and report data on adverse childhood experiences through the Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System and the Youth Risk Behavior Surveillance System. In collecting and reporting such data, States shall use the appropriate modules developed under section 302(2)(B), in addition to other appropriate modules.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8489A1312DF84319B54730E32ECD0922"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The collection of data authorized under subsection (a) may occur in fiscal year 2019 and every 2 years thereafter.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H08B09A92EAD7484895C80B3513E54E1E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data from tribal and rural areas</header><text>The Director shall require that each State, in collecting data in accordance with subsection (a), ensure that, as appropriate, data from tribal and rural areas within such State is included by oversampling from such areas.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2F79D3B7FBE40FC96BA976228B3C152"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $64,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2019 through 2021.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HBED34132DC7C4511947D4A5732850268"><enum>302.</enum><header>CDC analysis of child, youth, and adult trauma</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB9D1B1082E1C4411A0AD896E45A3E5DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct an analysis of—</text> <subparagraph id="HAC14D4BB66AE4F9FBC6DC12C0B42F4C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the prevalence of child, youth, and adult trauma experienced in the United States, including assessments of the types of the most prominent adverse childhood experiences, and disparities by race and ethnicity, by geographic distribution, and by socioeconomic status;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65B34BD8CE9949A0B231957B8F70CB82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the public health impact of adverse childhood experiences, including the correlation of such experiences with trends in life expectancy and whether the scope of such experiences constitutes a public health epidemic;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1681733AC251467B9CD37B739E1F1432"><enum>(C)</enum><text>modules that measure and assess adverse childhood experiences, for development and ultimate inclusion in the Youth Risk Behavior Surveillance System; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B475DCE759942D2B4F278B4A267AAD6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>outcomes modules that measure and evaluate the utilization and efficacy of trauma-informed interventions, such as mental health services or other clinical or sub-clinical care, for ultimate inclusion in the Youth Risk Behavior Surveillance System and the Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57FA83FB4CC94876B6FDDD554C292C40"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, submit to Congress a report on the analysis under paragraph (1) that includes recommendations on—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1E6C4E621664A0F94B439565223E5D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>what communities can do to mitigate the impact of adverse childhood experiences and how Indian tribes, social service providers, law enforcement, health care practitioners, public health agencies, educational institutions, and other community stakeholders may collaborate to improve efforts to identify, connect to appropriate services, and provide treatment and support for children and youth, and their families as appropriate, who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8DD978FE6214313BF4E86CA1C9050F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>modules for inclusion in the appropriate surveillance systems, as described in subparagraphs (C) and (D) of paragraph (1); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1CAC800B0A054AF68743269ADA5192FD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention can utilize data collected through surveillance systems to target specific populations or geographic locations with a high incidence of measured Adverse Childhood Experiences, including by considering such data when awarding grants and contracts to entities serving such populations or locations.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H8B9948C644E747F1A5D36ECCB027C69A"><enum>303.</enum><header>Government accountability study on barriers to and opportunities for trauma-informed identification
			 and treatment</header>
				<subsection id="HBE0EA462F5F743A0BC440940C6FE9FC5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header>
 <paragraph id="H16AAA528E9994471AC55895739DAB0BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General shall conduct a study of the barriers to, and the opportunities for increasing, the early identification and treatment of children and youth, and their families as appropriate, who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E7E6C78684541979CDABD75975BF31E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In conducting the study, the Comptroller General shall examine—</text> <subparagraph id="HDA82328FD010458F839C2AB38EC3247D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ways in which such identification and treatment could be facilitated in early childhood education and care settings and elementary and secondary schools, such as through improved teacher preparation, professional development, and curriculum design, and the development of the cognitive and social-emotional skills of students;</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEFC3380581841998353A367EAB863E1"><enum>(B)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF9F71B6F60E14A9B81E0793BD88619AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the extent to which State Medicaid plans use early and periodic screening, diagnostic, and treatment services (as defined in section 1905(r) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(r)</external-xref>) that are provided in accordance with the requirements of section 1902(a)(43) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(43)</external-xref>)) to provide trauma-informed services to children and youth, and their families as appropriate, who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA3BFED7BBC684C1FA3559252E2395927" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>barriers to increased utilization of such screening, diagnostic, and treatment services; and</text> </clause><clause id="H628A0D44B64A4B43B156BF941D3CAE9A" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the impact of State Medicaid plan design and State regulatory decisions on the provision of such services;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1198508449554D6F8FE28E10212344A0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the feasibility of, State experiences with, and considerations regarding, systematic collection and sharing of data that—</text>
 <clause id="H0570023F13D64B6E9E39A0DF4DF64604"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is carried out by health care providers, State, local, and tribal educational agencies, social service providers, law enforcement, and any other entity providing services in a covered setting (as defined in section 101(f));</text>
 </clause><clause id="H25E75B683C78475CAB095E46AD497EE8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>relies on common data measures, fosters communication and coordination across covered settings (as so defined), and promotes shared accountability for the data; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H44360266C9984887BF22D053A791FBB0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>relates to the screening, referral, and support of children and youth, and their families as appropriate, who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FF8349FDCA941A594D5D966CE7F704B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>privacy and consent issues affecting identification and treatment of children and youth who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma, including considerations regarding information collected and reported by providers and regarding parental consent;</text>
						</subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD19937773ECA4FDD9B37985509F03424"><enum>(E)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4A8D4752EB524F908D20F212E4F996B5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the comprehensive, coordinated, and multisector process through which State, local, and tribal educational agencies locate, identify, and screen infants and toddlers with disabilities, and children with disabilities (including such children who are youth), under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1400">20 U.S.C. 1400</external-xref> et seq.); and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4B7520C8E7034B3C8BB7DB006D261680" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>considerations, strategies, alignment opportunities, and applicability for trauma-informed models for conducting such location, identification, and screening;</text>
							</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC6A4354720E4E9885FD37B70F4D613A"><enum>(F)</enum>
 <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF43D9AC5C11C4393A5C3383EF3098E5D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>clinical child and adolescent mental health and child- and youth-serving social service workforce capacity, including analyzing that capacity by setting, geographic distribution, and population served; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H36B2053400C041B0BBE4CC351E8218A3" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>barriers that contribute to any shortages in professionals in that workforce; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE8365FA99A44D9A974522E7D3A67241"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the cost-effectiveness and success of providing services through school-based health centers as a method of—</text>
 <clause id="H3D22665326E649D38189DE10041F60DB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>addressing the needs of students who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma; and</text> </clause><clause id="HD14404A90EBB4C7DBFE5CB3E9F9B2FCA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improving their academic achievement.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H64F332B4F22A45BE81C607F9B08F76FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Comptroller General shall submit a report containing the results of the study to—</text> <paragraph id="H284E4A9B9EFF4950A665E71EA674698B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, the Committee on Finance, the Committee on Indian Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BF727BF61434CC3967D56B3D6D1A20C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Education and the Workforce, the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on Natural Resources, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H419530B12D484D9F8A6F91C59E9BC96B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6391E99F7BA4EC28EFFB0259B2B0289"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Child with a disability</header><text>The term <term>child with a disability</term> has the meaning given the term in section 602 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1401">20 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB0283E8A66EF47CE93E32F1710E6E621"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Infant or toddler with a disability</header><text>The term <term>infant or toddler with a disability</term> has the meaning given the term in section 632 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1432">20 U.S.C. 1432</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCB1E9B8E92D648599FDB5FF77DBE067E"><enum>304.</enum><header>NIH report on trauma</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director of the National Institutes of Health, not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, shall submit to Congress a report on the activities of the National Institutes of Health with respect to trauma (including trauma that stems from child abuse, exposure to violence, and toxic stress) and the implications of trauma for children, youth, and adults. Such report shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="HCDC8B79A22334941BD44172C67552D99"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the comprehensive research agenda of the National Institutes of Health with respect to trauma;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE59FD55C64F4119B0389E289A5067E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the capacity, expertise, and review mechanisms of the National Institutes of Health with respect to the evaluation and examination of research proposals related to child trauma, including coordination across institutes and centers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H30E78413DB9E4A83835C3CE195EFEE17"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the relevance of trauma to other diseases, outcomes, and domains;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H495EBBB156F14E0F904165352C111479"><enum>(4)</enum><text>strategies to link and analyze data from multiple independent sources, including child welfare, health care (including mental health care), law enforcement, and education systems, to enhance research efforts and improve health outcomes;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2C93EEA06FC9409494076396D16B9B34"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the efficacy of existing interventions, including clinical treatment methods, child- and family-focused prevention models, and community-based approaches, in mitigating the effects of experiencing trauma and improving health and societal outcomes; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9721D85F3084BE3A8AE5F2A4764DC6D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>identification of gaps in understanding in the field of trauma and areas of greatest need for further research related to trauma.</text>
				</paragraph></section></title><title commented="no" id="H100B3EB0770C4C8B866537F2FCC5E12F" level-type="subsequent" style="OLC"><enum>IV</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Evaluation of new interventions and improving service delivery</header>
			<section id="H82BA2C425E554F169FEA7FD80ED2CE2F"><enum>401.</enum><header>Clarification of definition of Medicaid EPSDT services; demonstration project to test
			 trauma-informed delivery of EPSDT services</header>
 <subsection id="HE060BA0752F8401AB542CBA04CC9522D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Clarification of definition of EPSDT services</header><text>Section 1905(r) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(r)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H9A6DC9385E5345258FB5356AA187E628"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H223E1B2B1E724ED09ACBC64E8B7A1965"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(ii), by inserting <quote>(including in the immediate aftermath of exposure to a traumatic event)</quote> after <quote>medically necessary</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA0B22809DE943EDA5FF4813F0B99902"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(i), by inserting <quote>and any past exposure to traumatic events</quote> after <quote>health development</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HABF61DF06FAF40D49247A392CA35B246"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by inserting <quote>including any defects, illnesses, and conditions (including symptoms of a possible mental health disorder that are not sufficiently acute for a diagnosis of a clinical mental health disorder) stemming from exposure to traumatic events,</quote> after <quote>screening services,</quote>.</text>
					</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H033BC2CA70844B329361993D9B52B33E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Trauma-Informed delivery of EPSDT services demonstration project</header>
 <paragraph id="H8AABA8D658E0440B989AF554260BEB05"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall make grants to States to conduct demonstration projects under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</external-xref> et seq.) to test innovative, trauma-informed approaches for delivering early and periodic screening, diagnostic, and treatment services (as defined in section 1905(r) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(r)</external-xref>)) to eligible children.</text>
					</paragraph><paragraph id="HF63A3320AF1E4ED69F6C8B25435CCA4A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope and duration</header>
 <subparagraph id="HCA0C9B9D547247568A099EB3B9A1E535"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The Secretary shall select 10 States to participate in the demonstration project.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H245A8295C1D443FE8CC92E84FAB40599"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Selection</header> <clause id="H91668428B2A341A2AC4EB5D080A37779"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Diversity</header><text>In selecting States to participate in the demonstration project, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <subclause id="HE465E31D2BD24CF1A3F6D0C09C63F0BD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>ensure that geographically diverse areas, including rural and underserved areas, are included; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="HE22DB4743EDC4A4AB93F66FF408C45B9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>include at least 2 States in which Indian tribes or tribal organizations (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1603">25 U.S.C. 1603</external-xref>)) are located.</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HAAFC432B2C3F4F9F84D82F7CACE31AEE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In selecting States to participate in the demonstration project, the Secretary shall give priority to States that—</text>
 <subclause id="HBC406173351F438ABC1AA78A87CD87D9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>use a value-based payment methodology for paying providers for services provided under the State Medicaid program, including services related to healthy child development;</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HC7ECE7C3F82E43698EBAA69E9512CACC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>use an alternative payment model under the State Medicaid program that enables cross-sector collaboration, provision of trauma-informed services, and supports for healthy child development; or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H2A9D64EAEAC04812BC40C459984E99A4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>integrate information technology between child- and youth-serving sectors to improve coordination and outcomes.</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5BE8BEA0CA4F4003A175FFF65592312D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The demonstration project shall begin not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and shall be conducted for a period of 4 years.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H496F1ACEDED741399853C76A12325939"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this subsection, a State that is participating in the demonstration project shall demonstrate that it has implemented the following measures with respect to the State Medicaid program:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H706EF0CF34A2475C8414764042400E47"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The State Medicaid program allows for the provision of early and periodic screening, diagnostic, and treatment services—</text>
 <clause id="HD577BB7FC2014477BA44362E8FA91DC6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in a diverse set of settings, including schools, hospitals, primary care settings, Federally-qualified health centers (as defined in section 1905(l)(2)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(l)(2)(B)</external-xref>)), and tribally-operated health facilities, without undue restrictions on the settings in which providers are permitted to furnish such services; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H3DF36A24597E4B5AA4B7215683A0EB96"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by the full scope of providers that are licensed or otherwise authorized under State law to provide the services, including trained peers through eligible peer support services, community health workers, or subclinical case managers.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EB761D3976440A2AA0D3607100B13C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Where necessary to improve or promote the health of an eligible child, the State Medicaid program provides for payment for services provided to the parent of the child.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H942902906B15449DA4B5098F655EF690"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The State Medicaid program has procedures in place to coordinate across settings, which may include coordinating with law enforcement, juvenile justice agencies, schools (including preschools and after-school programs), hospitals, primary care providers, tribally-operated health facilities, mental health and substance use treatment facilities, and child welfare providers, to ensure that eligible children who experience trauma receive the appropriate services.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H78A4F7D149AC46D89878DE7BAF9AE907"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Where appropriate, the State Medicaid program coordinates with facilities of the Indian Health Service (including a hospital, nursing facility, or any other type of facility which provides services of a type otherwise covered under the program) and other tribally-operated health facilities to ensure eligible children have access to adequate qualified providers that are licensed or otherwise authorized under State law to furnish the services.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8861C97FDB424BBF8E6C9ED139745935"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there is appropriated $75,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2017 through 2021 to carry out this subsection.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFBD9F8295BDD46AEBD6EA8AD13639016"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H7D0DD858231245E59FBFDF02A137E7BF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Demonstration project</header><text>The term <term>demonstration project</term> means the demonstration project established under this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H98B09FD7EFB84B60B1EC130432D7F076"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible child</header><text>The term <term>eligible child</term> means an individual who is under age 21 and who is enrolled in a State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE7D990A2F0BF4BA38FEDB3B7800679FD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B143556DB2C448D950A3923ED82C668"><enum>(D)</enum><header>State Medicaid program</header><text>The term <term>State Medicaid program</term> means a State plan or waiver under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</external-xref> et seq.).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8609E27EB526422092114176630E3B13"><enum>402.</enum><header>Health professional shortage areas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 332(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254e">42 U.S.C. 254e(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E2E82DFDA0041F69549FAEED33B606D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A), by inserting <quote>(including a community health center operated in an elementary or secondary school)</quote> after <quote>community health center</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80F998059A78440FBFAA68E052D975CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA403E5456B7548C9B078FB2A2BF0CDFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, and residents</quote> and inserting <quote>, residents</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA30CECA164A44DEBDB488AA7E3BD079"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, and a population group that the Secretary determines has experienced trauma (such as through acute or long-term exposure to substantial discrimination, historical or cultural oppression, intergenerational poverty, civil unrest, a high rate of violence, or a high rate of drug overdose mortality)</quote> before <quote>may be</quote>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H505AC51EB5FC4765B2A0C810266C6A11" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>403.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Training and certification guidelines for community figures</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, shall conduct a study on, and establish guidelines for States to consider with respect to, the training and certification of community figures, including community mentors, peers with lived experiences, and faith-based leaders, to build awareness of trauma and promote linkages to community services, provide case management services, and conduct appropriate trauma-informed screening for individuals who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma. Such training and certification guidelines shall include recommendations for experience, education, and supervision requirements for, and partnerships between, such trained and certified community figures and other health care providers such that the trained and certified community figures may be reimbursed through the State Medicaid plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396</external-xref> et seq.) for furnishing services to individuals enrolled in such plan.</text>
			</section><section id="H7715CFBE57DD4197A74C1C224A8215A8"><enum>404.</enum><header>Training for health care workforce</header>
 <subsection id="H35AE524705C94E20A9822D9D06D69E82"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mental and behavioral health education and training program</header><text>Section 756 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294e-1">42 U.S.C. 294e–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4649AD681828492FBA48FFF43A0D5D9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H85D2ED78E4224E479CB1C7102CB6EA83"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>, trauma,</quote> after <quote>focus on child and adolescent mental health</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05600C31A3774AEEA4615C64ACCAA6EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraphs (2) and (3), by inserting <quote>trauma-informed care and</quote> before <quote>substance use disorder prevention and treatment services</quote>; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFBE144FF1594C49860F7F4EDBDCF470"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> <subparagraph id="H51215EBF38A0412EAEF2F497A545EEA4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A73574A96884A03957BA64046807BD5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D914937AF434406AAE3293D45E16032"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H50A6F81FF9704509A2CBD24F9DFD3814" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H0B1E2AA5F37E42C098C9104BB377829C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>programs with academic study and community practice related to trauma, its impact on mental and behavioral health outcomes, and appropriate interventions, which may include best practices developed under section 101 of the <short-title>Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</short-title></text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0681F5F522154036877E49C3253AC7D6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training demonstration program</header><text>Section 760 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294k">42 U.S.C. 294k</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1D38964034D645C2871B19782FEF34CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8AE81E754B1E430CA3E8BC6ECA8FBA9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraphs (1) and (2), by inserting <quote>trauma-informed</quote> after <quote>integrate</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB308C09A2384E7BA8515D3F11B48436"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(A), by inserting <quote>, and recognize and address the impacts of experiencing trauma on children, youth, and families</quote> before the semicolon;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD31AEC93FF9544699D7ABC6A3E1F15B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="HC4DE42F6D18E477E88902CCD3D575EF8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A)—</text>
 <clause id="H0186ED8BBF6F4FD59DAC070F35AC6763"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i)(II), by inserting <quote>trauma-informed</quote> after <quote>integrated</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HB3AFCF317B4C4455B04A060BC3B22092"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii)(III), by inserting <quote>trauma-informed</quote> before <quote>treatment</quote>; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21B85B8EC82A4F6A8D03BBC1B085B412"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A), by inserting <quote>trauma-informed</quote> after <quote>integrate</quote>;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D1F22AE5F7E475BA08818CC901F1217"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)(B), by inserting <quote>trauma-informed</quote> after <quote>integrate</quote>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9518DC19ED414458B389B14256250A3B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> <subparagraph id="HAC16C49C9BB843018FA3F441DB2CCBD2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text>
 <clause id="HE5C3BE23AC1C40D78272A0FB22959F7E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text> </clause><clause id="HBA2243A8286140FEA36F3AA2E6F66AC0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H6D12E8729833416D8D501EBC91A9983C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57C3A96598AC471CB3E26EFD68980ADB" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HEDA2F3F3CAA74C639D35AED9EB2538B5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provide training with academic study and community practice related to trauma, its impact on mental health outcomes, and appropriate interventions, which may include best practices developed under section 101 of the <short-title>Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</short-title></text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA630C50B2E0477FA00E2E4BF5F26038"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <clause id="H717DC8E38D984FDDB60A5DDEE8AAA3B6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H36E52C792AE44F9E86C67C1F09F6C75D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="HEFEF829EBFC54A4DB71CE37C5C6A3113"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
								<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H504E834ED4AD4F1E97D10F1AFA06EB44" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HD1768DC6B8C641B3A478E2E69BF61886"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provide training with academic study and community practice related to trauma, its impact on mental health outcomes, and appropriate interventions, which may include best practices developed under section 101 of the <short-title>Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</short-title></text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC396221364D54F3A8EAB2B38609A3C60"><enum>405.</enum><header>Trauma-related coordinating bodies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part G of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290hh">42 U.S.C. 290hh</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3F82AC00CD044A8A43A89D2651A0C51" style="OLC">
					<section id="H6ECBE190E5D248C0A4371163B90A584A"><enum>583.</enum><header>Trauma-related coordinating bodies</header>
						<subsection id="H3444CD90706548B8B3C094D02F0718B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header>
 <paragraph id="H56D3CCCBCFE4488DBDEB64EEB2BA22DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Administrator, shall make not more than 20 grants for demonstration projects to State, local, or tribal eligible entities to act as trauma-related coordinating bodies.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7543F3C5CAD3497C8EC9614CF7BCFB25"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make such a grant in an amount of not more than $4,000,000.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2A0CB0A6809E41AC86D4794D2ED85A1E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary shall make such a grant for a period of 4 years.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB820577EC5EF406F9E7E7B6CD80DD47D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header>
 <paragraph id="HFF6B6310772947139C0DA896C2BDDEE4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall include 1 or more representatives of each of the categories described in paragraph (2).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAE0DDF9D1D2F449AACB2BAB702EFCAE3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The categories referred to in paragraph (1) are—</text> <subparagraph id="HA63FF3508B7B4F1D8B60558BA8F1AA51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>agencies, such as public health or child welfare agencies, that provide services to prevent the impact of trauma among, identify, refer for services, or support (including providing treatment for) children and youth, and their families as appropriate, that have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47F1A8ADDDE34233A8C9ECBF699D0020"><enum>(B)</enum><text>faculty at an institution of higher education, or researchers or experts, in an area related to prevention of the impact of, identification of, referral for services for, or support (including treatment) for child and youth trauma;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H386043D918524337871441F54CAFC6D5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>hospitals or other health care institutions, such as mental health and substance use treatment facilities;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B0AAEE6BA6F4C44BCC7878F270659AD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>law enforcement;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H343C05E8C17D42CA84F2FD4EE61D6A99"><enum>(E)</enum><text>elementary or secondary schools, or early childhood education or care programs;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB05CE142A3F4C42AB0251B046C3D418"><enum>(F)</enum><text>community-based faith, human services, or social services organizations, including providers of after-school programs, home visiting programs, or programs to prevent or address the impact of violence; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39F3602329C7443AA19F2BAD150E8C78"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the general public, including individuals who have experienced trauma.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H96B7832F9B1D4D5B861D111430EADB51"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>In order for an entity to be eligible to receive the grant, the representatives included in the entity shall, collectively, have professional training and expertise concerning a broad range of adverse childhood experiences.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H159473F140FA4AC6882CAD457876359B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including information describing how the coordinating body will continue its activities after the end of the grant period.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HB1CE11B8403D477E99EB2E4089D77B26"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to entities proposing to serve communities that have faced trauma due to substantial discrimination, historical or cultural oppression, intergenerational poverty, civil unrest, a high rate of violence, or a high rate of drug overdose mortality.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF2FAD2EAEE4446D090B604DD4A550731"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An entity that receives a grant under this section to act as a coordinating body shall use the grant funds—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7C103E4948104DE283A13B14746827E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to bring together stakeholders who provide or use services in, or have expertise concerning, covered settings to identify community needs and resources related to services to prevent or address the impact of trauma, and to build on any needs assessments conducted by organizations or groups represented on the coordinating body;</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HD3AD55C41A414E489FBD38C104563E2F"><enum>(2)</enum>
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD2F8C97A002D4F1CA2EEECE4BA57BAF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to collect data, on indicators specified by the Secretary, that covers multiple covered settings; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CE77311CE7F4349A48CAFC68BD87499" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to use the data to identify unique community challenges, gaps in services, and high-need areas, related to services to prevent or address the impact of trauma;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6A977DEB27D4965A6BF0FADD2A4E118"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to build awareness, skills, and leadership (including through trauma-informed training and public outreach campaigns) related to implementing the best practices developed under section 101 of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017 (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>developed best practices</quote>);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCE4E62D979214F46AB5AA211A2CA4A47"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to pool resources of the members of the organizations and groups represented on the coordinating body, related to implementing the developed best practices; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD75D4DEC6CD14E668AC814F953BEA321"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to develop a strategic plan that identifies—</text> <subparagraph id="H6AE0450326264872992F92439E1E2BDE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>barriers to and gaps in the provision of services to prevent or address the impact of trauma; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC19D1707FB147BA8D713D23C516295C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>policy goals and coordination opportunities (including coordination in applying for grants) relating to implementing the developed best practices.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA4AF406326AE43FD97BC21C6C96F9BE6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text>Amounts made available under this section shall be used to supplement and not supplant other Federal, State, and local public funds and private funds expended to provide trauma-related coordination activities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H602C58BA293C424492517FF16563FFA5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>At the end of the period for which grants are made under this section, the Secretary shall conduct an evaluation of the activities carried out under each grant under this section. In conducting the evaluation, the Secretary shall assess the outcomes of the grant activities carried out by each grant recipient.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H231CEAA932064B438E09985BD54095FF"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $80,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2018 through 2021.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H054D49220C75420994BBA7A0A71C2803"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>covered setting</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 101(f) of the Trauma-Informed Care for Children and Families Act of 2017.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</section><section id="H53BF878A08284C988C0D757B099204CA"><enum>406.</enum><header>Expansion of performance partnership pilot for children who have experienced or are at risk of
 experiencing trauma</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 526 of the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services, and Education, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12301">42 U.S.C. 12301</external-xref> note) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1515195DC1C04D29A4777AF87ECB5CA1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H29DEBD5A90144954BCF8C2394E25EAFA" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H728ADBDCBB9F445980B02392F713F9AE"><enum>(4)</enum><text><quote>To improve outcomes for children and youth, and their families as appropriate, who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma</quote> means to increase the rate at which individuals who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma, including those who are low-income, homeless, in foster care, involved in the juvenile justice system, unemployed, or not enrolled in or at risk of dropping out of an educational institution and live in a community that has faced acute or long-term exposure to substantial discrimination, historical oppression, intergenerational poverty, civil unrest, or a high rate of violence, achieve success in meeting educational, employment, health, developmental, community reentry, or other key goals.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H674ACEB493BA41749419AFBAD072E9AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H568B02A6F2C4444AA184F958311E7D80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">fiscal year 2014</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">fiscal years 2018 through 2022</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H506CE220EF2B464FA7DC4D5CBF6AB726"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) and (2) as subparagraphs (A) and (B), respectively, and by moving such subparagraphs, as so redesignated, 2 ems to the right;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC75C0F4437948F499F84C0AA7608A5B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Federal agencies</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H162E549203224FD09ACFC52F1E8D596B" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H0AD2E7E60F974A8FBFC46A3F249F0643"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disconnected youth pilots</header><text>Federal agencies</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFCBA057C6B6436D8D561D57B991C0AB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC410E441CD6546C9BC12D283FA08926D" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H304F07E97D014DCEADFD9E96090C333C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Trauma-informed care pilots</header><text>Federal agencies may use Federal discretionary funds that are made available in this Act or any Act appropriating funds for any of fiscal years 2018 through 2022 to carry out up to 10 Performance Partnership Pilots. Such Pilots shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2DB5152475224601BF2DC18CC875AB26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be designed to improve outcomes for children and youth, and their families as appropriate, who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BA9D316E5DD4D979BBDE0D55B71EF1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>involve Federal programs targeted on children and youth, and their families as appropriate, who have experienced or are at risk of experiencing trauma.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC518C4DFB164CCC829AFA41FA47E913"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(2)(A), by striking <quote>2018</quote> and inserting <quote>2022</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99BFE1E4C7FC4A49912F05D7AC5ED826"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by striking <quote>2018</quote> and inserting <quote>2022</quote>.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="HD0ADCEC3CC6148C1A4A41701103196C5"><enum>407.</enum><header>Trauma-informed teaching</header>
 <subsection id="HB50A9D89BF6B45B092AFE5F75FB56058"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Partnership grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 202 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1022a">20 U.S.C. 1022a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4596282494074159AAD45B10A4A4A2E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(6)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1A8330DD50834D8D85169ABEC2086A7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (H) through (K) as subparagraphs (I) through (L), respectively; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5A621EB19ED4485886782D9C77AAD2D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (G) the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC59EAF2A927B4CD9B6264B606B2707D2" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph id="HA7EEC9D6BE4B4A45AE2E23959671B02A"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the partnership will prepare general education and special education teachers to work with students who have experienced trauma (including students who are involved in the foster care or juvenile justice systems or runaway or homeless youth) and in alternative education settings in which high populations of youth with trauma exposure may learn (including settings for correctional education, juvenile justice, pregnant and parenting students, or youth who have re-entered school after a period of absence due to dropping out);</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF13D489BF9054D0BA00C18FC58EC0818"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1)(A)(i)—</text> <subparagraph id="H271701B9CC624F30B83157AF23173105"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subclause (II), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8009E2FAE7ED406FB4AD48328394BC8E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subclause (III) as subclause (IV); and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A42AE83088D4AA8BE85539C3B67680E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subclause (II) the following:</text>
							<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9CBD973586A547CBB9D81BAD78AAE736" style="OLC">
 <subclause id="H724385690CF04D289CCBE6D8C5C3DFBB"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such teachers to adopt evidence-based approaches for improving behavior (such as positive behavior interventions and supports and restorative justice), supporting social and emotional learning, mitigating the effects of trauma, improving the learning environment in the school, and for reducing the need for suspensions, expulsions, corporal punishment, referrals to law enforcement, and other actions that remove students from instruction; and</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H28E1085CEF924BDB85FB9D0413C678F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB8571779A757446DB8E9B092B878A088" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H130B37A386754C0DBA3B86B6D5C372D0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Trauma-informed practice and work in alternative education settings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing the teaching skills of prospective and, as applicable, new elementary school and secondary school teachers to adopt evidence-based trauma-informed teaching strategies—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0CD3885F57CC4456A509A56D6115AD7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to—</text> <clause id="H9C5D59FC647D48139374422C6699CBB5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>recognize the signs of trauma and its impact on learning;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H65E863A83D4A44E1ABF9AE6439B81365"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maximize student engagement; and</text> </clause><clause id="H7D3DA978B7D24727A426252471657D73"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>minimize suspension and expulsion; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97CA9C546C37425FBBFF209A2647D6C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>including programs training teachers to work with students with exposure to traumatic events (including students involved in the foster care or juvenile justice systems) and in alternative academic settings for youth unable to participate in a traditional public school program in which high populations of students with trauma exposure may learn (such as students involved in the foster care or juvenile justice systems, pregnant and parenting students, runaway and homeless students, and other youth who have re-entered school after a period of absence due to dropping out).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H622E292385B548548EA9E09FB24C7564"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 203(b)(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1022b">20 U.S.C. 1022b(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD42FB80651F84FFCBD9633E100EC4710"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5CD142E8A3304A88BB1C5C811F417E90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HFE4F384A80B04E70AE79C86C3299404B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H74C0465A4542493A9DB1879360EBA90A" style="OLC">
 <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93A8AB48858E4367940F204338A79810"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to eligible partnerships that have a high-quality proposal for trauma training programs for general education and special education teachers.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
					</paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill>


