<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HA8D493F1E51F4166A5096B512DBF2044" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4176 IH: Air Cargo Security Improvement Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4176</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171031">October 31, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To strengthen air cargo security, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4CD45BF210AC402F9D91FD9777C51456" style="OLC">
 <section id="HAA252E5705E84042B982F7027BB57D0D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Air Cargo Security Improvement Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H37A375572F76425099542B0E71F81FD4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of air cargo security office</header> <subsection id="H7A81E4F7ED8E47DBB3ECDA99260AD4F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/449">chapter 449</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEEE9AF6C98D24465AC2D425284B9CED5" style="USC">
					<section id="H7AA8CB0463E6402E8644E8B22373CD4D"><enum>44947.</enum><header>Air cargo security office</header>
 <subsection id="HCAFED32E836D4C0DB36C1226A43A1574"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall establish an air cargo security office to carry out all policy and engagement with air cargo security stakeholders.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA00AE8967C784E0B8B6F73FD2D9384D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Leadership; Staffing</header><text>The air cargo security office established pursuant to subsection (a) shall be headed by an individual in the Senior Executive Service and be staffed by not fewer than four full-time equivalents, including the head of the office.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF35D28830EFE41D6B1CE0C7AA068F506"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/449">chapter 449</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item related to section 44946 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H89E8543987F3473C81F24CA8985A20A4" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">44947. Air cargo security office.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H354283B56B6C4A448AE990D258A1FDA8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Pilot program for air cargo computed tomography</header>
 <subsection id="H4E01AE2B49884A1D8D829A9C2DC55E95"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, in coordination with the Under Secretary for Science and Technology of the Department of Homeland Security, shall conduct a pilot program to test the expanded use of screening equipment using computed tomography technology to screen air cargo on passenger-carrying aircraft. Such program shall conclude not later than two years after such program is commenced.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4474E4F53F3E470BBC8F90B9BF4A8E22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Briefings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the beginning of the pilot program under subsection (a) and every six months thereafter until the completion of such program, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall brief the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate on the progress of such program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H05C4ECB524934E659A9967F1C2D904AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after completion of the pilot program under subsection (a), the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on the results of such pilot program with, as appropriate, a plan to integrate computed tomography technology into domestic and international air cargo screening operations, including at overseas last point of departure airports.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H232B02F88E094D629C34771BCACB4CD5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Air cargo regulation review</header>
 <subsection id="H13149CC379654A5C9A93A785B9622E7D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Not later than 150 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on actions to improve the Certified Cargo Screening Program as established by the Administrator in September 2009. The report shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H47DBEF4BB7D64003BB26AB41AF82E549"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review the degree to which the Program is effective at fully addressing evolving threats to air cargo, particularly as air cargo volumes fluctuate;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H90451B29ACCA4D19A89E4B98E01B47E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>review any vulnerabilities in the Program and effectiveness of information sharing with air cargo security stakeholders; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H59F4391DC3B548559CE64B5E91A94ECF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include information on actions to be taken to address findings in paragraphs (1) and (2), including information on plans to issue new rulemaking, if necessary.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF1F366C632E74F82B29697C1383F3688"><enum>5.</enum><header>Comptroller general review</header>
 <subsection id="HA35C221F71794645B1096B48F2A8E312"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H1C690EFD495B4B28817F0F8A1A5931B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review the Department of Homeland Security’s analysis and intelligence pre-screening processes and procedures for the examination of air cargo entering the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H79CF0064D83741DFB072F0EB4356279A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review the computed tomography technology pilot program for air cargo screening on passenger-carrying aircraft, conducted pursuant to section 3;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HEDDE0AB71C3C4EC7B0BE8F611BE9A10B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assess the effectiveness of the Department’s risk-based strategy for examining air cargo and ensuring compliance with air cargo security rules and regulations; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5F57889499C543C1A2362360FF63B4CA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review the Department’s information sharing procedures and practices for disseminating information to relevant stakeholders on preventing, mitigating, and responding to air cargo related threats.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5C90B263698249D5B397F05EA29A3875"><enum>6.</enum><header>Air cargo advance screening program</header>
 <subsection id="H9E8F7CAD322248F2A0E628F74BA0E89C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle B of title IV of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/211">6 U.S.C. 211</external-xref> et seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H2BA534AB12FF40A0AA1E69612CCEBB4E" style="OLC">
					<section id="HD8C882560A3349DE9D3DCD8433231C30"><enum>420.</enum><header>Air cargo advance screening program</header>
 <subsection id="H7579FD6BA9184EDE9E48237416A90A08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, consistent with the requirements of the Trade Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/210">Public Law 107–210</external-xref>), shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="H40BF8EDDDBB449D48021AF4029B0FFBE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish an air cargo advance screening program (in this section referred to as the <quote>ACAS Program</quote>) for the collection by U.S. Customs and Border Protection of advance electronic information from air carriers and other persons within the supply chain regarding cargo being transported to the United States by air;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7FE2BB2205F14DE2BE1D2280A5850F0B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>under such program, require that such information be transmitted by such air carriers and other persons at the earliest point practicable prior to loading of such cargo onto an aircraft destined to or transiting through the United States;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0855DE79859143E68D1192B0B3ED268E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish appropriate communications systems with freight forwarders, shippers, and air carriers;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3FD4A90556BC4FB9BD1DE4FB00425EDA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish a system that will allow freight forwarders, shippers, and air carriers to provide shipment level data for air cargo, departing from any location that is inbound to the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H979E95B1FD174E268F4FF31A72698240"><enum>(5)</enum><text>coordinate with the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration to identify opportunities in which the information furnished in compliance with the ACAS Program could be used by the Administrator.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0963C06BF0034265987E18A2CFEB0053"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inspection of high-Risk cargo</header><text>Under the ACAS Program, the Secretary shall ensure that all cargo that has been identified as high risk is inspected—</text>
 <paragraph id="H327D3F7C6F5E4F6085699C7E1E086AFD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prior to the loading of such cargo onto aircraft at the last point of departure; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDC1867270BB14848809578F2D613FE2B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>at an earlier point in the supply chain, before departing for the United States.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H59DA713A2A914C61B970A88595DED1BB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out the ACAS Program, the Secretary shall consult with relevant stakeholders, as appropriate, to ensure the implementation of an operationally feasible and practical approach to the collection of advance information with respect to cargo on aircraft departing for the United States, and that the inspection of high-risk cargo recognizes the significant differences among air cargo business models and modes of transportation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC5AA9EEF08DF417A9E8A213B7ED50913"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Analysis</header><text>The Secretary may analyze the information referred to in subsection (a) in the Department’s automated targeting system and integrate such information with other intelligence to enhance the accuracy of the risk assessment process under the ACAS Program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC13DAE3D153B4497A83913F9F8213716"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No duplication</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out this section in a manner that, after the ACAS Program is fully in effect, ensures, to the greatest extent practicable, that the ACAS Program does not duplicate other Department programs or requirements relating to the submission of air cargo data or the inspection of high-risk cargo.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE954BEC950884EB183CCACC7FCC006B2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Consideration of industry</header><text>In carrying out the ACAS Program, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H0D9CB1B8B32E45279B2C32CEF2D63C10"><enum>(1)</enum><text>take into consideration that the content and timeliness of the available data may vary among entities in the air cargo industry and among countries, and shall explore procedures to accommodate such variations while maximizing the contribution of such data to the risk assessment process under the ACAS Program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7CF68FFFC96243919333F4C7C43AD311"><enum>(2)</enum><text>test the business processes, technologies, and operational procedures required to provide advance information with respect to cargo on aircraft departing for the United States and carry out related inspection of high-risk cargo, while ensuring minimization of delays and other negative impacts on vital supply chains; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAAB5B6F1B987493D9B79B450210A2C05"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consider the cost, benefit, and feasibility before establishing any set time period for submission of certain elements of the data for air cargo under this section in line with the regulatory guidelines specified in Executive Order No. 13563, and any successor Executive order or regulation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAB404D5B47E44008BB7675EE519E57E4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>The Secretary shall provide guidance for participants in the ACAS Program regarding the requirements for participation, including requirements for transmitting shipment level data.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HF0617CA00EEB4696A9E56378B227D7C6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Use of data</header><text>The Secretary shall use the data provided under the ACAS Program for targeting shipments for screening and aviation security purposes only.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3AF1D4253FF34BE9AAFA41291426E6A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Final rule</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall issue a final regulation to implement the ACAS Program under section 420 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (as added by subsection (a) of this section) to include the electronic transmission to U.S. Customs and Border Protection of data elements for targeting cargo, including appropriate security elements of shipment level data, as determined by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H104FADDFDB89470CB02CEEB4730F173D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the commencement of the ACAS Program under section 420 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (as added by subsection (a) of this section), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report detailing the operational implementation of providing advance information under the ACAS Program and the value of such information in targeting cargo.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H967E80181878425B98DBC26956AA2C62"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 419 the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H27F45AB71A5442BC86CCED83276FBF0E" style="OLC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 420. Air cargo advance screening program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="HE1AA0F83F3F049DEBE44BB884B646F0E"><enum>7.</enum><header>Third party canine cargo screening</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1307 of the Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/1116">6 U.S.C. 1116</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H27B168939EAD4CF781A6DF675922C0F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsections (f) and (g); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A7B1D4DC0AD40BFBB4ECA84E80B6F25"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding after subsection (e) the following new subsection:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H4CD1270D1CD345668CAD73B380C483E3" style="OLC">
					<subsection id="HB962A0C9D7B1417E9AFF0E897E04B0CE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Third party canine teams for air cargo security</header>
 <paragraph id="HE89D6F3711724E47B2CF14BD80CB578A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to enhance the screening of air cargo and ensure that third party explosives detection canine assets are leveraged for such purpose, the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, shall, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H86B26F3ED5384C9CB0C862469CB89035"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop and issue standards for the use of such third party explosives detection canine assets for the primary screening of air cargo;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87D7C99D631640CEB43407BAC42B25F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop a process to identify qualified non-Federal entities that will certify such canine assets that meet the standards established by the Administrator under subparagraph (A);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E87CF4887F146B8AA74CDEF382AA68E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that such entities qualified to certify such canine assets shall be independent from entities that will train and provide canines to end users of such canine assets;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H882F68AEDD4B472B93B996F17D80B25E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establish a system of Transportation Security Administration audits of the process developed under subparagraph (B); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7221ADB87BD246AE8AE0257C894BC4CD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provide that canines certified for the primary screening of air cargo can be used by air carriers, foreign air carriers, freight forwarders, and shippers.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0D38F142B274EDC9F64D3A4CD7A82E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Beginning on the date that the development of the process under paragraph (1)(B) is complete, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, shall—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFEF33C62DB9C4B17A33F3D345699724D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilitate the deployment of third party explosives detection canine assets under paragraph (1) that meet the certification standards of the Administration, as determined by the Administrator;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73958DD16ED9455BBD875C9B131B0726"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make such standards available to vendors seeking to train and deploy such canine assets; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H573747C72D304CA2B07D1DE6AF009290"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that all costs for the training and certification of canines, and for the use of supplied canines, are borne by private industry and not the Federal Government.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF793BC5D2F434E8189B7530ECB8B1673"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H724B94499CF54FA3A86171E4BFA89820"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Air carrier</header><text>The term <quote>air carrier</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 40102 of title 49, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6CE84ED414C4905A33853E92A6B32F7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Foreign air carrier</header><text>The term <quote>foreign air carrier</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 40102 of title 49, United States Code.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07B0E02993754404B89DE2DAF48AF524"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Third party explosives detection canine asset</header><text>The term <quote>third party explosives detection canine asset</quote> means any explosives detection canine or handler not owned or employed, respectively, by the Transportation Security Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></section><section id="H4339F85ADA274A2FA27CE611E8FFACF0"><enum>8.</enum><header>Known shipper program review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator shall request the Air Cargo Subcommittee of Aviation Security Advisory Committee (established under section 44946 of title 49, United States Code) to—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HF0A22A703C0C40EDA4B2E9BFB4D94F9E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a comprehensive review and security assessment of the known shipper program under 1548.17 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBBF9A730C238403F8DC5E74DD597C8D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommend whether the Known Shipper Program should be modified or eliminated considering the full implementation of 100 percent screening under section 44901(g) of title 49, United States Code; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8BAFA8C622DE4D84BD4F7C978F465BB0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>report its findings and recommendations to the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


