<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H5F07F160BCB742D49561C1436B406EA0" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1202 IH: Red Hill Oversight and Environmental Protection Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1202</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170217">February 17, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001050">Ms. Hanabusa</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="G000571">Ms. Gabbard</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for environmental oversight and remediation activities at Red Hill Bulk Fuel Storage
			 Facility.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HF27FD357E8CF44A8A8967C8A8F215B4C" style="OLC">
 <section id="H40B7CCDBCF6146459F925BAFD53AD51E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Red Hill Oversight and Environmental Protection Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8B771784535D4D25833B274DCFC58E75"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
 <paragraph id="H9935D3D9C2534AD9987FE67BD46284C9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrative order on consent/statement of work; (AOC/SOW)</header><text>The terms <quote>Administrative Order on Consent/Statement of Work</quote> and <quote>(AOC/SOW)</quote> mean a legally enforceable agreement between the United States Department of the Navy (Navy), the Defense Logistics Agency (DLA), the United States Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), Region 9, and the State of Hawaii Department of Health (DOH) that the parties voluntarily entered into on September 28, 2015 (EPA DKT NO. RCRA 7003–R9–2015–01/DOH DKT NO. 15–UST–EA–01).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF6A092A91F784B3896AF3C0A2FC57BB1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional defense committees</header><text>The term <quote>congressional defense committees</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a)(16) of title 10, United States Code.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H4242823FE8A141578D720582654E8C54"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Facility</header><text>The term <quote>facility</quote> means the Red Hill Bulk Fuel Storage Facility located on Oahu, Hawaii.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HE218CE6F4EAA48B3B26B2EDA07741EDE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="H35E98F0BA1304F9B966766BCC4289742"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Construction on the Red Hill Bulk Fuel Storage Facility began in secret in December 1940.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3465617CD2354F95B97F4C333537698A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>More than 3,900 workers constructed the underground facility.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1CBF150B53943F0822065DF0396F21E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Construction of the facility continued nonstop except for the time of the attack on Pearl Harbor, on December 7, 1941. The facility was completed in September 1943, nine months ahead of schedule.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0D3BB26269B2413290FAF419A5ECC4F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The facility was constructed underground in hollowed out volcanic rock to allow for maximum protection of the fuel supply.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5BF1E7184B16493281A779FFE56E6379"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The facility’s 20 steel tanks are encased by 2.5–4 feet of concrete and surrounded by basalt bedrock.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C7526AEF95E447287DA1CFD6985D024"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Only 18 fuel tanks are currently operational.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8769BDD50F494D34BACD6FDF3D9BD5DD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The facility is the largest single Department of Defense fuel storage facility in the Pacific theater.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6BF934344A7244AEA3837710026BF71A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The facility protects more than 250,000,000 gallons of fuel.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HC9025C845EC24D57928F2CAFCBE2B5FB"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The fuels stored are marine diesel, F–76, and two types of jet fuel: JP–5 and JP–8.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7AD980A9B345408BB8E523E0DDC09D4F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The fuel stored at the facility directly supports vessels and aircraft of—</text> <subparagraph id="H7A108153D6154FB39DC630CCA090E453"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the United States Navy and Air Force in Hawaii, the Pacific theater, and around the world;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB5AD0ABCBCE4AA98B3C9116816DC1EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Hawaii National Guard;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8810B46B81464046AD4B185FC1A5175D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the United States Coast Guard; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFFB87FA2D684577A339DBB999670630"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB80837B56FC340DBBE673859F4359E9B"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The facility allows the United States military to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCFC2AD80FA5446919C23C37D16ED190D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>maintain a forward presence;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CA7047A721648B4AF4C069B9D3F7030"><enum>(B)</enum><text>build cooperation with partner nations, including through the biannual Rim of the Pacific exercise;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE9C290351F54284A300825CF0429AD2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure maritime security; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05AC561B45C645D4A70E43130E3DC783"><enum>(D)</enum><text>maintain regional stability.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H05119FFE097C418F9AC975F5AE12E922"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Military forward presence—</text> <subparagraph id="H73D9F2E5C23C458A8D95A2549487C143"><enum>(A)</enum><text>keeps sea lanes open; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9275C8BD156344AA9808378A98ADD888"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensures the free flow of commerce to Hawaii, the continental United States, and the Indo-Asia-Pacific region.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H66DC338BF3474878951588EC4E74A5F9"><enum>(13)</enum><text>In 1991, the facility was used as a transfer point for moving fuel from the continental United States to the Persian Gulf.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HAB3A25C0C134463498C264421FD8E0C5"><enum>(14)</enum><text>This transfer of fuel was done as part of the first Gulf War.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7DF1497915014163AA713D3B0EFB0AC1"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The facility was declassified in 1995.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H221AF01F635B49C69E8466A959ECA5B4"><enum>(16)</enum><text>The facility is physically protected and cyber-hardened.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C22DFF45FD84CA0A3E8484ABA818296"><enum>(17)</enum><text>The facility can be operated entirely off the electric grid by using gravity flow to transport fuel from the facility to Pearl Harbor, Hickam Airfield, and a truck loading site.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H112634AE6ECE4637A9246FFC36F5C4A0"><enum>(18)</enum><text>The facility is located approximately 100 feet above the basal groundwater table on the boundary of the Waimalu and Moanalua Aquifer Systems.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H103116849DFE4AB887B1925A72D27043"><enum>(19)</enum><text>The Waimalu and Moanalua aquifers are sources of potable water and are potentially vulnerable to contamination from an unscheduled discharge of fuel from the facility.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0B8DBB5371954F3F90B53A2A9F277DC9"><enum>(20)</enum><text>The Navy and the Defense Logistics Agency have kept the drinking water safe through 70 years of operation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0EA94479BC64ED5BF9CAA51E1ACD47C"><enum>(21)</enum><text>The Navy and the Defense Logistics Agency are responsible for protecting the public from unscheduled fuel leaks that may pose a risk to the drinking water.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H66290ECDA8D7429ABCDFB0B370B5DBC9"><enum>(22)</enum><text>The facility has experienced unscheduled fuel leaks as evidenced by stains beneath several of the existing fuel tanks.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H01D2F6E70C964FF7BB084F92AF48BE82"><enum>(23)</enum><text>Chronic releases of petroleum, oils, and lubricants have the potential to cause damage to Oahu’s drinking water supply.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA71DD04CDDE40B78980D038756FE6E5"><enum>(24)</enum><text>Historic records compiled by the Navy in a 2008 ground water protection plan indicated that there were more than 30 leaks dating back to 1947.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6933510A6E464CC1BDD8B7A8B7FE6D7E"><enum>(25)</enum><text>The 2008 ground water protection plan suggested at least 170,000 gallons of fuel has leaked since the facility began operating.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3848A28D273D4D53922F7D3C9186FD8C"><enum>(26)</enum><text>In January 2014, the United States Navy discovered a loss of fuel from Tank #5 and notified the Environmental Protection Agency and the Hawaii Department of Health (DOH).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H28154824576749C1BE18E3AC726F2767"><enum>(27)</enum><text>The Navy estimated the fuel loss at approximately 27,000 gallons.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H03FB5CB416464B439A6D3ED41FDC979C"><enum>(28)</enum><text>Following the January 2014 fuel release, the EPA and DOH negotiated an enforceable agreement, an Administrative Order on Consent (AOC), with the Navy and the DLA [EPA DKT NO. RCRA 7003–R9–2015–01/DOH DKT NO. 15–UST–EA–01].</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H96440EBDB9D3482A998860E9BEBE9924"><enum>(29)</enum><text>The order requires the Navy and the DLA to take actions, subject to DOH and EPA approval.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HDEBC3287B038447B88CDE8CC4D9771AB"><enum>(30)</enum><text>The order addresses fuel releases and implementable infrastructure improvements to protect human health and the environment.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H92D1FB6567D04D86B83AC92FBB197E7B"><enum>(31)</enum><text>The order includes a Statement of Work (SOW) that lays out the specific tasks the Navy and the DLA must implement.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC8F185E7150D44518F88CF29DF31BD61"><enum>(32)</enum><text>The SOW consists of 8 sections on overall project management:</text> <subparagraph id="H5D0E0563047146FAB5A54AB9E5FA14A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Tank inspection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFA1FBE166684E1B8AFDAD00333E9C87"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Repair and maintenance.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DCFF78AAB664B6E97C1167CD2971361"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Tank upgrade alternatives.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H032099D2F0EA4496BD8437F1AE0E774B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Release detection and tank tightness testing.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F8FD3534AFB41FC8204A724EEB9B871"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Corrosion and metal fatigue practices.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39090BD05A0242B3A8D60DF117D89D0B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Investigation and remediation of releases.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF86057729A5C4728ADB03B7D53063D16"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Groundwater protection and evaluation.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DE34CD125C54A89B3153108FDB36E23"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Risk and vulnerability assessment.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A0F01CEC3124DFC8A28C882756130D5"><enum>(33)</enum><text>Each section includes deadlines for the Navy and DLA to meet planned deliverables.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H845A2A0C682B4EF3B5A75806F376AD06"><enum>(34)</enum><text>The Fiscal Year 2018–2019 Area Cost Factor for Pearl Harbor is 2.26.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB5C9E1A17C784F0F806095ADA4194CB5"><enum>(35)</enum><text>The Area Cost Factor may impact decisionmaking for sustainment, repair, and maintenance priorities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CB04826A9464AC9826CAED9D9CA67DA"><enum>(36)</enum><text>Since the January 2014 fuel loss, the Navy has—</text> <subparagraph id="H4EC423DE57544375B2E7741DC10ABAC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increased standards for contractor workmanship;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41B496525D3B4337B0BE9885A329C127"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increased government oversight;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9A0524449FB4886A2A8070619DEC655"><enum>(C)</enum><text>updated operator procedures;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93C4FAE328E149038B16A04BC2452163"><enum>(D)</enum><text>increased training;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC3DAF74E2BD4DD0A2B9D2EE3BEF78FB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>instituted new safeguards, checks, balances, and alarm procedures; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE024664EBEE142919E6BA7C2A2CD59E9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>installed two additional groundwater monitoring wells.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E0A8652866B48BEAF8287A372B9572B"><enum>(37)</enum><text>The facility has 12 total groundwater monitoring sites.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HE5DC433BBC8045078C1DB20CA2DF5212"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H4078F9BCB72C4AFB81923DA5276126D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the facility is a national strategic asset that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H3125A9EAF34A4BBB9C3ED4C9F260D5D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>supports combatant commander theater security requirements;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H291DB7DC65F44ABB9AFB3521AC396447"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supports contingency operations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1E50A29568044E78822C74128D12371"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides essential and timely support to the United States and allies’ military mobilizations and disaster response efforts in the Indo-Asia-Pacific and around the world; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD67AF30D3D5A4FDD9E4E4961A0AA4FEB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is routinely used to support normal transit of Navy and Air Force movements in the region;</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C64E5649AE54BD9A66B8EA5C1617C49"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the facility in its current form cannot be replicated anywhere else in the world;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H25A975CD0A4540F2AC5C2A7F71A4D45D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>moving the fuel to another storage facility in the Indo-Asia-Pacific would have implications for the United States military force structure in the State of Hawaii and put at risk billions of dollars in annual economic activity that the Armed Forces bring to the State of Hawaii;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF67285E3B2F4B84A45E1F9BDBD92C2D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>if the facility were closed, the United States Armed Forces would be unable to support the National Military Strategy, including the goals of the United States Pacific Commander, and national security interests would be significantly undermined;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8F772462DF52437D917A1CE80D8E4D5B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>constant vigilance is required to ensure that facility degradation and fuel leaks do not pose a threat to the people of Hawaii, especially the drinking water on Oahu;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC25B499695D242CBBC5CBAC6ABAA2746"><enum>(6)</enum><text>despite its importance, the facility continues to face long-term challenges without robust and consistent funding that provides the Navy and DLA with the resources needed to improve the tanks and associated infrastructure;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H396954ED0C064234B26562B598C34C2D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>achieving the AOC/SOW deliverables is a multiyear effort that will require sustained commitment from the Department of Defense and Congress;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF0F62728F31D47A18B76706295009306"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the annual budget submissions of the Department of Defense and the Environmental Protection Agency must adequately reflect the funding requirements necessary to meet the deliverables committed to under the AOC/SOW;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC55107578A1B4A288A2E37C30C07292F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the Department of Defense must also include information about how future years budgets will support the near-term and long-term measures detailed in the reported schedule of work to prevent future fuel leaks; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H79EA58BBAD3F4A18AD6E2D9DFA13A88E"><enum>(10)</enum><text>for facility sustainment and maintenance, Pearl Harbor has a high Area Cost Factor (ACF), and the Department of Defense should develop a strategy that fiscally accounts for that ACF.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H8BBEAB16207C4B058F4A752183A7B7A0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Budget submissions</header>
			<subsection id="HDB5A4823A8524666A3CDDBECA75EFE95"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Department of defense</header>
 <paragraph id="HD26535D14DD44CE2A7743B43945D7F13"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual budget justification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of the Navy, shall ensure that the budget justification materials submitted to Congress in support of the Department of Defense budget for any fiscal year (as submitted with the budget of the President under section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code) include a description of how the Department will use funds to support any deliverables that the parties to the AOC/SOW have identified as necessary to mitigate and prevent fuel leaks at the Red Hill Bulk Fuel Storage Facility on Oahu, Hawaii.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7466F2890C2A49CE8385696A84A99223"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Future years defense program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of the Navy, shall ensure that each future-years defense program submitted to Congress under section 221 of title 10, United States Code, describes how the Department will use funds to support any deliverables that the parties to the AOC/SOW have identified as necessary to mitigate and prevent fuel leaks at the Red Hill Bulk Fuel Storage Facility on Oahu, Hawaii, in the period covered by the future-years defense program.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE1E2CC6DB344AF987E74ADA705DE8FE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Environmental protection agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall ensure that the budget justification materials submitted to Congress in support of the budget for the Agency for any fiscal year (as submitted with the budget of the President under section 1105(a) of title 31) includes a description of how the Agency will use funds to support any deliverables that the parties of the AOC/SOW have identified as necessary to mitigate and prevent fuel leaks at the Red Hill Bulk Fuel Storage Facility on Oahu, Hawaii.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H0D3604A089AA498AA43DE8D235C54C45"><enum>6.</enum><header>Annual locality adjustment of dollar thresholds applicable to Red Hill</header>
 <subsection id="HD76762636EEA42909AD56FCFAA46BBB7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the dollar limitations in section 2805 of title 10, United States Code, the Secretary of Defense may obligate or expend, from the amounts described in subsection (b), not more than $6,780,000 to carry out an unspecified minor military construction project for the sustainment and maintenance of the Red Hill Bulk Fuel Storage Facility on Oahu, Hawaii.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H60C776A971D7427A8B901BFCB7492FF8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amounts</header><text>The amounts described in this subsection are—</text> <paragraph id="HCF3064728E38417FB2807469EB85B224"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">amounts authorized to be appropriated for the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance, Defense-wide, for any of fiscal years 2017 through 2030; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF907354545041DE8E32B7D45841A26E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">amounts authorized to be appropriated for the Department of Defense for military construction not otherwise authorized by law for any of fiscal years 2017 through 2030.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA0E1E88FCC4E4D3883260257303812EB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with section 2805(b) of title 10, United States Code, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees written notice of any decision to carry out an unspecified minor military construction project under subsection (a). Such notice shall include—</text>
 <paragraph id="H49A7048E81EA4CAD9FF41BC8CBA0890D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the justification for the project; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H59CC49846F3849B1A118080AE8AC525F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the estimated cost of the project.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E63D8728B44462BAB7B6E9A4EAB0D66"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority to carry out a project under subsection (a) shall terminate on September 30, 2030.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

