<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HB767313701834FAD9946078530FBDBF1" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4153 IH: Federal Law Enforcement and Public Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4153</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171026">October 26, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to improve safety and security for service weapons used by
			 Federal law enforcement officers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8AD5351B1ADC4C3AAE37603919C03028" style="OLC">
 <section id="HDBB935F690844A63998A0B9B8CFA9E1E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Law Enforcement and Public Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H0C683B2BFB294C3785CBE135B322F0C3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving safety and security for service weapons used by Federal law enforcement officers</header> <subsection id="HCCEDDB3890914C9CA53F6DA260DD787F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/203">Chapter 203</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5EFB12355C2643278779D6D55309E91D" style="USC">
					<section id="H8EB45977F16B46D388F4C87962B70F78"><enum>3064.</enum><header>Safety and security of service weapons used by Federal law enforcement officers</header>
 <subsection id="H8E8C81C203DD4D5F866BE295683ABB4C"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each civilian or military Federal law enforcement agency shall prescribe requirements for the safe locking and storage of service firearms when they are not in use, to be followed by each Federal law enforcement officer in that agency and each person who assists that agency in its law enforcement functions, who carries a firearm as a service weapon, or who makes arrests for offenses against the United States or carries out protective security functions. The agency shall provide the appropriate equipment needed to comply with those requirements to each person to whom that agency’s requirements prescribed under this subsection apply.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0537D98C38544E569E39D5D90064F9A4"><enum>(b)</enum><text>In prescribing the requirements under subsection (a) the head of each agency shall adopt the following minimum standards for safe storage and locking:</text>
 <paragraph id="H1028D321E11C4DA6AC8DB9B42239FD49"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Officers are responsible for the safe storage of their service firearm when not in their personal possession by using smart guns and smart locks, trigger locks, safes, gunlock boxes, or other means approved by the agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24C2F9F2E36D48A48E105723C7D2CC66"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Service firearms shall not be stored in government-owned or government-provided vehicles or personally owned vehicles except for temporary storage when at court, when other options for safekeeping are not available, or if authorized by the agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDB1C99BCAD834A4C951FAF2201144802"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any violation of the requirements constitutes grounds for discipline, for which the agency shall consider imposing minimum punishment standards.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6347D62ABA554DF8A28A24FA00975208"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The head of each Federal civilian or military law enforcement agency shall report any loss or theft of a service firearm from that agency, any law enforcement officer in that agency, or any person assisting such an officer—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC6A812E6ECA843769BAECC8268CB39DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to relevant State and local law enforcement agencies; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8AAD67601C4D41DBA1DB7FA16BE3743A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the agency or department’s Office of Professional Responsibility, Internal Affairs, or Inspector General.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H756DA173CD294A6A91220F982B9F82EB"><enum>(d)</enum><text>The head of each civilian or military Federal law enforcement agency shall take appropriate action to ensure that any person who assists that agency in its law enforcement functions and carries a firearm in the course of doing so is trained in safe storage and locking practices.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6D1E7C561BC14394BBA25AC426D88791"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each civilian and military Federal law enforcement agency shall provide written materials to each Federal law enforcement officer in that agency, and each person who assists that agency in its law enforcement functions, who carries a firearm as a service weapon, about the statistical risks of keeping a firearm at home, especially if it is easily accessible.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDA257F32761647D7B5CE6E4BEA2ED5B8"><enum>(f)</enum><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, including the provision of equipment under subsection (a), such sums as may be necessary.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H561BBE80DA6448B68FC51A5A353B0D07"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/203">chapter 203</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H754B9FD4BF0443808516898360161F94" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">3064. Safety and security of service weapons used by Federal law enforcement officers.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


