<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H719B81039A194B7AB01DEA34D0E79A51" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3329 EH: Hizballah International Financing Prevention Amendments Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3329</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 to impose additional sanctions with respect to Hizballah, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HBFCFF7C84E3A4CF29574CF6AC152CB14" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA95395CCC3C24C439D6D0125FFCB9836" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="H1DEF9ABF02C543BB9F7D3B895112EEBB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hizballah International Financing Prevention Amendments Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDD5F6599AAB64D92AA0E388D56B483FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry idref="HA95395CCC3C24C439D6D0125FFCB9836" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H4A0A7A74CB03481BA33C0299E2F4AB86" level="title">Title I—Prevention of access by Hizballah to international financial and other institutions</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF43E560F9B344AD1839264691AEAF490" level="section">Sec. 101. Mandatory sanctions with respect to fundraising and recruitment activities for Hizballah.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H2D7FB0036F774310BD49D97B1FFC115A" level="section">Sec. 102. Modification of report with respect to financial institutions that engage in certain transactions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HFC4AEFFFC488451A8B3B6CA7A62B3CA1" level="section">Sec. 103. Sanctions against foreign states that support Hizballah.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H5C26BE6B580D4E7492A7F27203F561D7" level="section">Sec. 104. Prohibitions and conditions with respect to certain accounts held by foreign financial institutions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H512DCEC986E34CC682AC7B11C1BF3E2B" level="section">Sec. 105. United States strategy to prevent hostile activities by Iran and disrupt and degrade Hizballah’s illicit networks in the Western Hemisphere.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HFA16ADD3918748809902E0FB2E6AA5CD" level="title">Title II—Narcotics trafficking and significant transnational criminal activities of Hizballah</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HA52CF3082A5E47D48CBABD483F554964" level="section">Sec. 201. Blocking of property of affiliated networks of Hizballah.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H01E882A63D234E41BC56F59F8FFC9E00" level="section">Sec. 202. Report on racketeering activities engaged in by Hizballah.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HFB5B269E286C439D921C196162DF9776" level="section">Sec. 203. Modification of report on activities of foreign governments to disrupt global logistics networks and fundraising, financing, and money laundering activities of Hizballah.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF50A2E60B73942EBA5BC1E9A73B1F66B" level="section">Sec. 204. Report on combating the illicit tobacco trafficking networks used by Hizballah and other foreign terrorist organizations.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H18F5FD0506364444B0D5CEF4A440F493" level="title">Title III—General provisions</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HFD110B8BB7AC4C1EBA4098D93B273AC1" level="section">Sec. 301. Regulatory authority.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HA8EB4EEA81CB4977AF46C4CF518D2D96" level="section">Sec. 302. Implementation; penalties; judicial review; exemptions.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section> 
<title id="H4A0A7A74CB03481BA33C0299E2F4AB86" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Prevention of access by Hizballah to international financial and other institutions</header> 
<section id="HF43E560F9B344AD1839264691AEAF490"><enum>101.</enum><header>Mandatory sanctions with respect to fundraising and recruitment activities for Hizballah</header> 
<subsection id="H9C69136F314A4339AF7BC0121821DE18"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 101 of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H40228FDF819F4855AEC12577C767F39F" style="OLC"> <section id="HB546D8BA80004E41B0A442DF9DA5863F"><enum>101.</enum><header>Mandatory sanctions with respect to fundraising and recruitment activities for Hizballah</header> <subsection id="HF65FDB74752D4653AF836AAC2BD58785"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall, on or after the date of the enactment of this section, impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person that the President determines knowingly assists, sponsors, or, provides significant financial, material, or technological support for—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5871FF4C890C45ADBD1EFF052FC3F634"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Bayt al-Mal, Jihad al-Bina, the Islamic Resistance Support Association, the Foreign Relations Department of Hizballah, the External Security Organization of Hizballah, or any successor or affiliate thereof;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF545C355DF424C3E8539FBD5365705AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>al-Manar TV, al Nour Radio, or the Lebanese Media Group, or any successor or affiliate thereof;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA1369F1BF61E4EDA83E041934E85B801"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a foreign person determined by the President to be engaged in fundraising or recruitment activities for Hizballah; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3F698220F1F404BBE3C191080E777D1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a foreign person owned or controlled by a foreign person described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2D17EDA7B3E0439BBB8100A6C078E8A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header> 
<paragraph id="HE039F3FC84AF4116B458B99E83AD239A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HB93E137AE1E547E284CAF30BD10B5062"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Asset blocking</header><text>The exercise of all powers granted to the President by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) (except that the requirements of section 202 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>) shall not apply) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of a foreign person determined by the President to be subject to subsection (a) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H431CD78A41584642A290F4273EE9734A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Aliens ineligible for visas, admission, or parole</header> 
<clause id="H5B16836779014BA0876B52FD979A32B2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien who the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or designee of one of such Secretaries) determines is subject to subsection (a) is—</text> <subclause id="H468706DEF70D45509497D94CD7833CB1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H0D035EAD66A9473FB08C723752758C76"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H5098F2BB19CC4A46BA70FE225418698D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> et seq.).</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HBC4183AA04C446E9932907914A3339F5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header> 
<subclause id="H108E8A77ED944C0F929B351D168FFC59"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security shall revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien who the President determines is subject to subsection (a), regardless of when issued.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H876E17DE03B3468E9219482244D9969F"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under subclause (I) shall take effect immediately and shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the possession of the alien.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H94EE2AA731064B44B4DCA9C717E52128"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations prescribed under paragraph (1)(A) to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of such section 206.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5C3D03C0253D4F37BF59838F9CB4CCCA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1702">50 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref> and 1704) to carry out this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1A77ECFDDD51472B93A2677BA5745DD5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver</header> 
<paragraph id="H0F41D28E136940349C76E7B07B258A78"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may, for periods not to exceed 180 days, waive the imposition of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign person or foreign persons if the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that such waiver is in the national security interests of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAEF49E8B1D6F427DB102EA29A19FFD13"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header> <subparagraph id="H79A41B280CD34C41B5FB306074269F82"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Before waiver exercised</header><text>Before a waiver under paragraph (1) takes effect with respect to a foreign person, the President shall notify and brief the appropriate congressional committees on the status of the involvement of the foreign person in activities described in subsection (a).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3490C04B886A4566BB983370918D4F5A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>After waiver exercised</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the issuance of a waiver under paragraph (1) with respect to a foreign person, and every 120 days thereafter while the waiver remains in effect, the President shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on the status of the involvement of the foreign person in activities described in subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8B21F8D1C0894027A791F194EEB25CAE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Hizballah International Financing Prevention Amendments Act of 2017</short-title>, and every 180 days thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate a report that lists the foreign persons that the President has credible evidence knowingly assists, sponsors, or provides significant financial, material, or technological support for the foreign persons described in paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4) of subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H48A1F2E1877B41B68FD3C3EF97B61FAD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H572FA225EFD042BA998D0F9C9D922EBC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admitted; alien</header><text>The terms <term>admitted</term> and <term>alien</term> have meanings given those terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0970C570D56842D59AFBF08A40D163A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H7ABED86285374F1D9C0114C49991D86C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1EF09048ACC34813AB30ABF5CAC11EE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0F8745B022047E3877889A91F309D25"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Entity</header><text>The term <term>entity</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H34B188DFB94E4712BEE114EC5926F049"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a partnership, association, corporation, or other organization, group, or subgroup; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFFBD2484E54D402784682F41BBCB44BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a governmental entity</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H588118B24F9347A8B267D1B7C3EC7934"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fundraising or recruitment activities</header><text>The term <term>fundraising or recruitment activities</term> includes online fundraising and other online commercial activities, or other means of such fundraising, recruitment, and retention, as determined by the President.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42D9E90530CF470AA46D362A9D95B5F4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Hizballah</header><text>The term <term>Hizballah</term> has the meaning given such term in section 102(f).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H770B265828424C119FA1787798EF3250"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means an individual or entity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF2731096E4DC47E2B0C29657DE6FD3A5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means a United States citizen, permanent resident alien, entity organized under the laws of the United States (including foreign branches), or a person in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H17CF7512E21647FCA93439EB3C49C04C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 is amended by striking the item relating to section 101 and inserting the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B6FAA8760314681B2A6FC3D920BC3DB" style="OLC"> <toc> <toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 101. Mandatory sanctions with respect to fundraising and recruitment activities for Hizballah.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H2D7FB0036F774310BD49D97B1FFC115A"><enum>102.</enum><header>Modification of report with respect to financial institutions that engage in certain transactions</header> <subsection id="H631131F6233F4869813780FE217F8524"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (d) of section 102 of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H55453DE98B9A4710AD898C667192E6C3" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HC6FFD2281F3F470D81092D136F024A7B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report on financial institutions organized under the laws of state sponsors of terrorism</header> 
<paragraph id="H4A99E57C508E4005852F6B79623F8F2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Hizballah International Financing Prevention Amendments Act of 2017</short-title>, and annually thereafter for a period not to exceed 3 years, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate a report that—</text> <subparagraph id="H6E339F31125343079B058532EAF644A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies each foreign financial institution described in paragraph (2) that the President determines engages in one or more activities described in subsection (a)(2);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H99171D1CECE0453FB534723A3E482452"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides a detailed description of each such activity; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HE5883930B1B24EDB88280A540C557EC9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contains a determination with respect to each such foreign financial institution that is identified under subparagraph (A) as engaging in one or more activities described in subsection (a)(2) as to whether or not such foreign financial institution is in violation of Executive Order No. 13224 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism) or section 2339B of title 18, United States Code, by reason of engaging in one or more such activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8DFDFF72358B4C32B0005274C68EB4DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign financial institution described</header> 
<subparagraph id="H75A05770EB954BD88BDA89CC32C240C6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A foreign financial institution described in this paragraph is a foreign financial institution—</text> <clause id="H7F31DEB7226A4025BEA6EA8C2B6345F8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that, wherever located, is—</text> 
<subclause id="H80AC6715CC264CC6B9A81BFFEB5FFAF8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>organized under the laws of a state sponsor of terrorism or any jurisdiction within a state sponsor of terrorism;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF50E782573004A05A98BBFD9A9CB767E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>owned or controlled by the government of a state sponsor of terrorism;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HFF8810CF58A8459694BF8A064ED6E6F2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>located in the territory of a state sponsor of terrorism; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HECFFB54054A84912A668783D37325E58"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>owned or controlled by a foreign financial institution described in subclause (I), (II), or (III); and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H61EEBB5919504009AA185A70313C6C11"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the capitalization of which exceeds $10,000,000.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H48085A259B3644C88D259742FD1A5BF2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State sponsor of terrorism</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>state sponsor of terrorism</term> means a country the government of which the Secretary of State has determined is a government that has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism for purposes of—</text> 
<clause id="H4C25790BBA9047D4A01BD62568068B02"><enum>(i)</enum><text>section 6(j) of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4605">50 U.S.C. 4605(j)</external-xref>) (as continued in effect pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.));</text></clause> <clause id="H1D20B7AA4F914D2CAA85D59858FFE5EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371</external-xref>);</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA3524447494342859511B7306CA97616"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>section 40 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780</external-xref>); or</text></clause> <clause id="HDB7FCCAFBE3B4AB28E704D7C4D0B2E77"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other provision of law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H62E9C987DF9F46D789E4CB3D0CFA11DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H8B9456A6F18B4A14ADAA5F722EF95D4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all countries should designate the entirety of Hizballah as a terrorist organization; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E61AC2B58944821928053CA30EF5CE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the notion of separate Hizballah political and military <quote>wings</quote> is an artificial construct that attempts to legitimize Hizballah members of parliament and Hizballah cabinet officials who are complicit in Hizballah’s use of violence and coercion against its political opponents.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC9FE0E0A94CF404D9402B6AF53C2974F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Modification of definition of Hizballah</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause (ii) of section 102(f)(1)(E) of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8A65F99E554B44368A660046709900A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(I)</quote> and inserting <quote>(I)(aa)</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B913B568F544837B777C72429EE032C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(II)</quote> and inserting <quote>(bb)</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H53F319A03E1D47E59859C733BCFD6365"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of Hizballah.</quote> and inserting <quote>of Hizballah; or</quote>; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H693495053491407694B33772A21E07FD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H049BFF0C31C84BDD894F84293A9FFF9A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subclause id="H01E965C025CC4A27AEEE2C19D033B57D"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who the President determines is an agent or affiliate of, or is owned or controlled by Hizballah.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBB2593555CFE4549B0442F01395CC5DD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="H68FA08B19EF34C178DC84454BD140833"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains a description of any sanctions described in section 102 of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) apply with respect to a foreign financial institution by reason of engaging in an activity described in subsection (a)(2) of such section with a member of the Lebanese parliament or any cabinet official of the Lebanese Republic who is a member of Hizballah or identifies as such. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H251236B1457E407EBEF46522566A37A0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by this subsection shall be transmitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6856AC9D2FB74C8AAA9414351F59323B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7180AA3820A04ED2917CE30A372836C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Appropriations, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB4F6FA8CE19C42949138DE57F7AEF1E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Appropriations, the Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HFC4AEFFFC488451A8B3B6CA7A62B3CA1"><enum>103.</enum><header>Sanctions against foreign states that support Hizballah</header> 
<subsection id="H1B713C67B47944A0AB144F5ABCCB5056"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title I of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D466DD61B074F1E9719E69B44A0FE40" style="OLC"> <section id="H07C6B10DD3934B9CBD91E2A565E3CA83"><enum>103.</enum><header>Sanctions against foreign states that support Hizballah</header> <subsection id="HE6E28B8DDB27466F81FD5C6FECCB760C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sanctions against certain agencies and instrumentalities of foreign states</header> <paragraph id="H0CAB6B05673C4A9A8395A0EE9FD458F3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, and as appropriate thereafter, the President shall impose the sanctions described in paragraph (3) with respect to any agency or instrumentality of a foreign state described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7BAE80659D745CE80120897D17AC73D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency or instrumentality described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agency or instrumentality of a foreign state described in this paragraph is an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state that the President determines has, on or after the date of the enactment of this section, knowingly—</text> <subparagraph id="H3426C1A4C3894AFA99D7EB7570FB6BD2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">directly or indirectly conducted combat operations with, or supported combat operations of, Hizballah or an entity owned or controlled by Hizballah; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE23FBA71343E45D7A7BE0F48AB78B789"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">directly or indirectly provided significant financial or material support for, or significant arms or related material to, Hizballah or an entity owned or controlled by Hizballah.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF12DACF9461744E7B45C8289D024C891"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sanctions described in this paragraph are the exercise of all powers granted to the President by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) (except that the requirements of section 202 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>) shall not apply) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAB6FFDE1E0EA49F1A973F964863877B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions against state sponsors of terrorism</header> 
<paragraph id="HD3F366F6A9D641B68C791C3972C46D93"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state that engages in the activities described in subsection (a) that is an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state described in paragraph (3), the President shall, pursuant to section 6 of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (as continued in effect pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.)), require a license under the Export Administration Regulations to export or re-export to that foreign state any item designated by the Secretary of Commerce as <quote>EAR 99</quote>, other than food, medicine, medical devices, or similarly licensed items.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A415CC7B8334E328B34CC819612C627"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Auditing requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state that engages in the activities described in subsection (a) that is an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state described in paragraph (3), or the Government of the Russian Federation if the President determines such Government is engaged in the activities described in subsection (a), the President shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD296796386D3407E8FDA17587B2D6FDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that United States persons, and foreign persons subject to United States jurisdiction, exercise enhanced due diligence in the jurisdiction of that foreign state to ensure such persons do not directly or indirectly finance Hizballah or engage in transactions with foreign persons that directly or indirectly finance Hizballah;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H16DFECB137D04D33B10ADA43F029E168"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that United States persons, and foreign persons subject to United States jurisdiction, maintain—</text> 
<clause id="H4506F99BA89645C08F6305B856356999"><enum>(i)</enum><text>internal controls to prevent such persons from engaging in a transaction or transactions with Hizballah; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC5E9373A45B542DE8F09C3925AF37218"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>full compliance with relevant laws and regulations; </text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3795E8070AEF4DECAB1B8F13D0A255DA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that United States persons, and foreign persons subject to United States jurisdiction, engage an auditor to perform due diligence to ascertain whether—</text> <clause id="HF11C1671DAE24E2883B332F4C25726B2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the internal controls of such person are effective; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1F94BBF2B99844B28D5FF3D3E271D79C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any transactions of such person are directly or indirectly financing Hizballah; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H48112B84D55240E39F9BDA4DBBC9100F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensure the accuracy of the independent private sector audits and other due diligence processes by providing recommendations for the processes used to carry out such audits, including to—</text> 
<clause id="HF1A6D02976EB4024998146C164BA82FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>improve the accuracy of such audits; and</text></clause> <clause id="H9094886D76694DE9955F32D82C542177"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish standards of best practices.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE34039B8694F4E4B81F5C52E5F6E9750"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign state described</header><text>A foreign state described in this paragraph is a foreign state that—</text> <subparagraph id="H972D1FC09F7640F7A3D8305C0E624069"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President determines has, on or after the date of the enactment of this section, knowingly provided significant financial or material support for, or arms or related material to—</text> 
<clause id="H96B7B6EFCC964214A533A0852EB0AA61"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Hizballah; or</text></clause> <clause id="H541FE99244414541AEB5ABCFF2D249C8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an entity owned or controlled by Hizballah; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1AAB62003F934918B63B7C0C99845D70"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is a state sponsor of terrorism.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H81E573A4DA1C4993B4A2CEEA3304C9DF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header> <paragraph id="H67AF103441324E19A9921F05B7AA4F3B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may, for periods not to exceed 180 days, waive the imposition of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign state or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state if the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that such waiver is vital to the national security interests of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C5733E5501944DC9D28F14039109181"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header> 
<subparagraph id="H02EF698FD3CF47DEAF05CE5940C0A21B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Before waiver exercised</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before a waiver under paragraph (1) takes effect with respect to a foreign state or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state, the President shall notify and brief the appropriate congressional committees on the status of the involvement of the foreign state in activities described in subsection (b)(3) or involvement of the agency or instrumentality of a foreign state in activities described in subsection (a)(2), as the case may be.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H9888F3E0CFFA45558BE1834613939517"><enum>(B)</enum><header>After waiver exercised</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the issuance of a waiver under paragraph (1) with respect to a foreign state or an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state, and every 120 days thereafter while the waiver remains in effect, the President shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on the status of the involvement of the foreign state in activities described in subsection (b)(3) or involvement of the agency or instrumentality of a foreign state in activities described in subsection (a)(2), as the case may be.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD23FB67F478E4611BD11476A8F03A209"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report on supply chain of Hizballah’s missile production facilities</header> 
<paragraph id="H0B6F17F8BAA24F8394BE3FA8CE71F010"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and the Committee on Appropriations and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate on a report that contains the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H8558ED07F0884FE493D00F00265486FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An analysis of the foreign and domestic supply chain that significantly facilitates, supports, or otherwise aids Hizballah’s acquisition or development of missile production facilities.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFDA6991F4C4D4559946C018E3E768167"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the geographic distribution of the foreign and domestic supply chain described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD318280A525342C7841AB82AB7BDA807"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of the provision of goods, services, or technology transferred to Hizballah by the Government of Iran or its affiliates to indigenously manufacture or otherwise produce missiles.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF8D66D68C82947C6BD5658B0256B56E1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An identification of foreign persons that have, on or after the date of the enactment of this subsection, and based on credible evidence—</text> <clause id="H5FF12A12D9164EF1A6D1B7D0D3800794"><enum>(i)</enum><text>knowingly provided significant financial or material support for, or significant arms or related material to, Hizballah or an entity owned or controlled by Hizballah; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5AB69F849E4B4719A145D5F5DA969E94"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>knowingly facilitated the transfer of significant arms or related materiel to Hizballah utilizing commercial aircraft or air carriers.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF8B653D0609D4D73BA427CDD00245B2C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A description of the steps that the President is taking to disrupt the foreign and domestic supply chain described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H97EACC0EBB4D4B8AA6685504D99FFBBD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC54857BAFC834F2E9D156429C9FC52E1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H573EC5F4143C45238C6E9D78CA23416B"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Agency or instrumentality of a foreign state; foreign state</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>agency or instrumentality of a foreign state</term> and <term>foreign state</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 1603 of title 28, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H58DF796C2A3F4307AD6C3E855CA0D679"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H96B45EC017084ACA84E8A4823FA8C004"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCEE207AFA9D74584ADCA26EF5BB46AE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on Finance, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA029DB9E2554893B6B7DF162AF07C52"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Arms or related material</header><text>The term <term>arms or related material</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HCF17AAD8B59A4CCE9F47C8577EE6ADFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>nuclear, biological, chemical, or radiological weapons or materials or components of such weapons;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1A165C59EDED4E1FB88B967805DB9FD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ballistic or cruise missile weapons or materials or components of such weapons;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1113BC9B932948B3BC2ECDC950E398DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>destabilizing numbers and types of advanced conventional weapons;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCB5D11165E80414E802EF3944F91EDF1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>defense articles or defense services, as those terms are defined in paragraphs (3) and (4), respectively, of section 47 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2794">22 U.S.C. 2794</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBE80F54BFF7545FA938751EBB11B52C1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>defense information, as that term is defined in section 644 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2403">22 U.S.C. 2403</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD73135B5A2CC4F2F9C0CBD45EFD11021"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Export Administration Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Export Administration Regulations</term> means subchapter C of chapter VII of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE25CF6857A2245BFA102B3892D204A44"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Hizballah</header><text>The term <term>Hizballah</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102(f).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0AA9D9EF0CD4C3A9654E1A1C5693298"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State sponsor of terrorism</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>state sponsor of terrorism</term> means a country the government of which the Secretary of State has determined is a government that has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism for purposes of—</text> <subparagraph id="HF2AF5B76A7564610AC8AE1203E15EBC4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 6(j) of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4605">50 U.S.C. 4605(j)</external-xref>) (as continued in effect pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.));</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H239BA100FB8C48CE885546E0A5B37DAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9EAE6FAD16704496A182267B3F9B586D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>section 40 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE2F776A97F0242C080CA63B7D460EDBA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H9D7CBF5B2D0548479064EE82D8834825"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 102 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0AA6F397700B461E8B2D059DA40D3C1C" style="OLC"> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 103. Sanctions against foreign states that support Hizballah.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2EC9D4D192E541669522183F050F2EF7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on significant material support and arms or related materiel provided by the Russian Federation to Hizballah</header> 
<paragraph id="H82D1C5B2F68444EFAA5400813F166F2B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H977D1C0D21FC47D4BBA547A1D46DA729"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of significant material support and arms or related material that the Government of the Russian Federation has, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act, knowingly, directly or indirectly, provided to Hizballah or an entity owned or controlled by Hizballah.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCA13874CD916492890E8C872CFE5D4ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An analysis of the extent to which Russian strategic weapons deployed in Syria, including air defense systems, have provided protection for Hizballah fighters in Syria.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1D6C6C282CEC46D79FF2FFFCBF890BE2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of whether Russian counter-proliferation safeguards can ensure that any arms or related materiel described in subparagraph (A) will not be used against Israel in the future. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H51B331EECDB3430A98D97AFD3BF22F92"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1C6A7267CAC47AD8A54BE6638CA25D2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC6D59FCCEA1041D7A22A0ECAC8BAB1DB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 103 of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015, as added by this section.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87C6D28D63E0444994F87BD9E9672A17"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Arms or related material</header><text>The term <quote>arms or related material</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 103 of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015, as added by this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5C26BE6B580D4E7492A7F27203F561D7"><enum>104.</enum><header>Prohibitions and conditions with respect to certain accounts held by foreign financial institutions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 104(c)(2)(A)(ii) of the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8513">22 U.S.C. 8513(c)(2)(A)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before <quote>or support for acts of international terrorism</quote> the following <quote>, including Hizballah (as defined in section 102(f)(1)(E) of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note)), and any affiliates or successors thereof,</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H512DCEC986E34CC682AC7B11C1BF3E2B"><enum>105.</enum><header>United States strategy to prevent hostile activities by Iran and disrupt and degrade Hizballah’s illicit networks in the Western Hemisphere</header> <subsection id="H9B9C54FF2A0244CBADF73612DA680C65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy to prevent hostile activities by Iran and disrupt and degrade Hizballah’s illicit networks in the Western Hemisphere that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE3EBA4769E894002A7568C8DC45223D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies Department of State priorities, in coordination with other executive branch agencies, for defining United States policy to protect United States interests from Iranian and Hizballah threats in the Western Hemisphere;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BAEA38D453F4C1196219BAA137702E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinates with other executive branch agencies to ensure that information-sharing, interdictions, arrests, investigations, indictments, sanctions, and designations related to Hizballah individuals or networks in the Western Hemisphere are integrated, coordinated, and publicly communicated by the United States in a manner that supports United States interests;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCC03FD4371AA44F0B19733439A1E4E6B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>describes Iranian and Hizballah activities in the Western Hemisphere, their relationships with transnational criminal organizations in the region, their use of the region’s commodities trade to engage in illicit activities, and their use of Latin American and Caribbean visas, including through Citizenship by Investment Programs to seek admittance into the United States, as well as a plan to address any security vulnerabilities to the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA9EFED02B09419B848810CA6BE078EF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>includes a review of all relevant United States sanctions that relate to Hizballah’s activities in Latin America and the Caribbean and an assessment of their use, effectiveness, and any capability gaps;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0E0C71742BE43FD9DF53B270E7C3EC3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>includes a review of the use of the Department of State’s rewards program under section 36 of the State Department Basic Authorities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2708">22 U.S.C. 2708</external-xref>) to obtain information related to Latin America-based Hizballah operatives and illicit networks and an assessment of the effectiveness of this program for targeting Hizballah in the Western Hemisphere;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC5701F11F2A64CCFB5818B11A4060C7D" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>includes a review of all relevant United States sanctions on financial institutions in Latin America and the Caribbean that engage in activities outlined by section 102 of Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) and an assessment of the use of the authorities outlined, their effectiveness, and recommendations for improvement;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDACAA3CBE7DB45148EFE911604D1B1CF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>describes Hizballah criminal support networks, including country facilitation, in the Western Hemisphere and outlines a United States approach to partners in the region to address those illicit networks and build country capacity to combat the transnational criminal activities of Hizballah; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F0BDEF8AB8E4D2688A3AFF50484A5CB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>includes a review of the actions of governments in the Western Hemisphere to identify, investigate, and prosecute Latin America-based Hizballah operatives, and enforce sanctions either personally or to their business interests of Latin America-based Hizballah operatives as well as recommendations for United States action towards governments who refuse to impose sanctions or who willingly facilitate Latin America-based Hizballah illicit activities.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA3F286F151E547B49ED7C2B31186192C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The strategy required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form to the greatest extent possible but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEF35BF5B00F8465FB5DDB2763A56AB6F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H508C9F98B7344A54BDDB0A8DE9F75772"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00A2AF9A2D594040A1F0E650FC8E3D49"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H113091BCE7AC421BAAAB7DCD8BEACB5C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Diplomatic engagement</header> 
<paragraph id="HB0A9EDB1AF1E4F4D805C48C70C2890B5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title I of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; 129 Stat. 2206; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note), as amended by section 103 of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H0A8434547A10402294DCE9A44213CFE9" style="OLC"> <section id="HCB12AA4640B847DDB822467E465D1D05"><enum>104.</enum><header>Diplomatic initiatives</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the President shall instruct—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFFA0283E01724EDB9BF10CE8DCC0E855"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of State to increase cooperation with countries in the Western Hemisphere to assist in strengthening the capacity of governments to prevent hostile activity by Iran and disrupt and degrade Hizballah’s illicit networks operating in the region, including diplomatic engagement that involves—</text> <subparagraph id="HF88439919FBC4F42A10D4FAECAA5FFCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>efforts to target and expose illicit networks, arrest perpetrators, freeze assets, and attack Iran and Hizballah’s use of illicit networks using international trade and banking systems;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2A8A6B2E116F4BE2ADC5A5287BBB40B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>efforts to revoke or deny visas from those implicated in Hizballah’s activity in the region, including lawyers, accountants, business partners, service providers, and politicians who knowingly facilitate or fail to take measures to counter Hizballah’s illicit finance in their own jurisdictions;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8BCEE98AC28345E1A48BA51B90C00769"><enum>(C)</enum><text>efforts to assist willing nations with the development of counter-organized crime legislation, the strengthening of financial investigative capacity, and a fully-vetted counter-organized crime judicial model in places plagued with corruption; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFD6716AED90D4E609F6454A5C5C77EE8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>efforts to persuade governments in the region to list Hizballah as a terrorist organization;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H024D89AA077C4FB0B26EA8F362265057"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States Permanent Representative to the Organization of American States to work to secure support at the Organization of American States for a resolution that would declare Hizballah as a terrorist organization and address Hizballah’s illicit networks operating in the region;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5759BEC0AA704C55BAD50FC0D42EA358"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States Ambassador to the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) to work to secure a report on compliance by participating states with OSCE Decision Number 1063, the <quote>Consolidated Framework for the Fight Against Terrorism</quote>, in regard to Hizballah, with particular focus on the mandate to <quote>suppress the financing of terrorism, including its links with money-laundering and illegal economic activities</quote>, especially as it relates transatlantic relations, including with Latin America and the Caribbean; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H896DF7E1377F44739B2C0570DD83578E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>United States diplomats to work with international forums, including the Financial Action Task Force, to identify government entities within Latin America and the Caribbean that provide support, facilitation, or assistance to individuals affiliated with Hizballah in the Western Hemisphere.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82EE9349874F4BFF9445289A9E148A2D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 is amended by inserting after the item related to section 103 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block id="H6FF7A5BC9C854C77ACD61E488A0500FA" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 104. Diplomatic initiatives.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></title> <title id="HFA16ADD3918748809902E0FB2E6AA5CD" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Narcotics trafficking and significant transnational criminal activities of Hizballah</header> <section id="HA52CF3082A5E47D48CBABD483F554964"><enum>201.</enum><header>Blocking of property of affiliated networks of Hizballah</header> <subsection id="H74970053662A48C889919E94C0007666"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 201 of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E81D07DB95E44D5B3C177436BC6DAD8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE4C9D5BAF1734BE9A2E08D37060DD041"><enum>201.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to affiliated networks of Hizballah</header> 
<subsection id="HFC869AF2D3E84579BBF7B3310845C8CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this section, and as appropriate thereafter, the President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to affiliated networks of Hizballah, including by reason of significant transnational criminal activities of such networks.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H147911948C204CDEB414B171390EB9F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are sanctions applied with respect to a foreign person pursuant to Executive Order No. 13581 (75 Fed. Reg. 44,757) (as such Executive order was in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this section).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H257261D866914F7BAE56620D380A4A4E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Hizballah</term> has the meaning given such term in section 102(f).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H7847BD086091416B912ACEFDFBC45580"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text>The table of contents for the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H66D947F8A431488D8E395BBF33F9E72B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to title II and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD862E80C563946DAA1CFAD0104506112" style="OLC"> <toc> <toc-entry bold="off" level="title">Title II—Imposition of sanctions with respect to affliated networks of Hizballah and reports and briefings on narcotics trafficking and significant transnational criminal activities of Hizballah</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">and</continuation-text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2D96951A71741FD9B589087C38044FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to section 201 and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H145E5646E67A42B485ECB0E72F406140" style="OLC"> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 201. Imposition of sanctions with respect to affiliated networks of Hizballah.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFC12D5776B374402A8F914254FAC56B2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section take effect on the date that is 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H01E882A63D234E41BC56F59F8FFC9E00"><enum>202.</enum><header>Report on racketeering activities engaged in by Hizballah</header> <subsection id="H99B7D54FC18D4411A3899D3CD1483835"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 202 of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE31216E25EB14D09901245CCC43C5080" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEF8027F783F248A98A79D1E2D8E1B9ED"><enum>202.</enum><header>Report on racketeering activities engaged in by Hizballah</header> 
<subsection id="HE89136502B6F4FF2AA7CB089812D0691"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Hizballah International Financing Prevention Amendments Act of 2017</short-title>, and annually thereafter for the following 5 years, the Assistant Attorney General for the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice and the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration, in coordination with the Secretary of the Treasury and the heads of other applicable Federal agencies, shall jointly submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the following:</text> <paragraph id="H4F7929FA2B574040B21DA995FA49C0F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Activities that Hizballah, and agents and affiliates of Hizballah, have engaged in that are racketeering activities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF70FE1E1D9AB48228FE72C1E73BDE693"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The extent to which Hizballah, and agents and affiliates of Hizballah, engage in a pattern of such racketeering activities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAB034A9B32C454085A9BFA368828531"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Form of report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in an unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5BB348A521614F438C814775D9D3B6D5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HE2DCD549E4E241DC9EE82C9C8772D64E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1E0FB158F06D4A4F992AA2144D367BD0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF34F7C8651F3470CBACC9E45FEE6FBB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H199F70B3EF4E4865A136E9AB6490EB38"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hizballah</header><text>The term <term>Hizballah</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102(f).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B7F24E460044926B32C1C6EF146DEE8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Racketeering activity</header><text>The term <term>racketeering activity</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1961(1) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3E6EBF58730B4291B32DA05A768EE167"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 is amended by striking the item relating to section 202 and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C93261AEFE0445B819318C245D2AB6A" style="OLC"> <toc> <toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 202. Report on racketeering activities engaged in by Hizballah.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="HFB5B269E286C439D921C196162DF9776"><enum>203.</enum><header>Modification of report on activities of foreign governments to disrupt global logistics networks and fundraising, financing, and money laundering activities of Hizballah</header> <subsection id="H86785FD316C249EC852E44686BF85E0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 204(a)(1) of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1CE8723FFFE446149EA75DC147324158"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>this Act</quote> and inserting <quote>the <short-title>Hizballah International Financing Prevention Amendments Act of 2017</short-title>, and annually thereafter for the following 5 years</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD9DE1C51251D45178027BED0D22239A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)(ii)(II), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6AB4BE6BCE1549E2A808EB3C59441528"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>and free-trade zones.</quote> and inserting <quote>free-trade zones, business partnerships and joint ventures, and other investments in small and medium-sized enterprises;</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB0AEDACB3BB42BF9316CA0363EC1D26"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45442A6F147C47E1A1B788C78A7F9952" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H25B05222008D4918BC468A642E5E19B9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a list of provinces, municipalities, and local governments outside of Lebanon that expressly consent to, or with knowledge allow, tolerate, or disregard the use of their territory by Hizballah to carry out terrorist activities, including training, financing, and recruitment;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB7F49F69564472D9E482A4780B8F258"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a description of the total aggregate revenues and remittances that Hizballah receives from the global logistics networks of Hizballah, including—</text> 
<clause id="H9F414F19D50A45BDB459A63F69BDD4C8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a list of Hizballah's sources of revenue, including sources of revenue based on illicit activity, revenues from Iran, charities, and other business activities; and</text></clause> <clause id="H03AD007467E34985959CF9F367477258"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a list of Hizballah's expenditures, including expenditures for ongoing military operations, social networks, and external operations;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H23EB65DD7FF14D88967EA47140F08326"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a survey of national and transnational legal measures available to target Hizballah's financial networks;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HECFCB627BEDA4A758D3FE38A66DBE11C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of Hizballah’s financial operations in areas under its operational or political control in Lebanon and Syria and available measures to target Hizballah’s financial operations in those areas;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3E91933704144566B407B5527EBC505A"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a review of Hizballah’s international operational capabilities, including in the United States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5A714BD0BDB743D1856FC48240827D3B"><enum>(K)</enum><text>a review of—</text> 
<clause id="HED68AC21283149D69C6FD7AD4C7AC28B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total number and value of Hizballah-related assets seized and forfeited; and</text></clause> <clause id="HFE453D3B451B4B9EB68494067360198C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total number of indictments, prosecutions, and extraditions of Hizballah members or affiliates.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H868F2CA496074A41883772AA280DB131"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on estimated net worth of and determination with respect to senior Hizballah members</header> 
<paragraph id="HF2E8C74E162B43BA9D781390C4DB8C8F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than annually thereafter for the following 2 years, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains—</text> <subparagraph id="H1A3793754BDA4134BAE5963AD6DC1D07"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the estimated total net worth of each individual described in paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2292013591EE4E5EBA491A549B8994CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of how funds of each individual described in paragraph (2) were acquired, and how such funds have been used or employed; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA3C1EC9913EB4509B478E118E7F6D5C1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a determination of whether each individual described in paragraph (2) meets the criteria described in paragraph (3) or (4) of section 1263(a) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBEC5C2F82FCE47F1BB8133BDE388A985"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individuals described</header><text>The individuals described in this paragraph are the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H2ACA47B8ACA7478E8C7A69EAA2B97E81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary General of Hizballah.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7CE3F7B0E0C4476DA19334A47007B6C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Members of the Hizballah Politburo.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H34DAECA35CB542F8BE6FC7238D42C607"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other individual that the President determines is a senior foreign political figure of Hizballah, is associated with Hizballah, or otherwise provides significant support to Hizballah.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFEDBA831863048B18DE263761F69BFBE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form of report; public availability</header> 
<subparagraph id="H12F1F6C3D1FC4D2C8225EE50168DFD3F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H98DBFAD48E534DDEB604AA3D78E09EC1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The unclassified portion of the report required under paragraph (1) shall be made available to the public and posted on the website of the Department of State and all United States Embassy websites.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2BEEC3FD9F4C4D26B7899FDB591E7501"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="HE2088281E0224A12AFD899FDCC2EC43A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<clause id="H6AAD836C3C814833B6D5F926B4716FAC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives; and</text></clause> <clause id="H00D4767A64884350AF437487382E75E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBF24563C2AEA49F8BC78058E2FCF3D6B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Funds</header><text>The term <term>funds</term> means—</text> <clause id="HF46F7E7EDCE8422B9CB5D7D181A993F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>cash;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0F7D205913404BE89A693F8CDF939D49"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>equity;</text></clause> <clause id="HA4BAAD6B7E2C4E85806687133C1256AE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other intangible asset the value of which is derived from a contractual claim, including bank deposits, bonds, stocks, a security (as defined in section 2(a) of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77b">15 U.S.C. 77b(a)</external-xref>)), or a security or an equity security (as those terms are defined in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>)); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF1A26B71F759442CA93204F5F51976F1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>anything else of value that the President determines to be appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H43D66BD833AA41BC94E71A809EE866E7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Senior foreign political figure</header><text>The term <term>senior foreign political figure</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1010.605 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF50A2E60B73942EBA5BC1E9A73B1F66B"><enum>204.</enum><header>Report on combating the illicit tobacco trafficking networks used by Hizballah and other foreign terrorist organizations</header> 
<subsection id="H9468A6CD46B44ED2941D7C7A68583502"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on combating the illicit tobacco trafficking networks used by Hizballah and other foreign terrorist organizations to finance their operations, as described in the report submitted to Congress in December 2015 by the Department of State, the Department of Justice, the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Homeland Security, and the Department of Health and Human Services entitled, <quote>The Global Illicit Trade in Tobacco: A Threat to National Security.</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H53183B1BDAD24ECBA4EE094D88D53B4A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be addressed</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H206023EC658040E9A788CB2D160CBB40"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the steps to be taken by Federal agencies to combat the illicit tobacco trafficking networks used by Hizballah, other foreign terrorist organizations, and other illicit actors.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC5C713369784ED1A1E578B69F91FEDE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the steps to be taken to engage State and local law enforcement authorities in efforts to combat illicit tobacco trafficking networks operating within the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8B7738AB2CCD4A6B86221AEA3EB79BCD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the steps to be taken to engage foreign government law enforcement and intelligence authorities in efforts to combat illicit tobacco trafficking networks operating outside the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF626B8EA32E54B36A9F202432FF96360"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recommendations for legislative or administrative action needed to address the threat of illicit tobacco trafficking networks.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFADA7CA857AF4929A05574E088A5054B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H399A3334F8A04AB9AD09BE5715C5A2EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Homeland Security, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD68A80F643044869A1A8CF811E2449BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on Finance, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title> <title id="H18F5FD0506364444B0D5CEF4A440F493" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>General provisions</header> <section id="HFD110B8BB7AC4C1EBA4098D93B273AC1"><enum>301.</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header> <subsection id="H270F1E840AC54338B42DB7AC63FE5537"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, prescribe regulations as necessary for the implementation of this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB745A821A8DC465FA0D5C1BE2009730B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Briefing to Congress</header><text>Not later than 10 days before the prescription of regulations under subsection (a), the President shall brief the appropriate congressional committees of the proposed regulations and the provisions of this Act and the amendments made by this Act that the regulations are implementing.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H99840B739D5346768159B28C1638CABE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0F2EF859D8884567B942781BC5A633F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F6DBCF53F074FDBBB7FD1AE806572A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" id="HA8EB4EEA81CB4977AF46C4CF518D2D96"><enum>302.</enum><header>Implementation; penalties; judicial review; exemptions</header> 
<subsection id="HFDFADD32722340C98830D1628261318A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title I of the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/102">Public Law 114–102</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note), as amended by sections 103 and 105 of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEDB13F9213B34660A7546494E3B67479" style="OLC"> <section id="HBE6896D14B6644FD8AF6D1A7496929D8"><enum>105.</enum><header>Implementation; penalties; judicial review; exemptions; rule of construction</header> <subsection id="HE190C9A9D30249108002CB32CD4EA2D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1702">50 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref> and 1704) to carry out sections 101 and 103.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4A80D8ECBBD74E658293EB63AD631DCA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations prescribed to carry out section 101 or 103 to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of such section 206.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4349BEF87754443AB07553A74B8BE377"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Procedures for judicial review of classified information</header> <paragraph id="HA14A7E053D8F481CAF22D61915BEA926"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a finding, or a prohibition, condition, or penalty imposed as a result of any such finding, is based on classified information (as defined in section 1(a) of the Classified Information Procedures Act (18 U.S.C. App.)) and a court reviews the finding or the imposition of the prohibition, condition, or penalty, the President may submit such information to the court ex parte and in camera.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8F35AD5FB13B4F96A446D504060E2D19"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to confer or imply any right to judicial review of any finding under section 101 or 103 or any prohibition, condition, or penalty imposed as a result of any such finding.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2F2215ECCBB7407288539529B79878CD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text>The following activities shall be exempt from sections 101 and 103:</text> 
<paragraph id="H566B79F7A2DD49D0B056EDC5D4D46FB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any authorized intelligence, law enforcement, or national security activities of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H745441113A3E4B43BBC11D7A234EB4CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any transaction necessary to comply with United States obligations under the Agreement between the United Nations and the United States of America regarding the Headquarters of the United States, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, or under the Convention on Consular Relations, done at Vienna April 24, 1963, and entered into force March 19, 1967, or any other United States international agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB3836CF72D69409099564193F6859277"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in section 101 or 103 shall be construed to limit the authority of the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> et seq.) or under any other provision of law.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HE4B52CDF9CD74402AC5F161C97E18BA0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Hizballah International Financing Prevention Act of 2015 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 104, as added by section 105(c) of this Act, the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H947DC817A30843B4A0D83B44A1602734" style="OLC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 105. Implementation; penalties; judicial review; exemptions; rule of construction.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></title> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20171025" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives October 25, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


