<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H84E1FF9BB3DD45E9BEE10386AE6D1E74" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 4439 IH: Modernizing Credit Opportunities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-11-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4439</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171116">November 16, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001074">Mr. Hollingsworth</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001156">Mr. McHenry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000569">Mr. Luetkemeyer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Revised Statutes, the Bank Service Company Act, the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, and
			 the Home Owners’ Loan Act to clarify that the role of the insured
			 depository institution as lender and the location of an insured depository
			 institution under applicable law are not affected by any contract between
			 the institution and a third-party service provider, and to clarify that
			 Federal preemption of State usury laws applies to any loan to which an
			 insured depository institution is the party to which the debt is initially
			 owed according to its terms, and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H6976EB4233474C73A20CFC23761B187D" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9CA3D8CBF406456FA1B4CEB2054570AF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Modernizing Credit Opportunities Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H5A92F991CDFC4C799ABA664993A0EA61"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H36607387995A475FA7364B08FF8DB0BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Insured depository institutions have found efficiencies in their lending operations through a variety of different relationships with nondepository institutions that perform different lending-related functions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD79C7EA6899F4D1D978B224A6A2028BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Federal banking regulators have recognized that insured depository institutions may enter into relationships with third parties to originate loans, have recognized the benefits of these arrangements for institutions and borrowers alike, and have issued guidance to ensure the safety and soundness of such relationships and to protect borrowers.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C23401FC9464937AD4A54EF87CDDD38"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Insured depository institutions routinely engage in third-party lending arrangements and regulators have long recognized that third-party lending arrangements provide institutions with the ability to supplement, enhance or expedite lending services for their customers, and that engaging in third-party lending arrangements also enables institutions to reduce the cost of delivering credit products, to expand access to credit, and to achieve strategic goals.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDF887CD12B6146FAA1A0FFDB364F486B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Litigation concerning loans made by an insured depository institution that involve arrangements with third parties that perform lending-related functions have required the courts to determine the identity and location of the lender but have reached inconsistent results.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H112B430173564446AED9B957AED217D9"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Inconsistencies in the determinations of the identity and location of the lender under judicially crafted multi-factor balancing tests lessen the efficiency of the lending process, reduce the transparency of the lending process for both lenders and borrowers, and jeopardize the substantial benefits of third-party lending arrangements for borrowers and the economy.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC2022AF9293647D1A93328F2DA915CA5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In order to maximize efficiency and transparency, it is necessary to clarify and reinforce existing law by codifying clear and straightforward standards that establish that an insured depository institution is the lender on any loan or discount made, or upon any note, bill of exchange or other evidence of debt where it is the party to which the debt is initially owed according to its terms and that any relationship with a third party that performs lending-related functions does not affect the determination of such institution’s role as the lender or its location.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H5039ECF0C70B408B8A368EB53DEA3E3E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Location of insured depository institution</header>
 <subsection id="HC291E6F7111D4F17B21CE44F16A157E0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment to the Bank Service Company Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7 of the Bank Service Company Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1867">12 U.S.C. 1867</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1221588749DF4C4FB9BD3F901173D2FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (e); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF9F4071B6DA64C739DC1AB9C6E28CE2A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE790C8CC7C544C188C7BA64A1E21D37C" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H87C650FE79D64E0A9A4A3E420CAD318D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Location of insured depository institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The geographic location within the United States of a person performing services for an insured depository institution under subsection (c) or the existence of an economic relationship between an insured depository institution and another person shall not affect the determination of the location of such institution under other applicable law.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H32120C78FD4A478D848163373CBE6960"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendment to the Home Owners’ Loan Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5(d)(7) of the Home Owners’ Loan Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1464">12 U.S.C. 1464(d)(7)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF732D8370DB149A3AD7CE7310166FD6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (E) as subparagraph (F); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B375F7A231D4E50A8F6706DE3411443"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (D) the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6FEF862A20524BCEBE18CDEB4CC21550" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HA14B6C6732C644F1B298BC1F4677D12A"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Location of savings association</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The geographic location within the United States of a person performing services for a savings association under subparagraph (D) or the existence of an economic relationship between a savings association and another person shall not affect the determination of the location of the savings association under other applicable law.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA2443085BCB04CF683D80011BD561F74"><enum>4.</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header>
 <subsection id="H8DB978A4737741ADBBD31739D4A5E000"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment to the Revised Statutes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5197 of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/85">12 U.S.C. 85</external-xref>) is amended by inserting the following after the first sentence: <quote>A loan, discount, note, bill of exchange, or other debt is made by an association, and subject to the preceding sentence, where the association is the party to which the debt is owed according to the terms of the loan, discount, note, bill of exchange, or other debt, regardless of any later assignment. The existence of a service or economic relationship between an association and another person shall not affect the application of this section to the rate of interest upon the loan or discount made, or the note, bill, or other evidence of debt or the identity of the association as the lender under the agreement.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H88DD6888A3244800AB4B89232B584BAD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendment to the Federal Deposit Insurance Act</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 27 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1831d">12 U.S.C. 1831d(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>A loan, discount, note, bill of exchange, or other debt is made by a State bank or an insured branch of a foreign bank, and subject to the preceding sentence, where a State bank or an insured branch of a foreign bank is the party to which the debt is owed according to the terms of the loan, discount, note, bill of exchange or other debt, regardless of any later assignment. The existence of a service or economic relationship between a State bank or insured branch of a foreign bank and another person shall not affect the application of this subsection to the interest rate upon the loan or discount made, or upon the note, bill of exchange, or other evidence of debt or the identity of the State bank or insured branch of a foreign bank as the lender under the agreement.</quote>.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC18B9FD23CD148EABA7EFC4A24B372FD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amendment to the Home Owners’ Loan Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4(g)(1) of the Home Owners’ Loan Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1463">12 U.S.C. 1463(g)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>An extension of credit is made by a savings association, and subject to the preceding sentence, where a savings association is the party to which the debt is owed according to the terms of the debt, regardless of any later assignment. The existence of a service or economic relationship between a savings association and another person shall not affect the application of this subsection to the interest rate upon the extension of credit or the identity of the savings association as the lender under the agreement.</quote>.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


