<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HDF0C7877ED8940E8BC91D8F1503A14AF" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3001 IH: National Multimodal and Sustainable Freight Infrastructure Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3001</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170622">June 22, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001187">Mr. Meadows</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000409">Mr. Rohrabacher</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to establish a Multimodal Freight Funding Formula Program
			 and a National Freight Infrastructure Competitive Grant Program to improve
			 the efficiency and reliability of freight movement in the United States,
			 and for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H67C1608BDD75433E80E4EDA7B09662FD" style="OLC">
 <section id="H488377795E154B07A0A2C026B41FC25F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Multimodal and Sustainable Freight Infrastructure Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HADF047FE880040A9A3E6B38A83032304"><enum>2.</enum><header>Freight funding programs</header> <subsection id="H55DF9B17D0E247C1AF43A96ABC76A9AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/701">Chapter 701</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HC614BEF1D8A14973B25AFD395EF7043A" style="USC">
					<section id="HE457CB2758AD433CB7E25B981C0ABEA1"><enum>70104.</enum><header>Multimodal Freight Funding Formula Program</header>
 <subsection id="H85C831D30DBF4AE7BC1EBDE9394B77D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation shall establish a Multimodal Freight Funding Formula Program under which the Secretary shall distribute funds to States to improve the efficiency and reliability of freight movement in the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE4150A1479CC4AF7ABAFD068581157B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Formula apportionment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of funds made available to the Secretary for a fiscal year to carry out the Multimodal Freight Funding Formula Program under this section, the Secretary shall calculate the amount available to be apportioned to a State based on the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="H862AD3F9653748EA974D29C7D44E8A38"><enum>(1)</enum><text>6.25 percent in the ratio that—</text> <subparagraph id="HC8E62D35331A4730AC549ECC6A92F472"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of ports in each State; bears to</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5645E589809C41658ABC9D6EE146B94F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of ports in all States.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H998A6DE1AA9842C19DF2F741CED68056"><enum>(2)</enum><text>6.25 percent in the ratio that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2D3FD33557374DEFBCB330BAF29F9E88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of rail track-miles used for the movement of freight in each State; bears to</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA213544AB9E456D9D6ADB1527509FF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of such rail track-miles in all States.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D541CF7084143B08C75C466255D9DB8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>6.25 percent in the ratio that—</text> <subparagraph id="H9CEFE83E66E14E0084AB48B83225835D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of cargo-handling airports in each State; bears to</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE58B60AE97414CE8AB0E20CE6B0406E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of such airports in all States.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H13E758874D274D79B624F26A9145EC82"><enum>(4)</enum><text>6.25 percent in the ratio that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HAD78806CCA93425C913D3B5A8D0134B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of Interstate system miles in each State; bears to</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E475D6C335D4F938705E9C0E8CF1088"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of Interstate system miles in all States.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9C932E7E502499B8B3A2EE554D18876"><enum>(5)</enum><text>37.5 percent in the ratio that—</text> <subparagraph id="HA0C04506F9E34818A79DCA2643EE8938"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the tonnage of rail, waterborne, highway, and airport freight moved in each State; bears to</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H586C3AAD61044A41A41CC3EBA6E6A403"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the tonnage of such freight moved in all States.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H94011AE212E340FB810587188F0D7EDF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>37.5 percent in the ratio that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H58B36BF4A46B4CC9A96914D5C2A232BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the value of rail, waterborne, highway and airport freight moved in each State; bears to</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D543DE52A044BA29CC2110628186A7E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the value of such freight moved in all States.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8385D3CD5B704662ADF4CDC8283A94CC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Tier I eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide to a State in a fiscal year 40 percent of the amount of the funds available to the State under subsection (b) for that fiscal year if the State—</text>
 <paragraph id="HDBE9CF38E3514602B11ED2BAA08B4919"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has an established freight advisory committee in accordance with section 70201;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCEFB2AEFCECE4DED83704CCC24ECDA05"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developed any analyses or plans required for the completion of a State freight plan in accordance with section 70202;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC5783F675D684951B351AD4274F3D037"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has an approved State freight plan;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9D42D91CFBD84C179BA0A67F2DCE48DE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>has conducted a statewide analysis of freight needs and bottlenecks on all modes of transportation, including intermodal and last mile needs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6EECC6F4D4E84BFC8C19BEE7FAF04B8A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>demonstrates use of the statewide analysis of freight needs in prioritizing projects in the State freight plan;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9A42124FA52C48549E0FD1C507BC488D"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrates that the State will use the funding that it is provided under this paragraph for the highest priority projects identified in the freight investment plan described under section 70202; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H08823472CA2142EF9EF08A6BE55564D6"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrates that the program of projects will use the strategies and contribute to the goals described in the State freight plan to decrease—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H582B0B1FEF9E4DC38A294028429BB233"><enum>(A)</enum><text>greenhouse gas emissions;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39C3E2DBB43E466B9F6C43C7E4C58E91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>local air pollution, including ozone and ozone precursors, nitrogen oxides, sulfur dioxide, particulate matter, carbon monoxide, and lead;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H359747A505CF43E49F69E81C32EC1DE6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>water runoff and other adverse water impacts; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C996029E2A846249DB8E1E6C04B7D91"><enum>(D)</enum><text>wildlife habitat loss.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6BE0ABE06D3740CC8705F2C420B240DF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tier II eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide to a State in a fiscal year 60 percent of the amount of the funds available to the State under subsection (b) for that fiscal year if the State—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HBBE867F6053F49C3952AEBAE4AF8B6A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has met the eligibility criteria of subsection (c);</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8BB754A651CE43A299A85371C94EFEE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has conducted, in cooperation with at least 1 other State, a multistate analysis of freight needs and bottlenecks on all modes of transportation, including intermodal and last mile needs along a multistate freight corridor; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H06B0F1CD2BD148C7918C28EC4C395996"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has developed, in cooperation with at least one other State or a relevant entity in Canada or Mexico, a regional freight investment plan that focuses on the end-to-end investment needs of critical multistate freight corridors based on the multistate analysis of freight needs and bottlenecks on all modes of transportation, including intermodal and last mile needs.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H10E45E358960403798ABE5ED71FC082E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Redistribution of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make available under the National Freight Infrastructure Competitive Grant Program under section 70105 any funds that—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H46E949760833439F9DD5A2A563CD8557"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary calculated under subsection (b) as available to a State for a fiscal year but did not provide to that State for that fiscal year under subsection (c) or subsection (d); or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3DE1A3BAA5F444EC9B35F159AFCF92B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary provided to a State under subsection (c) or subsection (d) but remain unobligated in that State at the end of the third fiscal year following the fiscal year in which they were provided to the State.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C8B96020E6B4C48B1460D2E7DE3BAE7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Eligible uses</header><text>A State may use funds provided under this section only for—</text> <paragraph id="HE5A7B831CD174EDC84C204437CD77A01"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the development of corridor freight plans or regional freight plans; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADEEA1DCA6E444F3B1297DAB2B846BE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>one or more phases of capital projects, equipment, or operational improvements on roads, rails, landside infrastructure on ports and airports, and intermodal connectors included in a State freight plan for projects that—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H4840F2C9410A4A71A998793770EFF79F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>maintain or improve the efficiency and reliability of freight supply chains;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H888BDE96B2AD48FD8364990F1E194C8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrate public freight benefits;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18D7E5F8A6944AA0885A310544ED7A8F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improve modal components of a multimodal corridor that is critical to a State or region;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B4ECB3A50CF4662949548C4020A7490"><enum>(D)</enum><text>address freight needs to facilitate a regionally or nationally significant economic development issue;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5211B78FCDF49EBA72B940CCA50A6E5"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in accordance with the State freight plan, decrease—</text> <clause id="H3D13A663A38F41AC9B651FFE702D5419"><enum>(i)</enum><text>greenhouse gas emissions;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HF7E64D5CA5CE4F9799D192CB14799D75"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">local air pollution, including ozone and ozone precursors, nitrogen oxides, sulfur dioxide, particulate matter, carbon monoxide, and lead;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD974E0F93F9F4614B69441C9578E0BFF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>water runoff and other adverse water impacts; and</text> </clause><clause id="H4B83F75970D642DCBF75F95121D1EA60"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>wildlife habitat loss;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9630540517324F70947BACB7EADAC33C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>are multimodal, multi-jurisdictional, or corridor-based and address freight needs;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61561BB705BA4D41BB3BDB176667FB69"><enum>(G)</enum><text>relieve freight or non-freight access, congestion, or safety issues; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H359EFAD673F04AF381A082F3EBBDEF6B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>address first and last mile connectors.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE3EE9503C1A44372AC99C2C9C8309F1F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>EPA report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State that receives funds under this section shall collect data and, beginning 1 year from the date of the completion of each project or project phase that receives such funds, and annually thereafter for 15 years, report to the Secretary and the Administrator of Environmental Protection Agency on progress made toward greenhouse gas emission reductions and local air pollution reductions in accordance with the State freight plan. All relevant data and reporting shall be collected and reported in accordance with guidance developed by the Administrator in consultation with the Secretary.</text>
						</subsection><subsection id="H5E49DAEC1483491298C72290540A26C6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Federal Share</header>
 <paragraph id="HB873C6A6ACCE4FC79793A4FD1BA72282"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal share of the cost of a project carried out by a State using funds provided under this section may not be more than 80 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H207C013F45A543A6A65A898CE0F63B5E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional Federal share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of the cost of a project carried out by a State using funds provided under this section may be increased by 5 percent if the such 5 percent is used for the mitigation of diesel emissions from construction activities associated with the project. The Administrator of Environmental Protection Agency, in consultation with the Secretary, shall develop guidance for eligible equipment and activities consistent with existing State, local, and nonprofit clean construction guidelines.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE145E53F20344C87BF18E209A16BA45F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reservation of funds for territories</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before making a calculation under subsection (b), the Secretary shall withhold funds for distribution to each territory in an amount based on the freight infrastructure need of the territories, as determined by the Secretary. Such funds shall not otherwise be made available for distribution under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HEA22F913FD474F08BF10A006A8D16DC2"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated from the Freight Trust Fund to carry out this section an amount equal to 50 percent of the receipts of the Freight Trust Fund for each fiscal year beginning in fiscal year 2018.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC9818373D54941C781D19D85D76748DB"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Administration and oversight costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may retain up to one-half of 1 percent of the amounts available to carry out this section for each fiscal year for the cost of administration and oversight of projects funded under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H241C2F116AC649BCAA221AF1256B11B1"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts authorized under subsection (j) shall be—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H016EDE41C058456486F201A540CA4545"><enum>(1)</enum><text>available for obligation on October 1 of the fiscal year for which they are authorized; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H248D2FE0EE7E406ABFB11A09C2C30ED4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>available until expended.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5B85EBFBC344C73AC62AFD75F6AC883"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Application of rate requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall take such action as may be necessary to apply the requirements described under section 113 of title 23, as applicable, to any project receiving funds under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HE5F65254450A40B6A66248D563B74DF4"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="HE199D772B29D4AC9AE57BE799243BEA6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, and Puerto Rico.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8A1EB895120D4A8397018B4B76F59FDE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State Freight Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State freight plan</term> means the State freight plan described under section 70202.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0FF7261FDFC6445FB4043A8300B17B3F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Territory</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>territory</term> has the meaning given such term in section 165(c)(1) of title 23.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H05B70871977047F7A9D3246F646973B0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>70105.</enum><header>National Freight Infrastructure Competitive Grant Program</header>
 <subsection id="H015938B7490445C48D6A85C5742D5D17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation shall establish a National Freight Infrastructure Competitive Grant Program under which the Secretary shall make grants, on a competitive basis, to designated entities for eligible projects to improve the efficiency and reliability of freight movement in the United States.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H09B9B1329E0D49A59620ABD16F57E3F0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Project goals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Program, the Secretary shall prioritize projects that—</text> <paragraph id="HDA7D5E28876D43278A5A59A14889C53A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve the efficiency and reliability of freight transportation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2ED1ACB25F9C49329CCDC9D128A18F47"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reduce the cost of freight transportation;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H57B78F1B5FAF4562B0FEA6FE844E9DD7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improve the safety of freight transportation;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFBA36944BB0141EAB28473357C772EB6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>relieve bottlenecks in the freight transportation system;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H6A8CD0031DAA40EEA21D0E2848D44C89"><enum>(5)</enum><text>improve the state of good repair of the freight transportation system;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HBE42C168423D491087650E818948993A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contribute to the environmental goals described in the State freight plan; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3E00A59BF52C4572BF9B3187C565251B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>reduce the adverse impacts of freight transportation on communities traversed by freight.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF9F0D81F88AB44EDBBEEBB0A12079C71"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under the Program a designated entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBD77D9DF0A9043209636DBBDA2062DD3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A project is eligible for a grant under the Program only if the Secretary determines that the project—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HC16F9619A86B4052A77CB408AF5B92A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that is—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H1AC29458F5444E79B73FFDFD727B3689"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a capital investment project for a transportation infrastructure facility significantly used for the movement of freight; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H824DDEB84AC34B9CB40758DAED36C9F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">infrastructure necessary to mitigate the adverse impact of freight transportation on communities traversed by freight, including—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H6254FC4EB5354B3B8E6A68E493798DE2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a road, rail, or landside air or water facility;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HAF5F0730775F40C09735C1FD671AE7CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an intermodal facility such as a seaport or port on the inland waterway system, an airport, or a highway and rail intermodal facility;</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="H4B6B9E8BFD1F42F38A479465F2C0E6B6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a facility related to an international border crossing;</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="HDB2C080E7B3948F28B8D87C148AC5B8A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is for an operational improvement or equipment of a facility described in this paragraph; or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HD58320DE9E0B4BFE8E6DBB20CFE1A81E"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">railway-roadway grade separations and related improvements;</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H37AD50663930420DA97D6635B028C56B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>will help to achieve the goals set out in subsection (b);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE66B500D3C1C40AB8177B29D695B8632"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has non-Federal source or sources of committed financing, along with any Federal funds, sufficient to complete the project;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD306C86908714406B1A2EB8B2F366867"><enum>(4)</enum><text>has independent utility;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H630695CE6D9E4AE6933DE026E0AAA722"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is included in the State freight plan; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA0643EA308174CCCB0A7929A9F1B462D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>includes the development of project plans and analysis.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDD5EC68921D24FDDA28CEC7752A3FA30"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grant criteria</header><text>The Secretary shall select eligible projects for funding based on the following criteria:</text>
 <paragraph id="H47E2CA2A36EF46D395B4642D5AC110AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The extent to which the project is likely to advance the goals described in subsection (b).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H54790D525C0347CEBD603601036CDD71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The likely benefits of the project relative to its costs.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H35A951E0E0B5483784288A7073073946"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The extent to which the project demonstrates the use of innovative technology, strategies, and practices.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2367D25F7C864DEC99DCADF9EE6E53B2"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which the project uses onroad construction vehicles and nonroad construction equipment that meet the emission standards of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1F665E5306784DD4AC7FE6636B1328FE"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which the project demonstrates effective reductions (in accordance with the State freight plan) in—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H958E4FEF52E543B998630C7746932D54"><enum>(A)</enum><text>greenhouse gas emissions;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18CE3E917D7C492BBE2C93933B3E0BED"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">local air pollution, including ozone and ozone precursors, nitrogen oxides, sulfur dioxide, particulate matter, carbon monoxide, and lead;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8426E0FC35EC40E392C7FC585AE35DC3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>water runoff and other adverse water impacts; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E668AB817FC43A28C6F6E4383E47B03"><enum>(D)</enum><text>wildlife habitat loss.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0AAD250EB7D4AC1853477B4FAC61D0A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The likely effect of the project on increasing United States exports.</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H459012FFBC5D418B88424654369F042F"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The consistency of the project with the national freight strategic plan described under section 70102.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6F70BF5127E34B1E93E6091C2187243C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The extent to which the project leverages Federal funds by matching State, territorial, local, tribal, or private funds to the Federal funding requested under the Program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6773BBB3F8C845E2A6056056B562A8F9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The extent to which funds for the project are not available from other Federal sources.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H2E7BDE98495541009563C655E7B13ADF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Special Rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A minimum of 5 percent of funds made available under the Program for a fiscal year shall be provided to zero-emission freight demonstration projects, as defined by the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9AD8CE507A884DA1934B534BD1D53827"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Retrospective analysis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant agreement made under the Program shall require that the recipient collect data and report to the Secretary, at an appropriate time as determined by the Secretary, on—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H543298E763BA4CE7ADC115CB94CBA9E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the actual cost of constructing the project;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H147D3573F0324F3F8DB0B6A89D04D6C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the time required to complete the project and put it into service;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA6B3CEF4491441D492B6A2B4B9F30307"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the level of usage of the facility built or improved by the project;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H754F64CA96174EADACA8D338729678D8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the benefits of the project, measured in a way that is consistent with the benefits that were estimated in the application for funding that was submitted to the Secretary; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC1BA319844BB43148B07D01414B05FE9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any costs resulting from the project in addition to the costs of constructing the project.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB189E7E40723456EADD4DD700535EF89"><enum>(h)</enum><header>EPA report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant agreement made under the Program shall require that the recipient collect data and, beginning 1 year from the date of the completion of the project and annually thereafter for 15 years, report to the Secretary and the Administrator of Environmental Protection Agency on progress made toward greenhouse gas emission reductions and local air pollution reductions in accordance with the State freight plan. All relevant data and reporting shall be collected and reported in accordance with guidance developed by the Administrator in consultation with the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC109042157C24979AECED2700200F400"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Period of availability</header><text>In entering into agreements under this section, the Secretary shall ensure that any funds made available for a project that are not obligated or expended before the last day of the third fiscal year following the fiscal year in which the funds are made available are transferred back to the Secretary for making grants under the Program.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HAE06AFF765AF4BF18140D3C183578AFD"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Redistribution of funds</header><text>If a designated entity that received a grant under this section has made no obligation of funding with respect to such grant by the end of the third fiscal year following the fiscal year in which the Secretary awarded the grant, the Secretary shall—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H74165D0706114E0EA966846E83B02553"><enum>(1)</enum><text>withdraw the grant from the designated entity; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD987CD58CBC340119A4A1EB9F6C6F37A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>apply the funding to another grant under this section.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F13FDD0C1834BF3AFF833E52E8C6AFF"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Federal share</header>
 <paragraph id="HB646CA61219E4FD59BF8685D2D8803C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal share of the cost of a project for which a grant is made under the Program, as estimated by the Secretary, shall be not more than 80 percent.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F13EF62E004492AA175B5E17D84D447"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional Federal share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of the cost of a project carried out by a State using funds provided under this section may be increased by 5 percent if the such 5 percent is used for the mitigation of diesel emissions from construction activities associated with the project. The Administrator of Environmental Protection Agency, in consultation with the Secretary, shall develop guidance for eligible equipment and activities consistent with existing State, local, and nonprofit clean construction guidelines.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF4AC4BCB65F548CBBDC2BD3635AA3E8E"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Administration and oversight costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may retain up to one-half of 1 percent of the amounts made available to carry out this section for each fiscal year for the cost of administration and oversight of projects funded under the Program.</text>
						</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HCF5A10DA01904339A4523045EAC37D35"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Authorization and availability of funds</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="HD972B80C6B804AFDADF5EB26C3857CF2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated from the Freight Trust Fund to carry out this section an amount equal to 50 percent of the receipts of the Freight Trust Fund for each fiscal year beginning in fiscal year 2018.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0F596B45B758459D8A9EFA9119771593"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts authorized under paragraph (1) shall be—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H547D6E0B03814D3D9904927DC2181273"><enum>(A)</enum><text>available for obligation on October 1 of the fiscal year for which they are authorized; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAE71D5ED94BB40D28FB5109F97BFF355"><enum>(B)</enum><text>available for obligation until expended.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C3983C5100443EF88DCE332256D9E60"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Application of rate requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall take such action as may be necessary to apply the requirements described under section 113 of title 23, as applicable, to any project receiving funds under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8BEDD8C1DAC5496F94DCA507C975EA8F"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HB24125E01EFC4298A750C90E2A274ED5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designated entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>designated entity</term> means—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6C097B6A989F43F68AB30E44AB001948"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B02E85610964939A3D72A7564280EF9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a unit of local government;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA96070A4DAEF472697B974C0532C28C8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a metropolitan planning organization;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC3C7AC8CD1F4D5397519A5EBE6CB3CC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a public transportation authority (including a port authority);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92B9B3BC7BF94664BC6580D17534D79D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a tribal government; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83D7CEF7CB4643B7892C3E112C04B5E2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>or a consortium of the entities described in this paragraph.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA76632722DFF4BC382356300034B0591"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means any of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, and the United States Virgin Islands.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H128759186E9F47449448A03694E3DB0A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State Freight Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State freight plan</term> means the State freight plan described under section 70202.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="HBABCB23C0F2941FE933451A67024ED59"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/701">chapter 701</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FEF6F87A0FA43CAA66ABBF3A4E30B92" style="USC">
					<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
						<toc-entry level="section">70104. Multimodal Freight Funding Formula Program.</toc-entry>
						<toc-entry level="section">70105. National Freight Infrastructure Competitive Grant Program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="HE75C6D72378F4884A1DF65CD3004209B"><enum>3.</enum><header>National and State freight plans</header>
 <subsection id="H519A4E8C19474C4AAF1283874504DDC9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National freight strategic plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 70102(b) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H32771136C38B415589D05FCF83E2F00B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (10) by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HACD8D9834E5A4BF9A9162C2F683E6810"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (11) by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H442E1371E57A486B9214908DBB6FCE9F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDCA58C3072FF4510891254BDB8974027" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HBEE01AC9131849FFB4CCAF68B9519562"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">best practices to reduce greenhouse gas emissions, local air pollution, water runoff, and wildlife habitat loss.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3DC26CBDBE6F4120B1FF1C3FDEEA2337"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State freight advisory committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 70201 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3E47D2B9C883408199ECAE115E7DF588"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a) by striking <quote>representatives of ports, freight railroads,</quote> and all that follows through <quote>local governments</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H089B4EF3B8854819A5CBB4D837844942" style="USC">
 <text>representatives of—</text><paragraph id="idA55AEF4449D54DE8BCBAF914D3B41CF3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ports;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id8873FC17FB0F46CC983CC049629EB6FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>freight railroads;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD66870A8D0184010BAF939C8938FC957"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shippers;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idAD9130E33DBF48F69233647E51871EC8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>carriers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA1338F4043B643509D7B56E09C1D6F7E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>freight-related associations;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id2576C42DE37C494DBC8BD2D6974890EF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>third-party logistics providers;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idD0FC6A8D564C46BCB9BEF9ADD9393E09"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the freight industry workforce;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id0B8240C3BCF846C88FE8072F7AB36D66"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the transportation department of the State;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idA34C577054C34603B4495417E9135CF2"><enum>(9)</enum><text>metropolitan planning organizations;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="id992DA5F46D084AE4AC2B6309BEDFD5AA"><enum>(10)</enum><text>local governments;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id0E623F08FB9A429AA6678B0416D5D912"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the environmental protection department of the State, if applicable; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="idD722AA4850DC4EDCAC8ACDC916585E22"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the air resources board of the State, if applicable</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3AAEE2E2DAE5444A83DAC77FAC4C3C3A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (b) as subsection (c);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3478ADE6ED3E4BA090A403636D418F07"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A654612E9004EE9B84BC80823EF517D" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="H05AAEC9EE4894F56A0EB08DDF9323BF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member of a freight advisory committee established under subsection (a) shall be widely recognized to have qualifications sufficient to represent the interests of such member’s stakeholder group, including, as applicable—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE58D2F0D19D34630A52EF726DA0EE6D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a general business and financial experience;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C679B2526B642999B2E4884E9E04C3F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>experience or qualifications in the areas of freight transportation and logistics;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD71A4291FD624577ADE7137011BC1C28"><enum>(3)</enum><text>experience in transportation planning;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HCACA5F5C3E4E4D40A1626084F249D8D0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>experience representing employees of the freight industry; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F6044F1FF3749B6AA5105B980E61F01"><enum>(5)</enum><text>experience representing a State, local government, or metropolitan planning organization.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph><paragraph id="H320B422BD4EA4A8CAC75A2E58D8311FD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA0F49BDF55794DB7920BC67F6BDC2340"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (5) by inserting <quote>, including advising on the development of the freight investment plan</quote> after <quote>70202</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B44960901D74F4C85182E791766B343"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84F1DB6D5C77498A8594DF73D174E239" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="HF16EA85E87D245A38E733B8322012EBB"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">approve the State freight plan under section 70202, including the freight investment plan.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09B67F071FCC47ABB09D46A18B11141B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State freight plans</header><text>Section 70202 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H696F2A4A9CE040CD9C1EAF253C580733"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="HD680618FEF1E4382AB0ABCB341DF5965"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (9)—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="H3488B414011B4058BF0D96FADAA2E91E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and section 70104</quote> after <quote>section 167 of title 23</quote>; and</text> </clause><clause id="H348E34B939C2442CB2EAFFC72C76AC9C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H96F475CCD69D4A64A83C5B89751532AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (10) as paragraph (12); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3A7E98E7D6C84AF59189A7EA09763CEA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (9) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D7425E871E8404EB0889088DC624FD2" style="USC">
 <paragraph id="H299E192199DA42D3811BFC4264E33EE1"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strategies and goals to decrease—</text> <subparagraph id="H34EC6541C64B47FAADB10C742630514C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>greenhouse gas emissions;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H891B3D8AD3DC4F729107307D0283EFF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>local air pollution, including ozone and ozone precursors, nitrogen oxides, sulfur dioxide, particulate matter, carbon monoxide, and lead;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29F62FC88C1944C8AC4C62C78159D481"><enum>(C)</enum><text>water runoff and other adverse water impacts; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B8A4307014541039FA800AFA5B03D68"><enum>(D)</enum><text>wildlife habitat loss;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB4269E3DCD645F191D3B3554A37FB74"><enum>(11)</enum><text>strategies and goals to decrease the adverse impact of freight transportation on communities traversed by freight railroads; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H0A6D5A3ED66B46A7AF69392B4848FA67"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (f); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H08CF0D79679E426EB4FF4FEAEA4C24B5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C0447219EA344BE88B7EDAE7CBEB92E" style="USC">
 <subsection id="HA4B0DB2089AE457EBC9758487CE95C51"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall approve a freight plan if such plan meets the requirements of this section and is consistent with the National freight strategic plan described in section 70102. The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall certify any environmental goal or strategy provisions of the plan.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAE5528A0A61E42F38ADD4070FD07A5C8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Freight Trust Fund</header>
 <subsection id="H5E0030BF9C9B4E3E97180817D8A53597"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/98">chapter 98</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block id="HF3405C4E68684C7F81CFFBE55B288AC6">
					<section id="H42D5CB72C23B47539C7C60235661A613"><enum>9512.</enum><header>Freight Trust Fund</header>
 <subsection id="H98E08EE4005749D6A8E8EF303FF2F26B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Creation of Trust Fund</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the <quote>Freight Trust Fund</quote> (hereinafter in this section referred to as the <quote>Fund</quote>) consisting of such amounts as may be appropriated or credited to such Fund as provided in this section or section 9602(b).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFC1DD0AE752043478311CEAEE5E5B594"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfers to the fund</header><text>There are hereby appropriated to the Fund amounts equivalent to taxes received in the Treasury under section 4286.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H20FD1DBC3B8140C6AE4B0A57B6358343"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expenditures From Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts in the Fund shall be made available, as provided by appropriation Acts, for making expenditures to meet obligations authorized to be paid out of the Fund under section 2 of the <short-title>National Multimodal and Sustainable Freight Infrastructure Act</short-title>.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H6F0CC18C56974E2B9DC24C529CA8E042"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/98">chapter 98</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95DA25811E6249D3B0E03FE70C7C639A" style="OLC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="HF3405C4E68684C7F81CFFBE55B288AC6" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="H42D5CB72C23B47539C7C60235661A613" level="section">Sec. 9512. Freight Trust Fund.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection></section><section id="H9A3FC60D15054D298A6FEA8164C5A726"><enum>5.</enum><header>Freight mobility infrastructure tax</header>
 <subsection id="HE3E9813B92AD4C5EBB01B2B6A034E5A6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Imposition of tax</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/33">Chapter 33</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after subchapter C the following new subchapter:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H89E4A3D5FABE4A19A2865571CC01E9AC" style="OLC">
					<subchapter id="H130C17B2160146C78FB1015993F26C7E"><enum>D</enum><header>Ground Transportation Freight Tax</header>
						<toc container-level="subchapter-container" idref="H130C17B2160146C78FB1015993F26C7E" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="H12C94F9C0C1C45D28E8F2E7C74D5E153" level="section">Sec. 4286. Imposition of tax.</toc-entry></toc>
						<section id="H12C94F9C0C1C45D28E8F2E7C74D5E153"><enum>4286.</enum><header>Imposition of tax</header>
 <subsection id="HAAC484AEBC5E4D109BD40E9FEB13D977"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is hereby imposed upon taxable ground transportation of property within the United States a tax equal to 1 percent of the amount paid for such transportation.</text>
							</subsection><subsection id="HE694784A71B8447EA6A7FD2160A4EB6E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>By whom paid</header>
 <paragraph id="H294BDCFDC834405892FDD176C5D5970A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The tax imposed by subsection (a) shall be paid—</text> <subparagraph id="H8B004F0D804F46A58AEB069E59F19B03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by the person making the payment subject to tax, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93F7BCC7E642400EBDC7976CDF7B1AA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of transportation by a related person, by the person for whom such transportation is made.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B7C22F37A4E47138A4ED2782DBA909E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determinations of amounts paid in certain cases</header><text>For purposes of this section, rules similar to the rules of section 4271(c) shall apply.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H72972E66282547B4B53053D8255F31C9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transportation by related persons</header><text>In the case of transportation of property by the shipper or a person related to the shipper, the fair market value of such transportation shall be the amount which would be paid for transporting such property if such property were transported by an unrelated person, determined on an arms’ length basis.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H25059C19864045F7840CF3D27DAEADDA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions and special rule</header><text>For purposes of this subchapter—</text> <paragraph id="H02D1D8DBD1F348A4BD7D4D8CE52DC109"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Taxable ground transportation</header><text>The term <term>taxable ground transportation</term> means transportation of property by—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HEBC167E9C5984CDE8CBB86C0AF255DC2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>freight rail, or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A7D0FEDF73940FFBEECD13646106E56"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">truck trailer and semitrailer chassis and bodies, suitable for use with a trailer or semitrailer which has a gross vehicle weight of 26,000 pounds or more.</text>
 </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">For purposes of subparagraph (B), the terms <term>truck trailer</term> and <term>semitrailer</term> have the same meanings as such terms have in section 4051.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD15A9DF31FBC498CB86E08486648B89D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Related person</header><text>A person (hereinafter in this paragraph referred to as the <quote>related person</quote>) is related to any person if—</text> <subparagraph id="HC858139C48554448AA19D092B09C1242"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the related person bears a relationship to such person specified in section 267(b) or 707(b)(1), or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6635DADEB1C46158102A6A5E7341BD1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the related person and such person are engaged in trades or businesses under common control (within the meaning of subsections (a) and (b) of section 52).</text>
 </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">For purposes of the preceding sentence, in applying sections 267(b) and 707(b)(1), <quote>10 percent</quote> shall be substituted for <quote>50 percent</quote> each place it appears.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6397885EC9514DD09D9FC15C811F9147"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transportation outside the United States</header><text>In the case an amount paid for transportation any portion of which is outside the United States, the portion of such amount paid which is allocable to transportation within the United States shall be determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary. Such regulations shall include rules to include transportation outside the United States the primary purpose of which is to avoid the tax imposed by this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H477DC53F836A46819869D18BAF4E026E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exemption for United States and possessions and State and local governments</header><text>The tax imposed by subsection (a) shall not apply to amounts paid for transportation of property purchased for the exclusive use of the United States, or any State or political subdivision thereof.</text></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E98B6BFB7A7485A83E7CBAFA359F35D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credits or refunds to persons who collected certain taxes</header><text>Section 6415 of such Code is amended by striking <quote>or 4271</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>4271, or 4286</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="HC327781772584ADA8F6540D0DAD9931B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of subchapters for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after the item relating to subchapter C the following new item:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B3F7F6865EA4F3D86CDA5A45CC2AD72" style="OLC">
					<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H89E4A3D5FABE4A19A2865571CC01E9AC" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
						<toc-entry idref="H130C17B2160146C78FB1015993F26C7E" level="subchapter">Subchapter D. Ground Transportation Freight Tax</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1BAA5A7729C941EC91293D9C18D9E062"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall issue regulations to carry out the amendments made by this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H5EA1BC56E41C410982CEC5F0587DE9C3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to transportation beginning on or after the last day of the 180-day period beginning on the date of the issuance of regulations under subsection (c).</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


