<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H13C36020592546269B739396721C3686" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1931 IH: Corporate EXIT Fairness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1931</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170405">April 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001037">Mr. Capuano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Judy Chu of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000714">Mr. Conyers</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000984">Mr. Cummings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000288">Mr. Ellison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000287">Mr. Lewis of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000565">Mr. Loebsack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000480">Ms. Slaughter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000535">Mr. Gutiérrez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000062">Mr. Yarmuth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000563">Mr. Lipinski</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to discourage corporate inversions and to impose tax on
			 unrepatriated earnings and unrecognized gains in connection with corporate
			 expatriations.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H4A994F2D1DDA44B4A6C68ADC60790A97" style="OLC">
 <section id="HB97598D2AF93420DBA3D00DCD879EE84" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Corporate EXpatriates and Inverters Tax Fairness Act</short-title></quote> or as the <quote>Corporate EXIT Fairness Act</quote>.</text> </section><section id="H7248F5090B66470F8A68F97042E7A4A9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rules to discourage corporate inversions and impose tax on unrepatriated earnings and unrecognized gains in connection with corporate expatriations</header> <subsection id="H90DC673CDA8949D3962B6EF3FFA917CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rules relating to corporate inversions and corporate expatriations completed after January 4, 2017</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter C of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/80">chapter 80</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
				<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90ACC995543A4C2F89D7FBD57942E0F8" style="OLC">
					<section id="H1300251EADEA46A89EEA3D9FE0D3B056"><enum>7874A.</enum><header>Rules relating to corporate inversions and corporate expatriations</header>
						<subsection id="HE5BF930C0D96406F946C63A83F894EA8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unrepatriated earnings and unrecognized gains in connection with corporate expatriation</header>
 <paragraph id="HE0008533DCD04136A23BD7F3024EA521"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a corporate expatriation—</text> <subparagraph id="HB99C545A2A004C3C9EF6F6749B9A73EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the subpart F income of any applicable controlled foreign corporation for its last taxable year ending before the acquisition date shall be increased by the accumulated deferred foreign income of such corporation, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB7BF40A7C64410B92108E3E2BBBF326"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any gain position stock of any applicable controlled foreign corporation which is held by an expatriated entity on the acquisition date shall be treated as sold on such date for its fair market value.</text>
								</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E6678DCB2474E0EAAD4C98D4EEA1B87"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rules related to recognition of gain</header>
 <subparagraph id="H685EB61D2FA2487E8E3EC03F54C5F782"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application to dispositions during 5 years before acquisition date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any disposition of gain position stock of any applicable controlled foreign corporation by an expatriated entity at any time during the 5-year period ending on the acquisition date with respect to a corporate expatriation, such disposition shall be treated as a sale of such stock for its fair market value and the period of limitation on assessment and collection of any tax with respect to such disposition under section 6501 or 6502 shall commence not earlier than the acquisition date.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75DBE8E80469498B9025B2922E7F0FB6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Gain position stock</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>gain position stock</quote> means any stock if gain would arise from the sale of such stock.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C18B08DC4954A7585DAB05E236C2CE9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Gain taken into account; proper adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, in the case of any sale under paragraph (1)(B) or (2)(A), any gain arising from such sale shall be taken into account for the taxable year of the sale. In the case of any sale under paragraph (1)(B), proper adjustment shall be made in the amount of any gain or loss subsequently realized for gain taken into account under the preceding sentence.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C4AA20B4CE342C6A16AA0BD700C8282"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Foreign parent treated as domestic corporation</header><text>Notwithstanding section 7701(a)(4)—</text> <paragraph id="H48E97B5348C54265A64DB14A2B86A0A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application to corporate inversions</header><text>In the case of a corporate inversion, the foreign corporation making the acquisition described in subsection (c)(1) shall be treated for purposes of this title as a domestic corporation.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1225A6B7C8F0400494654E60FBDDD029"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elective application to corporate expatriations</header><text>If the common parent of the expanded affiliated group which includes the foreign corporation making the acquisition in a corporate expatriation elects the application of this paragraph and enters into an agreement with the Secretary providing the Secretary such assurances as the Secretary may require that the application of paragraph (1) will be administrable and enforceable with respect to such corporation—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H612556760BDA4C048E9B012724A3F97F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such foreign corporation shall be treated for purposes of this title as a domestic corporation, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H106B158E487F410CBE13A9D71F8E34E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to such corporate expatriation.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H021D50F0AF114B0A9E55A6E46509501C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Corporate inversion; corporate expatriation</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H8864381AE3FD47ABB07868F942DBCF59"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Corporate inversion</header><text>The term <quote>corporate inversion</quote> means the direct or indirect acquisition (pursuant to a plan or a series of related transactions) of substantially all of the assets of a domestic corporation or domestic partnership, substantially all of the trade or business assets of a domestic corporation or domestic partnership, or substantially all of the United States trade or business assets of a foreign partnership, by a foreign corporation if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HA1BC2555A700447F9C1688F54F648433"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such acquisition is completed after January 4, 2017,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EF39D4DE8754C3ABF37197D707B6786"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after the acquisition the expanded affiliated group which includes the foreign corporation does not have substantial business activities in the foreign country in which, or under the law of which, the foreign corporation is created or organized, when compared to the total business activities of such expanded affiliated group, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CB62EEEA6FD4E1598A9CFA3BD0CF8FF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>after the acquisition, either—</text> <clause id="H8CA19A57E99845B3AC79D9904D11878B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more than 50 percent of the stock (by vote or value) of the foreign corporation is held—</text>
 <subclause id="HFCBAB0F8FC8549FB8889D9C91DB9C976"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of an acquisition with respect to a domestic corporation, by former shareholders of the domestic corporation by reason of holding stock in the domestic corporation, or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H7161A020940B43D29B446A46D657F8EF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of an acquisition with respect to a partnership, by former partners of the partnership by reason of holding a capital or profits interest in the partnership, or</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="HA04DF6A0DFD744CF8E67BE5319273BE7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the management and control of the expanded affiliated group which includes the foreign corporation occurs, directly or indirectly, primarily within the United States, and such expanded affiliated group has significant domestic business activities.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA60BFFB767742B69D87061F4C4A6BA5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Corporate expatriation</header><text>The term <quote>corporate expatriation</quote> means any acquisition which is not described in paragraph (1) but which would be so described if paragraph (1) were applied without regard to subparagraphs (B) and (C) thereof.</text>
							</paragraph><paragraph id="HD070B41EAD6747FBBA229D7F6F00E502"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determinations with respect to management and control and business activities</header>
 <subparagraph id="H25F8B422379C41B692C7564514C94666"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Management and control</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1)(C)(ii)—</text> <clause id="H0A6A5ACBDC3E4C21AEE51FE55EB24E76"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations for purposes of determining cases in which the management and control of an expanded affiliated group is to be treated as occurring, directly or indirectly, primarily within the United States.</text>
 </clause><clause id="HC4EE3973A0F349FABC34B01690D639ED"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Executive officers and senior management</header><text>Such regulations shall provide that the management and control of an expanded affiliated group shall be treated as occurring, directly or indirectly, primarily within the United States if substantially all of the executive officers and senior management of the expanded affiliated group who exercise day-to-day responsibility for making decisions involving strategic, financial, and operational policies of the expanded affiliated group are based or primarily located within the United States. Individuals who in fact exercise such day-to-day responsibilities shall be treated as executive officers and senior management regardless of their title.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1E2756DE2B54CC4A7194C113793DD50"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Substantial business activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1)(B), the term <quote>substantial business activities</quote> shall have the meaning given such term under regulations in effect on January 4, 2017, except that the Secretary may issue regulations increasing the threshold percent in any of the tests under such regulations for determining if business activities constitute substantial business activities for purposes of this subsection.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF82A7D5777004AA3B12C9422E1572C8D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Significant domestic business activities</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)(C)(ii), an expanded affiliated group has significant domestic business activities if at least 25 percent of—</text>
 <clause id="H054EEDE21B614960A9A2798E0B3F5885"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the employees of the group are based in the United States,</text> </clause><clause id="HDFC5F5E8AF894AF5A8DE17AE68E5514D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the employee compensation incurred by the group is incurred with respect to employees based in the United States,</text>
 </clause><clause id="H203479BB8AD84CCD91D50EEC23C763A1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the assets of the group are located in the United States, or</text> </clause><clause id="H5E05E26818B648AD8DEE9E645276E36D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the income of the group is derived in the United States,</text>
									</clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">determined in the same manner as such determinations are made for purposes of determining
			 substantial business activities under regulations referred to in
			 subparagraph (B) as in effect on January 4, 2017, but applied by treating
			 all references in such regulations to <quote>foreign country</quote> and <quote>relevant foreign country</quote> as references to <quote>the United States</quote>. The Secretary may issue regulations decreasing the threshold percent in any of the tests under
			 such regulations for determining if business activities constitute
 significant domestic business activities for purposes of this subsection.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2C454676B00C4297950653E3F57980BD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Certain stock disregarded</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall not be taken into account in determining ownership under paragraph (1)(C)(i)—</text> <subparagraph id="H50B76215A52D4D62AAD71B4571F69676"><enum>(A)</enum><text>stock held by members of the expanded affiliated group which includes the foreign corporation, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H982E47A3C35E4455ACC3C3E3F5E600AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>stock of such foreign corporation which is sold in a public offering related to the acquisition described in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDC74104E084642B6B8A46DA01F6633F5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Plan deemed in certain cases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a foreign corporation completes an acquisition which would be described in paragraph (1) or (2) if such acquisition were pursuant to a plan and such acquisition is completed—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8AEE1C3E4D424AB59FA7346849EF020E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of an acquisition which would be so described in paragraph (1), during the 4-year period beginning on the date which is 2 years before the ownership requirements of paragraph (1)(C)(i) are met, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H351961383F784B82B42806C50FE5248C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an acquisition which would be so described in paragraph (2), during the 4-year period ending on the acquisition date,</text>
 </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">such acquisition shall be treated as pursuant to a plan.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB36561E125784B3B9480EEDFD57895C8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Certain transfers disregarded</header><text>The transfer of properties or liabilities (including by contribution or distribution) shall be disregarded if such transfers are part of a plan a principal purpose of which is to avoid the purposes of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H52D767F5E36C439E9AE8A7F832BD659C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Special rule for related partnerships</header><text>For purposes of applying paragraph (1)(C)(i) to the acquisition of a trade or business of a partnership, except as provided in regulations, all partnerships which are under common control (within the meaning of section 482) shall be treated as 1 partnership.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFF0DAF764EAE4CF8898268C47649EB69"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be appropriate to determine whether any transaction or series of transactions is a corporate inversion or corporate expatriation, including regulations—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB4C805A488494B039466CFBF1365527D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to treat warrants, options, contracts to acquire stock, convertible debt interests, and other similar interests as stock, and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2236D9DB75464B95AAA0EF9CCE1722AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to treat stock as not stock.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC62E0089AEBC4D6D81C6D34168D8ADDB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Other definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text>
							<paragraph id="H04A8E9E4AC1740F280A02626F53096CF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Accumulated deferred foreign income</header>
 <subparagraph id="H15B0B2C90D9C488B9EE8A39720A0EA11"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>accumulated deferred foreign income</term> means the excess of—</text> <clause id="H5E7F0EE050EC43D698303DD50465ADE6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the undistributed earnings of the controlled foreign corporation, over</text>
 </clause><clause id="HA92FC339215844EDB3E4F548D86EBDDD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the undistributed U.S. earnings of such controlled foreign corporation.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3149856F088C45E8BFB8B0DB07278F4C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Undistributed earnings</header><text>The term <term>undistributed earnings</term> means the earnings and profits of the controlled foreign corporation described in section 959(c)(3), determined—</text>
 <clause id="H72F01DC571B4428BA17EE48B7E587474"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as of the close of the taxable year described in subparagraph (A),</text> </clause><clause id="HB7A2F369943F4E7FAE59A3DB5541B135"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>without diminution by reason of distributions made during such taxable year, and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD5F92A01DD5843AABFEA78CA3FB171A7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>without regard to this paragraph.</text> </clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">For purposes of this chapter, any determination with respect to the treatment of distributions described in clause (ii) shall be made after the application of this paragraph to the earnings and profits described in the matter preceding clause (i).</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB766723D7E9346A4B9C32EEE6603D63D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Undistributed U.S. earnings</header><text>The term <term>undistributed U.S. earnings</term> has the meaning given the term <term>post-1986 undistributed U.S. earnings</term> in paragraph (5) of section 245(a), determined—</text>
 <clause id="H3A64AAFC9BAC4C26978F3114C04BC699"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as of the close of the taxable year described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, and</text> </clause><clause id="HD3BD139CF0E24A9B95E4D28968883110"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>without regard to <quote>post-1986</quote> each place it appears in the matter before subparagraph (A) of such paragraph (5).</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D98A03743AE4A3E8AEC3318D4067DCD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable controlled foreign corporation</header><text>The term <term>applicable controlled foreign corporation</term> means, with respect to any expatriated entity, any controlled foreign corporation with respect to which such entity was a United States shareholder at any time during the 5-year period ending on the acquisition date.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE6C770A14C0449248D298378666738E1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Expatriated entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>expatriated entity</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H85A409A0132A476A846E64B3A62302CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the corporation or partnership referred to in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) of subsection (c)(1) (including with respect to the application of such subsection pursuant to subsection (c)(2)), and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H227AA19C088E496C9FE5C49FBA5FC31C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any United States person who is related (within the meaning of section 267(b) or 707(b)(1)) to a corporation or partnership described in subparagraph (A).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6CA9C61B1E0471C844A0B26549AFDE6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Acquisition date</header><text>The term <term>acquisition date</term> means the date on which the acquisition described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (c), as the case may be, is completed.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H614151EDB8624A9DAF25AE5A7181AD16"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Expanded affiliated group</header><text>The term <quote>expanded affiliated group</quote> means an affiliated group as defined in section 1504(a) but without regard to section 1504(b)(3), except that section 1504(a) shall be applied by substituting <quote>more than 50 percent</quote> for <quote>at least 80 percent</quote> each place it appears.</text>
							</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB19058558B34E109D534DD5233A129F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <paragraph id="H5CC2454CBD2047E6BD9CB94A97A5B7DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Credits not allowed against tax on unrepatriated earnings and unrecognized gains</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any expatriated entity and any United States shareholder of an applicable controlled foreign corporation, credits (other than the credit allowed by section 901) shall be allowed against the tax imposed by chapter 1 on such entity or corporation for any taxable year with respect to which any amount is included in income under subsection (a) only to the extent such tax exceeds the product of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HF259C760198F4DBD9DA6784B861AF04D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount so included in income, and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9939A97E93374BB9B413044226C2A17B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the highest rate of tax specified in section 11(b)(1).</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">For purposes of determining the credit allowed by section 901, such income shall be treated as from
 sources within the United States.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C190E1643F24840A55F1478CA58F1CA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination with section 172 and minimum tax</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 860E(a) shall apply for purposes of subsection (a).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBDE79291D9EB4188BB4E94CEF530DED2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Special rule for treaties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in section 894 or 7852(d) or in any other provision of law shall be construed as permitting an exemption, by reason of any treaty obligation of the United States heretofore or hereafter entered into, from the provisions of this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H02651357C0E744AAAEF9458EDA3B1F11"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall provide such regulations as are necessary to carry out this section, including regulations providing for such adjustments to the application of this section as are necessary to prevent the avoidance of the purposes of this section, including the avoidance of such purposes through—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5168CD4260494192A69B0B4B341674AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the use of related persons, pass-through or other noncorporate entities, or other intermediaries, or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H249B61F04FEC4F099DA73DD9382FC5BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transactions designed to have persons cease to be (or not become) members of expanded affiliated groups or related persons.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</subsection><subsection id="HE13F0DA666014526BB18BF78A1184FFB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modifications to rules relating to corporate inversions completed on or before January 4, 2017</header>
 <paragraph id="H937668974BC242F7B8E776DA7A94BBE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7874">section 7874</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9BFB15466B5C42E8A52176F1572C4831" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H6C566FCAA24844A099DB42D6C9E3F794"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inverted corporations treated as domestic corporations</header> <paragraph id="H114EB2F4DC4648888BAC62124AA241EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 7701(a)(4), a foreign corporation shall be treated for purposes of this title as a domestic corporation if—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H2B0A086CFE1444E991A53A1CFABB47E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such corporation would be a surrogate foreign corporation if subsection (a)(2) were applied by substituting <quote>80 percent</quote> for <quote>60 percent</quote>, or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74E165FC485F4AEA95F60275F2FBA05B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such corporation is an inverted domestic corporation.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD81F96898B1F41E6A8846550CBC082E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inverted domestic corporation</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, a foreign corporation shall be treated as an inverted domestic corporation if, pursuant to a plan (or a series of related transactions)—</text>
 <subparagraph commented="no" id="HC2E4CE4B36294A9FAD4CD7CD5D59DD7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the entity completes after May 8, 2014, and on or before January 4, 2017, the direct or indirect acquisition of—</text>
 <clause commented="no" id="HC753D07EDCF74BEE9F8DF8AD53AF4F5F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">substantially all of the assets of a domestic corporation or domestic partnership,</text> </clause><clause commented="no" id="H35903C590E914AE28FA4E261904094BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>substantially all of the trade or business assets of a domestic corporation or domestic partnership, or</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" id="HE2240F6F1F02409C8C1BFA1174C2689E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>substantially all of the United States trade or business assets of a foreign partnership, and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE665DB1B41B44D78B0608C64FFBC36FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after the acquisition, either—</text>
 <clause id="H41A8A003001848DAB15F134528C9BCA5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>more than 50 percent of the stock (by vote or value) of the entity is held—</text> <subclause id="HF3A1B1289C244E379ECD99D211461598"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of an acquisition with respect to a domestic corporation, by former shareholders of the domestic corporation by reason of holding stock in the domestic corporation, or</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="H24E3914E4AA24E30962B6FEC0A4CBFB7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of an acquisition with respect to a partnership, by former partners of the partnership by reason of holding a capital or profits interest in the partnership, or</text>
 </subclause></clause><clause id="H48BC0EEADC51445082E499DD46076116"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the management and control of the expanded affiliated group which includes the entity occurs, directly or indirectly, primarily within the United States, and such expanded affiliated group has significant domestic business activities.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H928D2C4DC1234D818F9D8559F969572A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception for corporations with substantial business activities in foreign country of organization</header><text>A foreign corporation described in paragraph (2) shall not be treated as an inverted domestic corporation if after the acquisition the expanded affiliated group which includes the entity has substantial business activities in the foreign country in which or under the law of which the entity is created or organized when compared to the total business activities of such expanded affiliated group. For purposes of subsection (a)(2)(B)(iii) and the preceding sentence, the term <term>substantial business activities</term> shall have the meaning given such term under regulations in effect on May 8, 2014, except that the Secretary may issue regulations increasing the threshold percent in any of the tests under such regulations for determining if business activities constitute substantial business activities for purposes of this paragraph.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H2F2F4F4F83A3455992BE8FB47BD87A41"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Management and control</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (2)(B)(ii)—</text> <subparagraph id="H35DD173DF5EF469BBCDA01593A78AF47"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe regulations for purposes of determining cases in which the management and control of an expanded affiliated group is to be treated as occurring, directly or indirectly, primarily within the United States. The regulations prescribed under the preceding sentence shall apply to periods after May 8, 2014.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD064E35B7BFC4878B8BB527306B493AE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Executive officers and senior management</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such regulations shall provide that the management and control of an expanded affiliated group shall be treated as occurring, directly or indirectly, primarily within the United States if substantially all of the executive officers and senior management of the expanded affiliated group who exercise day-to-day responsibility for making decisions involving strategic, financial, and operational policies of the expanded affiliated group are based or primarily located within the United States. Individuals who in fact exercise such day-to-day responsibilities shall be treated as executive officers and senior management regardless of their title.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBA8943488EF4742BEDFCFCA5748001D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Significant domestic business activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (2)(B)(ii), an expanded affiliated group has significant domestic business activities if at least 25 percent of—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H54EAE8409AC147B893EEB269FFD69926"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the employees of the group are based in the United States,</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H207E522F22D64701821ECB2EDC76E64D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the employee compensation incurred by the group is incurred with respect to employees based in the United States,</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12060614A34146348F6C54900B287AE2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the assets of the group are located in the United States, or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DDD6C1EA093409CB952DA56A97CCDB8"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the income of the group is derived in the United States,</text>
								</subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">determined in the same manner as such determinations are made for purposes of determining
			 substantial business activities under regulations referred to in paragraph
			 (3) as in effect on May 8, 2014, but applied by treating all references in
			 such regulations to <quote>foreign country</quote> and <quote>relevant foreign country</quote> as references to <quote>the United States</quote>. The Secretary may issue regulations decreasing the threshold percent in any of the tests under
			 such regulations for determining if business activities constitute
			 significant domestic business activities for purposes of this paragraph.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph><paragraph id="H20949C6019354F8B9C4A041C56C15DB8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header>
 <subparagraph id="HEB35979B9E3C49EAB9E1246BD1D7F6F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Clause (i) of section 7874(a)(2)(B) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>after March 4, 2003,</quote> and inserting <quote>after March 4, 2003, and before May 9, 2014,</quote>.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC61B542F17AC488CB6B820259BAFF523"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Subsection (c) of section 7874 of such Code is amended—</text>
 <clause id="H39C03AD6188A461794A7D0A4D665F0B3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <subclause id="H1A59ABE8189749B5B933109001FFDB47"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (a)(2)(B)(ii)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (a)(2)(B)(ii) and (b)(2)(B)(i)</quote>, and</text>
 </subclause><subclause id="HF4573F3963A444DDB27A3F8B01208011"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or (b)(2)(A)</quote> after <quote>(a)(2)(B)(i)</quote> in subparagraph (B),</text> </subclause></clause><clause id="H3810AE50FE4F48D4A28D7359D7245BED"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting <quote>or (b)(2)(B)(i), as the case may be,</quote> after <quote>(a)(2)(B)(ii)</quote>,</text>
 </clause><clause id="HE2FF4677239F45E7B2FFB5697C254D91"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>subsection (a)(2)(B)(ii)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (a)(2)(B)(ii) and (b)(2)(B)(i)</quote>, and</text> </clause><clause id="H2328989BF6E94491AC585B2070ABA1AD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by inserting <quote>or inverted domestic corporation, as the case may be,</quote> after <quote>surrogate foreign corporation</quote>.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF325277CB05A486D949BB22D9899B7B3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments related to stock compensation of insiders in expatriated
			 corporations</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H3B007C5313564251922C2A881426F75C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4985(a)(1) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>section 1(h)(1)(C)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 1(h)(1)(D)</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9C8710B8AF441E380DC4AB59737DD7F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 4985(c) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>or section 7874A(c)(1) (without regard to subparagraph (C) thereof)</quote> after <quote>section 7874(a)(2)(B)(i)</quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB9B63520F3BF44E6B9DA6CC7801E68A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 4985(e)(2)(A) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>or section 7874A(d)(3)</quote> after <quote>section 7874(a)(2)</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBB093810F31C4C6FA81DAA10D8C15793"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header> <paragraph id="H7332FE3409814BCFA2101F813B0AFD5B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The heading for section 7874 of such Code is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">expatriated entities and their foreign parents</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">corporate inversions completed on or before January 4, 2017</header-in-text></quote>.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7A6CEE2D4EE44FFCA5756801EDE240CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The table of sections for subchapter C of chapter 80 of such Code is amended by striking the item relating to section 7874 and inserting the following new items:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA397B08FCA8B4F2683C31888D63DF8CD" style="OLC">
						<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H90ACC995543A4C2F89D7FBD57942E0F8" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 7874. Rules relating to corporate inversions completed on or before January 4, 2017.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry idref="H1300251EADEA46A89EEA3D9FE0D3B056" level="section">Sec. 7874A. Rules relating to corporate inversions and corporate expatriations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3FDD996AB65F4B69A55E44550212779C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header>
 <paragraph id="HA999D2CE0DDF41D098B16440F090F144"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall apply taxable years ending after January 4, 2017.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H396393A093C64B4B9C96F2C4BD68BC31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modifications to rules relating to corporate inversions completed on or before January 4, 2017</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (b) shall apply to taxable years ending after May 8, 2014.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

