<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HF2EF3A596D984CE59B2D5290B7A42B7A" key="H" public-private="public" stage-count="1">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1973 : Protecting Young Victims from Sexual Abuse Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code>
		<congress>115th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session>1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 1973</legis-num>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
		<action><action-date date="20170605">June 5, 2017</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
		<official-title display="yes">To prevent the sexual abuse of minors and amateur athletes by requiring the prompt reporting of
			 sexual abuse to law enforcement authorities, and for other purposes. </official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H3002678097D740D2882D1A7748C78D29" style="OLC">
 <section id="HA99BE4E4115B4D17A28330728BA0FA27" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Young Victims from Sexual Abuse Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HC8C52B79896343E59EB6D12F5C298822"><enum>2.</enum><header>Required reporting of child and sexual abuse at facilities under the jurisdiction of amateur sports organizations recognized by the United States Olympic Committee</header> <subsection id="H7C9824A70ADE4A62862DED0C02257F01"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 226 of the Victims of Child Abuse Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/13031">42 U.S.C. 13031</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA12F20F0926E46FCB67AC65B986F1D29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="HFA4B5E73CEDE45F8A40162C18F374FBC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A person who</quote> and inserting the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H97AAD25DAD0D4125A17B6BDD84FE66CD" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H076AB24487374C758503B6158D49C625"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered professionals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB16AB15AA5C4E8A921F0475B08073C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
						<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H037E77B3562641079E85403FFFFD039D" style="OLC">
 <paragraph id="H1F1D4C0C88E54922A67CB3AD53484475"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered individual who learns of facts that give reason to suspect that a child has suffered an incident of child abuse shall as soon as possible make a report of the suspected abuse to the agency designated by the Attorney General under subsection (d).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0F5C29878284C9C9D136A317B282084"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)(1)</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HB081EA928A9E46A19C44AFBC6BAC334A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H06CBBFDB7DB9499AB2EEB8C0CA47B76C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3214D1CAA50E4611B9DADE8333EC08A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5B1E361D030468F9E4E8B44FD5A5AC7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAFF9E9F824084FD9A6CD595EC4AB5A28" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H543CA58CCACF4705BA73822174DAAFDD"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>covered individual</quote> means an adult who is authorized by a national governing body or a member of a national governing body to interact with a minor or amateur athlete at an amateur sports organization facility or at any event sanctioned by a national governing body or a member of a national governing body;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1EE513C5ECBB43EE917733E4B12F45BC"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the term <quote>event</quote> includes travel, practice, competition, and health or medical treatment; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEB156FAA2D194AE2AA062EC2B5BCAF07"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the terms <quote>amateur athlete</quote>, <quote>amateur sports organization</quote>, and <quote>national governing body</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 220501(b) of title 36, United States Code.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H095831DEF6104E60A252CCF761E76068"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (d), in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>and for all covered facilities</quote> after <quote>reside</quote>;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9C1490D241EC40468FFAA9EDEB50E845"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (f), in the first sentence—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H6839AB933FA840FAB727AD9368E6EF70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and on all</quote> and inserting <quote>on all</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8216721EEFC34E0185D2B193AF24AEAE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and for all covered facilities,</quote> after <quote>lands,</quote>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9809C5947AAC45EEAB42F9B0FEB703FB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (h), by inserting <quote>and all covered individuals,</quote> after <quote>facilities,</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H76DADC3BAD3C4FE3BFE6C9AF1E88F0EF"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H18F87CF8F3B1407B8311915AA9973B59" style="OLC">
 <subsection id="HBB75DE430C1742149FA7F430911694E1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to require a victim of child abuse to self-report the abuse.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FB1CA84163940A18A502C6BBFFAFC99"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalty for failure to report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2258 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <quote>facility,</quote> the following: <quote>or a covered individual (as described in subsection (a)(2) of such section 226) who</quote>.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HCFF606E1BD224EFC8E49C02B89D77C01"><enum>3.</enum><header>Civil remedy for personal injuries</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2255 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H3DC267B203C24509B411A05C9D8B9BA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFDAF35B9D4714026974934B6F04F57ED" style="USC"> <subsection id="H15AC24DAE84D4342B34A08AAD166CEE4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who, while a minor, was a victim of a violation of section 1589, 1590, 1591, 2241(c), 2242, 2243, 2251, 2251A, 2252, 2252A, 2260, 2421, 2422, or 2423 of this title and who suffers personal injury as a result of such violation, regardless of whether the injury occurred while such person was a minor, may sue in any appropriate United States District Court and shall recover the actual damages such person sustains or liquidated damages in the amount of $150,000, and the cost of the action, including reasonable attorney’s fees and other litigation costs reasonably incurred. The court may also award punitive damages and such other preliminary and equitable relief as the court determines to be appropriate.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H412ED520131843E791EDAC52FD58605F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>filed within</quote> and all that follows through the end and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0A279850AA0747B3971FBD15A4D41B71" style="USC"> <text>filed—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H3A18F368D35F46928446DD8F2C0D431D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 10 years after the date on which the plaintiff reasonably discovers the later of—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H475C0A76D08B4DB7B700F51CCD22C867"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the violation that forms the basis for the claim; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H57A4CA4A92904435B36ABD49DDED7BED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the injury that forms the basis for the claim; or</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E867FAA86814473BF1183C766BCF984"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 10 years after the date on which a legal disability ends.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6E7B49BD22344C25AC8C3F609C281F5C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F6B62449AA643AE86CC2EA4B44CAE78" style="USC"> <subsection id="H3532D020F08D43B7A4AF5C17CD35744E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Venue; Service of process</header> <paragraph id="H576D514F4D17436AA0F943E2F4501106"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Venue</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any action brought under subsection (a) may be brought in the district court of the United States that meets applicable requirements relating to venue under section 1391 of title 28.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H537AB5B942634AF29C36600695E828DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Service of process</header><text>In an action brought under subsection (a), process may be served in any district in which the defendant—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H18BAD2BC70644DEC837F073BDA8F0A04"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is an inhabitant; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EB947C84CE746DEBC65CEABC8168DD7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be found.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H35A9216C1AE744539BF1D6AB738948A4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Expansion of authorities and duties of amateur sports organizations recognized by the United States
			 Olympic Committee to prevent the abuse of minor and amateur athletes</header>
 <subsection id="H173BB9D527DE4C6AA29410B1FB28FC4C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expansion of authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 220523(a) of title 36, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H976C80C42A2A4E56B10DE282FC8364E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7F11C0D5945E4A4BA450DC53C4B7EF67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H3ED93CD6F8D34AF287784C74AC2324CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F86330FBA864820BFE58CBF3FFB9527" style="USC">
 <paragraph id="H9357B8782B214C3392C445998E569D77"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop training, oversight practices, policies, and procedures to prevent the abuse, including physical abuse and sexual abuse, of any minor or amateur athlete by any adult.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB396C61B63524CABBC92889849EC682B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional duties</header><text>Section 220524 of such title is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA6C75FC910574BE49F4D5AA40B15E334"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC">In general</header-in-text>.—</quote> before <quote>For the sport</quote>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA51FE2B680243AB9ADFB4C513044AA0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H9BEDE88640064EB288A2154A59484F3D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking the period and inserting a semicolon; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1E8289C2CF2B421E80044DC63B39B727"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H830E98C857A2482FAD460AC8CBDACDCA" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H09E94641C308461FA8B606FAA9C7ED9C"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and enforce policies, mechanisms, and procedures to prevent the abuse, including physical abuse and sexual abuse, of any minor or amateur athlete, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8ECF61BACAC84F11BD1098EAD3D81E13"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requiring all adults authorized by a national governing body or a member of a national governing body to interact with a minor or amateur athlete at an amateur sports organization facility or at any event sanctioned by a national governing body or a member of a national governing body, to report facts that give reason to suspect child abuse, including sexual abuse, as required by relevant Federal or State law, to law enforcement authorities and other appropriate authorities, including an entity designated by the corporation to investigate and resolve such allegations;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56589F628FC64E81949F341FAE43C11C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing a mechanism, approved by a trained expert on child abuse, that allows an individual to easily report an incident of child abuse as described in subparagraph (A) to the national governing body or another authority, including an entity designated by the corporation;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBB29859584449209C1BF304D7838B56"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reasonable procedures designed to avoid one-on-one interactions between an amateur athlete who is a minor and an adult (who is not the minor’s legal guardian) at an amateur sports organization facility, at any event sanctioned by a national governing body, or any event sanctioned by a member of a national governing body, without being observable or interruptible by another adult, except where the safety and welfare of the minor requires;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9EB493F69A84D39838AD55527673006"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">oversight procedures, including regular and random audits, not to exceed once a year, conducted by subject matter experts unaffiliated with the national governing body, of all members and adults described in subparagraph (A) to ensure that policies and procedures developed under this paragraph are followed correctly and that consistent training is offered and given to all members regarding prevention of sexual abuse; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38BF10122EBA4ED987D3010D921069E4"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requiring dedicated information and resources, which may include sexual assault hotlines and victims’ support resources, to be clearly listed on the national governing body’s official website; and</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AF57813D27E4CBD8EFB422B92578DF4"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a national governing body with jurisdiction over more than one amateur sports organization facility or event, establish a mechanism by which—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H1AF11F9AC2E74422A72ECAE01170FC43"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the national governing body can—</text> <clause id="H49F48EA60C1748B08D00956FDD7F92DE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receive a report of suspected sexual misconduct by an adult authorized by a national governing body or a member of a national governing body to interact with a minor or amateur athlete at an amateur sports organization facility or at any event sanctioned by a national governing body or a member of a national governing body; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HB5774B29C9874479895EA0227815867A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>confidentially share a report received under clause (i) with each of the other amateur sports organizations, facilities, or members under the jurisdiction of the national governing body; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H00A08881211C4E45B8E10305F7052C36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an amateur sports organization, facility, or member under the jurisdiction of the national governing body can—</text>
 <clause id="H1F3607D593DE48AA934CA4FF2C91699B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>review the reports received by the national governing body under subparagraph (A)(i) to assess any allegations of sexual misconduct made in such reports; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H4F7441A9D4644AEC8FAA42649585B60D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>withhold providing to an adult who is the subject of an allegation of sexual misconduct in a report reviewed under clause (i) authority to interact with a minor or amateur athlete at such organization, facility, or event until the resolution of such allegation.</text>
								</clause></subparagraph></paragraph><subsection id="H1F4F954EB7B84C1FB34827EEF6799B62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limited liability for the United States Olympic Committee, national governing bodies, and an entity
			 designated by the United States Olympic Committee to investigate and
			 resolve sexual misconduct allegations</header>
 <paragraph id="H593BC39C49D045B8958C5F1D231714EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraphs (2), no civil or criminal action may be brought in any Federal or State court against the United States Olympic Committee, a national governing body, or an amateur sports organization, facility, or event under the jurisdiction of a national governing body, or an entity designated by the United States Olympic Committee to investigate and resolve sexual misconduct allegations described in subsection (a)(11), including any director, officer, employee, or agent of such entity, if the action arises from the execution of the responsibilities or functions described in subsection (a)(11).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H56128ADF70EB4975AF715F028C42D318"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Intentional, reckless, or other misconduct</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a civil or criminal action if the United States Olympic Committee, a national governing body, an amateur sports organization, facility, or event under the jurisdiction of a national governing body, or an entity designated by the United States Olympic Committee to investigate and resolve sexual misconduct allegations described in subsection (a)(11), or a director, officer, employee, or agent of such entity acted or failed to act—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HB517A065B5164663B253EB6B3F9305FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with reckless disregard for a risk of causing injury; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FE4CF8736994AA88970BC32329F0485"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for a purpose unrelated to the performance of any responsibility or function described in subsection (a)(11).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFC32A95BC034D1585060EF50CDE9F21"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limited effect</header><text>Nothing in this section shall apply to any act or omission arising out of any responsibility or function not described in subsection (a)(11).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB0BF55CA70F5492CBFA50CE6F069CFFE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Section 220522 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B5DF8D99B784D0099BE817C7139C755" style="USC"> <subsection id="H9E0D1A1EC1BA4EDB85B2277CC7AD15D9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in subsection (a) shall be construed to limit the ability of a national governing body to develop a policy or procedure to prevent an individual who is the subject of an allegation of sexual misconduct from interacting with a minor or amateur athlete until such time as the national governing body, or an entity with applicable jurisdiction resolves such allegation.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3A9D4595FFF64B4C99D31C87B61A0105"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Review of recognition of amateur sports organizations as national governing bodies</header><text>Section 220521(d) of title 36, United States Code, is<pagebreak></pagebreak> amended by striking <quote>may</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>shall</quote>.</text> </subsection></section></legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date chamber="House" date="20170525">Passed the House of Representatives May 25, 2017.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Karen L. Haas,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

