<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2CD18F003D9A467A879E36D2DC2E06F5" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3930 IH: Hurricane Harvey Small Business Recovery Grants Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-10-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3930</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20171003">October 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O'Rourke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000132">Mr. Vela</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000588">Mr. Richmond</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Al Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Eddie Bernice Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell of Alabama</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Office of Hurricane Harvey Small Business Recovery Grants in the Small Business
			 Administration to compensate certain small business concerns for
			 substantial economic injury suffered as a result of Hurricane Harvey in
			 August 2017.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HFEBC0044E0F54FF5ABE25D375FB044C2" style="OLC">
 <section id="H94BC9F3EF5524F39BC3BF0376FAC32E9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hurricane Harvey Small Business Recovery Grants Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H99458468A9584E74BC9CD2EDF36E1E5E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the following definitions apply:</text>
 <paragraph id="HB05E8AF2C992401D9C8CF080EE5A4CA7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Claim</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>claim</term> means a claim by an injured concern under this Act for payment for substantial economic injury suffered by the injured concern as a result of Hurricane Harvey.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H67679E29A5854C94A5521C6EBE6C1815"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Claimant</header><text>The term <term>claimant</term> means an injured concern that submits a claim under section 4(b).</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H38E0472EE72641AB8F22554ED273F787"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Small Business Administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H316BB1F67DF94156977E39EBB31E8CFA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Injured concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>injured concern</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HE8E73E66A9FA4C999E7A00230A8E956D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a small business concern that is located in an area that is a qualified disaster area as a result of Hurricane Harvey; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0339A51D37294900A9ADFC0AA57D6DED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text> <clause id="H1181DDD4007E4AB9B0376FA48BAEDE02"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a lender that holds a mortgage on or security interest in real or personal property affected by Hurricane Harvey; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="H9B11C25A4E9A4EC191BDB1D758332DB2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person that holds a lien on real or personal property affected by Hurricane Harvey.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EF998D30BCA417BBA3AAF608749142C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Office</header><text>The term <term>Office</term> means the Office of Hurricane Harvey Small Business Recovery Grants established by section 3.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="H16B492AA1932461AA56A2822D6C79D2D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Office of Hurricane Harvey Small Business Recovery Grants</header>
 <subsection id="H76D0C3706CB14C06A592E29F16E4D049"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established within the Small Business Administration an office to be known as the <quote>Office of Hurricane Harvey Small Business Recovery Grants</quote>.</text> </subsection><subsection id="H1FE9A5634DDC46289A37735EDF953D51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Office shall receive, process, and pay claims in accordance with section 4.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1B63387442C6497292986385471D4DD7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Office—</text> <paragraph id="HD7B7B98085A2469F8844A453ACE8055B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be funded from funds made available under this Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1B508C8C2DFC4131A36FE941F87DA02B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may reimburse any other Federal agency for provision of assistance in the receipt and processing of claims.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC8C6F037399C436E950628B0F6D741B2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Personnel</header>
 <paragraph id="H19EEB4FDEE0947F98DD55924C8EF12E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office may appoint and fix the compensation of such temporary personnel as are necessary to carry out the duties of the Office, without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC6E4507FF87943D7835F1F4D273A3DB9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Personnel from other agencies</header><text>On the request of the Administrator, the head of any other Federal agency may detail, on a reimbursable basis, any of the personnel of the agency to the Federal Emergency Management Agency to assist the Office in carrying out the duties of the Office under this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F2BEB4904EA415C86FD425BC7B3B067"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect on other SBA duties</header><text>The establishment of the Office shall not diminish the authority of, or funding available to, the Administrator to carry out the responsibilities of the Small Business Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H708427F7FAF4424C8452700B6756A986"><enum>4.</enum><header>Compensation for victims of Hurricane Harvey</header>
 <subsection id="H26D14706482C444882E71C87261DB621"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each injured concern may receive compensation for substantial economic injury suffered as a result of Hurricane Harvey, as determined by the Administrator.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H84BF40655EF64925AFFAB8DFE8720191"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission of claims</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which interim final regulations are promulgated under subsection (h), an injured concern may submit to the Administrator a written claim for compensation for substantial economic injury suffered as a result of Hurricane Harvey.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9CA7E40A265F463081A184D1FF0B9518"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Handling of claims</header><text>The Administrator shall investigate, adjust, grant, deny, settle, or compromise any claim submitted under subsection (b).</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HC12FC7A6DC0041F4B5317854DAC31692"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Amount of grant</header>
 <paragraph id="HACFFBA1CC84248C998961E29A2BFD99C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any grant made to an injured concern—</text> <subparagraph id="H9A5EB132958D49C69A45D4675B485823"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be limited to the amount necessary to compensate the injured concern for substantial economic injury described in paragraph (2) suffered as a result of Hurricane Harvey during the period beginning on August 25, 2017, and ending on August 25, 2018;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8C3047C561F4E7E96E68053FA458A8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not include—</text> <clause id="H0AB9A755F65944A0A6675370B1E1BDCD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>interest on the amount of the payment before the date of settlement or payment of a claim; or</text>
 </clause><clause id="HD8BC9E1E88AE4371A314352625F17BAB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>punitive damages or any other form of noncompensatory damages; and</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7FF04030D8E47778E2E780439822A05"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall not exceed $100,000, except in the case of a grant application for which the Administrator determines that a greater amount up to $250,000 is appropriate.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EF508ACA9A34DEC8E2981228D01C38A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Substantial economic injury</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under paragraph (1), an injured concern may receive payment for substantial economic injury consisting of one or more of the following:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8B7A04919F1244D3A9137F2757C63919"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An uninsured or underinsured property loss.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10D598B140664195AC5E342A0809794E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Damage to or destruction of physical infrastructure.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5555A8E77E145B5BF3BC0023283D8B5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Damage to or destruction of tangible assets or inventory.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB83DADDDB1B47EB8B348682DBEDB73C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A business interruption loss.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1574D5F1D5674900851020C8149AD19F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Overhead costs.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9789C117C1F84AA9B589E6CA92485ED9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Employee wages for work not performed.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B69563BBBC64DD7A58D0FDDE091255C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>An insurance deductible.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H467082B86E0E4C9E95C23DC235EF4FA3"><enum>(H)</enum><text>A temporary relocation expense.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AFD924FE0F0494BB6E9E8EAA7F8BEA8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Debris removal and other cleanup costs.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55387A38C6B54FB9B5D2BDE281A41A8D"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other type of substantial economic injury that the Administrator determines to be appropriate.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3F9FFC06F3F4E65A36B5731A89A2EA7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header>
 <subparagraph id="HA75B6B6D22264C17A207FAB7730AF524"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A claimant shall have the burden of demonstrating substantial economic injury.</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3263612D9C7B412F8BB5EBFA5E288E8B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Absence of documents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If documentary evidence substantiating substantial economic injury is not reasonably available, the Administrator may pay a claim based on an affidavit or other documentation executed by the claimant.</text>
					</subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE63B02E76822428AA2DDD8AD786F97F3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Payment of claims</header>
				<paragraph id="H6F4ECE6B66F44AF88FC78C4E28A8A81E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination and payment of amount</header>
 <subparagraph id="H2E8A46117DE94EF9B9A6551EEBC65173"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, not later than 180 days after the date on which a claim is submitted under subsection (b), the Administrator shall—</text>
 <clause id="HEAE9548FF4C84540886C6A1DA843575D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determine the amount, if any, to be paid for the claim; and</text> </clause><clause id="H13DD37BB13A448358FA6133477E42789"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>pay the amount.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78E90FDB114646F98122A2698D85EB5D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Administrator may establish priorities for processing and paying claims based on—</text> <clause id="HFAA5C0546C354E9795906E01D6AFFD23"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an assessment of the needs of the claimants; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="H72128A5FDA104437BA27DD3487BE2880"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other criteria that the Administrator determines to be appropriate.</text> </clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9916732E8A0248968D8F82B3ED48E410"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Parameters of determination</header><text>In determining and paying a claim, the Administrator shall determine only—</text>
 <clause id="H7EB01608406A4687B71EBA92F1D6A99B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether the claimant is an injured concern; and</text> </clause><clause id="H080F37E915CB4588A54585D1722AC286"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the injuries that are the subject of the claim resulted from Hurricane Harvey.</text>
						</clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57148A85A61D4D8C80BE96A8CD3848E9"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Insurance and other benefits</header>
 <clause id="H8D4050F8F0F042D683635FEEA32FC9E9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), to prevent recovery by a claimant in excess of the equivalent of actual amount of the substantial economic injury suffered by the claimant in accordance with subsection (d), the Administrator shall reduce the amount to be paid for the claim by an amount that is equal to the sum of the payments or settlements of any kind that were paid, or will be paid, with respect to the claim, including payments by an insurance company.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H33DA9C2566244885823B853CD4D91744"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Government loans</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply to the receipt by a claimant of any Federal, State, or local government loan that is required to be repaid by the claimant.</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2629E8F60F06407A9768D8BA8CB438A0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advance or partial payments</header><text>At the request of a claimant, the Administrator may make one or more advance or partial payments before the final approval of a grant.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75A83853B8EA4C808E9F55223008E0E7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Recovery of funds improperly paid or misused</header><text>The Administrator may recover any portion of a payment on a grant that was improperly paid to the claimant as a result of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEE380D97CAF64170AF320EDB9E4B1EF0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>fraud or misrepresentation on the part of the claimant or a representative of the claimant;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H42DD13F3D2B343BA82E09BAA37F7FEB0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a material mistake on the part of the Administrator;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7C81DD9AB0B84DEF95BB2A0A536C84B3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the payment of insurance or benefits described in subsection (e)(1)(D) that were not taken into account in determining the amount of the payment; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H04DF0BCBA61846B79AF5187107F2B09F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the failure of the claimant to cooperate in an audit.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCEEDDA9C6C5F4781A684F052CBE8F143"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Appeals of decisions</header> <paragraph id="H3AC1E28AB5A6468184C302161EF3A460"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Right of appeal</header><text>A claimant may appeal a decision concerning payment of a claim by filing, not later than 60 days after the date on which the claimant is notified that the claim of the claimant will or will not be paid, a notice of appeal in the case of a decision on a claim relating to a business loss, with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Administration.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H702CC49D8617433E93575F27BB49EC13"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period for decision</header><text>A decision concerning an appeal under paragraph (1) shall be rendered not later than 90 days after the date on which the notice of appeal is received.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9208F259564D4DB4A23B5A9464407D6A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, not later than 45 days after the date of enactment of this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="H4E6D5654222A423198560E7CCDE4E69A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Administrator shall promulgate and publish in the Federal Register interim final regulations for the processing and payment of claims; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9975FD73799841A98028EF481640C613"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Administrator and the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall jointly promulgate and publish in the Federal Register procedures under which a dispute concerning payment of a claim may be settled through an appeals process described in subsection (g).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1B94ACC1184C43D7BC3B5D436DC04A99"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Public information</header><text>At the time of publication of interim final regulations under subsection (h), the Administrator shall publish a clear, concise, and easily understandable explanation of the grant program established under this Act the procedural and other requirements of the regulations promulgated under subsection (h). Such explanation shall be—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE3B9CD7B55E64D4A8A1AFDBCC40FA53C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>disseminated through brochures, pamphlets, radio, television, the print news media, and such other media as the Administrator determines to be likely to reach prospective claimants; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4CC9D8965B73422D882EAACD54E52D2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provided in English, Spanish, and any other language that the Administrator determines to be appropriate.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA050425097C4A14B1FB46872F1D410A"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Administrator shall coordinate with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, other Federal, State and local agencies, and any other individual or entity, as the Administrator determines to be necessary to ensure the efficient administration of the claims process.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H6C7ADF0197BF49A7AB077C581426A348"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Applicability of debt collection requirements</header>
 <paragraph id="HE62EB1B116DB484D937C55E2B6D6A639"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3716 of title 31, United States Code, shall not preclude any payment on a claim.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0E630EEE8E0341249712F885E9867EDD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assignment and exemption from claims of creditors</header> <subparagraph id="H761D2E893DF04762AE857C7045D9350A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Assignment</header><text>No assignment, release, or commutation of a payment due or payable under this Act shall be valid.</text>
					</subparagraph><subparagraph id="H075F351444734AAE86081DD9745CD2D6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exemption</header>
 <clause id="HD13753300AC0449680DD37C47AC2AADC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A payment under this Act shall be exempt from all claims of creditors and from levy, execution, attachment, or other remedy for recovery or collection of a debt.</text>
 </clause><clause id="H27D9BA8BD51248FBB3BBC81C882E801D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Nonwaivable exemption</header><text>The exemption provided by clause (i) may not be waived.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H566091FFC1BD4E199F81958C1D38A44F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reports and audits</header> <subsection id="H76D6A363E0FB4649A381693878E635D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of promulgation of interim final regulations under section 4(h) and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report that describes the claims submitted under section 4(b) during the year preceding the date of submission of the report, including, with respect to each claim—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7AFCA537805C47AD80A3A760F3657463"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the amount claimed;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H100DEAF9F4BF42B08BED80E244F58DB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a brief description of the nature of the claim; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H03BF62B6A21E401F8A9D3698A57FC1A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the status or disposition of the claim, including the amount of any payment on the claim.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA09E79311AC43B0BA0A6131F7370ECD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Audits</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC160E828A7174F6AB870BFA5E0EF3380"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct an annual audit of the payment of all claims submitted under section 4(b); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0C41ACFC4A1C472BA6C4F1C9C98336A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 120 days after the date on which the Administrator submits the initial report required by subsection (a) and annually thereafter, submit to Congress a report on the results of the audit.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6A9190123B3F4D88B5FF96286A22417B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
 <subsection id="HC9CAA58FA2374C328AE9C66C51F02E5F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act—</text> <paragraph id="HE7724D2ECCB4452D841B9402D783F9C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the Office of Business Recovery Grants established under section 3 to administer the claims process, $25,000,000; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H72B5FD31C29845D89D1E2D3F94B16D6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for payment of claims, $975,000,000.</text> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFFC054E2839940AF88184C79BCF0EEA5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts made available under subsection (a) shall remain available until expended.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HAB785E56B26F4423A1228248E4E40B76"><enum>7.</enum><header>Termination of authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The authority provided by this Act terminates effective 30 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
		</section></legis-body></bill>


