<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="HC61AE81DD7694F1FB59DCC46A4786212" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 2327 IH: Puppies Assisting Wounded Servicemembers Act of 2017</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2327</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170503">May 3, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000621">Mr. DeSantis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001289">Mr. Byrne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000625">Mr. Donovan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001036">Mr. Hensarling</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001073">Mr. Hurd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000255">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000554">Mr. LoBiondo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000598">Mr. Polis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000583">Mr. Thomas J. Rooney of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001191">Ms. Sinema</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000017">Mr. Zeldin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Jody B. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000387">Mr. Knight</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000213">Mr. Barton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000448">Mr. Franks of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000582">Miss González-Colón of Puerto Rico</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000410">Mr. Gene Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001107">Mr. Curbelo of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000487">Mr. Royce of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000592">Mr. Poe of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000170">Mr. O'Rourke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000475">Mr. Trott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001290">Mr. Brat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001105">Mrs. Comstock</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000819">Mr. Walker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make grants to eligible organizations to provide
			 service dogs to veterans with severe post-traumatic stress disorder, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H255FC2D705A34905A47EC4040A411156" style="OLC">
 <section id="H9A55E6A03B2D4C46B890684F44CD920B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Puppies Assisting Wounded Servicemembers Act of 2017</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PAWS Act of 2017</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="H8D3C35E2CE1D470AB2D1EF9BFCBEF249" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text>
 <paragraph id="H394D2B1E289A43EBBF204EA3B4AC245D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the analysis of veteran suicide published by the Department of Veterans Affairs in August 2016 and titled <quote>Suicide Among Veterans and Other Americans</quote>—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H74BC6E61C7774A5FA2C13B9071600EE0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an average of 20 veterans died by suicide each day in 2014;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB31206260724ABF8065C3CDD8B6241A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mental health disorders, including major depression and other mood disorders, have been associated with increased risk for suicide;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AC42698684E4D6094C40C61A2619EE6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">since 2001, the proportion of users of the Veterans Health Administration with mental health conditions or substance use disorders has increased from approximately 27 percent in 2001 to more than 40 percent in 2014; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4513D971C57E46DCA4828A64E109F994"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">overall, suicide rates are highest among patients with mental health and substance use disorder diagnoses who are in treatment and lower among those who received a mental health diagnoses but were not at risk enough to require enhanced care from a mental health provider.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DB6BC4DB54A495B802743983A94CAEA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Veterans Affairs must be more effective in its approach to reducing the burden of veteran suicide connected to mental health disorders, including post-traumatic stress disorder, and a pilot program and study to assess the benefits of pairing service dogs with veterans suffering from mental health disorders would allow the Department to better determine the efficacy of using service dogs as a nontraditional therapy to ensure the well-being of veterans.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H251CC2E434844B928A5B86806F04241A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pairing a service dog with a veteran costs approximately $25,000, including with respect to training of the service dog as well as training of the veteran with the service dog.</text>
			</paragraph></section><section id="HFDB24D5A092D4EEDA64CA613B87AF934"><enum>3.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs pilot program to provide grants for the provision of service dogs to
			 certain veterans with severe post-traumatic stress disorder</header>
 <subsection id="H16FB41B01BAA4DD1AE8F488C47CAA370"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a pilot program under which the Secretary provides a $25,000 grant to an eligible organization for each veteran referred to that organization for a service dog pairing.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="HB3F71EBBC90D4ABABAE60DE5A1553C5F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Benefits provided</header>
 <paragraph id="H8B645F80674845BDA2E7A1603D1CC11D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An organization that receives a grant under subsection (a) shall provide the following for each service dog and veteran participating in the pilot program:</text>
 <subparagraph id="H0675E1E4FFB34AE7ABBB144657C3ED73"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Coverage of a commercially available veterinary health insurance policy to maintain the health of the dog and keep the dog functioning in the prescribed role for the life of the dog.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC90EE12E7FA4CF39A6678599BC136AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Hardware, or repairs or replacements for hardware, that are clinically determined to be required by the dog to perform the tasks necessary to assist the veteran with the diagnosed disorder of the veteran.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2532BD62EDE3445B85F6A5D438614724"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Payments for travel expenses for the veteran to obtain the dog, calculated in the same manner as similar travel expenses provided pursuant to section 111 of title 38, United States Code.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FA2F38FAF764281B69D768E376FFD35"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other travel expenses</header><text>If a veteran is required to replace a service dog provided pursuant to a grant under this section, the Secretary shall pay for the travel expenses described in paragraph (1)(C) required to obtain a new service dog pursuant to subsection (c)(3), regardless of any other benefits the veteran is receiving for the first service dog under this section.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A312174C9DA424A97AC10E6605A5AFC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible organizations</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an organization shall—</text> <paragraph id="H2ADBBDF15FD84B33BAECEB001FEC660D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be a nonprofit organization that provides trained service dogs—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HFACD884030964EFBAD13306FC9A5069D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that—</text> <clause id="HE109112CA8094A3E9C8E514A8ACBBBA8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is certified by Assistance Dogs International;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H42AA7F0A4A594FECB9B417132032215C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on average, provides one-on-one training for each service dog and recipient for 30 hours or more over 90 days or more;</text>
 </clause><clause id="HFF9694D68DCA4DF9A3AD6A92183063C9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provides a wellness verification from a licensed veterinarian for each service dog;</text> </clause><clause id="H9457766DDDFE436883F7E19593016356"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>provides an in-house residential facility, or other accommodations nearby, in which service dog recipients stay for a minimum of 10 days while receiving at least 30 hours of training with their new service dog;</text>
 </clause><clause id="H369769F993134A65871A533ACD754B64"><enum>(v)</enum><text>ensures all service dogs pass the American Kennel Club Community Canine test and the ADI Public Access Test prior to permanent placement with a recipient; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HAD03CB0CC6ED43F492951BE966645CB5"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>provides follow-up support service for the life of the service dog, to include a contact plan between the veteran and organization to allow—</text>
 <subclause id="HE9F2941E9D1846C69BC7078DF7CA2DA0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the veteran to reach out for and receive adequate help with the service dog; and</text> </subclause><subclause id="H132FE8D06D1E4D3F8B3272B15E67D171"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the organization to communicate with the veteran to ensure that the service dog is being properly cared for; or</text>
 </subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CF6EEA23A774E4CBA2C3E7859883B6F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that meets the Association of Service Dog Providers for Military Veterans Service Dog Agency Standards that cater to the unique needs of veterans with post-traumatic stress disorder;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5282ACCBF8574C679C1756D8B238AFE8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>agree to cover all costs in excess of the grant amount to guarantee the benefits listed under subsection (b)(1);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H91081F997FD646D8AB58FA13BC024F66"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agree to reaccept or replace the service dog the organization provided to the veteran, if necessary, as determined by the organization and the veteran; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9FB29760463B4108993380328E95844F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary an application containing such information, certification, and assurances as the Secretary may require.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H05C507557AC948AB9A843291C0C8D553"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible veterans</header>
 <paragraph id="H9B4AD38241AE4E5189936B78CA05417B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall review and approve veterans eligible to participate under this section and shall refer approved veterans to eligible organizations. The period beginning on the date on which a veteran applies to participate under this section and the date on which the Secretary makes an approval determination may not exceed 90 days.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H725011D81EB94F6E8F8C7C8523141EDE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial eligibility</header><text>For purposes of this section, an eligible veteran is a veteran who is enrolled in the patient enrollment system of the Department of Veterans Affairs under section 1705 of title 38, United States Code, and—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H00B11340B61346D285FFD00CD9514AC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has been treated and has completed an established evidence-based treatment for post-traumatic stress disorder yet remains diagnosed with post-traumatic stress disorder by a qualified health care provider as rated on the post-traumatic stress disorder checklist (PCL–5);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H040A57B25BF24AD9B2A65BE862FEBEF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the health care provider or clinical team of the Department of Veterans Affairs that is treating the veteran for such disorder determines based upon medical judgment that the veteran may potentially benefit from a service dog; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6062E01D2CF456CB4E446D96A6C6AE5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>agrees to successfully complete training provided by an eligible organization pursuant to subsection (c).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H14AF8843A397459897B2BE9D3581AE43"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ongoing eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To remain eligible to participate in the pilot program, a veteran shall see the health care provider or clinical team of the Department of Veterans Affairs treating the veteran for such a disorder at least every six months to determine, based on a clinical evaluation of efficacy, whether the veteran continues to benefit from a service dog.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF1CC0110266848A1955BE21ED002B300"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Other cases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If at any point, the veteran is no longer able or willing to care for the service dog, the organization that provided the service dog and the veteran shall determine the appropriate recourse to ensure the safety of both the veteran and the service dog.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H46EF9E97B1CD4DAC9E1ABE29EA9D3B3B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Relationship to Department of Veterans Affairs benefits</header><text>The provision of a service dog to a veteran under this section is in addition to any other hospital care or medical service furnished by the Department for that veteran for post-traumatic stress disorder, and an improvement in symptoms as a result of the provision of a service dog shall not affect the eligibility of the veteran for any other benefit under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H939A5F5B21F541FAA6D869E02558E4BD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Metrics</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H1162101303754857A33A41E2EB04E8F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop metrics and other appropriate means to measure, with respect to veterans participating in the pilot program, the improvement in psychosocial function and therapeutic compliance of such veterans and changes with respect to the dependence on prescription narcotics and psychotropic medication of such veterans; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF09B8C89919B46DBBE91215CA24D358F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish processes to document and track the progress of such veterans under the pilot program in terms of the benefits and improvements noted as a result of the pilot program.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H953346664488431BB41CBBE8224B0400"><enum>(g)</enum><header>GAO briefing and study</header>
 <paragraph id="H3C4F9A62AF1449CE98C1BD4A509A366C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date on which the Secretary commences the pilot program under subsection (a), the Comptroller General of the United States shall provide to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a briefing on the methodology established for the pilot program.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HD4E5EFF6D19E4376A8C46452AB47E6A0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date on which the pilot program terminates, the Comptroller General shall submit to the committees specified in paragraph (1) a report on the pilot program. Such report shall include an evaluation of the approach and methodology used for the pilot program with respect to—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H5F7D660CBC464F599D2A07791A726950"><enum>(A)</enum><text>helping veterans with severe post-traumatic stress disorder return to civilian life;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4989AE7C21949D4B43CD7970F954884"><enum>(B)</enum><text>relevant metrics, including reduction in metrics such as reduction in scores under the post-traumatic stress disorder checklist (PCL–5), improvement in psychosocial function, and therapeutic compliance; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDA656D1504D4D9E99895B3C6547740B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reducing the dependence of participants on prescription narcotics and psychotropic medication.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB3D0B9DAEC83471FB946851FF4D4D9FC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated for the period of fiscal year 2018 through fiscal year 2023, $10,000,000 to carry out the pilot program under this section.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H0BCCDCABB17A4850B3DEB911B3FCC22D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Offset</header><text>The amounts otherwise authorized to be appropriated for Department of Veterans Affairs Office of Human Resources and Administration for the period of fiscal year 2018 through fiscal year 2023 shall be reduced by $10,000,000.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H9C0DCA38D33C4EECAD8C27FD59567B3A"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The authority to carry out a pilot program under this section shall terminate on the date that is five years after the date of the enactment of this Act. An eligible veteran in possession of a service dog furnished under the pilot program as of the termination of the pilot program may keep the service dog after the termination of the program for the life of the dog.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


