<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H2C13A036A745467B89895BAA62B1139B" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 1408 IH: Access to Insurance for All Americans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1408</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170307">March 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and the Workforce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Appropriations</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
			 provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To repeal the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act and the health care-related provisions in
			 the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 and to amend
			 title 5, United States Code, to offer Federal employee health benefits
			 plans to individuals who are not Federal employees, and for other
			 purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="H8F392229E2B341558BFFACF9EAD511E9" style="OLC">
 <section id="HC89034047FD8451A83EF9F0ECE2D25D0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Access to Insurance for All Americans Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section id="HFC1DD08B353543CAA059307E5040BC4B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Repeal of PPACA and health care-related provisions of HCERA</header> <subsection id="HE2F3FDE225364E20B8DE24A889F417AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>PPACA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective beginning with the first calendar year beginning 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>) is repealed and the provisions of law amended or repealed by such Act are restored or revived as if such Act had not been enacted.</text>
			</subsection><subsection id="H727D89A3FD05426A8857BE6482160D82"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Health care-Related provisions of HCERA</header>
 <paragraph id="HF499BA9DC90147F1B4E7A73CB94E4E14"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective beginning with the first calendar year beginning 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the health care-related provisions of the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/152">Public Law 111–152</external-xref>) are repealed and the provisions of law amended or repealed by such health care-related provisions are restored or revived as if such provisions had not been enacted.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H654A87F46D154A68866B4E0185582104"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Health care-related provisions defined</header><text>In paragraph (1), the term <term>health care-related provisions</term> means, with respect to the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010, title I and subtitle B of title II of such Act.</text>
				</paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5DD3EBCC1DBF4D05A1F457D8FDD9828D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Extension and modification of Federal employee health insurance</header>
			<subsection id="HBF898435205B407083D1C4BD0B95EEA0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>FEHBP</header>
 <paragraph id="HD550C79240AA4CCBA3DE016B7501AEF9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">Chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDFF1968B8C4646A2908D5168DFB9D72D" style="USC"> <section id="H2921C3318D28457AB28D89B20CCC8CCA"><enum>8915.</enum><header>Health insurance for individuals who are not Federal employees</header> <subsection id="H534DAD18E153444C900AE8A381160C87"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in this section, any individual may enroll in a health benefits plan provided under this chapter and receive health benefits, to the greatest extent practicable, in the same manner as an employee.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8B23DE156CD444F9A5B49FB32D44989D"><enum>(b)</enum><text>An individual may not enroll in a health benefits plan under this section if the individual—</text> <paragraph id="H5ED1868E8C354DA38B1960BB6A8DBDDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is enrolled or eligible to enroll for coverage under a public health insurance program, including—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H8FA7D9674BE14F6A80EB0AC2BA0DB1B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>title XVIII of the Social Security Act;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFD22C7F49E44DDA80EE74717841A91C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6007E779E61424FA692105A949E1D3C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a State plan under title XXI of the Social Security Act; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CA14C4D72F84381BC553D0D7D1B2932"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other program determined by the Office;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H01DF06502D8841A388D1CE63E6A45736"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is a member of the uniformed services as defined under section 101(a)(5) of title 10; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2D117FF74A5B4058BCA52329CD67D5A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is not a citizen or national of the United States or an alien lawfully present in the United States.</text>
								</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4A0DB02E400D40579D11420E5B23379B"><enum>(c)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAC2BEB585953435A846893A6ACFDB7A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Government contribution may be made for any individual enrolled in a health benefits plan pursuant to this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDFE85DB30A6A406591775496B2850476" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to regulations that the Office of Personnel Management may prescribe, an employer of an individual enrolled in such a plan may make a contribution on behalf of the individual.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEA47A6F9484D4AE2B24B55848827ABCD"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Office shall ensure that individuals enrolled in a health benefits plan under this section shall be in the same risk pool maintained for employees covered by this chapter.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HC7F17968574945E29A0328A4693A68BB"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office shall issue regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.</text> </subsection></section><section id="HB45AC1390F5643368987A127D8D73D96"><enum>8916.</enum><header>No lifetime or annual limits</header> <subsection id="H9A49866575AD48E294C4E480026F94C4"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A carrier offering a health benefits plan under this chapter may not establish—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7E457CD6FB444F17BD1CD4BA5A82B3C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">lifetime limits on the dollar value of benefits for any individual enrolled in such plan; or</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H051835D5748345FF98B8797CD50AF694"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">unreasonable annual limits (within the meaning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">section 223</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) on the dollar value of benefits for any such individual.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B8E6DFA912348D2AC69B6286125B8BC"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall not be construed to prevent a health benefits plan under this chapter from placing annual or lifetime per beneficiary limits on specific covered benefits to the extent that such limits are otherwise permitted under Federal or State law.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H991BF7F9963E4982B0E7964FAFB21A5D"><enum>8917.</enum><header>Non-discrimination in health care</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A carrier offering a health benefits plan under this chapter may not discriminate with respect to participation under the plan or coverage against any health care provider who is acting within the scope of that provider’s license or certification under applicable State law. This section shall not require that a health benefits plan or carrier contract with any health care provider willing to abide by the terms and conditions for participation established by the plan or issuer. Nothing in this section shall be construed as preventing a health benefits plan, a carrier, or the Director of the Office of Personnel Management from establishing varying reimbursement rates based on quality or performance measures.</text>
						</section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H426248D93AF74BF1B6A27A8897318B03"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Child under the age of 26</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8901(5) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>22</quote> in each instance it appears and inserting <quote>26</quote>.</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H449C76A1A6EB4CC9874E15F0E1A99965"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Sections 8916 and 8917 of such title (as added by paragraph (1)) shall begin to apply to any contract for health benefits plans entered into by the Office of Personnel Management under chapter 89 of such title after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4F88362D64C8431D85AC3F58BF7B3DDF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/8914">section 8914</external-xref> the following new items:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67BE8EB977294894B270F4641CDA2DA4" style="USC">
						<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
							<toc-entry level="section">8915. Health insurance for individuals who are not Federal employees.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry level="section">8616. No lifetime or annual limits.</toc-entry>
							<toc-entry level="section">8917. Non-discrimination in health care.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
				</paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE99C99CE1444A6192E251182D0A1346"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Dental and vision benefits</header>
 <paragraph id="HD53BE65E513A45F19218A3008D75F23D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Dental</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8952 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H25B22AB916B744BB94080DE67795ABCF" style="USC"> <subsection id="HF318D61941BB4FBDBFB28BFF781710D7"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office shall issue regulations necessary to enroll individuals described in section 8915 in dental benefits plan offered under this chapter, consistent with the requirements of such section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H8009E0DCAFAC4B42BCD1F6C8D715D1D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vision</header><text>Section 8982 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59737A1D5DF34C1DAFD20CA39979C805" style="USC"> <subsection id="H3BE5F950205B4D03A961CD3FC876CADB"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office shall issue regulations necessary to enroll individuals described in section 8915 in vision benefits plan offered under this chapter, consistent with the requirements of such section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7E023059757A4951A809B1B6F42CC441"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special enrollment period for Federal employees and uninsured individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall issue regulations to provide for a special enrollment period, to begin on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the date that is 180 after such date of enactment or the last day of the calendar year in which such date of enactment occurs, whichever is later, under which the following individuals may enroll in a health benefits plan under chapter 89, 89A, or 89B of title 5, United States Code:</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H858EFCDE8238452BBBD9A18D0239A6B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any employee (as that term is defined in section 8901(1) of such title) who is not enrolled in a health benefits plan under any such chapter but who is otherwise eligible to enroll in such a plan, including any employee excluded by section 1312(d)(3)(D) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2FA9894C68604F40B2C600F5B8D1AA16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any individual not covered by paragraph (1) and who is not covered by any health insurance, as determined by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4FF2AE75B9B34FC2B7A18F85ED97DEAF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enrollment of insured individuals who are not Federal employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For plan years beginning in the year immediately following the year in which this subsection is enacted, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall issue regulations to provide for the enrollment of individuals (as described under section 8915 of title 5, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)) in health benefits plans under chapter 89, 89A, or 89B of such title.</text>
			</subsection></section><section id="H8F8F9FF3B7C24CCC80850910F392DBFE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Deduction for premiums paid by FEHBP non-employee enrollees</header>
 <subsection id="H44B199CFE33E4B919BD98C3AC2A55FA1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part VII of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to additional itemized deductions) is amended—</text>
 <paragraph id="HA0FE42ACF5D740119A68DD88C7A91D2E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 224 as section 225; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H85811D4875984A96B470D3CFE5DB26C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 223 the following new section:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H084B1688DA88418784B80FCF7B53E4B8" style="OLC">
						<section commented="no" id="HC14CBF69B58F4F0D947FC06F5F63A814"><enum>224.</enum><header>Premiums paid for FEHBP coverage</header>
 <subsection commented="no" id="H1105252040BA482E9DFBCA4EE18E7510"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual, there shall be allowed as a deduction an amount equal to the amount paid as premiums during the taxable year for coverage for the taxpayer, the spouse of the taxpayer, and dependents under health insurance provided pursuant to section 8915 title 5, United States Code.</text>
							</subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H5398A8A15A984AAF8FD85B0B2F865DAE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special rules</header>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H2F8DC6360A644434842E01B672D7CFAC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coordination with medical deduction, etc</header><text>Any amount paid by a taxpayer for insurance to which subsection (a) applies shall not be taken into account in computing the amount allowable to the taxpayer as a deduction under section 162(l) or 213(a). Any amount taken into account in determining the credit allowed under section 35 shall not be taken into account for purposes of this section.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA63FFD2330EC4338B37BB855291074C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deduction not allowed for self-employment tax purposes</header><text>The deduction allowable by reason of this section shall not be taken into account in determining an individual’s net earnings from self-employment (within the meaning of section 1402(a)) for purposes of chapter 2.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB937F2CE689B4FEDA84C17F046DC984D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deduction allowed in computing adjusted gross income</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 62 of such Code is amended by inserting before the last sentence the following new paragraph:</text>
				<quoted-block id="H9FBBE979D2AB48B4A0601CC8D7E5809B">
 <paragraph id="H1782BD3E70D94BB59F83A9E32A34C8AE"><enum>(22)</enum><header>Premiums paid for FEHBP coverage</header><text>The deduction allowed by section 224.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection><subsection id="H4711B2B3DEE54DFB9A29A93F42A8F373"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for part VII of subchapter B of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by—</text>
 <paragraph id="HEF23C2C9D1DC4E85B712FC490D4976D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>redesignating the item relating to section 224 as an item relating to section 225; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H008EEC45344C45DD8156FFD72BAF8B23"><enum>(2)</enum><text>inserting before such item the following new item:</text>
					<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A6319A2DCF3420593716C43A08EDA01" style="OLC">
						<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="H084B1688DA88418784B80FCF7B53E4B8" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
							<toc-entry idref="HC14CBF69B58F4F0D947FC06F5F63A814" level="section">Sec. 224. Premiums paid for FEHBP coverage.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H764EAFC607A8431CA5C21CA49496D85B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years ending after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HF66EB78A6002407F8F8BDDBF2172A9A5"><enum>5.</enum><header>Plan for extension of Federal employee health benefits program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act and after consultation with appropriate experts, representatives of affected individuals, and Federal officers, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall submit a comprehensive plan to Congress that—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H797CDB35B7CA486EBEEBDB4890D7270F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provides for the orderly implementation of the amendments made by this Act; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H95AF1C83598B439EB06ED936CF9608F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes a schedule of actions to be taken to provide for that implementation.</text>
			</paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


