<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H375C0F8984234EC3BC8CEFD4BC873B53" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3066 IH: To direct the Secretary of Defense to carry out a program to protect United States students against foreign agents.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3066</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170627">June 27, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001170">Ms. Shea-Porter</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Permanent Select Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to carry out a program to protect United States students against foreign agents.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H12A1BAC834304B7EB555932A56F7C403" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6BCF2A9FF17C4333B88481975FD702DD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Department of Defense program to protect United States students against foreign agents</header> 
<subsection id="HCEEC6A71CC0C4539BAF4ACC578E67B73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall develop and implement a program to prepare United States students studying abroad through Department of Defense National Security Education Programs to recognize and protect themselves against recruitment efforts by intelligence agents.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H49A32F386542443C9352A809B46087FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall provide to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a briefing on the program required under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

