<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="traditional" dms-id="HC66D6D9A91A7455FA292197F02B95543" key="H" public-private="public">
	<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 3267 RH: Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 2018</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
		<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
		<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 164</calendar>
		<congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress>
		<session display="yes">1st Session</session>
		<legis-num>H. R. 3267</legis-num>
		<associated-doc display="yes" role="report">[Report No. 115–231]</associated-doc>
		<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
		<action>
			<action-date>July 17, 2017</action-date>
			<action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000523">Mr. Culberson</sponsor>, from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSAP00" deleted-display-style="bold-brackets">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name>, reported the following bill; which was committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State
			 of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
		</action>
		<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
		<official-title>Making appropriations for the Departments of Commerce and Justice, Science, and Related Agencies
			 for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018, and for other purposes.</official-title>
	</form>
	<legis-body id="H2534C708B454454F9FA3528CEDBF664B" style="appropriations">
 <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H45B7384833E443E88059B48E80F6CD33" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the following sums are appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2018, and for other purposes, namely:</text>
		</section><title commented="no" id="H0D088F9FA5F64CE0BEC7BCC881D72965" level-type="subsequent"><enum>I</enum>
			<appropriations-major commented="no" id="HB669226D07F042378B3BB2524F13756A"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Department of Commerce</header>
			</appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="HAE09927065824D53B22A2EA080BA1B26"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">International Trade Administration</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HD517E448F3A040C1A53736759FEC906E"><header>Operations and administration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses for international trade activities of the Department of Commerce provided for by law, and for engaging in trade promotional activities abroad, including expenses of grants and cooperative agreements for the purpose of promoting exports of United States firms, without regard to sections 3702 and 3703 of title 44, United States Code; full medical coverage for dependent members of immediate families of employees stationed overseas and employees temporarily posted overseas; travel and transportation of employees of the International Trade Administration between two points abroad, without regard to section 40118 of title 49, United States Code; employment of citizens of the United States and aliens by contract for services; rental of space abroad for periods not exceeding 10 years, and expenses of alteration, repair, or improvement; purchase or construction of temporary demountable exhibition structures for use abroad; payment of tort claims, in the manner authorized in the first paragraph of section 2672 of title 28, United States Code, when such claims arise in foreign countries; not to exceed $294,300 for official representation expenses abroad; purchase of passenger motor vehicles for official use abroad, not to exceed $45,000 per vehicle; obtaining insurance on official motor vehicles; and rental of tie lines, $480,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019, of which $13,000,000 is to be derived from fees to be retained and used by the International Trade Administration, notwithstanding section 3302 of title 31, United States Code: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That, of amounts provided under this heading, not less than $16,400,000 shall be for China antidumping and countervailing duty enforcement and compliance activities: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the provisions of the first sentence of section 105(f) and all of section 108(c) of the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2455">22 U.S.C. 2455(f)</external-xref> and 2458(c)) shall apply in carrying out these activities; and that for the purpose of this Act, contributions under the provisions of the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 shall include payment for assessments for services provided as part of these activities.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="HEA48FBDA7A054BDFBC28F89FF92AC979"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Bureau of Industry and Security</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H62250A758B0E4677A7D0950D915FD2B9"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Operations and Administration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses for export administration and national security activities of the Department of Commerce, including costs associated with the performance of export administration field activities both domestically and abroad; full medical coverage for dependent members of immediate families of employees stationed overseas; employment of citizens of the United States and aliens by contract for services abroad; payment of tort claims, in the manner authorized in the first paragraph of section 2672 of title 28, United States Code, when such claims arise in foreign countries; not to exceed $13,500 for official representation expenses abroad; awards of compensation to informers under the Export Administration Act of 1979, and as authorized by section 1(b) of the Act of June 15, 1917 (40 Stat. 223; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/401">22 U.S.C. 401(b)</external-xref>); and purchase of passenger motor vehicles for official use and motor vehicles for law enforcement use with special requirement vehicles eligible for purchase without regard to any price limitation otherwise established by law, $112,500,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the provisions of the first sentence of section 105(f) and all of section 108(c) of the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2455">22 U.S.C. 2455(f)</external-xref> and 2458(c)) shall apply in carrying out these activities: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That payments and contributions collected and accepted for materials or services provided as part of such activities may be retained for use in covering the cost of such activities, and for providing information to the public with respect to the export administration and national security activities of the Department of Commerce and other export control programs of the United States and other governments.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="H66A8D1E2230A49A4A3A5CF3FA0DFD51C"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Economic development administration</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HDC0101156B3840F5945856BBAA12667C"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Economic development assistance programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For grants for economic development assistance as provided by the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965, for trade adjustment assistance, and for grants authorized by section 27 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3722">15 U.S.C. 3722</external-xref>), $140,000,000, to remain available until expended, of which $17,000,000 shall be for grants under such section 27.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HF5C84F9BA8344D6DAB4B19823828DFB5"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of administering the economic development assistance programs as provided for by law, $36,000,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That these funds may be used to monitor projects approved pursuant to title I of the Public Works Employment Act of 1976, title II of the Trade Act of 1974, section 27 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3722">15 U.S.C. 3722</external-xref>), and the Community Emergency Drought Relief Act of 1977.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H199299DD5711480E9C8B8B3549FD4EAD"><header>Minority business development agency</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HFA37475692C14641BF980882FC9D5B83"><header>Minority business development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Department of Commerce in fostering, promoting, and developing minority business enterprise, including expenses of grants, contracts, and other agreements with public or private organizations, $34,000,000.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H2CC1616F8E73487685ADA82A7BF8A6B9"><header>Bureau of Economic Analysis</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HDE76DD62717A4688ADE6C8AD5981D73D"><header>Salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses, as authorized by law, of economic and statistical analysis programs of the Department of Commerce, $96,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H716AB16A7EFE4993936ECD564EE54A8F"><header>Bureau of the Census</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H275DD6EB18DC45D9853C58F5A85DE320"><header>Current surveys and programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses for collecting, compiling, analyzing, preparing and publishing statistics, provided for by law, $256,000,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That, from amounts provided herein, funds may be used for promotion, outreach, and marketing activities: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the Bureau of the Census shall collect and analyze data for the Annual Social and Economic Supplement to the Current Population Survey using the same health insurance questions included in previous years, in addition to the revised questions implemented in the Current Population Survey beginning in February 2014.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H4619CBF8F3BC403981FA2039905B1590"><header>Periodic censuses and programs</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H53335A9C86C148329736FBDB6B9DAD05"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses for collecting, compiling, analyzing, preparing and publishing statistics for periodic censuses and programs provided for by law, $1,251,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That, from amounts provided herein, funds may be used for promotion, outreach, and marketing activities: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That within the amounts appropriated, $2,580,000 shall be transferred to the <quote>Office of Inspector General</quote> account for activities associated with carrying out investigations and audits related to the Bureau of the Census: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not more than 50 percent of the amounts made available under this heading for information technology related to 2020 census delivery, including the Census Enterprise Data Collection and Processing (CEDCaP) program, may be obligated until the Secretary submits to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a plan for expenditure that: (1) identifies for each CEDCaP project/investment over $25,000: (A) the functional and performance capabilities to be delivered and the mission benefits to be realized; (B) the estimated lifecycle cost, including estimates for development as well as maintenance and operations; and (C) key milestones to be met; (2) details for each project/investment: (A) reasons for any cost and schedule variances; and (B) top risks and mitigation strategies; and (3) has been submitted to the Government Accountability Office.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H32B7CFA631C34251A5D8FC9A7EB9CB5D"><header>National telecommunications and information administration</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H70637D7D3D7447208B03581829A47B79"><header>Salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses, as provided for by law, of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA), $30,000,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That, notwithstanding <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/1535">31 U.S.C. 1535(d)</external-xref>, the Secretary of Commerce shall charge Federal agencies for costs incurred in spectrum management, analysis, operations, and related services, and such fees shall be retained and used as offsetting collections for costs of such spectrum services, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the Secretary of Commerce is authorized to retain and use as offsetting collections all funds transferred, or previously transferred, from other Government agencies for all costs incurred in telecommunications research, engineering, and related activities by the Institute for Telecommunication Sciences of NTIA, in furtherance of its assigned functions under this paragraph, and such funds received from other Government agencies shall remain available until expended.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H00B96067B0724BC598CF5B1624C9AB2C"><header>Public telecommunications facilities, planning and construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the administration of prior-year grants, recoveries and unobligated balances of funds previously appropriated are available for the administration of all open grants until their expiration.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HE030EA22DAB744EDAF37F62FC2AA75FD"><header>United States patent and trademark office</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H686A5E68D4C941C682BAF11213A19DAE"><header>Salaries and expenses</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H90175A980BCD4FC8A1E978F7A2313526"><header>(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) provided for by law, including defense of suits instituted against the Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the USPTO, $3,500,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the sum herein appropriated from the general fund shall be reduced as offsetting collections of fees and surcharges assessed and collected by the USPTO under any law are received during fiscal year 2018, so as to result in a fiscal year 2018 appropriation from the general fund estimated at $0: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That during fiscal year 2018, should the total amount of such offsetting collections be less than $3,500,000,000 this amount shall be reduced accordingly: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That any amount received in excess of $3,500,000,000 in fiscal year 2018 and deposited in the Patent and Trademark Fee Reserve Fund shall remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the Director of USPTO shall submit a spending plan to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate for any amounts made available by the preceding proviso and such spending plan shall be treated as a reprogramming under section 505 of this Act and shall not be available for obligation or expenditure except in compliance with the procedures set forth in that section: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That any amounts reprogrammed in accordance with the preceding proviso shall be transferred to the United States Patent and Trademark Office <quote>Salaries and Expenses</quote> account: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That from amounts provided herein, not to exceed $900 shall be made available in fiscal year 2018 for official reception and representation expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That in fiscal year 2018 from the amounts made available for <quote>Salaries and Expenses</quote> for the USPTO, the amounts necessary to pay (1) the difference between the percentage of basic pay contributed by the USPTO and employees under section 8334(a) of title 5, United States Code, and the normal cost percentage (as defined by section 8331(17) of that title) as provided by the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) for USPTO's specific use, of basic pay, of employees subject to subchapter III of chapter 83 of that title, and (2) the present value of the otherwise unfunded accruing costs, as determined by OPM for USPTO's specific use of post-retirement life insurance and post-retirement health benefits coverage for all USPTO employees who are enrolled in Federal Employees Health Benefits (FEHB) and Federal Employees Group Life Insurance (FEGLI), shall be transferred to the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund, the FEGLI Fund, and the FEHB Fund, as appropriate, and shall be available for the authorized purposes of those accounts: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That any differences between the present value factors published in OPM's yearly 300 series benefit letters and the factors that OPM provides for USPTO's specific use shall be recognized as an imputed cost on USPTO's financial statements, where applicable: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That, notwithstanding any other provision of law, all fees and surcharges assessed and collected by USPTO are available for USPTO only pursuant to section 42(c) of title 35, United States Code, as amended by section 22 of the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/29">Public Law 112–29</external-xref>): <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That within the amounts appropriated, $2,000,000 shall be transferred to the <quote>Office of Inspector General</quote> account for activities associated with carrying out investigations and audits related to the USPTO.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HFF019DC399AE44328BE835E5DFFA171D"><header>National institute of standards and technology</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H4668F084228248CF88AC48D782F408D7"><header>Scientific and technical research and services</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H793811A405D24278B3E5E68A4BAC80EA"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), $660,000,000, to remain available until expended, of which not to exceed $9,000,000 may be transferred to the <quote>Working Capital Fund</quote>: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $5,000 shall be for official reception and representation expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That NIST may provide local transportation for summer undergraduate research fellowship program participants.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H86EE4F4BBCBA47D186AAE6305C977D09"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Industrial technology services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses for industrial technology services, $105,000,000, to remain available until expended, of which $100,000,000 shall be for the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership, and of which $5,000,000 shall be for the National Network for Manufacturing Innovation.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H8B0962C682E7476D86D2D55506B9D840"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Construction of Research Facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For construction of new research facilities, including architectural and engineering design, and for renovation and maintenance of existing facilities, not otherwise provided for the National Institute of Standards and Technology, as authorized by sections 13 through 15 of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278c-278e">15 U.S.C. 278c–278e</external-xref>), $100,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the Secretary of Commerce shall include in the budget justification materials that the Secretary submits to Congress in support of the Department of Commerce budget (as submitted with the budget of the President under section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code) an estimate for each National Institute of Standards and Technology construction project having a total multi-year program cost of more than $5,000,000, and simultaneously the budget justification materials shall include an estimate of the budgetary requirements for each such project for each of the 5 subsequent fiscal years.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="HC57AF22BCA1746D29D816E06EC1CECE1"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">National oceanic and atmospheric administration</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H57BD5D557DA94DF2814DD789A175C00E"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Operations, research, and facilities</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H436832E0AC014D09B9D1133F339D9A9D"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of activities authorized by law for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, including maintenance, operation, and hire of aircraft and vessels; grants, contracts, or other payments to nonprofit organizations for the purposes of conducting activities pursuant to cooperative agreements; and relocation of facilities, $3,240,199,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019, except that funds provided for cooperative enforcement shall remain available until September 30, 2020: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That fees and donations received by the National Ocean Service for the management of national marine sanctuaries may be retained and used for the salaries and expenses associated with those activities, notwithstanding section 3302 of title 31, United States Code: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That in addition, $144,000,000 shall be derived by transfer from the fund entitled <quote>Promote and Develop Fishery Products and Research Pertaining to American Fisheries</quote>, which shall only be used for fishery activities related to the Saltonstall-Kennedy Grant Program, Cooperative Research, Annual Stock Assessments, Survey and Monitoring Projects, Interjurisdictional Fisheries Grants, and Fish Information Networks: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That of the $3,411,699,000 provided for in direct obligations under this heading, $3,240,199,000 is appropriated from the general fund, $144,000,000 is provided by transfer and $27,500,000 is derived from recoveries of prior year obligations: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That any deviation from the amounts designated for specific activities in the report accompanying this Act, or any use of deobligated balances of funds provided under this heading in previous years, shall be subject to the procedures set forth in section 505 of this Act: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That in addition, for necessary retired pay expenses under the Retired Serviceman's Family Protection and Survivor Benefits Plan, and for payments for the medical care of retired personnel and their dependents under the Dependents' Medical Care Act (10 U.S.C. ch. 55), such sums as may be necessary.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H1E9FD17D228044DE92476EFC82F3F09A"><header>Procurement, acquisition and construction</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HBAF6989DA2B645CDA05CB9DA0656B310"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For procurement, acquisition and construction of capital assets, including alteration and modification costs, of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, $1,643,110,000, to remain available until September 30, 2020, except that funds provided for acquisition and construction of vessels and construction of facilities shall remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That of the $1,656,110,000 provided for in direct obligations under this heading, $1,643,110,000 is appropriated from the general fund and $13,000,000 is provided from recoveries of prior year obligations: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That any deviation from the amounts designated for specific activities in the report accompanying this Act, or any use of deobligated balances of funds provided under this heading in previous years, shall be subject to the procedures set forth in section 505 of this Act: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the Secretary of Commerce shall include in budget justification materials that the Secretary submits to Congress in support of the Department of Commerce budget (as submitted with the budget of the President under section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code) an estimate for each National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration procurement, acquisition or construction project having a total of more than $5,000,000 and simultaneously the budget justification shall include an estimate of the budgetary requirements for each such project for each of the 5 subsequent fiscal years: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That, within the amounts appropriated, $1,302,000 shall be transferred to the <quote>Office of Inspector General</quote> account for activities associated with carrying out investigations and audits related to satellite procurement, acquisition and construction.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HAFCADA73E24C4333AB8BF7D34FA0496E"><header>Pacific coastal salmon recovery</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses associated with the restoration of Pacific salmon populations, $65,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That, of the funds provided herein, the Secretary of Commerce may issue grants to the States of Washington, Oregon, Idaho, Nevada, California, and Alaska, and to the Federally recognized tribes of the Columbia River and Pacific Coast (including Alaska), for projects necessary for conservation of salmon and steelhead populations that are listed as threatened or endangered, or that are identified by a State as at-risk to be so listed, for maintaining populations necessary for exercise of tribal treaty fishing rights or native subsistence fishing, or for conservation of Pacific coastal salmon and steelhead habitat, based on guidelines to be developed by the Secretary of Commerce: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That all funds shall be allocated based on scientific and other merit principles and shall not be available for marketing activities: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That funds disbursed to States shall be subject to a matching requirement of funds or documented in-kind contributions of at least 33 percent of the Federal funds.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H7EC19D90D21F495698F5F16E2084EAEF"><header>Fishermen's contingency fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For carrying out the provisions of title IV of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/372">Public Law 95–372</external-xref>, not to exceed $350,000, to be derived from receipts collected pursuant to that Act, to remain available until expended.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H8D33060232EA4806909867C06EAE5BB3"><header>Fisheries Disaster Assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the necessary expenses associated with the mitigation of fishery disasters, $20,000,000 to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That funds shall be used for mitigating the effects of commercial fishery failures and fishery resource disasters as declared by the Secretary of Commerce in 2017.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H69BB1BF4F6CE435599C236BF379D01A7"><header>Fisheries finance program account</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subject to section 502 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, during fiscal year 2018, obligations of direct loans may not exceed $24,000,000 for Individual Fishing Quota loans and not to exceed $100,000,000 for traditional direct loans as authorized by the Merchant Marine Act of 1936.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="HF61FE4E49C584F13A1561C76F3969ABF"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Departmental Management</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HB0DBC422B9A34691B11ADAF91DB8E82E"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses for the management of the Department of Commerce provided for by law, including not to exceed $4,500 for official reception and representation, $58,000,000.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H9C40368305434536B5F3C67A1CB748CD"><header>Renovation and modernization</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H5162AA79F6324C8087FC746127A850FD"><header> (including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses for the renovation and modernization of the Herbert C. Hoover Building, $1,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the Secretary of Commerce may transfer up to $8,224,000 to this account from funds available to the Department of Commerce: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the transfer authority provided in the first proviso is in addition to any other transfer authority contained in this Act: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That any transfer pursuant to the authority provided under this heading shall be treated as a reprogramming under section 505 of this Act and shall not be available for obligation or expenditure except in compliance with the procedures set forth in that section.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H201003948594493597B8C65CBF3E3609"><header>Office of inspector general</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of Inspector General in carrying out the provisions of the Inspector General Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.), $32,744,000.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H4E4D94CB220E4280A6B9DD0F98F1DB78"><header>General provisions—Department of commerce</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HE67BA8C74723481F87564F65549AA70A"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header>
 </appropriations-small><section id="H95BD0975E45B422E96AF80F212C243DA"><enum>101.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the current fiscal year, applicable appropriations and funds made available to the Department of Commerce by this Act shall be available for the activities specified in the Act of October 26, 1949 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1514">15 U.S.C. 1514</external-xref>), to the extent and in the manner prescribed by the Act, and, notwithstanding <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3324">31 U.S.C. 3324</external-xref>, may be used for advanced payments not otherwise authorized only upon the certification of officials designated by the Secretary of Commerce that such payments are in the public interest.</text>
 </section><section id="H4FC939A3C66E4DCFBF5CDBBB070B61AA"><enum>102.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the current fiscal year, appropriations made available to the Department of Commerce by this Act for salaries and expenses shall be available for hire of passenger motor vehicles as authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/1343">31 U.S.C. 1343</external-xref> and 1344; services as authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/3109">5 U.S.C. 3109</external-xref>; and uniforms or allowances therefor, as authorized by law (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/5901">5 U.S.C. 5901–5902</external-xref>).</text>
 </section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15DCEFCBC4C347F1A917DCCC712E2B9E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>103.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not to exceed 5 percent of any appropriation made available for the current fiscal year for the Department of Commerce in this Act may be transferred between such appropriations, but no such appropriation shall be increased by more than 10 percent by any such transfers: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That any transfer pursuant to this section shall be treated as a reprogramming of funds under section 505 of this Act and shall not be available for obligation or expenditure except in compliance with the procedures set forth in that section: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the Secretary of Commerce shall notify the Committees on Appropriations at least 15 days in advance of the acquisition or disposal of any capital asset (including land, structures, and equipment) not specifically provided for in this Act or any other law appropriating funds for the Department of Commerce.</text>
 </section><section id="HBCF5BCFB44444907A88505845FE1CEC2"><enum>104.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements set forth by section 105 of the Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/55">Public Law 112–55</external-xref>), as amended by section 105 of title I of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/6">Public Law 113–6</external-xref>, are hereby adopted by reference and made applicable with respect to fiscal year 2018: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the life cycle cost for the Joint Polar Satellite System is $11,322,125,000 and the life cycle cost for the Geostationary Operational Environmental Satellite R-Series Program is $10,828,059,000.</text>
 </section><section id="H5B5E63766DC3424BAC50D7E65DE6DE87"><enum>105.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may furnish services (including but not limited to utilities, telecommunications, and security services) necessary to support the operation, maintenance, and improvement of space that persons, firms, or organizations are authorized, pursuant to the Public Buildings Cooperative Use Act of 1976 or other authority, to use or occupy in the Herbert C. Hoover Building, Washington, DC, or other buildings, the maintenance, operation, and protection of which has been delegated to the Secretary from the Administrator of General Services pursuant to the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 on a reimbursable or non-reimbursable basis. Amounts received as reimbursement for services provided under this section or the authority under which the use or occupancy of the space is authorized, up to $200,000, shall be credited to the appropriation or fund which initially bears the costs of such services.</text>
 </section><section id="H3295BFC4A0604B9F947AF30F1157DBFC"><enum>106.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this title shall be construed to prevent a grant recipient from deterring child pornography, copyright infringement, or any other unlawful activity over its networks.</text>
 </section><section id="H364BA7623ECC40BB93FBD8C5AA045E72"><enum>107.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration is authorized to use, with their consent, with reimbursement and subject to the limits of available appropriations, the land, services, equipment, personnel, and facilities of any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States, or of any State, local government, Indian tribal government, Territory, or possession, or of any political subdivision thereof, or of any foreign government or international organization, for purposes related to carrying out the responsibilities of any statute administered by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text>
 </section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4790620EB534BF6BA25DFF6AD9AE064" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>108.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Technical Information Service shall not charge any customer for a copy of any report or document generated by the Legislative Branch unless the Service has provided information to the customer on how an electronic copy of such report or document may be accessed and downloaded for free online. Should a customer still require the Service to provide a printed or digital copy of the report or document, the charge shall be limited to recovering the Service's cost of processing, reproducing, and delivering such report or document.</text>
 </section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF23A8FCB074149E19092F4188F5EED29" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>109.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out the responsibilities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), the Administrator of NOAA is authorized to: (1) enter into grants and cooperative agreements with; (2) use on a non-reimbursable basis land, services, equipment, personnel, and facilities provided by; and (3) receive and expend funds made available on a consensual basis from: a Federal agency, State or subdivision thereof, local government, tribal government, territory, or possession or any subdivisions thereof: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That funds received for permitting and related regulatory activities pursuant to this section shall be deposited under the heading <quote>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration—Operations, Research, and Facilities</quote> and shall remain available until September 30, 2020, for such purposes: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That all funds within this section and their corresponding uses are subject to section 505 of this Act.</text>
 <appropriations-small id="H68059E0D3D524261A8FDB4859FA8F0A2"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Commerce Appropriations Act, 2018</short-title></quote>.</text> </appropriations-small></section></title><title commented="no" id="HB12DB121FD454D4E9A826A76CE18F644" level-type="subsequent"><enum>II</enum><header display-inline="no-display-inline">Department of Justice</header> <appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="HC055A3CA98E6424D93E5C0AE8204BAC4"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">General Administration</header> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H7C4C8C41F6A54EFE9D2FEFC416813A45"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the administration of the Department of Justice, $89,000,000, of which not to exceed $4,000,000 for security and construction of Department of Justice facilities shall remain available until expended.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HCCBC6036DFD5421BB9DA1EA090A75956"><header>Justice information sharing technology</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HAC6EFE9B680141CB9D7A9D16639D6436"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses for information sharing technology, including planning, development, deployment and departmental direction, $30,941,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the Attorney General may transfer up to $35,400,000 to this account, from funds available to the Department of Justice for information technology, to remain available until expended, for enterprise-wide information technology initiatives: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the transfer authority in the preceding proviso is in addition to any other transfer authority contained in this Act: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That any transfer pursuant to the first proviso shall be treated as a reprogramming under section 505 of this Act and shall not be available for obligation or expenditure except in compliance with the procedures set forth in that section.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H2B5DFB09D38E47A387DBCD04E5F4B6C8"><header>Executive Office for Immigration Review</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H5D96C94A1EE445E4BB5F579A59A1E170"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the administration of immigration-related activities of the Executive Office for Immigration Review, $504,500,000, of which $4,000,000 shall be derived by transfer from the Executive Office for Immigration Review fees deposited in the <quote>Immigration Examinations Fee</quote> account: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $35,000,000 of the total amount made available under this heading shall remain available until expended.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HECAEBB6028AC408FA1D247B6301615AD"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Office of Inspector General</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of Inspector General, $95,583,000, including not to exceed $10,000 to meet unforeseen emergencies of a confidential character.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HDF6AF81D7613475B91467E72CF0A832C"><header>United states parole commission</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H3E9DD9A9BAC047C5A9616C80C79D8EB9"><header>Salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the United States Parole Commission as authorized, $13,000,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That, notwithstanding any other provision of law, upon the expiration of a term of office of a Commissioner, the Commissioner may continue to act until a successor has been appointed.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="H3F56A45161FB4BC3BC636D6F7E314FF8"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Legal Activities</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H7D6A896F932C4E3397B0CAEFE8DE6045"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries and Expenses, General Legal Activities</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H6C795B68FA0F4492AE6CADF7D6573C66"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the legal activities of the Department of Justice, not otherwise provided for, including not to exceed $20,000 for expenses of collecting evidence, to be expended under the direction of, and to be accounted for solely under the certificate of, the Attorney General; the administration of pardon and clemency petitions; and rent of private or Government-owned space in the District of Columbia, $897,500,000, of which not to exceed $20,000,000 for litigation support contracts shall remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That of the amount provided for INTERPOL Washington dues payments, not to exceed $685,000 shall remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That of the total amount appropriated, not to exceed $9,000 shall be available to INTERPOL Washington for official reception and representation expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That of the amount appropriated, such sums as may be necessary shall be available to the Civil Rights Division for salaries and expenses associated with the election monitoring program under section 8 of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10305">52 U.S.C. 10305</external-xref>) and to reimburse the Office of Personnel Management for such salaries and expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That of the amounts provided under this heading for the election monitoring program, $3,390,000 shall remain available until expended.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HDD5F1B64B33D4E77A989C583B5E91FF6"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition, for reimbursement of expenses of the Department of Justice associated with processing cases under the National Childhood Vaccine Injury Act of 1986, not to exceed $10,000,000, to be appropriated from the Vaccine Injury Compensation Trust Fund.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HEF69E85829C94E3889FEA1692F93A292"><header>Salaries and expenses, antitrust division</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the enforcement of antitrust and kindred laws, $163,980,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That notwithstanding any other provision of law, fees collected for premerger notification filings under the Hart-Scott-Rodino Antitrust Improvements Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/18a">15 U.S.C. 18a</external-xref>), regardless of the year of collection (and estimated to be $126,000,000 in fiscal year 2018), shall be retained and used for necessary expenses in this appropriation, and shall remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the sum herein appropriated from the general fund shall be reduced as such offsetting collections are received during fiscal year 2018, so as to result in a final fiscal year 2018 appropriation from the general fund estimated at $37,980,000.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H7F0B15B34DDA406E9D93F131760BA61B"><header>Salaries and expenses, united states attorneys</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Offices of the United States Attorneys, including inter-governmental and cooperative agreements, $2,057,252,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That of the total amount appropriated, not to exceed $7,200 shall be available for official reception and representation expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $25,000,000 shall remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That each United States Attorney shall establish or participate in a task force on human trafficking.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H8952EFB2F8BE44AA8FF16F5F3C5FADDA"><header>United states trustee system fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the United States Trustee Program, as authorized, $225,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That, notwithstanding any other provision of law, deposits to the United States Trustee System Fund and amounts herein appropriated shall be available in such amounts as may be necessary to pay refunds due depositors: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That, notwithstanding any other provision of law, fees collected pursuant to section 589a(b) of title 28, United States Code, shall be retained and used for necessary expenses in this appropriation and shall remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That to the extent that fees collected in fiscal year 2018, net of amounts necessary to pay refunds due depositors, exceed $225,000,000, those excess amounts shall be available in future fiscal years only to the extent provided in advance in appropriations Acts: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the sum herein appropriated from the general fund shall be reduced (1) as such fees are received during fiscal year 2018, net of amounts necessary to pay refunds due depositors, (estimated at $135,000,000) and (2) to the extent that any remaining general fund appropriations can be derived from amounts deposited in the Fund in previous fiscal years that are not otherwise appropriated, so as to result in a final fiscal year 2018 appropriation from the general fund estimated at $90,000,000.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H013D33DAA6C34B43A680C3C475D5AC3D"><header>Salaries and expenses, foreign claims settlement commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary to carry out the activities of the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission, including services as authorized by section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, $2,374,000.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H8FF138964CC442A29F1E9F51E1B7E302"><header>Fees and expenses of witnesses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For fees and expenses of witnesses, for expenses of contracts for the procurement and supervision of expert witnesses, for private counsel expenses, including advances, and for expenses of foreign counsel, $270,000,000, to remain available until expended, of which not to exceed $16,000,000 is for construction of buildings for protected witness safesites; not to exceed $3,000,000 is for the purchase and maintenance of armored and other vehicles for witness security caravans; and not to exceed $13,000,000 is for the purchase, installation, maintenance, and upgrade of secure telecommunications equipment and a secure automated information network to store and retrieve the identities and locations of protected witnesses: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That amounts made available under this heading may not be transferred pursuant to section 205 of this Act.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HEFE202ADEECE4A6DADCEB0A545A209F8"><header>Salaries and expenses, community relations service</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H32DD40B5F29E4F949ACF60F2FDCDE8D7"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Community Relations Service, $15,000,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That notwithstanding section 205 of this Act, upon a determination by the Attorney General that emergent circumstances require additional funding for conflict resolution and violence prevention activities of the Community Relations Service, the Attorney General may transfer such amounts to the Community Relations Service, from available appropriations for the current fiscal year for the Department of Justice, as may be necessary to respond to such circumstances: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That any transfer pursuant to the preceding proviso shall be treated as a reprogramming under section 505 of this Act and shall not be available for obligation or expenditure except in compliance with the procedures set forth in that section.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HA5DEF4291DC04C9EB91435616AE59CF2"><header>Assets forfeiture fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses authorized by subparagraphs (B), (F), and (G) of section 524(c)(1) of title 28, United States Code, $20,514,000, to be derived from the Department of Justice Assets Forfeiture Fund.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H0DB527B4B16F43BDBD53C0B6FE2C6383"><header>United states marshals service</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HDB91AEC69E28484A9A7B6E211663B410"><header>Salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the United States Marshals Service, $1,255,000,000, of which not to exceed $6,000 shall be available for official reception and representation expenses, and not to exceed $15,000,000 shall remain available until expended.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H7829B84A7FAC4F91BD6A007297DED3F2"><header>Construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For construction in space controlled, occupied or utilized by the United States Marshals Service for prisoner holding and related support, $10,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HD61F7B1F5A064088AE3B15515194D369"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal Prisoner Detention</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H5A6E955A23E94A4E8D5A9E5EC67A98D7"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses related to United States prisoners in the custody of the United States Marshals Service as authorized by section 4013 of title 18, United States Code, $1,536,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $20,000,000 shall be considered <quote>funds appropriated for State and local law enforcement assistance</quote> pursuant to section 4013(b) of title 18, United States Code: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the United States Marshals Service shall be responsible for managing the Justice Prisoner and Alien Transportation System: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That any unobligated balances available from funds appropriated under the heading <quote>General Administration, Detention Trustee</quote> shall be transferred to and merged with the appropriation under this heading.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H0DB527B4B16F43BDBD53C0B6FE2C638366"><header>National security division</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H6F0A5E6193BF430E9592D7C11BC2F021"><header>Salaries and expenses</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HA500EDC60FCA4BE88734331AC71F0A01"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary to carry out the activities of the National Security Division, $100,000,000, of which not to exceed $5,000,000 for information technology systems shall remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That notwithstanding section 205 of this Act, upon a determination by the Attorney General that emergent circumstances require additional funding for the activities of the National Security Division, the Attorney General may transfer such amounts to this heading from available appropriations for the current fiscal year for the Department of Justice, as may be necessary to respond to such circumstances: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That any transfer pursuant to the preceding proviso shall be treated as a reprogramming under section 505 of this Act and shall not be available for obligation or expenditure except in compliance with the procedures set forth in that section.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H2F897C3476E448998A40A0820827956F"><header>Interagency law enforcement</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H43A981D4940646F8888D0B140CBC21A7"><header>Interagency crime and drug enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses for the identification, investigation, and prosecution of individuals associated with the most significant drug trafficking organizations, transnational organized crime, and money laundering organizations not otherwise provided for, to include inter-governmental agreements with State and local law enforcement agencies engaged in the investigation and prosecution of individuals involved in transnational organized crime and drug trafficking, $526,000,000, of which $50,000,000 shall remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That any amounts obligated from appropriations under this heading may be used under authorities available to the organizations reimbursed from this appropriation.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H3B9C85B594504972B6D23EFFAF8163F8"><header>Federal bureau of investigation</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H6861BAED6ED04C959BA1EB61A250E72B"><header>Salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Federal Bureau of Investigation for detection, investigation, and prosecution of crimes against the United States, $8,814,747,000, of which not to exceed $216,900,000 shall remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $184,500 shall be available for official reception and representation expenses.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HDD768504ADD8478EB304D3CBD2861D15"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses, to include the cost of equipment, furniture, and information technology requirements, related to construction or acquisition of buildings, facilities and sites by purchase, or as otherwise authorized by law; conversion, modification and extension of federally owned buildings; preliminary planning and design of projects; and operation and maintenance of secure work environment facilities and secure networking capabilities; $51,895,000, to remain available until expended.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H94AD099FB9A343CF8D88FE983822DA15"><header>Drug enforcement administration</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H6C01E0A1AC7047FC9271B0089D9C92DB"><header>Salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Drug Enforcement Administration, including not to exceed $70,000 to meet unforeseen emergencies of a confidential character pursuant to section 530C of title 28, United States Code; and expenses for conducting drug education and training programs, including travel and related expenses for participants in such programs and the distribution of items of token value that promote the goals of such programs, $2,164,051,000, of which not to exceed $75,000,000 shall remain available until expended and not to exceed $90,000 shall be available for official reception and representation expenses.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="H2284BCD755DE40339442AE0EBE81C8C0"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HA1AA0E3B9AAB45F9945E291F07B251EC"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, for training of State and local law enforcement agencies with or without reimbursement, including training in connection with the training and acquisition of canines for explosives and fire accelerants detection; and for provision of laboratory assistance to State and local law enforcement agencies, with or without reimbursement, $1,293,776,000, of which not to exceed $36,000 shall be for official reception and representation expenses, not to exceed $1,000,000 shall be available for the payment of attorneys' fees as provided by section 924(d)(2) of title 18, United States Code, and not to exceed $20,000,000 shall remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That none of the funds appropriated herein shall be available to investigate or act upon applications for relief from Federal firearms disabilities under section 925(c) of title 18, United States Code: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That such funds shall be available to investigate and act upon applications filed by corporations for relief from Federal firearms disabilities under section 925(c) of title 18, United States Code: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That no funds made available by this or any other Act may be used to transfer the functions, missions, or activities of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives to other agencies or Departments.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H0296AA690ADD40AB8F5A7DA6208E5CEB"><header>Federal prison system</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H785947763CC540C1BFD6A35A107F5782"><header>Salaries and expenses</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H99AD0F5BED2B4466ACAA7AC6C363A342"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Federal Prison System for the administration, operation, and maintenance of Federal penal and correctional institutions, and for the provision of technical assistance and advice on corrections related issues to foreign governments, $7,070,248,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the Attorney General may transfer to the Department of Health and Human Services such amounts as may be necessary for direct expenditures by that Department for medical relief for inmates of Federal penal and correctional institutions: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the Director of the Federal Prison System, where necessary, may enter into contracts with a fiscal agent or fiscal intermediary claims processor to determine the amounts payable to persons who, on behalf of the Federal Prison System, furnish health services to individuals committed to the custody of the Federal Prison System: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $5,400 shall be available for official reception and representation expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $50,000,000 shall remain available for necessary operations until September 30, 2019: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That, of the amounts provided for contract confinement, not to exceed $20,000,000 shall remain available until expended to make payments in advance for grants, contracts and reimbursable agreements, and other expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the Director of the Federal Prison System may accept donated property and services relating to the operation of the prison card program from a not-for-profit entity which has operated such program in the past, notwithstanding the fact that such not-for-profit entity furnishes services under contracts to the Federal Prison System relating to the operation of pre-release services, halfway houses, or other custodial facilities.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H702DFD80AE57483E8F9E97D16659CD1C"><header>Buildings and facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For planning, acquisition of sites and construction of new facilities; purchase and acquisition of facilities and remodeling, and equipping of such facilities for penal and correctional use, including all necessary expenses incident thereto, by contract or force account; and constructing, remodeling, and equipping necessary buildings and facilities at existing penal and correctional institutions, including all necessary expenses incident thereto, by contract or force account, $95,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That labor of United States prisoners may be used for work performed under this appropriation.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HE53E2A9D26B947AA90681A1B5B678458"><header>Federal prison industries, incorporated</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Prison Industries, Incorporated, is hereby authorized to make such expenditures within the limits of funds and borrowing authority available, and in accord with the law, and to make such contracts and commitments without regard to fiscal year limitations as provided by section 9104 of title 31, United States Code, as may be necessary in carrying out the program set forth in the budget for the current fiscal year for such corporation.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HFB027FAB297B4D7CB2E73A116A973824"><header>Limitation on administrative expenses, federal prison industries, incorporated</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not to exceed $2,700,000 of the funds of the Federal Prison Industries, Incorporated, shall be available for its administrative expenses, and for services as authorized by section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, to be computed on an accrual basis to be determined in accordance with the corporation's current prescribed accounting system, and such amounts shall be exclusive of depreciation, payment of claims, and expenditures which such accounting system requires to be capitalized or charged to cost of commodities acquired or produced, including selling and shipping expenses, and expenses in connection with acquisition, construction, operation, maintenance, improvement, protection, or disposition of facilities and other property belonging to the corporation or in which it has an interest.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H514FFD23308447D3894E588BDCEBB095"><header>State and local law enforcement activities</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H0895059DD9F54D7BA7E6727261F4D85E"><header>Office on violence against women</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H7A38B678107B4F17A2E7B2FD978EAFED"><header>Violence against women prevention and prosecution programs</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HA49BD4A8D76148388E9ADC8E56122125"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For grants, contracts, cooperative agreements, and other assistance for the prevention and prosecution of violence against women, as authorized by the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3711">42 U.S.C. 3711</external-xref> et seq.) (<quote>the 1968 Act</quote>); the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/322">Public Law 103–322</external-xref>) (<quote>the 1994 Act</quote>); the Victims of Child Abuse Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/101/647">Public Law 101–647</external-xref>) (<quote>the 1990 Act</quote>); the Prosecutorial Remedies and Other Tools to end the Exploitation of Children Today Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/21">Public Law 108–21</external-xref>); the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5601">42 U.S.C. 5601</external-xref> et seq.) (<quote>the 1974 Act</quote>); the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/386">Public Law 106–386</external-xref>) (<quote>the 2000 Act</quote>); the Violence Against Women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/162">Public Law 109–162</external-xref>) (<quote>the 2005 Act</quote>); the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/4">Public Law 113–4</external-xref>) (<quote>the 2013 Act</quote>); and the Rape Survivor Child Custody Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/22">Public Law 114–22</external-xref>) (<quote>the 2015 Act</quote>); and for related victims services, $527,000,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That except as otherwise provided by law, not to exceed 5 percent of funds made available under this heading may be used for expenses related to evaluation, training, and technical assistance: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That of the amount provided—</text>
 <paragraph id="H47912E14421E497D839AD63107CBF045"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$215,000,000 is for grants to combat violence against women, as authorized by part T of the 1968 Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6B7D5856DE5C4A0F9A1ABD79480FC877"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$30,000,000 is for transitional housing assistance grants for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, or sexual assault as authorized by section 40299 of the 1994 Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4B602EF886D947A286E1F8C415DDE4B5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$3,500,000 is for the National Institute of Justice for research and evaluation of violence against women and related issues addressed by grant programs of the Office on Violence Against Women, which shall be transferred to <quote>Research, Evaluation and Statistics</quote> for administration by the Office of Justice Programs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE1B5CB1D332F4A7A914BE9D13322F1E8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$11,000,000 is for a grant program to provide services to advocate for and respond to youth victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking; assistance to children and youth exposed to such violence; programs to engage men and youth in preventing such violence; and assistance to middle and high school students through education and other services related to such violence: <italic>Provided</italic>, That unobligated balances available for the programs authorized by sections 41201, 41204, 41303, and 41305 of the 1994 Act, prior to its amendment by the 2013 Act, shall be available for this program: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That 10 percent of the total amount available for this grant program shall be available for grants under the program authorized by section 2015 of the 1968 Act: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That the definitions and grant conditions in section 40002 of the 1994 Act shall apply to this program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA80B1CD9CAB46AFBFCBA11F0AFE1640"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$53,000,000 is for grants to encourage arrest policies as authorized by part U of the 1968 Act, of which $4,000,000 is for a homicide reduction initiative;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HA9BF0471927749599ADB686E8B378500"><enum>(6)</enum><text>$35,000,000 is for sexual assault victims assistance, as authorized by section 41601 of the 1994 Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED945AE925A94A86881C0B9D54FDEB65"><enum>(7)</enum><text>$35,000,000 is for rural domestic violence and child abuse enforcement assistance grants, as authorized by section 40295 of the 1994 Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H40467BEB871D44309F8772B80BE1093A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>$20,000,000 is for grants to reduce violent crimes against women on campus, as authorized by section 304 of the 2005 Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HB05CC4E4650040DD856DDD9F949950BC"><enum>(9)</enum><text>$45,000,000 is for legal assistance for victims, as authorized by section 1201 of the 2000 Act;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H16E5D88190CC470D894B59A25849A4DB"><enum>(10)</enum><text>$5,000,000 is for enhanced training and services to end violence against and abuse of women in later life, as authorized by section 40802 of the 1994 Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCB2829DE26D94F3C9493207CA57778E7"><enum>(11)</enum><text>$16,000,000 is for grants to support families in the justice system, as authorized by section 1301 of the 2000 Act: <italic>Provided</italic>, That unobligated balances available for the programs authorized by section 1301 of the 2000 Act and section 41002 of the 1994 Act, prior to their amendment by the 2013 Act, shall be available for this program;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H644D2E69635C4071A0B06752EF2FFA8F"><enum>(12)</enum><text>$6,000,000 is for education and training to end violence against and abuse of women with disabilities, as authorized by section 1402 of the 2000 Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6D91C79FDFDE45F3A16B14DBFCCA94D2"><enum>(13)</enum><text>$500,000 is for the National Resource Center on Workplace Responses to assist victims of domestic violence, as authorized by section 41501 of the 1994 Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFDE0A9821D59470DB587D39A0310B3C1"><enum>(14)</enum><text>$1,000,000 is for analysis and research on violence against Indian women, including as authorized by section 904 of the 2005 Act: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such funds may be transferred to <quote>Research, Evaluation and Statistics</quote> for administration by the Office of Justice Programs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1D3A41E38C9147F8A450DCD8B89A600E"><enum>(15)</enum><text>$500,000 is for a national clearinghouse that provides training and technical assistance on issues relating to sexual assault of American Indian and Alaska Native women;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H9EF0842586B4468C878DCF8F08EDF335"><enum>(16)</enum><text>$4,000,000 is for grants to assist tribal governments;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H0DE5953249B549B88503690085A11984"><enum>(17)</enum><text>$45,000,000 for victim services programs for victims of trafficking, as authorized by section 107(b)(2) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/386">Public Law 106–386</external-xref>, for programs authorized under <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/164">Public Law 109–164</external-xref>, or programs authorized under <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/4">Public Law 113–4</external-xref>; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph committee-id="SSAP00" id="H291585367325429EA44E1D7CF3BD4070"><enum>(18)</enum><text>$1,500,000 for the purposes authorized under the 2015 Act.</text> </paragraph></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H67DCF854C8854558A2EB8E2D1122B777"><header>Office of Justice Programs</header> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HACDFFF7D32534ADB8B1548E0D732E30A"><header>Research, evaluation and statistics</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For grants, contracts, cooperative agreements, and other assistance authorized by title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<quote>the 1968 Act</quote>); subtitle D of title II of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/296">Public Law 107–296</external-xref>) (<quote>the 2002 Act</quote>); and other programs, $83,000,000, to remain available until expended, of which—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5F603C4BAF434946A5C634A609948A05"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$44,500,000 is for criminal justice statistics programs, and other activities, as authorized by part C of title I of the 1968 Act; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H384307DFC8C94C369D2624E597CBF0FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$38,500,000 is for research, development, and evaluation programs, and other activities as authorized by part B of title I of the 1968 Act and subtitle D of title II of the 2002 Act.</text>
 </paragraph></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H99BA0D8EF9F24FD886A8E825BCD2CE79"><header>State and local law enforcement assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For grants, contracts, cooperative agreements, and other assistance authorized by the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/322">Public Law 103–322</external-xref>) (<quote>the 1994 Act</quote>); the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<quote>the 1968 Act</quote>); the Justice for All Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/405">Public Law 108–405</external-xref>); the Victims of Child Abuse Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/101/647">Public Law 101–647</external-xref>) (<quote>the 1990 Act</quote>); the Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/164">Public Law 109–164</external-xref>); the Violence Against Women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/162">Public Law 109–162</external-xref>) (<quote>the 2005 Act</quote>); the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/248">Public Law 109–248</external-xref>) (<quote>the Adam Walsh Act</quote>); the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/386">Public Law 106–386</external-xref>); the NICS Improvement Amendments Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/180">Public Law 110–180</external-xref>); subtitle D of title II of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/296">Public Law 107–296</external-xref>) (<quote>the 2002 Act</quote>); the Public Safety Officer Medal of Valor Act of 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/12">Public Law 107–12</external-xref>); the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/199">Public Law 110–199</external-xref>); the Prioritizing Resources and Organization for Intellectual Property Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/403">Public Law 110–403</external-xref>); the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/473">Public Law 98–473</external-xref>); the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2013 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/4">Public Law 113–4</external-xref>) (<quote>the 2013 Act</quote>); the Comprehensive Addiction and Recovery Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/198">Public Law 114–198</external-xref>) (<quote>CARA</quote>); and other programs, $1,143,500,000, to remain available until expended as follows—</text>
 <paragraph commented="no" id="H91BAF9996072453992BB206AB7FE8B44"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$500,000,000 for the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant program as authorized by subpart 1 of part E of title I of the 1968 Act (except that section 1001(c), and the special rules for Puerto Rico under section 505(g) of title I of the 1968 Act shall not apply for purposes of this Act), of which, notwithstanding such subpart 1, $10,000,000 is for the Officer Robert Wilson III Memorial Initiative on Preventing Violence Against Law Enforcement Officer Resilience and Survivability (VALOR), $4,000,000 is for use by the National Institute of Justice for research targeted toward developing a better understanding of the domestic radicalization phenomenon, and advancing evidence-based strategies for effective intervention and prevention, $2,000,000 is for a program to improve juvenile indigent defense, $2,400,000 is for the operationalization, maintenance and expansion of the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System, $10,000,000 is for competitive and evidence-based programs to reduce gun crime and gang violence, $2,500,000 is for the Capital Litigation Improvement Grant Program, as authorized by section 426 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/405">Public Law 108–405</external-xref> and for grants for wrongful conviction review, $15,500,000 is for prison rape prevention and prosecution grants to States and units of local government, and other programs, as authorized by the Prison Rape Elimination Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/79">Public Law 108–79</external-xref>), and $10,000,000 is for white collar crime prevention grants, including as authorized by section 401 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/403">Public Law 110–403</external-xref>;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph committee-id="SSAP00" id="HD81E0112E60C40CC89337D185E005E85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$220,000,000 for the State Criminal Alien Assistance Program, as authorized by section 241(i)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1231">8 U.S.C. 1231(i)(5)</external-xref>): <italic>Provided</italic>, That no jurisdiction shall request compensation for any cost greater than the actual cost for Federal immigration and other detainees housed in State and local detention facilities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H49394D4081B74242B7E1A51D2096EA7E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$20,000,000 for sex offender management assistance, as authorized by the Adam Walsh Act, and related activities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5DA0458075149FC942C9BDE9D1B2486"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$22,500,000 for the matching grant program for law enforcement armor vests, as authorized by section 2501 of title I of the 1968 Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3335AAB58C6A4859AA2366B5B9426853"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$1,000,000 for the National Sex Offender Public Website;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H7FE2C98F2782407D803B7FBD4EBD21FD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>$73,000,000 for grants to States to upgrade criminal and mental health records for the National Instant Criminal Background Check System;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HED823D0E340E4A59B84BBD73916E6894"><enum>(7)</enum><text>$125,000,000 for DNA-related and forensic programs and activities, of which—</text> <subparagraph id="H6D74973E48B74B1791AFFB38291D8E40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$117,000,000 is for a DNA analysis and capacity enhancement program and for other local, State, and Federal forensic activities, including the purposes authorized under section 2 of the DNA Analysis Backlog Elimination Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/546">Public Law 106–546</external-xref>) (the Debbie Smith DNA Backlog Grant Program): <italic>Provided</italic>, That up to 4 percent of funds made available under this paragraph may be used for the purposes described in the DNA Training and Education for Law Enforcement, Correctional Personnel, and Court Officers program (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/405">Public Law 108–405</external-xref>, section 303);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6698FFE112E4C6799A6790CBAB5BBE3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$4,000,000 is for the purposes described in the Kirk Bloodsworth Post-Conviction DNA Testing Grant Program (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/405">Public Law 108–405</external-xref>, section 412); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6494C28CF402409DBE9F56633174A179"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$4,000,000 is for Sexual Assault Forensic Exam Program grants, including as authorized by section 304 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/405">Public Law 108–405</external-xref>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BADA8F3033A4E7ABE7E3A96D106DA24"><enum>(8)</enum><text>$9,000,000 for the court-appointed special advocate program, as authorized by section 217 of the 1990 Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H3F52F1F306B74A97B2DCE696EDBA0303"><enum>(9)</enum><text>$118,000,000 for comprehensive opioid abuse reduction activities, including as authorized by CARA, and for the following programs, which shall address opioid abuse reduction consistent with underlying program authorities—</text>
 <subparagraph id="H184799175EDF42F28A7E8C32DF940856"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$43,000,000 for Drug Courts, as authorized by section 1001(a)(25)(A) of title I of the 1968 Act;</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5F6BC0A2AB04CF4A3BD6C0E645A8FF5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$12,000,000 for mental health courts and adult and juvenile collaboration program grants, as authorized by parts V and HH of title I of the 1968 Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CF5AD87224C4C42BADAA8261C9A4067"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$12,000,000 for grants for Residential Substance Abuse Treatment for State Prisoners, as authorized by part S of title I of the 1968 Act;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA0B37A3FE754EE79B86326D4FBC457C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>$7,000,000 for a veterans treatment courts program; and</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04A5090D662C4444BD3CEE561F544F78"><enum>(E)</enum><text>$14,000,000 for a program to monitor prescription drugs and scheduled listed chemical products;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E236744A7684EDBA0C3EDDB303B51C8"><enum>(10)</enum><text>$10,000,000 for emergency law enforcement assistance for events occurring during or after fiscal year 2018, as authorized by section 609M of the Justice Assistance Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10501">42 U.S.C. 10501</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/473">Public Law 98–473</external-xref>); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H767EDC370DAD428BB561BAE2C8704401"><enum>(11)</enum><text>$45,000,000 for the Comprehensive School Safety Initiative:</text> </paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="appropriations-small"><italic>Provided</italic>, That, if a unit of local government uses any of the funds made available under this heading to increase the number of law enforcement officers, the unit of local government will achieve a net gain in the number of law enforcement officers who perform non-administrative public sector safety service.</continuation-text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HAD7C32D45F7D4A47A79865962AD3E89F"><header>Juvenile justice programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For grants, contracts, cooperative agreements, and other assistance, the following amounts are made available until expended—</text>
 <paragraph id="H42E7BA11257249258E88549BB15C2522"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$75,000,000 for youth mentoring grants;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HD268A2952610469C90B353A1196ED0CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$21,000,000 for programs authorized by the Victims of Child Abuse Act of 1990;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC77B53CB156C46A890A9148700D8E00F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$72,500,000 for missing and exploited children programs, including as authorized by sections 404(b) and 405(a) of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 (except that section 102(b)(4)(B) of the PROTECT Our Children Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/401">Public Law 110–401</external-xref>) shall not apply for purposes of this Act); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H078F3D89D0F74B28A7DCCD9840ADD99B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$2,000,000 for child abuse training programs for judicial personnel and practitioners, as authorized by section 222 of the Victims of Child Abuse Act of 1990.</text>
				</paragraph></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HDE2EE0173CD74166AF2207710C8336D5"><header>Public safety officer benefits</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H7EEE560D10B142A094FFCF8787BC963A"><header> (including transfer of funds) </header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For payments and expenses authorized under section 1001(a)(4) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968, such sums as are necessary (including amounts for administrative costs), to remain available until expended; and $16,300,000 for payments authorized by section 1201(b) of such Act and for educational assistance authorized by section 1218 of such Act, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That notwithstanding section 205 of this Act, upon a determination by the Attorney General that emergent circumstances require additional funding for such disability and education payments, the Attorney General may transfer such amounts to <quote>Public Safety Officer Benefits</quote> from available appropriations for the Department of Justice as may be necessary to respond to such circumstances: <italic>Provided further</italic>, That any transfer pursuant to the preceding proviso shall be treated as a reprogramming under section 505 of this Act and shall not be available for obligation or expenditure except in compliance with the procedures set forth in that section.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HD33229109FB94D6EAE10E92C30F65E76"><header>Community oriented policing services</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HED931130BE4A4CAAA12A1EA729EC2FB5"><header>community oriented policing services programs</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H54D7EE4835BE41E1A3C17FF6D59F786A"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For grants, contracts, cooperative agreements, and other assistance, the following amounts are made available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That any balances made available through prior year deobligations shall only be available in accordance with section 505 of this Act—</text>
 <paragraph id="HABB364EC2633456F9529C1E559127948"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$11,000,000 for anti-methamphetamine-related activities, which shall be transferred to the Drug Enforcement Administration upon enactment of this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H1CC41ECF85BC4156A6B3B12A6EE6A892"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$10,000,000 is for activities authorized by the POLICE Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/199">Public Law 114–199</external-xref>);</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2EDCD032B2994D5E9F08E0FF175E7AC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$65,000,000 for initiatives to improve police-community relations, as described in the report accompanying this Act;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF30A2694FF4B4C43828AF9843BF2EC51"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$68,000,000 for offender reentry programs and research, as authorized by the Second Chance Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/199">Public Law 110–199</external-xref>), without regard to the time limitations specified at section 6(1) of such Act, of which not to exceed $5,000,000 is for Children of Incarcerated Parents Demonstrations to enhance and maintain parental and family relationships for incarcerated parents as a reentry or recidivism reduction strategy, and $2,000,000 shall be for competitive grants focusing on girls in the juvenile justice system;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF474C43714384254A8B0C705BE3C3939"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$45,000,000 for a grant program for community-based sexual assault response reform; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H8310E2B3476A4C699551FD8774F0767C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>$35,000,000 is for regional information sharing activities, as authorized by part M of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968.</text>
				</paragraph></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H8A853B9C127F4396A974EF4579ACDBA6"><header>General provisions—Department of justice</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H74DC3DA8BF514B62AFD2B8455CC43B0E"><header> (including transfer of funds) </header>
 </appropriations-small><section id="HC7DFE64B88244C5BB5F33ACEE2B00CE4"><enum>201.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise made available in this title for official reception and representation expenses, a total of not to exceed $50,000 from funds appropriated to the Department of Justice in this title shall be available to the Attorney General for official reception and representation expenses.</text>
 </section><section id="HF47713C2270640748F0384064B5D1065"><enum>202.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated by this title shall be available to pay for an abortion, except where the life of the mother would be endangered if the fetus were carried to term, or in the case of rape or incest: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That should this prohibition be declared unconstitutional by a court of competent jurisdiction, this section shall be null and void.</text>
 </section><section id="HBDAF34CCBDEC4295BB4AEC6A0DDAA3FD"><enum>203.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated under this title shall be used to require any person to perform, or facilitate in any way the performance of, any abortion.</text>
 </section><section id="HDA3E32260EFB45B380E3D1B16B51E48F"><enum>204.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in the preceding section shall remove the obligation of the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to provide escort services necessary for a female inmate to receive such service outside the Federal facility: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That nothing in this section in any way diminishes the effect of section 203 intended to address the philosophical beliefs of individual employees of the Bureau of Prisons.</text>
 </section><section id="H15F15B8675FE4439B8901D71CBB655E0"><enum>205.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not to exceed 5 percent of any appropriation made available for the current fiscal year for the Department of Justice in this Act may be transferred between such appropriations, but no such appropriation, except as otherwise specifically provided, shall be increased by more than 10 percent by any such transfers: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That any transfer pursuant to this section shall be treated as a reprogramming of funds under section 505 of this Act and shall not be available for obligation except in compliance with the procedures set forth in that section.</text>
 </section><section id="H64028738E2F94EEA9445AFC50700C83B"><enum>206.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available under this title may be used by the Federal Bureau of Prisons or the United States Marshals Service for the purpose of transporting an individual who is a prisoner pursuant to conviction for crime under State or Federal law and is classified as a maximum or high security prisoner, other than to a prison or other facility certified by the Federal Bureau of Prisons as appropriately secure for housing such a prisoner.</text>
			</section><section id="HBC41EE7E48AF453DAA3D72591DA84263"><enum>207.</enum>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFD4626CE57824756870F89FFCC575AF9"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated by this Act may be used by Federal prisons to purchase cable television services, or to rent or purchase audiovisual or electronic media or equipment used primarily for recreational purposes.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H25333AC7CCDE4BBF8E553DDD3E270873"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Subsection (a) does not preclude the rental, maintenance, or purchase of audiovisual or electronic media or equipment for inmate training, religious, or educational programs.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H0C5C29D585A9453EA82BA317BCBB3D5D"><enum>208.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available under this title shall be obligated or expended for any new or enhanced information technology program having total estimated development costs in excess of $100,000,000, unless the Deputy Attorney General and the investment review board certify to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate that the information technology program has appropriate program management controls and contractor oversight mechanisms in place, and that the program is compatible with the enterprise architecture of the Department of Justice.</text>
 </section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H853D0BEA92004482B0261A61922E64F1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>209.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The notification thresholds and procedures set forth in section 505 of this Act shall apply to deviations from the amounts designated for specific activities in this Act and in the report accompanying this Act, and to any use of deobligated balances of funds provided under this title in previous years.</text>
 </section><section id="H162E95EDF2BC4AE28C8F1D2DB104AC93"><enum>210.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated by this Act may be used to plan for, begin, continue, finish, process, or approve a public-private competition under the Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76 or any successor administrative regulation, directive, or policy for work performed by employees of Federal Prison Industries, Incorporated.</text>
 </section><section id="HA3BB0B1AB2A5470B9F58BE4BAD4B2B56"><enum>211.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no funds shall be available for the salary, benefits, or expenses of any United States Attorney assigned dual or additional responsibilities by the Attorney General or his designee that exempt that United States Attorney from the residency requirements of section 545 of title 28, United States Code.</text>
 </section><section id="H5F06FF4D93E547D1B55891C80F9BC8FD"><enum>212.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the discretion of the Attorney General, and in addition to any amounts that otherwise may be available (or authorized to be made available) by law, with respect to funds appropriated by this title under the headings <quote>Research, Evaluation and Statistics</quote>, <quote>State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance</quote>, and <quote>Juvenile Justice Programs</quote>—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC3C4023BCF4B4CAF9D4259C2C41FA85E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>up to 3 percent of funds made available to the Office of Justice Programs for grant or reimbursement programs may be used by such Office to provide training and technical assistance; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H7E58FE2C0B3C4EC39D01397308A1F490"><enum>(2)</enum><text>up to 3 percent of funds made available for grant or reimbursement programs under such headings, except for amounts appropriated specifically for research, evaluation, or statistical programs administered by the National Institute of Justice and the Bureau of Justice Statistics, shall be transferred to and merged with funds provided to the National Institute of Justice and the Bureau of Justice Statistics, to be used by them for research, evaluation, or statistical purposes, without regard to the authorizations for such grant or reimbursement programs.</text>
 </paragraph></section><section id="HE0C2B1EAC44647769A638CC9F49DD886"><enum>213.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to any amounts that otherwise may be available (or authorized to be made available) by law, 7 percent of funds made available for grant or reimbursement programs—</text>
 <paragraph id="H56352261DE8B4298BC62CE2E46BC7E41"><enum>(1)</enum><text>under the heading <quote>State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance</quote> (except for funds made available under paragraph (2) under such heading); and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H497C7291BFFE48428FABC6658A92D47F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>under the headings <quote>Juvenile Justice Programs</quote> (except for funds made available under paragraph (3) under such heading) and <quote>Community Oriented Policing Services Programs</quote>, to be transferred to and merged with funds made available under the heading <quote>State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance</quote>,</text>
				</paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="section">shall be available for assistance to Indian tribes without regard to the authorizations for
 such grant or reimbursement programs.</continuation-text></section><section id="H12E10259D53A43FC893730923974194C"><enum>214.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, section 20109(a) of subtitle A of title II of the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/13709">42 U.S.C. 13709(a)</external-xref>) shall not apply to amounts made available by this or any other Act.</text>
 </section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H81BEF79288E447C493E164261E01A164" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>215.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available under this or any other Act, for fiscal year 2018 and each fiscal year thereafter, other than for the national instant criminal background check system established under section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/922">18 U.S.C. 922</external-xref> note), may be used by a Federal law enforcement officer to facilitate the transfer of an operable firearm to an individual if the Federal law enforcement officer knows or suspects that the individual is an agent of a drug cartel, unless law enforcement personnel of the United States continuously monitor or control the firearm at all times.</text>
			</section><section id="H7EDC9DEEB0884A10877A9892453127C2"><enum>216.</enum>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBF36E410F77A4956852D7A5DA8185031"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the income retained in the Department of Justice Working Capital Fund pursuant to title I of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/140">Public Law 102–140</external-xref> (105 Stat. 784; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/527">28 U.S.C. 527</external-xref> note) shall be available for obligation during fiscal year 2018, except up to $40,000,000 may be obligated for implementation of a unified Department of Justice financial management system.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H96DDCA1210CE4DE99A113327AF76F012"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Not to exceed $30,000,000 of the unobligated balances transferred to the capital account of the Department of Justice Working Capital Fund pursuant to title I of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/140">Public Law 102–140</external-xref> (105 Stat. 784; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/527">28 U.S.C. 527</external-xref> note) shall be available for obligation in fiscal year 2018, and any use, obligation, transfer or allocation of such funds shall be treated as a reprogramming of funds under section 505 of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDFA00E201B58424C8BB4D1828318D365"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Not to exceed $10,000,000 of the excess unobligated balances available under section 524(c)(8)(E) of title 28, United States Code, shall be available for obligation during fiscal year 2018, and any use, obligation, transfer or allocation of such funds shall be treated as a reprogramming of funds under section 505 of this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H057B326B75464D139FD075E02CF45F15"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Justice Appropriations Act, 2018</short-title></quote>.</text> </appropriations-small></title><title id="HE9A19586DE6147D2B71177A698B2EE6B"><enum>III</enum><header display-inline="no-display-inline">Science</header> <appropriations-intermediate id="HD0AC1F113DA242DF939A7CAA7103AC8A"><header>Office of science and technology policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in carrying out the purposes of the National Science and Technology Policy, Organization, and Priorities Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6601">42 U.S.C. 6601</external-xref> et seq.), hire of passenger motor vehicles, and services as authorized by section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, not to exceed $2,250 for official reception and representation expenses, and rental of conference rooms in the District of Columbia, $5,544,000.</text>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H73178DCE107442DBB3DEA373616DBC25"><header>National aeronautics and space administration</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H7F4AD50A8A834903A2A79324FA34DF9C"><header>Science</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses, not otherwise provided for, in the conduct and support of science research and development activities, including research, development, operations, support, and services; maintenance and repair, facility planning and design; space flight, spacecraft control, and communications activities; program management; personnel and related costs, including uniforms or allowances therefor, as authorized by sections 5901 and 5902 of title 5, United States Code; travel expenses; purchase and hire of passenger motor vehicles; and purchase, lease, charter, maintenance, and operation of mission and administrative aircraft, $5,858,500,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the formulation and development costs (with development cost as defined under section 30104 of title 51, United States Code) for the James Webb Space Telescope shall not exceed $8,000,000,000: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That should the individual identified under subsection (c)(2)(E) of section 30104 of title 51, United States Code, as responsible for the James Webb Space Telescope determine that the development cost of the program is likely to exceed that limitation, the individual shall immediately notify the Administrator and the increase shall be treated as if it meets the 30 percent threshold described in subsection (f) of section 30104: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That, of the amounts provided, $495,000,000 is for an orbiter and a lander to meet the science goals for the Jupiter Europa mission as outlined in the most recent planetary science decadal survey: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall use the Space Launch System as the launch vehicles for the Jupiter Europa mission, plan for an orbiter launch no later than 2022 and a lander launch no later than 2024, and include in the fiscal year 2019 budget the 5-year funding profile necessary to achieve these goals.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HB069346DA0CD4DA39725422C5C27AC34"><header>Aeronautics</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses, not otherwise provided for, in the conduct and support of aeronautics research and development activities, including research, development, operations, support, and services; maintenance and repair, facility planning and design; space flight, spacecraft control, and communications activities; program management; personnel and related costs, including uniforms or allowances therefor, as authorized by sections 5901 and 5902 of title 5, United States Code; travel expenses; purchase and hire of passenger motor vehicles; and purchase, lease, charter, maintenance, and operation of mission and administrative aircraft, $660,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H3BE7C8D0ECE745038CCF046C2CEFCEAD"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Space Technology</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses, not otherwise provided for, in the conduct and support of space technology research and development activities, including research, development, operations, support, and services; maintenance and repair, facility planning and design; space flight, spacecraft control, and communications activities; program management; personnel and related costs, including uniforms or allowances therefor, as authorized by sections 5901 and 5902 of title 5, United States Code; travel expenses; purchase and hire of passenger motor vehicles; and purchase, lease, charter, maintenance, and operation of mission and administrative aircraft, $686,500,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H2865675256A7446E893BC660B2259E77"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">exploration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses, not otherwise provided for, in the conduct and support of exploration research and development activities, including research, development, operations, support, and services; maintenance and repair, facility planning and design; space flight, spacecraft control, and communications activities; program management; personnel and related costs, including uniforms or allowances therefor, as authorized by sections 5901 and 5902 of title 5, United States Code; travel expenses; purchase and hire of passenger motor vehicles; and purchase, lease, charter, maintenance, and operation of mission and administrative aircraft, $4,550,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not less than $1,350,000,000 shall be for the Orion Multi-Purpose Crew Vehicle: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not less than $2,150,000,000 shall be for the Space Launch System (SLS) launch vehicle, which shall have a lift capability not less than 130 metric tons and which shall have core elements and an Exploration Upper Stage developed simultaneously: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That of the amounts provided for SLS, not less than $300,000,000 shall be for Exploration Upper Stage development: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That $600,000,000 shall be for exploration ground systems: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) shall provide to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, concurrent with the annual budget submission, a 5-year budget profile for an integrated budget that includes the Space Launch System, the Orion Multi-Purpose Crew Vehicle, and associated ground systems, that will meet the Exploration Mission 2 (EM–2) management agreement launch date of no later than 2021 at a success level equal to the Agency Baseline Commitment for EM–2 of the Orion Multi-Purpose Crew Vehicle: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That $450,000,000 shall be for exploration research and development.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HDE7CD50BE6254C5FB2E4ADD5A391852F"><header>Space operations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses, not otherwise provided for, in the conduct and support of space operations research and development activities, including research, development, operations, support and services; space flight, spacecraft control and communications activities, including operations, production, and services; maintenance and repair, facility planning and design; program management; personnel and related costs, including uniforms or allowances therefor, as authorized by sections 5901 and 5902 of title 5, United States Code; travel expenses; purchase and hire of passenger motor vehicles; and purchase, lease, charter, maintenance and operation of mission and administrative aircraft, $4,676,634,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HA416F52733A1456382DED22901D2C376"><header>Education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses, not otherwise provided for, in the conduct and support of aerospace and aeronautical education research and development activities, including research, development, operations, support, and services; program management; personnel and related costs, including uniforms or allowances therefor, as authorized by sections 5901 and 5902 of title 5, United States Code; travel expenses; purchase and hire of passenger motor vehicles; and purchase, lease, charter, maintenance, and operation of mission and administrative aircraft, $90,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019, of which $18,000,000 shall be for the Experimental Program to Stimulate Competitive Research and $40,000,000 shall be for the National Space Grant College and Fellowship Program.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HA14913E31661470391AFE2F3D506B553"><header>Safety, security and mission services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses, not otherwise provided for, in the conduct and support of science, aeronautics, space technology, exploration, space operations and education research and development activities, including research, development, operations, support, and services; maintenance and repair, facility planning and design; space flight, spacecraft control, and communications activities; program management; personnel and related costs, including uniforms or allowances therefor, as authorized by sections 5901 and 5902 of title 5, United States Code; travel expenses; purchase and hire of passenger motor vehicles; not to exceed $63,000 for official reception and representation expenses; and purchase, lease, charter, maintenance, and operation of mission and administrative aircraft, $2,826,200,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H740BBCF6C1D94003A23404509CC4D0C3"><header>Construction and environmental compliance and restoration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses for construction of facilities including repair, rehabilitation, revitalization, and modification of facilities, construction of new facilities and additions to existing facilities, facility planning and design, and restoration, and acquisition or condemnation of real property, as authorized by law, and environmental compliance and restoration, $486,100,000, to remain available until September 30, 2023: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That proceeds from leases deposited into this account shall be available for a period of 5 years to the extent and in amounts as provided in annual appropriations Acts: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That such proceeds referred to in the preceding proviso shall be available for obligation for fiscal year 2018 in an amount not to exceed $9,470,300: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That each annual budget request shall include an annual estimate of gross receipts and collections and proposed use of all funds collected pursuant to section 20145 of title 51, United States Code.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H4CE20F303A974BC090B5CA291DC59969"><header>Office of inspector general</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of Inspector General in carrying out the Inspector General Act of 1978, $37,900,000, of which $500,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2019.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H0DE3606CC9BA4F989F2248D334FC9EBA"><header>Administrative provisions</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H938905BA22FA44E7AB91A8DFD2B5C55F"><header>(including transfers of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Funds for any announced prize otherwise authorized shall remain available, without fiscal year limitation, until a prize is claimed or the offer is withdrawn.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not to exceed 5 percent of any appropriation made available for the current fiscal year for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration in this Act may be transferred between such appropriations, but no such appropriation, except as otherwise specifically provided, shall be increased by more than 10 percent by any such transfers, except that <quote>Construction and Environmental Compliance and Restoration</quote> may be increased up to 20 percent by such transfers. Balances so transferred shall be merged with and available for the same purposes and the same time period as the appropriations to which transferred. Any transfer pursuant to this provision shall be treated as a reprogramming of funds under section 505 of this Act and shall not be available for obligation except in compliance with the procedures set forth in that section.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The spending plan required by this Act shall be provided by NASA at the theme, program, project and activity level. The spending plan, as well as any subsequent change of an amount established in that spending plan that meets the notification requirements of section 505 of this Act, shall be treated as a reprogramming under section 505 of this Act and shall not be available for obligation or expenditure except in compliance with the procedures set forth in that section.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="H0834FEF21D1D4BAD900CFD23B8E7E3AB"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">National Science Foundation</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HF6F88762A1AD43919E069E9A6C914B3B"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Research and Related Activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses in carrying out the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1861">42 U.S.C. 1861</external-xref> et seq.), and <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/86/209">Public Law 86–209</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1880">42 U.S.C. 1880</external-xref> et seq.); services as authorized by section 3109 of title 5, United States Code; maintenance and operation of aircraft and purchase of flight services for research support; acquisition of aircraft; and authorized travel; $6,033,645,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019, of which not to exceed $544,000,000 shall remain available until expended for polar research and operations support, and for reimbursement to other Federal agencies for operational and science support and logistical and other related activities for the United States Antarctic program: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That receipts for scientific support services and materials furnished by the National Research Centers and other National Science Foundation supported research facilities may be credited to this appropriation.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H81A40AE438ED4115B33FCE6465AB2725"><header>Major research equipment and facilities construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses for the acquisition, construction, commissioning, and upgrading of major research equipment, facilities, and other such capital assets pursuant to the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1861">42 U.S.C. 1861</external-xref> et seq.), including authorized travel, $77,800,000, to remain available until expended.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HEB677133D4F44AD795520BD5B3299FBC"><header>Education and human resources</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses in carrying out science, mathematics and engineering education and human resources programs and activities pursuant to the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1861">42 U.S.C. 1861</external-xref> et seq.), including services as authorized by section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, authorized travel, and rental of conference rooms in the District of Columbia, $880,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2019.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HCA9C2209C9514A1DB82B32DD18AFFF38"><header>Agency operations and award management</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For agency operations and award management necessary in carrying out the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1861">42 U.S.C. 1861</external-xref> et seq.); services authorized by section 3109 of title 5, United States Code; hire of passenger motor vehicles; uniforms or allowances therefor, as authorized by sections 5901 and 5902 of title 5, United States Code; rental of conference rooms in the District of Columbia; and reimbursement of the Department of Homeland Security for security guard services; $328,510,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $8,280 is for official reception and representation expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That contracts may be entered into under this heading in fiscal year 2018 for maintenance and operation of facilities and for other services to be provided during the next fiscal year.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HD2350F2A59E6433B921AFAD2BEB153E5"><header>Office of the national science board</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses (including payment of salaries, authorized travel, hire of passenger motor vehicles, the rental of conference rooms in the District of Columbia, and the employment of experts and consultants under section 3109 of title 5, United States Code) involved in carrying out section 4 of the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1863">42 U.S.C. 1863</external-xref>) and <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/86/209">Public Law 86–209</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1880">42 U.S.C. 1880</external-xref> et seq.), $4,370,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $2,500 shall be available for official reception and representation expenses.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H8A9D96A66E6F4055BE9E55E45E7F28C8"><header>Office of inspector general</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of Inspector General as authorized by the Inspector General Act of 1978, $15,200,000, of which $400,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2019.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H4878CEEF0B4B4251BA23F6B577F5B9BA"><header>Administrative provisions</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H4B99BE61CBF14F82964CF423DCF593C9"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not to exceed 5 percent of any appropriation made available for the current fiscal year for the National Science Foundation in this Act may be transferred between such appropriations, but no such appropriation shall be increased by more than 15 percent by any such transfers. Any transfer pursuant to this paragraph shall be treated as a reprogramming of funds under section 505 of this Act and shall not be available for obligation except in compliance with the procedures set forth in that section.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director of the National Science Foundation shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate at least 30 days in advance of the acquisition or disposal of any capital asset (including land, structures, and equipment) not specifically provided for in this Act or any other law appropriating funds for the National Science Foundation.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HEB626F4FBA774148BAF6EC3DB8162841"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Science Appropriations Act, 2018</short-title></quote>.</text> </appropriations-small></title><title commented="no" id="HDD7906AD28E84A428951D59DAA7EA196" level-type="subsequent"><enum>IV</enum> <appropriations-major commented="no" id="H3685E121C02544E9B47C710EC46E9499"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Related Agencies</header> </appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="HF53AF0EB81834FAF831D616CAF4EEE33"><header>Commission on civil rights</header> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H82F377EE71734CD08F4C7A91638263E0"><header>Salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Commission on Civil Rights, including hire of passenger motor vehicles, $9,183,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That none of the funds appropriated in this paragraph may be used to employ any individuals under Schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5 of the Code of Federal Regulations exclusive of one special assistant for each Commissioner: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That none of the funds appropriated in this paragraph shall be used to reimburse Commissioners for more than 75 billable days, with the exception of the chairperson, who is permitted 125 billable days: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That none of the funds appropriated in this paragraph shall be used for any activity or expense that is not explicitly authorized by section 3 of the Civil Rights Commission Act of 1983 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1975a">42 U.S.C. 1975a</external-xref>).</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H17AB6CE773F34657B1C4AED908038517"><header>Equal employment opportunity commission</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HE8E6C08BAB2F41F4B4A171438E41FAD5"><header>Salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission as authorized by title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967, the Equal Pay Act of 1963, the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990, section 501 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, the Civil Rights Act of 1991, the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act (GINA) of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/233">Public Law 110–233</external-xref>), the ADA Amendments Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/325">Public Law 110–325</external-xref>), and the Lilly Ledbetter Fair Pay Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/2">Public Law 111–2</external-xref>), including services as authorized by section 3109 of title 5, United States Code; hire of passenger motor vehicles as authorized by section 1343(b) of title 31, United States Code; nonmonetary awards to private citizens; and up to $29,500,000 for payments to State and local enforcement agencies for authorized services to the Commission, $363,807,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the Commission is authorized to make available for official reception and representation expenses not to exceed $2,250 from available funds: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the Chair is authorized to accept and use any gift or donation to carry out the work of the Commission.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="H631B1576EC654066A1F3D14F7A8BDD14"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">International Trade Commission</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HE42C224BC0B44F798D05DB198A5D72E8"><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the International Trade Commission, including hire of passenger motor vehicles and services as authorized by section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, and not to exceed $2,250 for official reception and representation expenses, $92,500,000, to remain available until expended.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HAEA99343FAA642A3AACAC908FB48512D"><header>Legal services corporation</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HAE1F2C6D33C44253A03C199BF6217DBA"><header>Payment to the legal services corporation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For payment to the Legal Services Corporation to carry out the purposes of the Legal Services Corporation Act of 1974, $300,000,000, of which $267,000,000 is for basic field programs and required independent audits; $5,000,000 is for the Office of Inspector General, of which such amounts as may be necessary may be used to conduct additional audits of recipients; $19,000,000 is for management and grants oversight; $4,000,000 is for client self-help and information technology; $4,000,000 is for a Pro Bono Innovation Fund; and $1,000,000 is for loan repayment assistance: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the Legal Services Corporation may continue to provide locality pay to officers and employees at a rate no greater than that provided by the Federal Government to Washington, DC-based employees as authorized by section 5304 of title 5, United States Code, notwithstanding section 1005(d) of the Legal Services Corporation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2996">42 U.S.C. 2996(d)</external-xref>): <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the authorities provided in section 205 of this Act shall be applicable to the Legal Services Corporation: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That, for the purposes of section 505 of this Act, the Legal Services Corporation shall be considered an agency of the United States Government.</text>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H5829803058FB4AF1A1D7C0F272FADEC5"><header>Administrative provision—legal services corporation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated in this Act to the Legal Services Corporation shall be expended for any purpose prohibited or limited by, or contrary to any of the provisions of, sections 501, 502, 503, 504, 505, and 506 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/119">Public Law 105–119</external-xref>, and all funds appropriated in this Act to the Legal Services Corporation shall be subject to the same terms and conditions set forth in such sections, except that all references in sections 502 and 503 to 1997 and 1998 shall be deemed to refer instead to 2017 and 2018, respectively.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H0D1F5D6794D3437C83A9A98FEBD79CEF"><header>Marine mammal commission</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H476D75176AA244C49251B55EEC80690D"><header>Salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Marine Mammal Commission as authorized by title II of the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1361">16 U.S.C. 1361</external-xref> et seq.), $3,431,000.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HB14D5880448F438CA756527A8548087F"><header>Office of the United States Trade Representative</header>
			</appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H0F533A8F56704E35AF1D34A012CBE0DE"><header>Salaries and expenses</header>
 </appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H337CD4F7A9B0482AA7A34AF80C2A1F37"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the United States Trade Representative, including the hire of passenger motor vehicles and the employment of experts and consultants as authorized by section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, $53,000,000, of which $1,000,000 shall remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That of the total amount made available under this heading, not to exceed $124,000 shall be available for official reception and representation expenses.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HFC7022C167CF4AB6A246E83594CF8879"><header>Trade Enforcement Trust Fund</header>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H558ED0C236A54F2BA5206C3BF3ADBE12"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For activities of the United States Trade Representative authorized by section 611 of the Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/4405">19 U.S.C. 4405</external-xref>), including transfers, $15,000,000, to be derived from the Trade Enforcement Trust Fund: <italic>Provided</italic>, That any transfer pursuant to subsection (d)(1) of such section shall be treated as a reprogramming under section 505 of this Act.</text>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HD9F39CEB965541CC8AC0AA4745FF1DFC"><header>State justice institute</header>
 </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H6BA93305D2044B8DA5F1C51C2742FC8F"><header>Salaries and expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the State Justice Institute, as authorized by the State Justice Institute Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10701">42 U.S.C. 10701</external-xref> et seq.) $5,111,000, of which $500,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2019: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $2,250 shall be available for official reception and representation expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That, for the purposes of section 505 of this Act, the State Justice Institute shall be considered an agency of the United States Government.</text>
			</appropriations-small></title><title id="HC642DFA4FA9548DB880A151618A89D34"><enum>V</enum><header display-inline="no-display-inline">General provisions</header>
			<appropriations-small id="H8E1D3C73FA404827A6903F81CF2A144F"><header>(including rescissions)</header>
			</appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H896695E32BAB4F39B7886B78766F79E6"><header>(including transfers of funds)</header>
 </appropriations-small><section id="H24B18084AA754BDFAD39BE0340DFF8ED"><enum>501.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No part of any appropriation contained in this Act shall be used for publicity or propaganda purposes not authorized by the Congress.</text>
 </section><section id="H178B8D952F2A4E498B09A380FDBA20DB"><enum>502.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No part of any appropriation contained in this Act shall remain available for obligation beyond the current fiscal year unless expressly so provided herein.</text>
 </section><section id="HD9A6DBA1FEEA491E88932FAA7EA15E61"><enum>503.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The expenditure of any appropriation under this Act for any consulting service through procurement contract, pursuant to section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, shall be limited to those contracts where such expenditures are a matter of public record and available for public inspection, except where otherwise provided under existing law, or under existing Executive order issued pursuant to existing law.</text>
 </section><section id="HBEE932D180EA4A06AABCE636F542FD90"><enum>504.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or the application of such provision to any person or circumstances shall be held invalid, the remainder of the Act and the application of each provision to persons or circumstances other than those as to which it is held invalid shall not be affected thereby.</text>
 </section><section id="H9702FFC9F65B4CE983A98AC0BD911346"><enum>505.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds provided under this Act, or provided under previous appropriations Acts to the agencies funded by this Act that remain available for obligation or expenditure in fiscal year 2018, or provided from any accounts in the Treasury of the United States derived by the collection of fees available to the agencies funded by this Act, shall be available for obligation or expenditure through a reprogramming of funds that: (1) creates or initiates a new program, project or activity; (2) eliminates a program, project or activity; (3) increases funds or personnel by any means for any project or activity for which funds have been denied or restricted; (4) relocates an office or employees; (5) reorganizes or renames offices, programs or activities; (6) contracts out or privatizes any functions or activities presently performed by Federal employees; (7) augments existing programs, projects or activities in excess of $500,000 or 10 percent, whichever is less, or reduces by 10 percent funding for any program, project or activity, or numbers of personnel by 10 percent; or (8) results from any general savings, including savings from a reduction in personnel, which would result in a change in existing programs, projects or activities as approved by Congress; unless the House and Senate Committees on Appropriations are notified 15 days in advance of such reprogramming of funds.</text>
			</section><section id="H4C1EE92ECEC64114A39C02D36A3CC4A7"><enum>506.</enum>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD2472F81B30A4416AA0F6FF699B06671"><enum>(a)</enum><text>If it has been finally determined by a court or Federal agency that any person intentionally affixed a label bearing a <quote>Made in America</quote> inscription, or any inscription with the same meaning, to any product sold in or shipped to the United States that is not made in the United States, the person shall be ineligible to receive any contract or subcontract made with funds made available in this Act, pursuant to the debarment, suspension, and ineligibility procedures described in sections 9.400 through 9.409 of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
				</subsection><subsection id="HE74034B8D23C4B73B616628B34D9CAA3"><enum>(b)</enum>
 <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA896693D17844389A8DAED52DD43874F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To the extent practicable, with respect to authorized purchases of promotional items, funds made available by this Act shall be used to purchase items that are manufactured, produced, or assembled in the United States, its territories or possessions.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HCC7A675DA51A4A99B68E90B3FB077B44" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>promotional items</quote> has the meaning given the term in OMB Circular A–87, Attachment B, Item (1)(f)(3).</text> </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1A7B5560A7A94F86A98530A665FB73F8"><enum>507.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H50B1819E60EE459AB45A81C89067701B"><enum>(a)</enum><text>The Departments of Commerce and Justice, the National Science Foundation, and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall provide to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a quarterly report on the status of balances of appropriations at the account level. For unobligated, uncommitted balances and unobligated, committed balances the quarterly reports shall separately identify the amounts attributable to each source year of appropriation from which the balances were derived. For balances that are obligated, but unexpended, the quarterly reports shall separately identify amounts by the year of obligation.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H2CEB5040701A4994BD224FC76818ABA9"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The report described in subsection (a) shall be submitted within 30 days of the end of each quarter.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H8E989DADB48141209404440FF14EFDAB"><enum>(c)</enum><text>If a department or agency is unable to fulfill any aspect of a reporting requirement described in subsection (a) due to a limitation of a current accounting system, the department or agency shall fulfill such aspect to the maximum extent practicable under such accounting system and shall identify and describe in each quarterly report the extent to which such aspect is not fulfilled.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HDC35214388274C1EAA1C6A6191D738C1"><enum>508.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any costs incurred by a department or agency funded under this Act resulting from, or to prevent, personnel actions taken in response to funding reductions included in this Act shall be absorbed within the total budgetary resources available to such department or agency: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That the authority to transfer funds between appropriations accounts as may be necessary to carry out this section is provided in addition to authorities included elsewhere in this Act: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That use of funds to carry out this section shall be treated as a reprogramming of funds under section 505 of this Act and shall not be available for obligation or expenditure except in compliance with the procedures set forth in that section: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That for the Department of Commerce, this section shall also apply to actions taken for the care and protection of loan collateral or grant property.</text>
 </section><section id="H133B7371650E4B43B528EBBE7858C114"><enum>509.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds provided by this Act shall be available to promote the sale or export of tobacco or tobacco products, or to seek the reduction or removal by any foreign country of restrictions on the marketing of tobacco or tobacco products, except for restrictions which are not applied equally to all tobacco or tobacco products of the same type.</text>
			</section><section id="d64e1438">
				<enum>510.</enum>
 <text>None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to pay the salaries and expenses of personnel of the Department of Justice to obligate more than $4,632,000,000 during fiscal year 2018 from the fund established by section 1402 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/98/473">Public Law 98–473</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10601">42 U.S.C. 10601</external-xref>): <italic>Provided</italic>, That notwithstanding such section 1402(d), of the amounts available from the Fund for obligation, 5 percent shall be available for grants to Indian tribal governments to improve services and justice for victims of crime.</text>
 </section><section id="H33C8CC957A7041A7A21B53D8E0C49521"><enum>511.</enum><text>None of the funds made available to the Department of Justice in this Act may be used to discriminate against or denigrate the religious or moral beliefs of students who participate in programs for which financial assistance is provided from those funds, or of the parents or legal guardians of such students.</text>
 </section><section id="H0B7ACD5932BD4A79A8642D02B1963CF9"><enum>512.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be transferred to any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government, except pursuant to a transfer made by, or transfer authority provided in, this Act or any other appropriations Act.</text>
 </section><section id="H64B17A57871D49D7AAB17A427B2A292F"><enum>513.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any funds provided in this Act used to implement E-Government Initiatives shall be subject to the procedures set forth in section 505 of this Act.</text>
			</section><section id="HDF423697447845A59BB3E138B88F030B"><enum>514.</enum>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H50F44A59E13E40B28C8E698AF9DE82AD"><enum>(a)</enum><text>None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available under this Act may be used by the Departments of Commerce and Justice, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, or the National Science Foundation to acquire a high-impact or moderate-impact information system, as defined for security categorization in the National Institute of Standards and Technology's (NIST) Federal Information Processing Standard Publication 199, <quote>Standards for Security Categorization of Federal Information and Information Systems</quote> unless the agency has—</text>
 <paragraph id="HFE030EFA189647328DC00F602CA8312A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reviewed the supply chain risk for the information systems against criteria developed by NIST and the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to inform acquisition decisions for high-impact and moderate-impact information systems within the Federal Government;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4C862BF9C8CB4209AC2F839B5E7160BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reviewed the supply chain risk from the presumptive awardee against available and relevant threat information provided by the FBI and other appropriate agencies; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H4E9A7AAC7C124BBAA0628320ACC4FA56"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in consultation with the FBI or other appropriate Federal entity, conducted an assessment of any risk of cyber-espionage or sabotage associated with the acquisition of such system, including any risk associated with such system being produced, manufactured, or assembled by one or more entities identified by the United States Government as posing a cyber threat, including but not limited to, those that may be owned, directed, or subsidized by the People's Republic of China, the Islamic Republic of Iran, the Democratic People's Republic of Korea, or the Russian Federation.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H02499D9779B94BCAAE73AA69C8068D4A"><enum>(b)</enum><text>None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available under this Act may be used to acquire a high-impact or moderate-impact information system reviewed and assessed under subsection (a) unless the head of the assessing entity described in subsection (a) has—</text>
 <paragraph id="H9C27666564B04A95AC257794A49943F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>developed, in consultation with NIST, the FBI, and supply chain risk management experts, a mitigation strategy for any identified risks;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H6C938EF21A0A46AC845005904750D102"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determined, in consultation with NIST and the FBI, that the acquisition of such system is in the national interest of the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB78D551D1624355B64A994B0FFC0295"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reported that determination to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate and the agency Inspector General.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD2AC15F3018C4DB9B008AD2780BD4E4F"><enum>515.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act shall be used in any way whatsoever to support or justify the use of torture by any official or contract employee of the United States Government.</text>
			</section><section id="H6ACEA5578B3D4C43B43A9A6726EB2228"><enum>516.</enum>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC8C8D0430D4E4DBBA01CE86E4A98AC83"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law or treaty, in fiscal year 2018 and each fiscal year thereafter, none of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available under this Act or any other Act may be expended or obligated by a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States to pay administrative expenses or to compensate an officer or employee of the United States in connection with requiring an export license for the export to Canada of components, parts, accessories or attachments for firearms listed in Category I, section 121.1 of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations (International Trafficking in Arms Regulations (ITAR), part 121, as it existed on April 1, 2005) with a total value not exceeding $500 wholesale in any transaction, provided that the conditions of subsection (b) of this section are met by the exporting party for such articles.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HFB34740D019D40239ACBC7895FEF6094"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The foregoing exemption from obtaining an export license—</text> <paragraph id="HA2ED426F861F47669E19EEB2C794DC4C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>does not exempt an exporter from filing any Shipper's Export Declaration or notification letter required by law, or from being otherwise eligible under the laws of the United States to possess, ship, transport, or export the articles enumerated in subsection (a); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HF5C660F33DC04D3D9382A80A4710E118"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not permit the export without a license of—</text> <subparagraph id="H0E0D24108A3B46EC943D2B76D83E7556"><enum>(A)</enum><text>fully automatic firearms and components and parts for such firearms, other than for end use by the Federal Government, or a Provincial or Municipal Government of Canada;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74A37D7AF9394FE78C2C4D656BE61577"><enum>(B)</enum><text>barrels, cylinders, receivers (frames) or complete breech mechanisms for any firearm listed in Category I, other than for end use by the Federal Government, or a Provincial or Municipal Government of Canada; or</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE8105DB08F941F0880E34036F34BED3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>articles for export from Canada to another foreign destination.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1B3CADCFF2FE4859A8E9A7A6BE8DD0BC"><enum>(c)</enum><text>In accordance with this section, the District Directors of Customs and postmasters shall permit the permanent or temporary export without a license of any unclassified articles specified in subsection (a) to Canada for end use in Canada or return to the United States, or temporary import of Canadian-origin items from Canada for end use in the United States or return to Canada for a Canadian citizen.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HEE0B5486F088445C931E0BB37B5799FB"><enum>(d)</enum><text>The President may require export licenses under this section on a temporary basis if the President determines, upon publication first in the Federal Register, that the Government of Canada has implemented or maintained inadequate import controls for the articles specified in subsection (a), such that a significant diversion of such articles has and continues to take place for use in international terrorism or in the escalation of a conflict in another nation. The President shall terminate the requirements of a license when reasons for the temporary requirements have ceased.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HEAF50C20272D4408BCAB4950E0D60BF5"><enum>517.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in fiscal year 2018 and each fiscal year thereafter, no department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States receiving appropriated funds under this Act or any other Act shall obligate or expend in any way such funds to pay administrative expenses or the compensation of any officer or employee of the United States to deny any application submitted pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2778">22 U.S.C. 2778(b)(1)(B)</external-xref> and qualified pursuant to 27 CFR section 478.112 or .113, for a permit to import United States origin <quote>curios or relics</quote> firearms, parts, or ammunition.</text>
 </section><section id="H2DEBA370568247959ED77209F6905FA2"><enum>518.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to include in any new bilateral or multilateral trade agreement the text of—</text>
 <paragraph id="HE130F48D148243758AC13EC81793D946"><enum>(1)</enum><text>paragraph 2 of article 16.7 of the United States–Singapore Free Trade Agreement;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HAD1F1BFA1E454FDD96571AD178C7862A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>paragraph 4 of article 17.9 of the United States–Australia Free Trade Agreement; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5EAB91D1AB584139B1E0A2EF875D40A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>paragraph 4 of article 15.9 of the United States–Morocco Free Trade Agreement.</text> </paragraph></section><section id="H8E4E3A0D33AB4970A4F1B8A36B66C301"><enum>519.</enum><text>None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to authorize or issue a national security letter in contravention of any of the following laws authorizing the Federal Bureau of Investigation to issue national security letters: The Right to Financial Privacy Act of 1978; The Electronic Communications Privacy Act of 1986; The Fair Credit Reporting Act; The National Security Act of 1947; USA PATRIOT Act; USA FREEDOM Act of 2015; and the laws amended by these Acts.</text>
 </section><section id="HA0E81A0C2D70441FAD7E4D6C376004D1"><enum>520.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If at any time during any quarter, the program manager of a project within the jurisdiction of the Departments of Commerce or Justice, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, or the National Science Foundation totaling more than $75,000,000 has reasonable cause to believe that the total program cost has increased by 10 percent or more, the program manager shall immediately inform the respective Secretary, Administrator, or Director. The Secretary, Administrator, or Director shall notify the House and Senate Committees on Appropriations within 30 days in writing of such increase, and shall include in such notice: the date on which such determination was made; a statement of the reasons for such increases; the action taken and proposed to be taken to control future cost growth of the project; changes made in the performance or schedule milestones and the degree to which such changes have contributed to the increase in total program costs or procurement costs; new estimates of the total project or procurement costs; and a statement validating that the project's management structure is adequate to control total project or procurement costs.</text>
 </section><section id="HB826EA694E234B1BB8CF7F1C47E03479"><enum>521.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds appropriated by this Act, or made available by the transfer of funds in this Act, for intelligence or intelligence related activities are deemed to be specifically authorized by the Congress for purposes of section 504 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3094">50 U.S.C. 3094</external-xref>) during fiscal year 2018 until the enactment of the Intelligence Authorization Act for fiscal year 2018.</text>
 </section><section id="H9877A03143C04598BE292B224C3E6DFE"><enum>522.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available by this Act may be used to enter into a contract in an amount greater than $5,000,000 or to award a grant in excess of such amount unless the prospective contractor or grantee certifies in writing to the agency awarding the contract or grant that, to the best of its knowledge and belief, the contractor or grantee has filed all Federal tax returns required during the three years preceding the certification, has not been convicted of a criminal offense under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and has not, more than 90 days prior to certification, been notified of any unpaid Federal tax assessment for which the liability remains unsatisfied, unless the assessment is the subject of an installment agreement or offer in compromise that has been approved by the Internal Revenue Service and is not in default, or the assessment is the subject of a non-frivolous administrative or judicial proceeding.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="HBFD2FFFE838C422EB3EE5AD2B440B8B0"><header>(rescissions)</header>
				</appropriations-small></section><section id="H92D722F884A045D49D7108BE7C9BF118"><enum>523.</enum>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC62C3DF16F2F413CA95C98582EAF889A"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Of the unobligated balances from prior year appropriations available to the Department of Commerce, the following funds are hereby rescinded, not later than September 30, 2018, from the following accounts in the specified amounts—</text>
 <paragraph id="HB4443B9CF4AB403091426CD5BC9FB8E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text><quote>Economic Development Administration, Economic Development Assistance Programs</quote>, $47,000,000; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="HEC0831F15BB5456FB2320392FEF5DB04"><enum>(2)</enum><text><quote>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, Operations, Research, and Facilities</quote>, $20,000,000.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF0DC068BFDFF4E318A8D0F2FBA2EF8D1"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the unobligated balances available to the Department of Justice, the following funds are hereby rescinded, not later than September 30, 2018, from the following accounts in the specified amounts—</text>
 <paragraph id="HC43D4860D7294F339AC642B8ED9B7B18"><enum>(1)</enum><text><quote>Working Capital Fund</quote>, $409,834,000;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H54E1698876B544518516A43A7524D18A"><enum>(2)</enum><text><quote>Federal Bureau of Investigation, Salaries and Expenses</quote>, $195,000,000 from fees collected to defray expenses for the automation of fingerprint identification and criminal justice information services and associated costs;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H972CABC8E4CC41F49AE86243D1120024"><enum>(3)</enum><text><quote>State and Local Law Enforcement Activities, Office on Violence Against Women, Violence Against Women Prevention and Prosecution Programs</quote>, $17,500,000;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H86DBD63C7A5B4BB193919C55846E2B88"><enum>(4)</enum><text><quote>State and Local Law Enforcement Activities, Office of Justice Programs</quote>, $60,000,000;</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H624D2EC84FD64C9A94D12C2418DDC05F"><enum>(5)</enum><text><quote>State and Local Law Enforcement Activities, Community Oriented Policing Services</quote>, $17,500,000;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H48E84208AB354B4CB287545258A677BF"><enum>(6)</enum><text><quote>Legal Activities, Assets Forfeiture Fund</quote>, $304,000,000 is permanently rescinded; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H49484E2333D44B16BDBD7B0C4A205666"><enum>(7)</enum><text><quote>Federal Bureau of Investigation, Salaries and Expenses</quote>, $53,365,000.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7E0BB2F997A7479D896084D756BBC2BF"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The Departments of Commerce and Justice shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report no later than September 1, 2018, specifying the amount of each rescission made pursuant to subsections (a) and (b), and the Department of Justice shall ensure that sufficient balances are available in the <quote>Working Capital Fund</quote> to rescind the amount specified in subsection (b) and shall transfer unobligated balances from discretionary appropriations (except from <quote>Federal Bureau of Investigation, Salaries and Expenses</quote>, <quote>Fees and Expenses of Witnesses</quote>, <quote>Public Safety Officer Benefits</quote>, and amounts that were designated by the Congress as an emergency or disaster relief requirement pursuant to a concurrent resolution on the budget or section 251(b)(2) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985) made available in this Act to the Department into the <quote>Working Capital Fund</quote> if necessary to meet the amount specified in subsection (b) and this transfer authority is in addition to any other transfer authority contained in this Act.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H9168F02C96E148B089FCD341E32F643B"><enum>524.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to purchase first class or premium airline travel in contravention of sections 301–10.122 through 301–10.124 of title 41 of the Code of Federal Regulations.</text>
 </section><section id="HDABBBA5BB5004AB48812CEA1C69250BA"><enum>525.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to send or otherwise pay for the attendance of more than 50 employees from a Federal department or agency, who are stationed in the United States, at any single conference occurring outside the United States unless such conference is a law enforcement training or operational conference for law enforcement personnel and the majority of Federal employees in attendance are law enforcement personnel stationed outside the United States.</text>
 </section><section id="H720B8C4BEF3F4C3A97CD49FBF7AFB8A4"><enum>526.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available in this or any other Act may be used to transfer, release, or assist in the transfer or release to or within the United States, its territories, or possessions Khalid Sheikh Mohammed or any other detainee who—</text>
 <paragraph id="HAD32979870C545B5BBE3A5E02F77A2C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is not a United States citizen or a member of the Armed Forces of the United States; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H49BAD272779242528F87E7FCE4FDC26A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is or was held on or after June 24, 2009, at the United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, by the Department of Defense.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="H50919787769C4387AE6FEE6BE42D5FC6"><enum>527.</enum>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF3AF404AA6B24E3EBFED4C1B93D6F4C1"><enum>(a)</enum><text>None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available in this or any other Act may be used to construct, acquire, or modify any facility in the United States, its territories, or possessions to house any individual described in subsection (c) for the purposes of detention or imprisonment in the custody or under the effective control of the Department of Defense.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA6DFC22FA37C43A8812D97C2D4449C2C"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The prohibition in subsection (a) shall not apply to any modification of facilities at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H155758A4B44F47C1A4230D06C5A9E0CE"><enum>(c)</enum><text>An individual described in this subsection is any individual who, as of June 24, 2009, is located at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, and who—</text>
 <paragraph id="H7DC5E87A91B04A9F8984B39699548234"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is not a citizen of the United States or a member of the Armed Forces of the United States; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H2A9FEE59999B4F8EA07D9AD3D8C1CABC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is—</text>
 <subparagraph id="HCB5B7BBBFDCE479F8CDA9305BD96E6D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the custody or under the effective control of the Department of Defense; or</text> </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AB69AA578A840E5B695A97974D0352C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>otherwise under detention at United States Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE7F782AEC15048E0BE433525CFCF48A4"><enum>528.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall instruct any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States receiving funds appropriated under this Act to track undisbursed balances in expired grant accounts and include in its annual performance plan and performance and accountability reports the following:</text>
 <paragraph id="HDBE4317D4834498B8557DFEDF0C3D552"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Details on future action the department, agency, or instrumentality will take to resolve undisbursed balances in expired grant accounts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H24C539CC23D94A76A83413E5A930F32B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The method that the department, agency, or instrumentality uses to track undisbursed balances in expired grant accounts.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H12171ED59A7E46139E41A7B0D9FC39D4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Identification of undisbursed balances in expired grant accounts that may be returned to the Treasury of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HADBAE4BAE8634A9296B1E046C55C8BAF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In the preceding 3 fiscal years, details on the total number of expired grant accounts with undisbursed balances (on the first day of each fiscal year) for the department, agency, or instrumentality and the total finances that have not been obligated to a specific project remaining in the accounts.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="H0558C04FE9FA47E7A7305D6E276F1780"><enum>529.</enum>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFA3127FB38BA4EB9B3F96ECFFC0DE08E"><enum>(a)</enum><text>None of the funds made available by this Act may be used for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) or the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) to develop, design, plan, promulgate, implement, or execute a bilateral policy, program, order, or contract of any kind to participate, collaborate, or coordinate bilaterally in any way with China or any Chinese-owned company unless such activities are specifically authorized by a law enacted after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3D968AF617D54687B3A5FBA8C76D018E"><enum>(b)</enum><text>None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to effectuate the hosting of official Chinese visitors at facilities belonging to or utilized by NASA.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3045080CD033463BA7B0A32F44709F38"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The limitations described in subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to activities which NASA or OSTP, after consultation with the Federal Bureau of Investigation, have certified—</text>
 <paragraph id="H5266F29DD8834410B9B84718E39D1457"><enum>(1)</enum><text>pose no risk of resulting in the transfer of technology, data, or other information with national security or economic security implications to China or a Chinese-owned company; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HFB2BA1B6EB3B424C88BEB5E53DCA3A39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>will not involve knowing interactions with officials who have been determined by the United States to have direct involvement with violations of human rights.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5F19A4F540B748168EA3930B3A9DE78B"><enum>(d)</enum><text>Any certification made under subsection (c) shall be submitted to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, and the Federal Bureau of Investigation, no later than 30 days prior to the activity in question and shall include a description of the purpose of the activity, its agenda, its major participants, and its location and timing.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HDA4E0C746F4B4B848A813432FE54B623"><enum>530.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this or any other Act, for fiscal year 2018 and each fiscal year thereafter, may be used to pay the salaries or expenses of personnel to deny, or fail to act on, an application for the importation of any model of shotgun if—</text>
 <paragraph id="H8EA88A4A06ED4BD6BE571BC2BD872F98"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all other requirements of law with respect to the proposed importation are met; and</text> </paragraph><paragraph id="H74A761AF6D3C466BAB571EB4DF1693A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no application for the importation of such model of shotgun, in the same configuration, had been denied by the Attorney General prior to January 1, 2011, on the basis that the shotgun was not particularly suitable for or readily adaptable to sporting purposes.</text>
				</paragraph></section><section id="HE68721B237D3430398A77CB62E3EC8B2"><enum>531.</enum>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9E31D8711E0446EB9DFBA55343EC7D81"><enum>(a)</enum><text>None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to maintain or establish a computer network unless such network blocks the viewing, downloading, and exchanging of pornography.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD7F2202E48B8495C85A8CE4BB7368428"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Nothing in subsection (a) shall limit the use of funds necessary for any Federal, State, tribal, or local law enforcement agency or any other entity carrying out criminal investigations, prosecution, adjudication, or other law enforcement- or victim assistance-related activity.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="HA5B006E377924A55A01B0A4A4974F37C"><enum>532.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Departments of Commerce and Justice, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the National Science Foundation, the Commission on Civil Rights, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the International Trade Commission, the Legal Services Corporation, the Marine Mammal Commission, the Offices of Science and Technology Policy and the United States Trade Representative, and the State Justice Institute shall submit spending plans, signed by the respective department or agency head, to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate within 45 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text>
 </section><section id="H41B225D0FBA54B0B9E3E3C0365700798"><enum>533.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be obligated or expended to implement the Arms Trade Treaty until the Senate approves a resolution of ratification for the Treaty.</text>
 </section><section id="H872F885554CE4559B921986B2C1F3315"><enum>534.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Commerce, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and the National Science Foundation shall provide a quarterly report to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate on any official travel to China by any employee of such Department or agency, including the purpose of such travel.</text>
 </section><section id="H4E7BBBA0A82340758640DA71EB14292F"><enum>535.</enum><text>Of the amounts made available by this Act, not less than 10 percent of each total amount provided, respectively, for Public Works grants authorized by the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 and grants authorized by section 27 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3722">15 U.S.C. 3722</external-xref>) shall be allocated for assistance in persistent poverty counties: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That for purposes of this section, the term <quote>persistent poverty counties</quote> means any county that has had 20 percent or more of its population living in poverty over the past 30 years, as measured by the 1990 and 2000 decennial censuses and the most recent Small Area Income and Poverty Estimates.</text>
			</section><section id="H0BA953ADA0D140729C736FB70711585B"><enum>536.</enum>
 <text>None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to approve the registration or renewal of, or maintain the registration of, a mark, trade name, or commercial name, under the Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide for the registration and protection of trademarks used in commerce, to carry out the provisions of certain international conventions, and for other purposes</quote>, approved July 6, 1946 (commonly referred to as the <quote>Trademark Act of 1946</quote>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1051">15 U.S.C. 1051</external-xref> et seq.), including the receipt or acceptance of post-registration affidavits or declarations, where such mark, trade name, or commercial name is the same or substantially similar to a mark, trade name, or commercial name that was used in connection with a business or assets that were confiscated, as that term is defined in section 4(4) of the Cuban Liberty and Democratic Solidarity (LIBERTAD) Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6023">22 U.S.C. 6023(4)</external-xref>), unless the original owner of the mark, trade name, or commercial name, or the bona-fide successor-in-interest has expressly consented.</text>
			</section><section id="H5CA4EB6EA94E4495B2F8D6088F1B5AFA"><enum>537.</enum>
 <text>None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to require a person licensed under section 923 of title 18, United States Code, to report information to the Department of Justice regarding the sale of multiple rifles or shotguns to the same person.</text>
			</section><section id="HC356E4D2A3374B7B9F1E873F1AF93B03"><enum>538.</enum>
 <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H28D81AD8112D4EA698BFDA66F17181B1"><enum>(a)</enum><text>A State may bring a civil action against the United States in an appropriate United States district court for such declaratory and injunctive relief (including preliminary injunctive relief) as may be necessary to restore the sovereignty reserved to the States by the Constitution. It shall be duty of the courts of the United States to advance on the docket and to expedite to the greatest possible extent the disposition of any such action.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HD40B7FEFA1F744DB857446CEF6AB66C8"><enum>(b)</enum><text>This section shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act and continue in effect through all fiscal years thereafter.</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" id="HCCC9D6E732E949089D81D4E38A16B0F1"><enum>539.</enum><text>None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to relocate the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF) Canine Training Center or the ATF National Canine Division.</text>
 </section><section id="HDB7B0BA1576041CE9F48ADF993150C6C"><enum>540.</enum><text>None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to enter into a civil settlement agreement on behalf of the United States that includes a term requiring that any donation be made to any non-party by any party-defendant to such agreement.</text>
 </section><section id="HC0806C618E814F7FAD109427F35E3D63"><enum>541.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to implement or enforce the designation of any area of the Chesapeake Bay watershed as critical habitat for the Atlantic Sturgeon pursuant to the proposed rule published June 3, 2016 (81 Fed. Reg. 35701).</text>
 </section><section id="H8D7AEB3ECA0D4353A8FA8A88B2DDEA14"><enum>542.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used by the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission for the <quote>collection of information</quote>, as defined in the Paperwork Reduction Act (44 U.S.C. § 3502(3)(A)), from employers relating to employees’ earnings and hours worked, as set forth in and designated as Component 2 by the notice published by the Commission on July 14, 2016, in the Federal Register (81 Fed. Reg. 45479), or for any final <quote>collection of information</quote> related to such earnings and hours worked and to such notice.</text>
				<appropriations-small id="H7F1E7E8A3597444BA02CDA4217A3BE59"><header>spending reduction account</header>
 </appropriations-small></section><section id="HD05406782DB7425F99DBA4C1BF57E9C4"><enum>543.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$0.</text> <appropriations-small id="H90BEE6E0D8C14C8CBD158828D24B1CF5"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2018</short-title></quote>.</text>
				</appropriations-small></section></title></legis-body>
	<endorsement display="yes">
		<action-date>July 17, 2017</action-date>
		<action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement>
</bill>


