<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="H0D9296D89FD3484FAB944806F2A6DC48" key="H" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 956 IH: Effective Assistance of Counsel in the Digital Era Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2017-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">115th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 956</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20170207">February 7, 2017</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001093">Mr. Collins of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To regulate monitoring of electronic communications between a prisoner in a Bureau of Prisons
			 facility and that prisoner’s attorney or other legal representative, and
			 for other purposes.</official-title></form>
	<legis-body id="HDBC884DE9B484909A7DD8A2E810EF03B" style="OLC">
 <section id="H0F01E11AF2574C8888BD3A0F7ABB6492" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Effective Assistance of Counsel in the Digital Era Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94ACF01D5C33497F8F2719FB712DFD7F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Monitoring of electronic communications between prisoner and attorney</header> <subsection id="H19B0AD31BE39469A922BA699DB5F0614"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on monitoring</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall modify any program or system through which a prisoner (as such term is defined in section 107) sends or receives an electronic communication (as such term is defined in section 2510 of title 18, United States Code, and including the Trust Fund Limited Inmate Computer System) to exclude from monitoring the contents (as such term is defined in section 2510 of title 18, United States Code) of an electronic communication between a prisoner in a Bureau of Prisons facility and his or her attorney or other legal representative.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H1B5D1D90B1FC405EB690B770CD77A847"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Retention of contents</header><text>The modification required under subsection (a) may allow for the retention of the contents of the electronic communications described in subsection (a).</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H54BF783244AF4215B1ADF13283F9A6E5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a court of competent jurisdiction determines that there is sufficient evidence to support a reasonable belief of the Government that the information contained in an electronic communication described in subsection (a) was for the purpose of perpetrating a fraud or crime, an in camera review of the contents of the communication may be conducted.</text>
			</subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


